<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="36" verseCount="43" nextChapter="genesis_37.html" nextTitle="Genesis 37" prevChapter="genesis_35.html" prevTitle="Genesis 35" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the generations of Esau, who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Edom.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Esau took his wives of the daughters of Canaan; Adah the daughter of Elon the Hittite, and Aholibamah the daughter of Anah the daughter of Zibeon the Hivite;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Bashemath Ishmael's daughter, sister of Nebajoth.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Adah bare to Esau Eliphaz; and Bashemath bare Reuel;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Aholibamah bare Jeush, and Jaalam, and Korah: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Esau, which were born unto him in the land of Canaan.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Esau took his wives, and his sons, and his daughters, and all the persons of his house, and his cattle, and all his beasts, and all his substance, which he had got in the land of Canaan; and went into the country from the face of his brother Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For their riches were more than that they might dwell together; and the land wherein they were strangers could not bear them because of their cattle.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Thus dwelt Esau in mount Seir: Esau &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Edom.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the generations of Esau the father of the Edomites in mount Seir:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the names of Esau's sons; Eliphaz the son of Adah the wife of Esau, Reuel the son of Bashemath the wife of Esau.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the sons of Eliphaz were Teman, Omar, Zepho, and Gatam, and Kenaz.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Timna was concubine to Eliphaz Esau's son; and she bare to Eliphaz Amalek: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Adah Esau's wife.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Reuel; Nahath, and Zerah, Shammah, and Mizzah: these were the sons of Bashemath Esau's wife.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And these were the sons of Aholibamah, the daughter of Anah the daughter of Zibeon, Esau's wife: and she bare to Esau Jeush, and Jaalam, and Korah.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; dukes of the sons of Esau: the sons of Eliphaz the firstborn &lt;span class="extra"&gt;son&lt;/span&gt; of Esau; duke Teman, duke Omar, duke Zepho, duke Kenaz,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Duke Korah, duke Gatam, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; duke Amalek: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the dukes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that came&lt;/span&gt; of Eliphaz in the land of Edom; these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Adah.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Reuel Esau's son; duke Nahath, duke Zerah, duke Shammah, duke Mizzah: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the dukes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that came&lt;/span&gt; of Reuel in the land of Edom; these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Bashemath Esau's wife.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Aholibamah Esau's wife; duke Jeush, duke Jaalam, duke Korah: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the dukes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that came&lt;/span&gt; of Aholibamah the daughter of Anah, Esau's wife.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Esau, who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Edom, and these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; their dukes.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Seir the Horite, who inhabited the land; Lotan, and Shobal, and Zibeon, and Anah,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Dishon, and Ezer, and Dishan: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the dukes of the Horites, the children of Seir in the land of Edom.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the children of Lotan were Hori and Hemam; and Lotan's sister &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Timna.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the children of Shobal &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; these; Alvan, and Manahath, and Ebal, Shepho, and Onam.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the children of Zibeon; both Ajah, and Anah: this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was that&lt;/span&gt; Anah that found the mules in the wilderness, as he fed the asses of Zibeon his father.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the children of Anah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; these; Dishon, and Aholibamah the daughter of Anah.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the children of Dishon; Hemdan, and Eshban, and Ithran, and Cheran.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The children of Ezer &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; these; Bilhan, and Zaavan, and Akan.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The children of Dishan &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; these; Uz, and Aran.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the dukes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that came&lt;/span&gt; of the Horites; duke Lotan, duke Shobal, duke Zibeon, duke Anah,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Duke Dishon, duke Ezer, duke Dishan: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the dukes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that came&lt;/span&gt; of Hori, among their dukes in the land of Seir.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the kings that reigned in the land of Edom, before there reigned any king over the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And Bela the son of Beor reigned in Edom: and the name of his city &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Dinhabah.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And Bela died, and Jobab the son of Zerah of Bozrah reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And Jobab died, and Husham of the land of Temani reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And Husham died, and Hadad the son of Bedad, who smote Midian in the field of Moab, reigned in his stead: and the name of his city &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Avith.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And Hadad died, and Samlah of Masrekah reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And Samlah died, and Saul of Rehoboth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; the river reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And Saul died, and Baal-hanan the son of Achbor reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And Baal-hanan the son of Achbor died, and Hadar reigned in his stead: and the name of his city &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Pau; and his wife's name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Mehetabel, the daughter of Matred, the daughter of Mezahab.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the names of the dukes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that came&lt;/span&gt; of Esau, according to their families, after their places, by their names; duke Timnah, duke Alvah, duke Jetheth,</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Duke Aholibamah, duke Elah, duke Pinon,</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Duke Kenaz, duke Teman, duke Mibzar,</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Duke Magdiel, duke Iram: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the dukes of Edom, according to their habitations in the land of their possession: he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Esau the father of the Edomites.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>