<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="42" verseCount="38" nextChapter="genesis_43.html" nextTitle="Genesis 43" prevChapter="genesis_41.html" prevTitle="Genesis 41" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now when Jacob saw that there was corn in Egypt, Jacob said unto his sons, Why do ye look one upon another?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he said, Behold, I have heard that there is corn in Egypt: get you down thither, and buy for us from thence; that we may live, and not die.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And Joseph's ten brethren went down to buy corn in Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But Benjamin, Joseph's brother, Jacob sent not with his brethren; for he said, Lest peradventure mischief befall him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the sons of Israel came to buy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;corn&lt;/span&gt; among those that came: for the famine was in the land of Canaan.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Joseph &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the governor over the land, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it was&lt;/span&gt; that sold to all the people of the land: and Joseph's brethren came, and bowed down themselves before him &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; their faces to the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Joseph saw his brethren, and he knew them, but made himself strange unto them, and spake roughly unto them; and he said unto them, Whence come ye? And they said, From the land of Canaan to buy food.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Joseph knew his brethren, but they knew not him.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Joseph remembered the dreams which he dreamed of them, and said unto them, Ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; spies; to see the nakedness of the land ye are come.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they said unto him, Nay, my lord, but to buy food are thy servants come.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">We &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all one man's sons; we &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; true &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;, thy servants are no spies.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he said unto them, Nay, but to see the nakedness of the land ye are come.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And they said, Thy servants &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; twelve brethren, the sons of one man in the land of Canaan; and, behold, the youngest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this day with our father, and one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Joseph said unto them, That &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt; that I spake unto you, saying, Ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; spies:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Hereby ye shall be proved: By the life of Pharaoh ye shall not go forth hence, except your youngest brother come hither.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Send one of you, and let him fetch your brother, and ye shall be kept in prison, that your words may be proved, whether &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there be any&lt;/span&gt; truth in you: or else by the life of Pharaoh surely ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; spies.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he put them all together into ward three days.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Joseph said unto them the third day, This do, and live; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; I fear God:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">If ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; true &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;, let one of your brethren be bound in the house of your prison: go ye, carry corn for the famine of your houses:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But bring your youngest brother unto me; so shall your words be verified, and ye shall not die. And they did so.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">And they said one to another, We &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; verily guilty concerning our brother, in that we saw the anguish of his soul, when he besought us, and we would not hear; therefore is this distress come upon us.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Reuben answered them, saying, Spake I not unto you, saying, Do not sin against the child; and ye would not hear? therefore, behold, also his blood is required.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And they knew not that Joseph understood &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;; for he spake unto them by an interpreter.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And he turned himself about from them, and wept; and returned to them again, and communed with them, and took from them Simeon, and bound him before their eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">Then Joseph commanded to fill their sacks with corn, and to restore every man's money into his sack, and to give them provision for the way: and thus did he unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And they laded their asses with the corn, and departed thence.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And as one of them opened his sack to give his ass provender in the inn, he espied his money; for, behold, it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in his sack's mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he said unto his brethren, My money is restored; and, lo, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; even in my sack: and their heart failed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, and they were afraid, saying one to another, What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; God hath done unto us?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">And they came unto Jacob their father unto the land of Canaan, and told him all that befell unto them; saying,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The man, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;who is&lt;/span&gt; the lord of the land, spake roughly to us, and took us for spies of the country.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And we said unto him, We &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; true &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;; we are no spies:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">We &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; twelve brethren, sons of our father; one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not, and the youngest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this day with our father in the land of Canaan.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And the man, the lord of the country, said unto us, Hereby shall I know that ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; true &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;; leave one of your brethren &lt;span class='extra'&gt;here&lt;/span&gt; with me, and take &lt;span class='extra'&gt;food for&lt;/span&gt; the famine of your households, and be gone:</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And bring your youngest brother unto me: then shall I know that ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; no spies, but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; true &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men: so&lt;/span&gt; will I deliver you your brother, and ye shall traffick in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35" newPara="true">And it came to pass as they emptied their sacks, that, behold, every man's bundle of money &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in his sack: and when &lt;span class='extra'&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; they and their father saw the bundles of money, they were afraid.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And Jacob their father said unto them, Me have ye bereaved &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of my children&lt;/span&gt;: Joseph &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not, and Simeon &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not, and ye will take Benjamin &lt;span class='extra'&gt;away&lt;/span&gt;: all these things are against me.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And Reuben spake unto his father, saying, Slay my two sons, if I bring him not to thee: deliver him into my hand, and I will bring him to thee again.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And he said, My son shall not go down with you; for his brother is dead, and he is left alone: if mischief befall him by the way in the which ye go, then shall ye bring down my gray hairs with sorrow to the grave.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>