<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="22" nextChapter="genesis_9.html" nextTitle="Genesis 9" prevChapter="genesis_7.html" prevTitle="Genesis 7" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And God remembered Noah, and every living thing, and all the cattle that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; with him in the ark: and God made a wind to pass over the earth, and the waters asswaged;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The fountains also of the deep and the windows of heaven were stopped, and the rain from heaven was restrained;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the waters returned from off the earth continually: and after the end of the hundred and fifty days the waters were abated.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the ark rested in the seventh month, on the seventeenth day of the month, upon the mountains of Ararat.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the waters decreased continually until the tenth month: in the tenth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;month&lt;/span&gt;, on the first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the month, were the tops of the mountains seen.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And it came to pass at the end of forty days, that Noah opened the window of the ark which he had made:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he sent forth a raven, which went forth to and fro, until the waters were dried up from off the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Also he sent forth a dove from him, to see if the waters were abated from off the face of the ground;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But the dove found no rest for the sole of her foot, and she returned unto him into the ark, for the waters &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; on the face of the whole earth: then he put forth his hand, and took her, and pulled her in unto him into the ark.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he stayed yet other seven days; and again he sent forth the dove out of the ark;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the dove came in to him in the evening; and, lo, in her mouth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; an olive leaf pluckt off: so Noah knew that the waters were abated from off the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he stayed yet other seven days; and sent forth the dove; which returned not again unto him any more.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And it came to pass in the six hundredth and first year, in the first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;month&lt;/span&gt;, the first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the month, the waters were dried up from off the earth: and Noah removed the covering of the ark, and looked, and, behold, the face of the ground was dry.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And in the second month, on the seven and twentieth day of the month, was the earth dried.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And God spake unto Noah, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Go forth of the ark, thou, and thy wife, and thy sons, and thy sons' wives with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Bring forth with thee every living thing that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with thee, of all flesh, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; of fowl, and of cattle, and of every creeping thing that creepeth upon the earth; that they may breed abundantly in the earth, and be fruitful, and multiply upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Noah went forth, and his sons, and his wife, and his sons' wives with him:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Every beast, every creeping thing, and every fowl, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; whatsoever creepeth upon the earth, after their kinds, went forth out of the ark.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And Noah builded an altar unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and took of every clean beast, and of every clean fowl, and offered burnt offerings on the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; smelled a sweet savour; and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said in his heart, I will not again curse the ground any more for man's sake; for the imagination of man's heart &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; evil from his youth; neither will I again smite any more every thing living, as I have done.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">While the earth remaineth, seedtime and harvest, and cold and heat, and summer and winter, and day and night shall not cease.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>