<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="24" nextChapter="genesis_4.html" nextTitle="Genesis 4" prevChapter="genesis_2.html" prevTitle="Genesis 2" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now the serpent was more subtil than any beast of the field which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God had made. And he said unto the woman, Yea, hath God said, Ye shall not eat of every tree of the garden?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the woman said unto the serpent, We may eat of the fruit of the trees of the garden:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But of the fruit of the tree which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the midst of the garden, God hath said, Ye shall not eat of it, neither shall ye touch it, lest ye die.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the serpent said unto the woman, Ye shall not surely die:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For God doth know that in the day ye eat thereof, then your eyes shall be opened, and ye shall be as gods, knowing good and evil.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And when the woman saw that the tree &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; good for food, and that it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; pleasant to the eyes, and a tree to be desired to make &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; wise, she took of the fruit thereof, and did eat, and gave also unto her husband with her; and he did eat.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the eyes of them both were opened, and they knew that they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; naked; and they sewed fig leaves together, and made themselves aprons.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And they heard the voice of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God walking in the garden in the cool of the day: and Adam and his wife hid themselves from the presence of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God amongst the trees of the garden.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God called unto Adam, and said unto him, Where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; thou?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he said, I heard thy voice in the garden, and I was afraid, because I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; naked; and I hid myself.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he said, Who told thee that thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;wast&lt;/span&gt; naked? Hast thou eaten of the tree, whereof I commanded thee that thou shouldest not eat?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the man said, The woman whom thou gavest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; with me, she gave me of the tree, and I did eat.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God said unto the woman, What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thou hast done? And the woman said, The serpent beguiled me, and I did eat.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God said unto the serpent, Because thou hast done this, thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; cursed above all cattle, and above every beast of the field; upon thy belly shalt thou go, and dust shalt thou eat all the days of thy life:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And I will put enmity between thee and the woman, and between thy seed and her seed; it shall bruise thy head, and thou shalt bruise his heel.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Unto the woman he said, I will greatly multiply thy sorrow and thy conception; in sorrow thou shalt bring forth children; and thy desire &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; to thy husband, and he shall rule over thee.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And unto Adam he said, Because thou hast hearkened unto the voice of thy wife, and hast eaten of the tree, of which I commanded thee, saying, Thou shalt not eat of it: cursed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the ground for thy sake; in sorrow shalt thou eat &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; it all the days of thy life;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thorns also and thistles shall it bring forth to thee; and thou shalt eat the herb of the field;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat bread, till thou return unto the ground; for out of it wast thou taken: for dust thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt;, and unto dust shalt thou return.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Adam called his wife's name Eve; because she was the mother of all living.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Unto Adam also and to his wife did the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God make coats of skins, and clothed them.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God said, Behold, the man is become as one of us, to know good and evil: and now, lest he put forth his hand, and take also of the tree of life, and eat, and live for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Therefore the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God sent him forth from the garden of Eden, to till the ground from whence he was taken.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">So he drove out the man; and he placed at the east of the garden of Eden Cherubims, and a flaming sword which turned every way, to keep the way of the tree of life.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>