<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="48" verseCount="22" nextChapter="genesis_49.html" nextTitle="Genesis 49" prevChapter="genesis_47.html" prevTitle="Genesis 47" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass after these things, that &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; told Joseph, Behold, thy father &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; sick: and he took with him his two sons, Manasseh and Ephraim.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; told Jacob, and said, Behold, thy son Joseph cometh unto thee: and Israel strengthened himself, and sat upon the bed.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Jacob said unto Joseph, God Almighty appeared unto me at Luz in the land of Canaan, and blessed me,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And said unto me, Behold, I will make thee fruitful, and multiply thee, and I will make of thee a multitude of people; and will give this land to thy seed after thee &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an everlasting possession.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And now thy two sons, Ephraim and Manasseh, which were born unto thee in the land of Egypt before I came unto thee into Egypt, &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; mine; as Reuben and Simeon, they shall be mine.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And thy issue, which thou begettest after them, shall be thine, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; shall be called after the name of their brethren in their inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And as for me, when I came from Padan, Rachel died by me in the land of Canaan in the way, when yet &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; but a little way to come unto Ephrath: and I buried her there in the way of Ephrath; the same &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Beth-lehem.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Israel beheld Joseph's sons, and said, Who &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; these?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Joseph said unto his father, They &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; my sons, whom God hath given me in this &lt;i&gt;place&lt;/i&gt;. And he said, Bring them, I pray thee, unto me, and I will bless them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Now the eyes of Israel were dim for age, &lt;i&gt;so that&lt;/i&gt; he could not see. And he brought them near unto him; and he kissed them, and embraced them.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Israel said unto Joseph, I had not thought to see thy face: and, lo, God hath shewed me also thy seed.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Joseph brought them out from between his knees, and he bowed himself with his face to the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Joseph took them both, Ephraim in his right hand toward Israel's left hand, and Manasseh in his left hand toward Israel's right hand, and brought &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; near unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Israel stretched out his right hand, and laid &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; upon Ephraim's head, who &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the younger, and his left hand upon Manasseh's head, guiding his hands wittingly; for Manasseh &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the firstborn.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And he blessed Joseph, and said, God, before whom my fathers Abraham and Isaac did walk, the God which fed me all my life long unto this day,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The Angel which redeemed me from all evil, bless the lads; and let my name be named on them, and the name of my fathers Abraham and Isaac; and let them grow into a multitude in the midst of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And when Joseph saw that his father laid his right hand upon the head of Ephraim, it displeased him: and he held up his father's hand, to remove it from Ephraim's head unto Manasseh's head.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Joseph said unto his father, Not so, my father: for this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the firstborn; put thy right hand upon his head.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And his father refused, and said, I know &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, my son, I know &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;: he also shall become a people, and he also shall be great: but truly his younger brother shall be greater than he, and his seed shall become a multitude of nations.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And he blessed them that day, saying, In thee shall Israel bless, saying, God make thee as Ephraim and as Manasseh: and he set Ephraim before Manasseh.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Israel said unto Joseph, Behold, I die: but God shall be with you, and bring you again unto the land of your fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Moreover I have given to thee one portion above thy brethren, which I took out of the hand of the Amorite with my sword and with my bow.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>