<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="30" verseCount="43" nextChapter="genesis_31.html" nextTitle="Genesis 31" prevChapter="genesis_29.html" prevTitle="Genesis 29" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And when Rachel saw that she bare Jacob no children, Rachel envied her sister; and said unto Jacob, Give me children, or else I die.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Jacob's anger was kindled against Rachel: and he said, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Am&lt;/span&gt; I in God's stead, who hath withheld from thee the fruit of the womb?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And she said, Behold my maid Bilhah, go in unto her; and she shall bear upon my knees, that I may also have children by her.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And she gave him Bilhah her handmaid to wife: and Jacob went in unto her.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Bilhah conceived, and bare Jacob a son.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Rachel said, God hath judged me, and hath also heard my voice, and hath given me a son: therefore called she his name Dan.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Bilhah Rachel's maid conceived again, and bare Jacob a second son.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Rachel said, With great wrestlings have I wrestled with my sister, and I have prevailed: and she called his name Naphtali.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">When Leah saw that she had left bearing, she took Zilpah her maid, and gave her Jacob to wife.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Zilpah Leah's maid bare Jacob a son.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Leah said, A troop cometh: and she called his name Gad.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Zilpah Leah's maid bare Jacob a second son.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Leah said, Happy am I, for the daughters will call me blessed: and she called his name Asher.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And Reuben went in the days of wheat harvest, and found mandrakes in the field, and brought them unto his mother Leah. Then Rachel said to Leah, Give me, I pray thee, of thy son's mandrakes.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And she said unto her, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Is it&lt;/span&gt; a small matter that thou hast taken my husband? and wouldest thou take away my son's mandrakes also? And Rachel said, Therefore he shall lie with thee to night for thy son's mandrakes.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Jacob came out of the field in the evening, and Leah went out to meet him, and said, Thou must come in unto me; for surely I have hired thee with my son's mandrakes. And he lay with her that night.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And God hearkened unto Leah, and she conceived, and bare Jacob the fifth son.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Leah said, God hath given me my hire, because I have given my maiden to my husband: and she called his name Issachar.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Leah conceived again, and bare Jacob the sixth son.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Leah said, God hath endued me &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; a good dowry; now will my husband dwell with me, because I have born him six sons: and she called his name Zebulun.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And afterwards she bare a daughter, and called her name Dinah.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And God remembered Rachel, and God hearkened to her, and opened her womb.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And she conceived, and bare a son; and said, God hath taken away my reproach:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And she called his name Joseph; and said, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall add to me another son.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when Rachel had born Joseph, that Jacob said unto Laban, Send me away, that I may go unto mine own place, and to my country.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Give &lt;span class="extra"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; my wives and my children, for whom I have served thee, and let me go: for thou knowest my service which I have done thee.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Laban said unto him, I pray thee, if I have found favour in thine eyes, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;tarry: for&lt;/span&gt; I have learned by experience that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath blessed me for thy sake.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he said, Appoint me thy wages, and I will give &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And he said unto him, Thou knowest how I have served thee, and how thy cattle was with me.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">For &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it was&lt;/span&gt; little which thou hadst before I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;came&lt;/span&gt;, and it is &lt;span class="extra"&gt;now&lt;/span&gt; increased unto a multitude; and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath blessed thee since my coming: and now when shall I provide for mine own house also?</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And he said, What shall I give thee? And Jacob said, Thou shalt not give me any thing: if thou wilt do this thing for me, I will again feed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; keep thy flock:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">I will pass through all thy flock to day, removing from thence all the speckled and spotted cattle, and all the brown cattle among the sheep, and the spotted and speckled among the goats: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of such&lt;/span&gt; shall be my hire.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">So shall my righteousness answer for me in time to come, when it shall come for my hire before thy face: every one that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not speckled and spotted among the goats, and brown among the sheep, that shall be counted stolen with me.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And Laban said, Behold, I would it might be according to thy word.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And he removed that day the he goats that were ringstraked and spotted, and all the she goats that were speckled and spotted, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; every one that had &lt;span class="extra"&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; white in it, and all the brown among the sheep, and gave &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; into the hand of his sons.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And he set three days' journey betwixt himself and Jacob: and Jacob fed the rest of Laban's flocks.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37" newPara="true">And Jacob took him rods of green poplar, and of the hazel and chesnut tree; and pilled white strakes in them, and made the white appear which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the rods.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And he set the rods which he had pilled before the flocks in the gutters in the watering troughs when the flocks came to drink, that they should conceive when they came to drink.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And the flocks conceived before the rods, and brought forth cattle ringstraked, speckled, and spotted.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And Jacob did separate the lambs, and set the faces of the flocks toward the ringstraked, and all the brown in the flock of Laban; and he put his own flocks by themselves, and put them not unto Laban's cattle.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And it came to pass, whensoever the stronger cattle did conceive, that Jacob laid the rods before the eyes of the cattle in the gutters, that they might conceive among the rods.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">But when the cattle were feeble, he put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; not in: so the feebler were Laban's, and the stronger Jacob's.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And the man increased exceedingly, and had much cattle, and maidservants, and menservants, and camels, and asses.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>