<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="25" verseCount="34" nextChapter="genesis_26.html" nextTitle="Genesis 26" prevChapter="genesis_24.html" prevTitle="Genesis 24" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then again Abraham took a wife, and her name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Keturah.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And she bare him Zimran, and Jokshan, and Medan, and Midian, and Ishbak, and Shuah.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Jokshan begat Sheba, and Dedan. And the sons of Dedan were Asshurim, and Letushim, and Leummim.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the sons of Midian; Ephah, and Epher, and Hanoch, and Abida, and Eldaah. All these &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; the children of Keturah.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And Abraham gave all that he had unto Isaac.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But unto the sons of the concubines, which Abraham had, Abraham gave gifts, and sent them away from Isaac his son, while he yet lived, eastward, unto the east country.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the days of the years of Abraham's life which he lived, an hundred threescore and fifteen years.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then Abraham gave up the ghost, and died in a good old age, an old man, and full &lt;i&gt;of years&lt;/i&gt;; and was gathered to his people.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And his sons Isaac and Ishmael buried him in the cave of Machpelah, in the field of Ephron the son of Zohar the Hittite, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; before Mamre;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The field which Abraham purchased of the sons of Heth: there was Abraham buried, and Sarah his wife.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And it came to pass after the death of Abraham, that God blessed his son Isaac; and Isaac dwelt by the well Lahai-roi.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Now these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the generations of Ishmael, Abraham's son, whom Hagar the Egyptian, Sarah's handmaid, bare unto Abraham:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the names of the sons of Ishmael, by their names, according to their generations: the firstborn of Ishmael, Nebajoth; and Kedar, and Adbeel, and Mibsam,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Mishma, and Dumah, and Massa,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Hadar, and Tema, Jetur, Naphish, and Kedemah:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the sons of Ishmael, and these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; their names, by their towns, and by their castles; twelve princes according to their nations.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the years of the life of Ishmael, an hundred and thirty and seven years: and he gave up the ghost and died; and was gathered unto his people.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And they dwelt from Havilah unto Shur, that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; before Egypt, as thou goest toward Assyria: &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; he died in the presence of all his brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the generations of Isaac, Abraham's son: Abraham begat Isaac:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Isaac was forty years old when he took Rebekah to wife, the daughter of Bethuel the Syrian of Padan-aram, the sister to Laban the Syrian.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Isaac intreated the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for his wife, because she &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; barren: and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was intreated of him, and Rebekah his wife conceived.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the children struggled together within her; and she said, If &lt;i&gt;it be&lt;/i&gt; so, why &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I thus? And she went to enquire of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto her, Two nations &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in thy womb, and two manner of people shall be separated from thy bowels; and &lt;i&gt;the one&lt;/i&gt; people shall be stronger than &lt;i&gt;the other&lt;/i&gt; people; and the elder shall serve the younger.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And when her days to be delivered were fulfilled, behold, &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; twins in her womb.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the first came out red, all over like an hairy garment; and they called his name Esau.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And after that came his brother out, and his hand took hold on Esau's heel; and his name was called Jacob: and Isaac &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; threescore years old when she bare them.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And the boys grew: and Esau was a cunning hunter, a man of the field; and Jacob &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a plain man, dwelling in tents.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Isaac loved Esau, because he did eat of &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; venison: but Rebekah loved Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">And Jacob sod pottage: and Esau came from the field, and he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; faint:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Esau said to Jacob, Feed me, I pray thee, with that same red &lt;i&gt;pottage&lt;/i&gt;; for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; faint: therefore was his name called Edom.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Jacob said, Sell me this day thy birthright.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And Esau said, Behold, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; at the point to die: and what profit shall this birthright do to me?</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And Jacob said, Swear to me this day; and he sware unto him: and he sold his birthright unto Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Then Jacob gave Esau bread and pottage of lentiles; and he did eat and drink, and rose up, and went his way: thus Esau despised &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; birthright.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>