<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="16" nextChapter="genesis_17.html" nextTitle="Genesis 17" prevChapter="genesis_15.html" prevTitle="Genesis 15" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now Sarai Abram's wife bare him no children: and she had an handmaid, an Egyptian, whose name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Hagar.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Sarai said unto Abram, Behold now, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath restrained me from bearing: I pray thee, go in unto my maid; it may be that I may obtain children by her. And Abram hearkened to the voice of Sarai.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Sarai Abram's wife took Hagar her maid the Egyptian, after Abram had dwelt ten years in the land of Canaan, and gave her to her husband Abram to be his wife.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And he went in unto Hagar, and she conceived: and when she saw that she had conceived, her mistress was despised in her eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Sarai said unto Abram, My wrong &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; upon thee: I have given my maid into thy bosom; and when she saw that she had conceived, I was despised in her eyes: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; judge between me and thee.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But Abram said unto Sarai, Behold, thy maid &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in thy hand; do to her as it pleaseth thee. And when Sarai dealt hardly with her, she fled from her face.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; found her by a fountain of water in the wilderness, by the fountain in the way to Shur.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he said, Hagar, Sarai's maid, whence camest thou? and whither wilt thou go? And she said, I flee from the face of my mistress Sarai.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto her, Return to thy mistress, and submit thyself under her hands.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto her, I will multiply thy seed exceedingly, that it shall not be numbered for multitude.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto her, Behold, thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; with child, and shalt bear a son, and shalt call his name Ishmael; because the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath heard thy affliction.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he will be a wild man; his hand &lt;i&gt;will be&lt;/i&gt; against every man, and every man's hand against him; and he shall dwell in the presence of all his brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And she called the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that spake unto her, Thou God seest me: for she said, Have I also here looked after him that seeth me?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Wherefore the well was called Beer-lahai-roi; behold, &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; between Kadesh and Bered.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And Hagar bare Abram a son: and Abram called his son's name, which Hagar bare, Ishmael.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Abram &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; fourscore and six years old, when Hagar bare Ishmael to Abram.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>