<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="38" verseCount="30" nextChapter="genesis_39.html" nextTitle="Genesis 39" prevChapter="genesis_37.html" prevTitle="Genesis 37" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass at that time, that Judah went down from his brethren, and turned in to a certain Adullamite, whose name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Hirah.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Judah saw there a daughter of a certain Canaanite, whose name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Shuah; and he took her, and went in unto her.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And she conceived, and bare a son; and he called his name Er.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And she conceived again, and bare a son; and she called his name Onan.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And she yet again conceived, and bare a son; and called his name Shelah: and he was at Chezib, when she bare him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Judah took a wife for Er his firstborn, whose name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Tamar.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Er, Judah's firstborn, was wicked in the sight of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; slew him.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Judah said unto Onan, Go in unto thy brother's wife, and marry her, and raise up seed to thy brother.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Onan knew that the seed should not be his; and it came to pass, when he went in unto his brother's wife, that he spilled &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on the ground, lest that he should give seed to his brother.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the thing which he did displeased the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: wherefore he slew him also.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then said Judah to Tamar his daughter in law, Remain a widow at thy father's house, till Shelah my son be grown: for he said, Lest peradventure he die also, as his brethren &lt;span class='extra'&gt;did&lt;/span&gt;. And Tamar went and dwelt in her father's house.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And in process of time the daughter of Shuah Judah's wife died; and Judah was comforted, and went up unto his sheepshearers to Timnath, he and his friend Hirah the Adullamite.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And it was told Tamar, saying, Behold thy father in law goeth up to Timnath to shear his sheep.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And she put her widow's garments off from her, and covered her with a vail, and wrapped herself, and sat in an open place, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the way to Timnath; for she saw that Shelah was grown, and she was not given unto him to wife.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">When Judah saw her, he thought her &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; an harlot; because she had covered her face.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he turned unto her by the way, and said, Go to, I pray thee, let me come in unto thee; (for he knew not that she &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; his daughter in law.) And she said, What wilt thou give me, that thou mayest come in unto me?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he said, I will send &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt; a kid from the flock. And she said, Wilt thou give &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; a pledge, till thou send &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And he said, What pledge shall I give thee? And she said, Thy signet, and thy bracelets, and thy staff that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in thine hand. And he gave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; her, and came in unto her, and she conceived by him.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And she arose, and went away, and laid by her vail from her, and put on the garments of her widowhood.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Judah sent the kid by the hand of his friend the Adullamite, to receive &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; pledge from the woman's hand: but he found her not.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then he asked the men of that place, saying, Where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the harlot, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; openly by the way side? And they said, There was no harlot in this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And he returned to Judah, and said, I cannot find her; and also the men of the place said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; there was no harlot in this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Judah said, Let her take &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to her, lest we be shamed: behold, I sent this kid, and thou hast not found her.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And it came to pass about three months after, that it was told Judah, saying, Tamar thy daughter in law hath played the harlot; and also, behold, she &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with child by whoredom. And Judah said, Bring her forth, and let her be burnt.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">When she &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; brought forth, she sent to her father in law, saying, By the man, whose these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are, am&lt;/span&gt; I with child: and she said, Discern, I pray thee, whose &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; these, the signet, and bracelets, and staff.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Judah acknowledged &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, and said, She hath been more righteous than I; because that I gave her not to Shelah my son. And he knew her again no more.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And it came to pass in the time of her travail, that, behold, twins &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in her womb.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And it came to pass, when she travailed, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the one&lt;/span&gt; put out &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; hand: and the midwife took and bound upon his hand a scarlet thread, saying, This came out first.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And it came to pass, as he drew back his hand, that, behold, his brother came out: and she said, How hast thou broken forth? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; breach &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; upon thee: therefore his name was called Pharez.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And afterward came out his brother, that had the scarlet thread upon his hand: and his name was called Zarah.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>