<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="29" nextChapter="genesis_10.html" nextTitle="Genesis 10" prevChapter="genesis_8.html" prevTitle="Genesis 8" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And God blessed Noah and his sons, and said unto them, Be fruitful, and multiply, and replenish the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the fear of you and the dread of you shall be upon every beast of the earth, and upon every fowl of the air, upon all that moveth &lt;i&gt;upon&lt;/i&gt; the earth, and upon all the fishes of the sea; into your hand are they delivered.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Every moving thing that liveth shall be meat for you; even as the green herb have I given you all things.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But flesh with the life thereof, &lt;i&gt;which is&lt;/i&gt; the blood thereof, shall ye not eat.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And surely your blood of your lives will I require; at the hand of every beast will I require it, and at the hand of man; at the hand of every man's brother will I require the life of man.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Whoso sheddeth man's blood, by man shall his blood be shed: for in the image of God made he man.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And you, be ye fruitful, and multiply; bring forth abundantly in the earth, and multiply therein.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And God spake unto Noah, and to his sons with him, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And I, behold, I establish my covenant with you, and with your seed after you;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And with every living creature that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with you, of the fowl, of the cattle, and of every beast of the earth with you; from all that go out of the ark, to every beast of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I will establish my covenant with you; neither shall all flesh be cut off any more by the waters of a flood; neither shall there any more be a flood to destroy the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And God said, This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the token of the covenant which I make between me and you and every living creature that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with you, for perpetual generations:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">I do set my bow in the cloud, and it shall be for a token of a covenant between me and the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And it shall come to pass, when I bring a cloud over the earth, that the bow shall be seen in the cloud:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And I will remember my covenant, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; between me and you and every living creature of all flesh; and the waters shall no more become a flood to destroy all flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the bow shall be in the cloud; and I will look upon it, that I may remember the everlasting covenant between God and every living creature of all flesh that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And God said unto Noah, This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the token of the covenant, which I have established between me and all flesh that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And the sons of Noah, that went forth of the ark, were Shem, and Ham, and Japheth: and Ham &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the father of Canaan.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the three sons of Noah: and of them was the whole earth overspread.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Noah began &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; an husbandman, and he planted a vineyard:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he drank of the wine, and was drunken; and he was uncovered within his tent.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Ham, the father of Canaan, saw the nakedness of his father, and told his two brethren without.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Shem and Japheth took a garment, and laid &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; upon both their shoulders, and went backward, and covered the nakedness of their father; and their faces &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; backward, and they saw not their father's nakedness.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Noah awoke from his wine, and knew what his younger son had done unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And he said, Cursed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; Canaan; a servant of servants shall he be unto his brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And he said, Blessed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Shem; and Canaan shall be his servant.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">God shall enlarge Japheth, and he shall dwell in the tents of Shem; and Canaan shall be his servant.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">And Noah lived after the flood three hundred and fifty years.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And all the days of Noah were nine hundred and fifty years: and he died.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>