<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="23" verseCount="20" nextChapter="genesis_24.html" nextTitle="Genesis 24" prevChapter="genesis_22.html" prevTitle="Genesis 22" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Sarah was an hundred and seven and twenty years old: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;these were&lt;/span&gt; the years of the life of Sarah.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Sarah died in Kirjath-arba; the same &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Hebron in the land of Canaan: and Abraham came to mourn for Sarah, and to weep for her.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And Abraham stood up from before his dead, and spake unto the sons of Heth, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; a stranger and a sojourner with you: give me a possession of a buryingplace with you, that I may bury my dead out of my sight.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the children of Heth answered Abraham, saying unto him,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Hear us, my lord: thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; a mighty prince among us: in the choice of our sepulchres bury thy dead; none of us shall withhold from thee his sepulchre, but that thou mayest bury thy dead.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Abraham stood up, and bowed himself to the people of the land, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to the children of Heth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he communed with them, saying, If it be your mind that I should bury my dead out of my sight; hear me, and intreat for me to Ephron the son of Zohar,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">That he may give me the cave of Machpelah, which he hath, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the end of his field; for as much money as it is worth he shall give it me for a possession of a buryingplace amongst you.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Ephron dwelt among the children of Heth: and Ephron the Hittite answered Abraham in the audience of the children of Heth, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of all that went in at the gate of his city, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Nay, my lord, hear me: the field give I thee, and the cave that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; therein, I give it thee; in the presence of the sons of my people give I it thee: bury thy dead.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Abraham bowed down himself before the people of the land.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he spake unto Ephron in the audience of the people of the land, saying, But if thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;wilt give it&lt;/span&gt;, I pray thee, hear me: I will give thee money for the field; take &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; of me, and I will bury my dead there.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Ephron answered Abraham, saying unto him,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">My lord, hearken unto me: the land &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is worth&lt;/span&gt; four hundred shekels of silver; what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; that betwixt me and thee? bury therefore thy dead.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Abraham hearkened unto Ephron; and Abraham weighed to Ephron the silver, which he had named in the audience of the sons of Heth, four hundred shekels of silver, current &lt;span class='extra'&gt;money&lt;/span&gt; with the merchant.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And the field of Ephron, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in Machpelah, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; before Mamre, the field, and the cave which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; therein, and all the trees that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the field, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in all the borders round about, were made sure</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Unto Abraham for a possession in the presence of the children of Heth, before all that went in at the gate of his city.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And after this, Abraham buried Sarah his wife in the cave of the field of Machpelah before Mamre: the same &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Hebron in the land of Canaan.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the field, and the cave that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; therein, were made sure unto Abraham for a possession of a buryingplace by the sons of Heth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>