<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="18" nextChapter="genesis_21.html" nextTitle="Genesis 21" prevChapter="genesis_19.html" prevTitle="Genesis 19" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Abraham journeyed from thence toward the south country, and dwelled between Kadesh and Shur, and sojourned in Gerar.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Abraham said of Sarah his wife, She &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my sister: and Abimelech king of Gerar sent, and took Sarah.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But God came to Abimelech in a dream by night, and said to him, Behold, thou &lt;i&gt;art but&lt;/i&gt; a dead man, for the woman which thou hast taken; for she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a man's wife.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But Abimelech had not come near her: and he said, Lord, wilt thou slay also a righteous nation?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Said he not unto me, She &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my sister? and she, even she herself said, He &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my brother: in the integrity of my heart and innocency of my hands have I done this.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And God said unto him in a dream, Yea, I know that thou didst this in the integrity of thy heart; for I also withheld thee from sinning against me: therefore suffered I thee not to touch her.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Now therefore restore the man &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; wife; for he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a prophet, and he shall pray for thee, and thou shalt live: and if thou restore &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; not, know thou that thou shalt surely die, thou, and all that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; thine.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Therefore Abimelech rose early in the morning, and called all his servants, and told all these things in their ears: and the men were sore afraid.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then Abimelech called Abraham, and said unto him, What hast thou done unto us? and what have I offended thee, that thou hast brought on me and on my kingdom a great sin? thou hast done deeds unto me that ought not to be done.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Abimelech said unto Abraham, What sawest thou, that thou hast done this thing?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Abraham said, Because I thought, Surely the fear of God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not in this place; and they will slay me for my wife's sake.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And yet indeed &lt;i&gt;she is&lt;/i&gt; my sister; she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the daughter of my father, but not the daughter of my mother; and she became my wife.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And it came to pass, when God caused me to wander from my father's house, that I said unto her, This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy kindness which thou shalt shew unto me; at every place whither we shall come, say of me, He &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my brother.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Abimelech took sheep, and oxen, and menservants, and womenservants, and gave &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; unto Abraham, and restored him Sarah his wife.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Abimelech said, Behold, my land &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; before thee: dwell where it pleaseth thee.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And unto Sarah he said, Behold, I have given thy brother a thousand &lt;i&gt;pieces&lt;/i&gt; of silver: behold, he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; to thee a covering of the eyes, unto all that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; with thee, and with all &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt;: thus she was reproved.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">So Abraham prayed unto God: and God healed Abimelech, and his wife, and his maidservants; and they bare &lt;i&gt;children&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had fast closed up all the wombs of the house of Abimelech, because of Sarah Abraham's wife.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>