<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="32" nextChapter="genesis_6.html" nextTitle="Genesis 6" prevChapter="genesis_4.html" prevTitle="Genesis 4" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the book of the generations of Adam. In the day that God created man, in the likeness of God made he him;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Male and female created he them; and blessed them, and called their name Adam, in the day when they were created.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And Adam lived an hundred and thirty years, and begat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;a son&lt;/span&gt; in his own likeness, after his image; and called his name Seth:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the days of Adam after he had begotten Seth were eight hundred years: and he begat sons and daughters:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And all the days that Adam lived were nine hundred and thirty years: and he died.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Seth lived an hundred and five years, and begat Enos:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Seth lived after he begat Enos eight hundred and seven years, and begat sons and daughters:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And all the days of Seth were nine hundred and twelve years: and he died.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And Enos lived ninety years, and begat Cainan:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Enos lived after he begat Cainan eight hundred and fifteen years, and begat sons and daughters:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And all the days of Enos were nine hundred and five years: and he died.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And Cainan lived seventy years, and begat Mahalaleel:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Cainan lived after he begat Mahalaleel eight hundred and forty years, and begat sons and daughters:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And all the days of Cainan were nine hundred and ten years: and he died.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And Mahalaleel lived sixty and five years, and begat Jared:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Mahalaleel lived after he begat Jared eight hundred and thirty years, and begat sons and daughters:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And all the days of Mahalaleel were eight hundred ninety and five years: and he died.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And Jared lived an hundred sixty and two years, and he begat Enoch:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Jared lived after he begat Enoch eight hundred years, and begat sons and daughters:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And all the days of Jared were nine hundred sixty and two years: and he died.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">And Enoch lived sixty and five years, and begat Methuselah:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Enoch walked with God after he begat Methuselah three hundred years, and begat sons and daughters:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And all the days of Enoch were three hundred sixty and five years:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Enoch walked with God: and he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; not; for God took him.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Methuselah lived an hundred eighty and seven years, and begat Lamech:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Methuselah lived after he begat Lamech seven hundred eighty and two years, and begat sons and daughters:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And all the days of Methuselah were nine hundred sixty and nine years: and he died.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">And Lamech lived an hundred eighty and two years, and begat a son:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And he called his name Noah, saying, This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;same&lt;/span&gt; shall comfort us concerning our work and toil of our hands, because of the ground which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath cursed.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Lamech lived after he begat Noah five hundred ninety and five years, and begat sons and daughters:</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And all the days of Lamech were seven hundred seventy and seven years: and he died.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And Noah was five hundred years old: and Noah begat Shem, Ham, and Japheth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>