<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="32" nextChapter="genesis_11.html" nextTitle="Genesis 11" prevChapter="genesis_9.html" prevTitle="Genesis 9" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the generations of the sons of Noah, Shem, Ham, and Japheth: and unto them were sons born after the flood.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The sons of Japheth; Gomer, and Magog, and Madai, and Javan, and Tubal, and Meshech, and Tiras.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the sons of Gomer; Ashkenaz, and Riphath, and Togarmah.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the sons of Javan; Elishah, and Tarshish, Kittim, and Dodanim.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">By these were the isles of the Gentiles divided in their lands; every one after his tongue, after their families, in their nations.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And the sons of Ham; Cush, and Mizraim, and Phut, and Canaan.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the sons of Cush; Seba, and Havilah, and Sabtah, and Raamah, and Sabtecha: and the sons of Raamah; Sheba, and Dedan.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Cush begat Nimrod: he began to be a mighty one in the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He was a mighty hunter before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: wherefore it is said, Even as Nimrod the mighty hunter before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the beginning of his kingdom was Babel, and Erech, and Accad, and Calneh, in the land of Shinar.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Out of that land went forth Asshur, and builded Nineveh, and the city Rehoboth, and Calah,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Resen between Nineveh and Calah: the same &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a great city.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Mizraim begat Ludim, and Anamim, and Lehabim, and Naphtuhim,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Pathrusim, and Casluhim, (out of whom came Philistim,) and Caphtorim.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And Canaan begat Sidon his firstborn, and Heth,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the Jebusite, and the Amorite, and the Girgasite,</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the Hivite, and the Arkite, and the Sinite,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the Arvadite, and the Zemarite, and the Hamathite: and afterward were the families of the Canaanites spread abroad.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the border of the Canaanites was from Sidon, as thou comest to Gerar, unto Gaza; as thou goest, unto Sodom, and Gomorrah, and Admah, and Zeboim, even unto Lasha.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the sons of Ham, after their families, after their tongues, in their countries, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; in their nations.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Unto Shem also, the father of all the children of Eber, the brother of Japheth the elder, even to him were &lt;i&gt;children&lt;/i&gt; born.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The children of Shem; Elam, and Asshur, and Arphaxad, and Lud, and Aram.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the children of Aram; Uz, and Hul, and Gether, and Mash.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Arphaxad begat Salah; and Salah begat Eber.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And unto Eber were born two sons: the name of one &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Peleg; for in his days was the earth divided; and his brother's name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Joktan.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Joktan begat Almodad, and Sheleph, and Hazarmaveth, and Jerah,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Hadoram, and Uzal, and Diklah,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Obal, and Abimael, and Sheba,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Ophir, and Havilah, and Jobab: all these &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; the sons of Joktan.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And their dwelling was from Mesha, as thou goest unto Sephar a mount of the east.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the sons of Shem, after their families, after their tongues, in their lands, after their nations.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the families of the sons of Noah, after their generations, in their nations: and by these were the nations divided in the earth after the flood.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>