<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="18" nextChapter="genesis_14.html" nextTitle="Genesis 14" prevChapter="genesis_12.html" prevTitle="Genesis 12" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Abram went up out of Egypt, he, and his wife, and all that he had, and Lot with him, into the south.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Abram &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; very rich in cattle, in silver, and in gold.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he went on his journeys from the south even to Beth-el, unto the place where his tent had been at the beginning, between Beth-el and Hai;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Unto the place of the altar, which he had made there at the first: and there Abram called on the name of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And Lot also, which went with Abram, had flocks, and herds, and tents.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the land was not able to bear them, that they might dwell together: for their substance was great, so that they could not dwell together.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And there was a strife between the herdmen of Abram's cattle and the herdmen of Lot's cattle: and the Canaanite and the Perizzite dwelled then in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Abram said unto Lot, Let there be no strife, I pray thee, between me and thee, and between my herdmen and thy herdmen; for we &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; not the whole land before thee? separate thyself, I pray thee, from me: if &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thou wilt take&lt;/span&gt; the left hand, then I will go to the right; or if &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thou depart&lt;/span&gt; to the right hand, then I will go to the left.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Lot lifted up his eyes, and beheld all the plain of Jordan, that it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; well watered every where, before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; destroyed Sodom and Gomorrah, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; as the garden of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, like the land of Egypt, as thou comest unto Zoar.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then Lot chose him all the plain of Jordan; and Lot journeyed east: and they separated themselves the one from the other.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Abram dwelled in the land of Canaan, and Lot dwelled in the cities of the plain, and pitched &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; tent toward Sodom.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But the men of Sodom &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; wicked and sinners before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; exceedingly.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Abram, after that Lot was separated from him, Lift up now thine eyes, and look from the place where thou art northward, and southward, and eastward, and westward:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For all the land which thou seest, to thee will I give it, and to thy seed for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And I will make thy seed as the dust of the earth: so that if a man can number the dust of the earth, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; shall thy seed also be numbered.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Arise, walk through the land in the length of it and in the breadth of it; for I will give it unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Then Abram removed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; tent, and came and dwelt in the plain of Mamre, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in Hebron, and built there an altar unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>