<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="21" verseCount="34" nextChapter="genesis_22.html" nextTitle="Genesis 22" prevChapter="genesis_20.html" prevTitle="Genesis 20" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; visited Sarah as he had said, and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did unto Sarah as he had spoken.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For Sarah conceived, and bare Abraham a son in his old age, at the set time of which God had spoken to him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Abraham called the name of his son that was born unto him, whom Sarah bare to him, Isaac.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Abraham circumcised his son Isaac being eight days old, as God had commanded him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Abraham was an hundred years old, when his son Isaac was born unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And Sarah said, God hath made me to laugh, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so that&lt;/span&gt; all that hear will laugh with me.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And she said, Who would have said unto Abraham, that Sarah should have given children suck? for I have born &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; a son in his old age.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the child grew, and was weaned: and Abraham made a great feast the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;same&lt;/span&gt; day that Isaac was weaned.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And Sarah saw the son of Hagar the Egyptian, which she had born unto Abraham, mocking.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Wherefore she said unto Abraham, Cast out this bondwoman and her son: for the son of this bondwoman shall not be heir with my son, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; with Isaac.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the thing was very grievous in Abraham's sight because of his son.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And God said unto Abraham, Let it not be grievous in thy sight because of the lad, and because of thy bondwoman; in all that Sarah hath said unto thee, hearken unto her voice; for in Isaac shall thy seed be called.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And also of the son of the bondwoman will I make a nation, because he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy seed.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Abraham rose up early in the morning, and took bread, and a bottle of water, and gave &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; unto Hagar, putting &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on her shoulder, and the child, and sent her away: and she departed, and wandered in the wilderness of Beer-sheba.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the water was spent in the bottle, and she cast the child under one of the shrubs.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And she went, and sat her down over against &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; a good way off, as it were a bowshot: for she said, Let me not see the death of the child. And she sat over against &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, and lift up her voice, and wept.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And God heard the voice of the lad; and the angel of God called to Hagar out of heaven, and said unto her, What aileth thee, Hagar? fear not; for God hath heard the voice of the lad where he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Arise, lift up the lad, and hold him in thine hand; for I will make him a great nation.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And God opened her eyes, and she saw a well of water; and she went, and filled the bottle with water, and gave the lad drink.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And God was with the lad; and he grew, and dwelt in the wilderness, and became an archer.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he dwelt in the wilderness of Paran: and his mother took him a wife out of the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And it came to pass at that time, that Abimelech and Phichol the chief captain of his host spake unto Abraham, saying, God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with thee in all that thou doest:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Now therefore swear unto me here by God that thou wilt not deal falsely with me, nor with my son, nor with my son's son: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; according to the kindness that I have done unto thee, thou shalt do unto me, and to the land wherein thou hast sojourned.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Abraham said, I will swear.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Abraham reproved Abimelech because of a well of water, which Abimelech's servants had violently taken away.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Abimelech said, I wot not who hath done this thing: neither didst thou tell me, neither yet heard I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of it&lt;/span&gt;, but to day.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Abraham took sheep and oxen, and gave them unto Abimelech; and both of them made a covenant.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Abraham set seven ewe lambs of the flock by themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Abimelech said unto Abraham, What &lt;span class="extra"&gt;mean&lt;/span&gt; these seven ewe lambs which thou hast set by themselves?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And he said, For &lt;span class="extra"&gt;these&lt;/span&gt; seven ewe lambs shalt thou take of my hand, that they may be a witness unto me, that I have digged this well.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Wherefore he called that place Beer-sheba; because there they sware both of them.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Thus they made a covenant at Beer-sheba: then Abimelech rose up, and Phichol the chief captain of his host, and they returned into the land of the Philistines.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Abraham&lt;/span&gt; planted a grove in Beer-sheba, and called there on the name of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the everlasting God.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And Abraham sojourned in the Philistines' land many days.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>