<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="50" verseCount="26" nextChapter="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus 1" prevChapter="genesis_49.html" prevTitle="Genesis 49" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Joseph fell upon his father's face, and wept upon him, and kissed him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Joseph commanded his servants the physicians to embalm his father: and the physicians embalmed Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And forty days were fulfilled for him; for so are fulfilled the days of those which are embalmed: and the Egyptians mourned for him threescore and ten days.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And when the days of his mourning were past, Joseph spake unto the house of Pharaoh, saying, If now I have found grace in your eyes, speak, I pray you, in the ears of Pharaoh, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">My father made me swear, saying, Lo, I die: in my grave which I have digged for me in the land of Canaan, there shalt thou bury me. Now therefore let me go up, I pray thee, and bury my father, and I will come again.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Pharaoh said, Go up, and bury thy father, according as he made thee swear.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And Joseph went up to bury his father: and with him went up all the servants of Pharaoh, the elders of his house, and all the elders of the land of Egypt,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And all the house of Joseph, and his brethren, and his father's house: only their little ones, and their flocks, and their herds, they left in the land of Goshen.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And there went up with him both chariots and horsemen: and it was a very great company.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they came to the threshingfloor of Atad, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; beyond Jordan, and there they mourned with a great and very sore lamentation: and he made a mourning for his father seven days.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And when the inhabitants of the land, the Canaanites, saw the mourning in the floor of Atad, they said, This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a grievous mourning to the Egyptians: wherefore the name of it was called Abel-mizraim, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; beyond Jordan.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And his sons did unto him according as he commanded them:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For his sons carried him into the land of Canaan, and buried him in the cave of the field of Machpelah, which Abraham bought with the field for a possession of a buryingplace of Ephron the Hittite, before Mamre.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And Joseph returned into Egypt, he, and his brethren, and all that went up with him to bury his father, after he had buried his father.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And when Joseph's brethren saw that their father was dead, they said, Joseph will peradventure hate us, and will certainly requite us all the evil which we did unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And they sent a messenger unto Joseph, saying, Thy father did command before he died, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">So shall ye say unto Joseph, Forgive, I pray thee now, the trespass of thy brethren, and their sin; for they did unto thee evil: and now, we pray thee, forgive the trespass of the servants of the God of thy father. And Joseph wept when they spake unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And his brethren also went and fell down before his face; and they said, Behold, we &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; thy servants.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Joseph said unto them, Fear not: for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; I in the place of God?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But as for you, ye thought evil against me; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; God meant it unto good, to bring to pass, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; this day, to save much people alive.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Now therefore fear ye not: I will nourish you, and your little ones. And he comforted them, and spake kindly unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And Joseph dwelt in Egypt, he, and his father's house: and Joseph lived an hundred and ten years.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Joseph saw Ephraim's children of the third &lt;span class='extra'&gt;generation&lt;/span&gt;: the children also of Machir the son of Manasseh were brought up upon Joseph's knees.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Joseph said unto his brethren, I die: and God will surely visit you, and bring you out of this land unto the land which he sware to Abraham, to Isaac, and to Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Joseph took an oath of the children of Israel, saying, God will surely visit you, and ye shall carry up my bones from hence.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">So Joseph died, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; an hundred and ten years old: and they embalmed him, and he was put in a coffin in Egypt.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>