<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="26" nextChapter="genesis_5.html" nextTitle="Genesis 5" prevChapter="genesis_3.html" prevTitle="Genesis 3" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Adam knew Eve his wife; and she conceived, and bare Cain, and said, I have gotten a man from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And she again bare his brother Abel. And Abel was a keeper of sheep, but Cain was a tiller of the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And in process of time it came to pass, that Cain brought of the fruit of the ground an offering unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Abel, he also brought of the firstlings of his flock and of the fat thereof. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had respect unto Abel and to his offering:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But unto Cain and to his offering he had not respect. And Cain was very wroth, and his countenance fell.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Cain, Why art thou wroth? and why is thy countenance fallen?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">If thou doest well, shalt thou not be accepted? and if thou doest not well, sin lieth at the door. And unto thee &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; his desire, and thou shalt rule over him.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Cain talked with Abel his brother: and it came to pass, when they were in the field, that Cain rose up against Abel his brother, and slew him.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Cain, Where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Abel thy brother? And he said, I know not: &lt;i&gt;Am&lt;/i&gt; I my brother's keeper?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he said, What hast thou done? the voice of thy brother's blood crieth unto me from the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And now &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; thou cursed from the earth, which hath opened her mouth to receive thy brother's blood from thy hand;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">When thou tillest the ground, it shall not henceforth yield unto thee her strength; a fugitive and a vagabond shalt thou be in the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Cain said unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, My punishment &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; greater than I can bear.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Behold, thou hast driven me out this day from the face of the earth; and from thy face shall I be hid; and I shall be a fugitive and a vagabond in the earth; and it shall come to pass, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; every one that findeth me shall slay me.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, Therefore whosoever slayeth Cain, vengeance shall be taken on him sevenfold. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; set a mark upon Cain, lest any finding him should kill him.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And Cain went out from the presence of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and dwelt in the land of Nod, on the east of Eden.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Cain knew his wife; and she conceived, and bare Enoch: and he builded a city, and called the name of the city, after the name of his son, Enoch.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And unto Enoch was born Irad: and Irad begat Mehujael: and Mehujael begat Methusael: and Methusael begat Lamech.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And Lamech took unto him two wives: the name of the one &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Adah, and the name of the other Zillah.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Adah bare Jabal: he was the father of such as dwell in tents, and &lt;i&gt;of such as have&lt;/i&gt; cattle.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And his brother's name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Jubal: he was the father of all such as handle the harp and organ.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Zillah, she also bare Tubal-cain, an instructer of every artificer in brass and iron: and the sister of Tubal-cain &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Naamah.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Lamech said unto his wives, Adah and Zillah, Hear my voice; ye wives of Lamech, hearken unto my speech: for I have slain a man to my wounding, and a young man to my hurt.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">If Cain shall be avenged sevenfold, truly Lamech seventy and sevenfold.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And Adam knew his wife again; and she bare a son, and called his name Seth: For God, &lt;i&gt;said she&lt;/i&gt;, hath appointed me another seed instead of Abel, whom Cain slew.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And to Seth, to him also there was born a son; and he called his name Enos: then began men to call upon the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>