<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="32" nextChapter="genesis_12.html" nextTitle="Genesis 12" prevChapter="genesis_10.html" prevTitle="Genesis 10" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the whole earth was of one language, and of one speech.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And it came to pass, as they journeyed from the east, that they found a plain in the land of Shinar; and they dwelt there.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they said one to another, Go to, let us make brick, and burn them throughly. And they had brick for stone, and slime had they for morter.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they said, Go to, let us build us a city and a tower, whose top &lt;i&gt;may reach&lt;/i&gt; unto heaven; and let us make us a name, lest we be scattered abroad upon the face of the whole earth.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came down to see the city and the tower, which the children of men builded.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said, Behold, the people &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; one, and they have all one language; and this they begin to do: and now nothing will be restrained from them, which they have imagined to do.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Go to, let us go down, and there confound their language, that they may not understand one another's speech.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">So the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; scattered them abroad from thence upon the face of all the earth: and they left off to build the city.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Therefore is the name of it called Babel; because the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did there confound the language of all the earth: and from thence did the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; scatter them abroad upon the face of all the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the generations of Shem: Shem &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; an hundred years old, and begat Arphaxad two years after the flood:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Shem lived after he begat Arphaxad five hundred years, and begat sons and daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Arphaxad lived five and thirty years, and begat Salah:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Arphaxad lived after he begat Salah four hundred and three years, and begat sons and daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Salah lived thirty years, and begat Eber:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Salah lived after he begat Eber four hundred and three years, and begat sons and daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Eber lived four and thirty years, and begat Peleg:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Eber lived after he begat Peleg four hundred and thirty years, and begat sons and daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Peleg lived thirty years, and begat Reu:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Peleg lived after he begat Reu two hundred and nine years, and begat sons and daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Reu lived two and thirty years, and begat Serug:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Reu lived after he begat Serug two hundred and seven years, and begat sons and daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Serug lived thirty years, and begat Nahor:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Serug lived after he begat Nahor two hundred years, and begat sons and daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Nahor lived nine and twenty years, and begat Terah:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Nahor lived after he begat Terah an hundred and nineteen years, and begat sons and daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Terah lived seventy years, and begat Abram, Nahor, and Haran.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">Now these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the generations of Terah: Terah begat Abram, Nahor, and Haran; and Haran begat Lot.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Haran died before his father Terah in the land of his nativity, in Ur of the Chaldees.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Abram and Nahor took them wives: the name of Abram's wife &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Sarai; and the name of Nahor's wife, Milcah, the daughter of Haran, the father of Milcah, and the father of Iscah.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">But Sarai was barren; she &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; no child.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Terah took Abram his son, and Lot the son of Haran his son's son, and Sarai his daughter in law, his son Abram's wife; and they went forth with them from Ur of the Chaldees, to go into the land of Canaan; and they came unto Haran, and dwelt there.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And the days of Terah were two hundred and five years: and Terah died in Haran.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>