<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="43" verseCount="34" nextChapter="genesis_44.html" nextTitle="Genesis 44" prevChapter="genesis_42.html" prevTitle="Genesis 42" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the famine &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; sore in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And it came to pass, when they had eaten up the corn which they had brought out of Egypt, their father said unto them, Go again, buy us a little food.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Judah spake unto him, saying, The man did solemnly protest unto us, saying, Ye shall not see my face, except your brother &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; with you.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">If thou wilt send our brother with us, we will go down and buy thee food:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But if thou wilt not send &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, we will not go down: for the man said unto us, Ye shall not see my face, except your brother &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; with you.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Israel said, Wherefore dealt ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; ill with me, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; to tell the man whether ye had yet a brother?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they said, The man asked us straitly of our state, and of our kindred, saying, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; your father yet alive? have ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;another&lt;/span&gt; brother? and we told him according to the tenor of these words: could we certainly know that he would say, Bring your brother down?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Judah said unto Israel his father, Send the lad with me, and we will arise and go; that we may live, and not die, both we, and thou, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; also our little ones.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I will be surety for him; of my hand shalt thou require him: if I bring him not unto thee, and set him before thee, then let me bear the blame for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For except we had lingered, surely now we had returned this second time.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And their father Israel said unto them, If &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it must be&lt;/span&gt; so now, do this; take of the best fruits in the land in your vessels, and carry down the man a present, a little balm, and a little honey, spices, and myrrh, nuts, and almonds:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And take double money in your hand; and the money that was brought again in the mouth of your sacks, carry &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; again in your hand; peradventure it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; an oversight:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Take also your brother, and arise, go again unto the man:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And God Almighty give you mercy before the man, that he may send away your other brother, and Benjamin. If I be bereaved &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of my children&lt;/span&gt;, I am bereaved.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And the men took that present, and they took double money in their hand, and Benjamin; and rose up, and went down to Egypt, and stood before Joseph.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And when Joseph saw Benjamin with them, he said to the ruler of his house, Bring &lt;span class='extra'&gt;these&lt;/span&gt; men home, and slay, and make ready; for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;these&lt;/span&gt; men shall dine with me at noon.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the man did as Joseph bade; and the man brought the men into Joseph's house.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the men were afraid, because they were brought into Joseph's house; and they said, Because of the money that was returned in our sacks at the first time are we brought in; that he may seek occasion against us, and fall upon us, and take us for bondmen, and our asses.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And they came near to the steward of Joseph's house, and they communed with him at the door of the house,</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And said, O sir, we came indeed down at the first time to buy food:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And it came to pass, when we came to the inn, that we opened our sacks, and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;every&lt;/span&gt; man's money &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the mouth of his sack, our money in full weight: and we have brought it again in our hand.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And other money have we brought down in our hands to buy food: we cannot tell who put our money in our sacks.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he said, Peace &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; to you, fear not: your God, and the God of your father, hath given you treasure in your sacks: I had your money. And he brought Simeon out unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the man brought the men into Joseph's house, and gave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; water, and they washed their feet; and he gave their asses provender.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they made ready the present against Joseph came at noon: for they heard that they should eat bread there.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And when Joseph came home, they brought him the present which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in their hand into the house, and bowed themselves to him to the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And he asked them of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; welfare, and said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; your father well, the old man of whom ye spake? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; he yet alive?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they answered, Thy servant our father &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in good health, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; yet alive. And they bowed down their heads, and made obeisance.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And he lifted up his eyes, and saw his brother Benjamin, his mother's son, and said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; this your younger brother, of whom ye spake unto me? And he said, God be gracious unto thee, my son.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Joseph made haste; for his bowels did yearn upon his brother: and he sought &lt;span class='extra'&gt;where&lt;/span&gt; to weep; and he entered into &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; chamber, and wept there.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And he washed his face, and went out, and refrained himself, and said, Set on bread.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And they set on for him by himself, and for them by themselves, and for the Egyptians, which did eat with him, by themselves: because the Egyptians might not eat bread with the Hebrews; for that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an abomination unto the Egyptians.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And they sat before him, the firstborn according to his birthright, and the youngest according to his youth: and the men marvelled one at another.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And he took &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and sent&lt;/span&gt; messes unto them from before him: but Benjamin's mess was five times so much as any of theirs. And they drank, and were merry with him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>