<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="32" verseCount="32" nextChapter="genesis_33.html" nextTitle="Genesis 33" prevChapter="genesis_31.html" prevTitle="Genesis 31" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Jacob went on his way, and the angels of God met him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And when Jacob saw them, he said, This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; God's host: and he called the name of that place Mahanaim.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Jacob sent messengers before him to Esau his brother unto the land of Seir, the country of Edom.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he commanded them, saying, Thus shall ye speak unto my lord Esau; Thy servant Jacob saith thus, I have sojourned with Laban, and stayed there until now:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And I have oxen, and asses, flocks, and menservants, and womenservants: and I have sent to tell my lord, that I may find grace in thy sight.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And the messengers returned to Jacob, saying, We came to thy brother Esau, and also he cometh to meet thee, and four hundred men with him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then Jacob was greatly afraid and distressed: and he divided the people that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; with him, and the flocks, and herds, and the camels, into two bands;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And said, If Esau come to the one company, and smite it, then the other company which is left shall escape.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And Jacob said, O God of my father Abraham, and God of my father Isaac, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which saidst unto me, Return unto thy country, and to thy kindred, and I will deal well with thee:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I am not worthy of the least of all the mercies, and of all the truth, which thou hast shewed unto thy servant; for with my staff I passed over this Jordan; and now I am become two bands.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Deliver me, I pray thee, from the hand of my brother, from the hand of Esau: for I fear him, lest he will come and smite me, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the mother with the children.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And thou saidst, I will surely do thee good, and make thy seed as the sand of the sea, which cannot be numbered for multitude.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And he lodged there that same night; and took of that which came to his hand a present for Esau his brother;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Two hundred she goats, and twenty he goats, two hundred ewes, and twenty rams,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Thirty milch camels with their colts, forty kine, and ten bulls, twenty she asses, and ten foals.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he delivered &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; into the hand of his servants, every drove by themselves; and said unto his servants, Pass over before me, and put a space betwixt drove and drove.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he commanded the foremost, saying, When Esau my brother meeteth thee, and asketh thee, saying, Whose &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; thou? and whither goest thou? and whose &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; these before thee?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Then thou shalt say, &lt;i&gt;They be&lt;/i&gt; thy servant Jacob's; it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a present sent unto my lord Esau: and, behold, also he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; behind us.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And so commanded he the second, and the third, and all that followed the droves, saying, On this manner shall ye speak unto Esau, when ye find him.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And say ye moreover, Behold, thy servant Jacob &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; behind us. For he said, I will appease him with the present that goeth before me, and afterward I will see his face; peradventure he will accept of me.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">So went the present over before him: and himself lodged that night in the company.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And he rose up that night, and took his two wives, and his two womenservants, and his eleven sons, and passed over the ford Jabbok.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he took them, and sent them over the brook, and sent over that he had.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And Jacob was left alone; and there wrestled a man with him until the breaking of the day.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And when he saw that he prevailed not against him, he touched the hollow of his thigh; and the hollow of Jacob's thigh was out of joint, as he wrestled with him.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And he said, Let me go, for the day breaketh. And he said, I will not let thee go, except thou bless me.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And he said unto him, What &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy name? And he said, Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he said, Thy name shall be called no more Jacob, but Israel: for as a prince hast thou power with God and with men, and hast prevailed.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Jacob asked &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, and said, Tell &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt;, I pray thee, thy name. And he said, Wherefore &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; it &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thou dost ask after my name? And he blessed him there.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Jacob called the name of the place Peniel: for I have seen God face to face, and my life is preserved.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And as he passed over Penuel the sun rose upon him, and he halted upon his thigh.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Therefore the children of Israel eat not &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; the sinew which shrank, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; upon the hollow of the thigh, unto this day: because he touched the hollow of Jacob's thigh in the sinew that shrank.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>