<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="22" nextChapter="genesis_7.html" nextTitle="Genesis 7" prevChapter="genesis_5.html" prevTitle="Genesis 5" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, when men began to multiply on the face of the earth, and daughters were born unto them,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That the sons of God saw the daughters of men that they &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; fair; and they took them wives of all which they chose.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said, My spirit shall not always strive with man, for that he also &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; flesh: yet his days shall be an hundred and twenty years.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">There were giants in the earth in those days; and also after that, when the sons of God came in unto the daughters of men, and they bare &lt;i&gt;children&lt;/i&gt; to them, the same &lt;i&gt;became&lt;/i&gt; mighty men which &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; of old, men of renown.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; saw that the wickedness of man &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; great in the earth, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; every imagination of the thoughts of his heart &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; only evil continually.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And it repented the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him at his heart.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said, I will destroy man whom I have created from the face of the earth; both man, and beast, and the creeping thing, and the fowls of the air; for it repenteth me that I have made them.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But Noah found grace in the eyes of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the generations of Noah: Noah was a just man &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; perfect in his generations, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Noah walked with God.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Noah begat three sons, Shem, Ham, and Japheth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The earth also was corrupt before God, and the earth was filled with violence.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And God looked upon the earth, and, behold, it was corrupt; for all flesh had corrupted his way upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And God said unto Noah, The end of all flesh is come before me; for the earth is filled with violence through them; and, behold, I will destroy them with the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Make thee an ark of gopher wood; rooms shalt thou make in the ark, and shalt pitch it within and without with pitch.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And this &lt;i&gt;is the fashion&lt;/i&gt; which thou shalt make it &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt;: The length of the ark &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; three hundred cubits, the breadth of it fifty cubits, and the height of it thirty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">A window shalt thou make to the ark, and in a cubit shalt thou finish it above; and the door of the ark shalt thou set in the side thereof; &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; lower, second, and third &lt;i&gt;stories&lt;/i&gt; shalt thou make it.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And, behold, I, even I, do bring a flood of waters upon the earth, to destroy all flesh, wherein &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the breath of life, from under heaven; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; every thing that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the earth shall die.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But with thee will I establish my covenant; and thou shalt come into the ark, thou, and thy sons, and thy wife, and thy sons' wives with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And of every living thing of all flesh, two of every &lt;i&gt;sort&lt;/i&gt; shalt thou bring into the ark, to keep &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; alive with thee; they shall be male and female.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Of fowls after their kind, and of cattle after their kind, of every creeping thing of the earth after his kind, two of every &lt;i&gt;sort&lt;/i&gt; shall come unto thee, to keep &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; alive.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And take thou unto thee of all food that is eaten, and thou shalt gather &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to thee; and it shall be for food for thee, and for them.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Thus did Noah; according to all that God commanded him, so did he.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>