<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="26" verseCount="35" nextChapter="genesis_27.html" nextTitle="Genesis 27" prevChapter="genesis_25.html" prevTitle="Genesis 25" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And there was a famine in the land, beside the first famine that was in the days of Abraham. And Isaac went unto Abimelech king of the Philistines unto Gerar.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared unto him, and said, Go not down into Egypt; dwell in the land which I shall tell thee of:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Sojourn in this land, and I will be with thee, and will bless thee; for unto thee, and unto thy seed, I will give all these countries, and I will perform the oath which I sware unto Abraham thy father;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And I will make thy seed to multiply as the stars of heaven, and will give unto thy seed all these countries; and in thy seed shall all the nations of the earth be blessed;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Because that Abraham obeyed my voice, and kept my charge, my commandments, my statutes, and my laws.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And Isaac dwelt in Gerar:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the men of the place asked &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; of his wife; and he said, She &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my sister: for he feared to say, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;She is&lt;/span&gt; my wife; lest, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;said he&lt;/span&gt;, the men of the place should kill me for Rebekah; because she &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; fair to look upon.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And it came to pass, when he had been there a long time, that Abimelech king of the Philistines looked out at a window, and saw, and, behold, Isaac &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; sporting with Rebekah his wife.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Abimelech called Isaac, and said, Behold, of a surety she &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy wife: and how saidst thou, She &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my sister? And Isaac said unto him, Because I said, Lest I die for her.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Abimelech said, What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this thou hast done unto us? one of the people might lightly have lien with thy wife, and thou shouldest have brought guiltiness upon us.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Abimelech charged all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; people, saying, He that toucheth this man or his wife shall surely be put to death.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Then Isaac sowed in that land, and received in the same year an hundredfold: and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; blessed him.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the man waxed great, and went forward, and grew until he became very great:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For he had possession of flocks, and possession of herds, and great store of servants: and the Philistines envied him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For all the wells which his father's servants had digged in the days of Abraham his father, the Philistines had stopped them, and filled them with earth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Abimelech said unto Isaac, Go from us; for thou art much mightier than we.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And Isaac departed thence, and pitched his tent in the valley of Gerar, and dwelt there.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Isaac digged again the wells of water, which they had digged in the days of Abraham his father; for the Philistines had stopped them after the death of Abraham: and he called their names after the names by which his father had called them.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Isaac's servants digged in the valley, and found there a well of springing water.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the herdmen of Gerar did strive with Isaac's herdmen, saying, The water &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; ours: and he called the name of the well Esek; because they strove with him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they digged another well, and strove for that also: and he called the name of it Sitnah.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And he removed from thence, and digged another well; and for that they strove not: and he called the name of it Rehoboth; and he said, For now the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath made room for us, and we shall be fruitful in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he went up from thence to Beer-sheba.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared unto him the same night, and said, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the God of Abraham thy father: fear not, for I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; with thee, and will bless thee, and multiply thy seed for my servant Abraham's sake.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And he builded an altar there, and called upon the name of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and pitched his tent there: and there Isaac's servants digged a well.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">Then Abimelech went to him from Gerar, and Ahuzzath one of his friends, and Phichol the chief captain of his army.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Isaac said unto them, Wherefore come ye to me, seeing ye hate me, and have sent me away from you?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they said, We saw certainly that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was with thee: and we said, Let there be now an oath betwixt us, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; betwixt us and thee, and let us make a covenant with thee;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">That thou wilt do us no hurt, as we have not touched thee, and as we have done unto thee nothing but good, and have sent thee away in peace: thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; now the blessed of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And he made them a feast, and they did eat and drink.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And they rose up betimes in the morning, and sware one to another: and Isaac sent them away, and they departed from him in peace.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And it came to pass the same day, that Isaac's servants came, and told him concerning the well which they had digged, and said unto him, We have found water.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And he called it Shebah: therefore the name of the city &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Beer-sheba unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">And Esau was forty years old when he took to wife Judith the daughter of Beeri the Hittite, and Bashemath the daughter of Elon the Hittite:</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Which were a grief of mind unto Isaac and to Rebekah.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>