<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="47" verseCount="31" nextChapter="genesis_48.html" nextTitle="Genesis 48" prevChapter="genesis_46.html" prevTitle="Genesis 46" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then Joseph came and told Pharaoh, and said, My father and my brethren, and their flocks, and their herds, and all that they have, are come out of the land of Canaan; and, behold, they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in the land of Goshen.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he took some of his brethren, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; five men, and presented them unto Pharaoh.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Pharaoh said unto his brethren, What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; your occupation? And they said unto Pharaoh, Thy servants &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; shepherds, both we, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; also our fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They said moreover unto Pharaoh, For to sojourn in the land are we come; for thy servants have no pasture for their flocks; for the famine &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; sore in the land of Canaan: now therefore, we pray thee, let thy servants dwell in the land of Goshen.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Pharaoh spake unto Joseph, saying, Thy father and thy brethren are come unto thee:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The land of Egypt &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; before thee; in the best of the land make thy father and brethren to dwell; in the land of Goshen let them dwell: and if thou knowest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; men of activity among them, then make them rulers over my cattle.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Joseph brought in Jacob his father, and set him before Pharaoh: and Jacob blessed Pharaoh.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Pharaoh said unto Jacob, How old &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; thou?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Jacob said unto Pharaoh, The days of the years of my pilgrimage &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; an hundred and thirty years: few and evil have the days of the years of my life been, and have not attained unto the days of the years of the life of my fathers in the days of their pilgrimage.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Jacob blessed Pharaoh, and went out from before Pharaoh.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And Joseph placed his father and his brethren, and gave them a possession in the land of Egypt, in the best of the land, in the land of Rameses, as Pharaoh had commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Joseph nourished his father, and his brethren, and all his father's household, with bread, according to &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; families.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; no bread in all the land; for the famine &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; very sore, so that the land of Egypt and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; the land of Canaan fainted by reason of the famine.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Joseph gathered up all the money that was found in the land of Egypt, and in the land of Canaan, for the corn which they bought: and Joseph brought the money into Pharaoh's house.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And when money failed in the land of Egypt, and in the land of Canaan, all the Egyptians came unto Joseph, and said, Give us bread: for why should we die in thy presence? for the money faileth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Joseph said, Give your cattle; and I will give you for your cattle, if money fail.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And they brought their cattle unto Joseph: and Joseph gave them bread &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in exchange&lt;/span&gt; for horses, and for the flocks, and for the cattle of the herds, and for the asses: and he fed them with bread for all their cattle for that year.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">When that year was ended, they came unto him the second year, and said unto him, We will not hide &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; from my lord, how that our money is spent; my lord also hath our herds of cattle; there is not ought left in the sight of my lord, but our bodies, and our lands:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Wherefore shall we die before thine eyes, both we and our land? buy us and our land for bread, and we and our land will be servants unto Pharaoh: and give &lt;span class='extra'&gt;us&lt;/span&gt; seed, that we may live, and not die, that the land be not desolate.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Joseph bought all the land of Egypt for Pharaoh; for the Egyptians sold every man his field, because the famine prevailed over them: so the land became Pharaoh's.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And as for the people, he removed them to cities from &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; end of the borders of Egypt even to the &lt;span class='extra'&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; end thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Only the land of the priests bought he not; for the priests had a portion &lt;span class='extra'&gt;assigned them&lt;/span&gt; of Pharaoh, and did eat their portion which Pharaoh gave them: wherefore they sold not their lands.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Then Joseph said unto the people, Behold, I have bought you this day and your land for Pharaoh: lo, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;here is&lt;/span&gt; seed for you, and ye shall sow the land.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And it shall come to pass in the increase, that ye shall give the fifth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;part&lt;/span&gt; unto Pharaoh, and four parts shall be your own, for seed of the field, and for your food, and for them of your households, and for food for your little ones.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they said, Thou hast saved our lives: let us find grace in the sight of my lord, and we will be Pharaoh's servants.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Joseph made it a law over the land of Egypt unto this day, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; Pharaoh should have the fifth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;part&lt;/span&gt;; except the land of the priests only, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; became not Pharaoh's.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And Israel dwelt in the land of Egypt, in the country of Goshen; and they had possessions therein, and grew, and multiplied exceedingly.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Jacob lived in the land of Egypt seventeen years: so the whole age of Jacob was an hundred forty and seven years.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And the time drew nigh that Israel must die: and he called his son Joseph, and said unto him, If now I have found grace in thy sight, put, I pray thee, thy hand under my thigh, and deal kindly and truly with me; bury me not, I pray thee, in Egypt:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">But I will lie with my fathers, and thou shalt carry me out of Egypt, and bury me in their buryingplace. And he said, I will do as thou hast said.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And he said, Swear unto me. And he sware unto him. And Israel bowed himself upon the bed's head.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>