<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="35" verseCount="29" nextChapter="genesis_36.html" nextTitle="Genesis 36" prevChapter="genesis_34.html" prevTitle="Genesis 34" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And God said unto Jacob, Arise, go up to Beth-el, and dwell there: and make there an altar unto God, that appeared unto thee when thou fleddest from the face of Esau thy brother.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then Jacob said unto his household, and to all that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him, Put away the strange gods that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; among you, and be clean, and change your garments:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And let us arise, and go up to Beth-el; and I will make there an altar unto God, who answered me in the day of my distress, and was with me in the way which I went.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they gave unto Jacob all the strange gods which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in their hand, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;all their&lt;/span&gt; earrings which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in their ears; and Jacob hid them under the oak which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; by Shechem.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they journeyed: and the terror of God was upon the cities that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; round about them, and they did not pursue after the sons of Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">So Jacob came to Luz, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the land of Canaan, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;, Beth-el, he and all the people that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he built there an altar, and called the place El-beth-el: because there God appeared unto him, when he fled from the face of his brother.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But Deborah Rebekah's nurse died, and she was buried beneath Beth-el under an oak: and the name of it was called Allon-bachuth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And God appeared unto Jacob again, when he came out of Padan-aram, and blessed him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And God said unto him, Thy name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Jacob: thy name shall not be called any more Jacob, but Israel shall be thy name: and he called his name Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And God said unto him, I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; God Almighty: be fruitful and multiply; a nation and a company of nations shall be of thee, and kings shall come out of thy loins;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the land which I gave Abraham and Isaac, to thee I will give it, and to thy seed after thee will I give the land.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And God went up from him in the place where he talked with him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Jacob set up a pillar in the place where he talked with him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; a pillar of stone: and he poured a drink offering thereon, and he poured oil thereon.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Jacob called the name of the place where God spake with him, Beth-el.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And they journeyed from Beth-el; and there was but a little way to come to Ephrath: and Rachel travailed, and she had hard labour.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And it came to pass, when she was in hard labour, that the midwife said unto her, Fear not; thou shalt have this son also.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And it came to pass, as her soul was in departing, (for she died) that she called his name Ben-oni: but his father called him Benjamin.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Rachel died, and was buried in the way to Ephrath, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Beth-lehem.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Jacob set a pillar upon her grave: that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the pillar of Rachel's grave unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">And Israel journeyed, and spread his tent beyond the tower of Edar.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And it came to pass, when Israel dwelt in that land, that Reuben went and lay with Bilhah his father's concubine: and Israel heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;. Now the sons of Jacob were twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The sons of Leah; Reuben, Jacob's firstborn, and Simeon, and Levi, and Judah, and Issachar, and Zebulun:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The sons of Rachel; Joseph, and Benjamin:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the sons of Bilhah, Rachel's handmaid; Dan, and Naphtali:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And the sons of Zilpah, Leah's handmaid; Gad, and Asher: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Jacob, which were born to him in Padan-aram.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And Jacob came unto Isaac his father unto Mamre, unto the city of Arbah, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Hebron, where Abraham and Isaac sojourned.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the days of Isaac were an hundred and fourscore years.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Isaac gave up the ghost, and died, and was gathered unto his people, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; old and full of days: and his sons Esau and Jacob buried him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>