<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="1" name="Genesis" bookPage="genesis.html" title="Genesis" chapterCount="50" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="exodus_1.html" nextTitle="Exodus" prevBook="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation">
    <chapter number="39" verseCount="23" nextChapter="genesis_40.html" nextTitle="Genesis 40" prevChapter="genesis_38.html" prevTitle="Genesis 38" chapterPage="genesis_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Joseph was brought down to Egypt; and Potiphar, an officer of Pharaoh, captain of the guard, an Egyptian, bought him of the hands of the Ishmeelites, which had brought him down thither.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was with Joseph, and he was a prosperous man; and he was in the house of his master the Egyptian.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And his master saw that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; with him, and that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made all that he did to prosper in his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Joseph found grace in his sight, and he served him: and he made him overseer over his house, and all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; he had he put into his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And it came to pass from the time &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; he had made him overseer in his house, and over all that he had, that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; blessed the Egyptian's house for Joseph's sake; and the blessing of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was upon all that he had in the house, and in the field.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he left all that he had in Joseph's hand; and he knew not ought he had, save the bread which he did eat. And Joseph was &lt;span class="extra"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; goodly &lt;span class="extra"&gt;person&lt;/span&gt;, and well favoured.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And it came to pass after these things, that his master's wife cast her eyes upon Joseph; and she said, Lie with me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But he refused, and said unto his master's wife, Behold, my master wotteth not what &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with me in the house, and he hath committed all that he hath to my hand;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;There is&lt;/span&gt; none greater in this house than I; neither hath he kept back any thing from me but thee, because thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; his wife: how then can I do this great wickedness, and sin against God?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And it came to pass, as she spake to Joseph day by day, that he hearkened not unto her, to lie by her, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; to be with her.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And it came to pass about this time, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Joseph&lt;/span&gt; went into the house to do his business; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; none of the men of the house there within.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And she caught him by his garment, saying, Lie with me: and he left his garment in her hand, and fled, and got him out.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And it came to pass, when she saw that he had left his garment in her hand, and was fled forth,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">That she called unto the men of her house, and spake unto them, saying, See, he hath brought in an Hebrew unto us to mock us; he came in unto me to lie with me, and I cried with a loud voice:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And it came to pass, when he heard that I lifted up my voice and cried, that he left his garment with me, and fled, and got him out.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And she laid up his garment by her, until his lord came home.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And she spake unto him according to these words, saying, The Hebrew servant, which thou hast brought unto us, came in unto me to mock me:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And it came to pass, as I lifted up my voice and cried, that he left his garment with me, and fled out.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And it came to pass, when his master heard the words of his wife, which she spake unto him, saying, After this manner did thy servant to me; that his wrath was kindled.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Joseph's master took him, and put him into the prison, a place where the king's prisoners &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; bound: and he was there in the prison.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">But the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was with Joseph, and shewed him mercy, and gave him favour in the sight of the keeper of the prison.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the keeper of the prison committed to Joseph's hand all the prisoners that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the prison; and whatsoever they did there, he was the doer &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The keeper of the prison looked not to any thing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that was&lt;/span&gt; under his hand; because the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was with him, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which he did, the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to prosper.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>