<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="36" verseCount="38" nextChapter="exodus_37.html" nextTitle="Exodus 37" prevChapter="exodus_35.html" prevTitle="Exodus 35" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then wrought Bezaleel and Aholiab, and every wise hearted man, in whom the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; put wisdom and understanding to know how to work all manner of work for the service of the sanctuary, according to all that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Moses called Bezaleel and Aholiab, and every wise hearted man, in whose heart the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had put wisdom, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; every one whose heart stirred him up to come unto the work to do it:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they received of Moses all the offering, which the children of Israel had brought for the work of the service of the sanctuary, to make it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;withal&lt;/span&gt;. And they brought yet unto him free offerings every morning.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And all the wise men, that wrought all the work of the sanctuary, came every man from his work which they made;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And they spake unto Moses, saying, The people bring much more than enough for the service of the work, which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded to make.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Moses gave commandment, and they caused it to be proclaimed throughout the camp, saying, Let neither man nor woman make any more work for the offering of the sanctuary. So the people were restrained from bringing.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For the stuff they had was sufficient for all the work to make it, and too much.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And every wise hearted man among them that wrought the work of the tabernacle made ten curtains &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; fine twined linen, and blue, and purple, and scarlet: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; cherubims of cunning work made he them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The length of one curtain &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; twenty and eight cubits, and the breadth of one curtain four cubits: the curtains &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; all of one size.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he coupled the five curtains one unto another: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the other&lt;/span&gt; five curtains he coupled one unto another.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he made loops of blue on the edge of one curtain from the selvedge in the coupling: likewise he made in the uttermost side of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;another&lt;/span&gt; curtain, in the coupling of the second.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Fifty loops made he in one curtain, and fifty loops made he in the edge of the curtain which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the coupling of the second: the loops held one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;curtain&lt;/span&gt; to another.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he made fifty taches of gold, and coupled the curtains one unto another with the taches: so it became one tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And he made curtains &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; goats' &lt;span class='extra'&gt;hair&lt;/span&gt; for the tent over the tabernacle: eleven curtains he made them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The length of one curtain &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; thirty cubits, and four cubits &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the breadth of one curtain: the eleven curtains &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; of one size.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he coupled five curtains by themselves, and six curtains by themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he made fifty loops upon the uttermost edge of the curtain in the coupling, and fifty loops made he upon the edge of the curtain which coupleth the second.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And he made fifty taches &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; brass to couple the tent together, that it might be one.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he made a covering for the tent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; rams' skins dyed red, and a covering &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; badgers' skins above &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And he made boards for the tabernacle &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; shittim wood, standing up.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The length of a board &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; ten cubits, and the breadth of a board one cubit and a half.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">One board had two tenons, equally distant one from another: thus did he make for all the boards of the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he made boards for the tabernacle; twenty boards for the south side southward:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And forty sockets of silver he made under the twenty boards; two sockets under one board for his two tenons, and two sockets under another board for his two tenons.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And for the other side of the tabernacle, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which is&lt;/span&gt; toward the north corner, he made twenty boards,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And their forty sockets of silver; two sockets under one board, and two sockets under another board.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And for the sides of the tabernacle westward he made six boards.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And two boards made he for the corners of the tabernacle in the two sides.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And they were coupled beneath, and coupled together at the head thereof, to one ring: thus he did to both of them in both the corners.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And there were eight boards; and their sockets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; sixteen sockets of silver, under every board two sockets.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And he made bars of shittim wood; five for the boards of the one side of the tabernacle,</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And five bars for the boards of the other side of the tabernacle, and five bars for the boards of the tabernacle for the sides westward.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And he made the middle bar to shoot through the boards from the one end to the other.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And he overlaid the boards with gold, and made their rings &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; gold &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; places for the bars, and overlaid the bars with gold.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35" newPara="true">And he made a vail &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine twined linen: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; cherubims made he it of cunning work.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And he made thereunto four pillars &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; shittim &lt;span class='extra'&gt;wood&lt;/span&gt;, and overlaid them with gold: their hooks &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were of&lt;/span&gt; gold; and he cast for them four sockets of silver.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37" newPara="true">And he made an hanging for the tabernacle door &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine twined linen, of needlework;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And the five pillars of it with their hooks: and he overlaid their chapiters and their fillets with gold: but their five sockets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were of&lt;/span&gt; brass.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>