<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="36" nextChapter="exodus_17.html" nextTitle="Exodus 17" prevChapter="exodus_15.html" prevTitle="Exodus 15" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And they took their journey from Elim, and all the congregation of the children of Israel came unto the wilderness of Sin, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; between Elim and Sinai, on the fifteenth day of the second month after their departing out of the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the whole congregation of the children of Israel murmured against Moses and Aaron in the wilderness:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the children of Israel said unto them, Would to God we had died by the hand of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the land of Egypt, when we sat by the flesh pots, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; when we did eat bread to the full; for ye have brought us forth into this wilderness, to kill this whole assembly with hunger.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Then said the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto Moses, Behold, I will rain bread from heaven for you; and the people shall go out and gather a certain rate every day, that I may prove them, whether they will walk in my law, or no.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And it shall come to pass, that on the sixth day they shall prepare &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which they bring in; and it shall be twice as much as they gather daily.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Moses and Aaron said unto all the children of Israel, At even, then ye shall know that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath brought you out from the land of Egypt:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And in the morning, then ye shall see the glory of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for that he heareth your murmurings against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; we, that ye murmur against us?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Moses said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;This shall be&lt;/span&gt;, when the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall give you in the evening flesh to eat, and in the morning bread to the full; for that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; heareth your murmurings which ye murmur against him: and what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; we? your murmurings &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not against us, but against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And Moses spake unto Aaron, Say unto all the congregation of the children of Israel, Come near before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for he hath heard your murmurings.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And it came to pass, as Aaron spake unto the whole congregation of the children of Israel, that they looked toward the wilderness, and, behold, the glory of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared in the cloud.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I have heard the murmurings of the children of Israel: speak unto them, saying, At even ye shall eat flesh, and in the morning ye shall be filled with bread; and ye shall know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And it came to pass, that at even the quails came up, and covered the camp: and in the morning the dew lay round about the host.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And when the dew that lay was gone up, behold, upon the face of the wilderness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there lay&lt;/span&gt; a small round thing, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; small as the hoar frost on the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And when the children of Israel saw &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, they said one to another, It &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; manna: for they wist not what it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt;. And Moses said unto them, This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the bread which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath given you to eat.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the thing which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath commanded, Gather of it every man according to his eating, an omer for every man, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;according to&lt;/span&gt; the number of your persons; take ye every man for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in his tents.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the children of Israel did so, and gathered, some more, some less.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And when they did mete &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; with an omer, he that gathered much had nothing over, and he that gathered little had no lack; they gathered every man according to his eating.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Moses said, Let no man leave of it till the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Notwithstanding they hearkened not unto Moses; but some of them left of it until the morning, and it bred worms, and stank: and Moses was wroth with them.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they gathered it every morning, every man according to his eating: and when the sun waxed hot, it melted.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And it came to pass, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; on the sixth day they gathered twice as much bread, two omers for one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt;: and all the rulers of the congregation came and told Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he said unto them, This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is that&lt;/span&gt; which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath said, To morrow &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the rest of the holy sabbath unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: bake &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which ye will bake &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to day&lt;/span&gt;, and seethe that ye will seethe; and that which remaineth over lay up for you to be kept until the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they laid it up till the morning, as Moses bade: and it did not stink, neither was there any worm therein.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Moses said, Eat that to day; for to day &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a sabbath unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: to day ye shall not find it in the field.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Six days ye shall gather it; but on the seventh day, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which is&lt;/span&gt; the sabbath, in it there shall be none.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And it came to pass, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; there went out &lt;span class='extra'&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of the people on the seventh day for to gather, and they found none.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, How long refuse ye to keep my commandments and my laws?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">See, for that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath given you the sabbath, therefore he giveth you on the sixth day the bread of two days; abide ye every man in his place, let no man go out of his place on the seventh day.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">So the people rested on the seventh day.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And the house of Israel called the name thereof Manna: and it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; like coriander seed, white; and the taste of it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; like wafers &lt;span class='extra'&gt;made&lt;/span&gt; with honey.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">And Moses said, This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the thing which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commandeth, Fill an omer of it to be kept for your generations; that they may see the bread wherewith I have fed you in the wilderness, when I brought you forth from the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And Moses said unto Aaron, Take a pot, and put an omer full of manna therein, and lay it up before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to be kept for your generations.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">As the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses, so Aaron laid it up before the Testimony, to be kept.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And the children of Israel did eat manna forty years, until they came to a land inhabited; they did eat manna, until they came unto the borders of the land of Canaan.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Now an omer &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the tenth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;part&lt;/span&gt; of an ephah.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>