<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="23" nextChapter="exodus_6.html" nextTitle="Exodus 6" prevChapter="exodus_4.html" prevTitle="Exodus 4" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And afterward Moses and Aaron went in, and told Pharaoh, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, Let my people go, that they may hold a feast unto me in the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Pharaoh said, Who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that I should obey his voice to let Israel go? I know not the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, neither will I let Israel go.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they said, The God of the Hebrews hath met with us: let us go, we pray thee, three days' journey into the desert, and sacrifice unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God; lest he fall upon us with pestilence, or with the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the king of Egypt said unto them, Wherefore do ye, Moses and Aaron, let the people from their works? get you unto your burdens.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Pharaoh said, Behold, the people of the land now &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; many, and ye make them rest from their burdens.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Pharaoh commanded the same day the taskmasters of the people, and their officers, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Ye shall no more give the people straw to make brick, as heretofore: let them go and gather straw for themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the tale of the bricks, which they did make heretofore, ye shall lay upon them; ye shall not diminish &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ought&lt;/span&gt; thereof: for they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; idle; therefore they cry, saying, Let us go &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; sacrifice to our God.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Let there more work be laid upon the men, that they may labour therein; and let them not regard vain words.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And the taskmasters of the people went out, and their officers, and they spake to the people, saying, Thus saith Pharaoh, I will not give you straw.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Go ye, get you straw where ye can find it: yet not ought of your work shall be diminished.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">So the people were scattered abroad throughout all the land of Egypt to gather stubble instead of straw.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the taskmasters hasted &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, saying, Fulfil your works, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; daily tasks, as when there was straw.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the officers of the children of Israel, which Pharaoh's taskmasters had set over them, were beaten, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; demanded, Wherefore have ye not fulfilled your task in making brick both yesterday and to day, as heretofore?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Then the officers of the children of Israel came and cried unto Pharaoh, saying, Wherefore dealest thou thus with thy servants?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">There is no straw given unto thy servants, and they say to us, Make brick: and, behold, thy servants &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; beaten; but the fault &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in thine own people.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But he said, Ye &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; idle, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ye are&lt;/span&gt; idle: therefore ye say, Let us go &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; do sacrifice to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Go therefore now, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; work; for there shall no straw be given you, yet shall ye deliver the tale of bricks.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the officers of the children of Israel did see &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in evil &lt;span class="extra"&gt;case&lt;/span&gt;, after it was said, Ye shall not minish &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ought&lt;/span&gt; from your bricks of your daily task.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And they met Moses and Aaron, who stood in the way, as they came forth from Pharaoh:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they said unto them, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; look upon you, and judge; because ye have made our savour to be abhorred in the eyes of Pharaoh, and in the eyes of his servants, to put a sword in their hand to slay us.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Moses returned unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and said, Lord, wherefore hast thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; evil entreated this people? why &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thou hast sent me?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For since I came to Pharaoh to speak in thy name, he hath done evil to this people; neither hast thou delivered thy people at all.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>