<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="35" verseCount="35" nextChapter="exodus_36.html" nextTitle="Exodus 36" prevChapter="exodus_34.html" prevTitle="Exodus 34" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Moses gathered all the congregation of the children of Israel together, and said unto them, These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the words which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath commanded, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ye&lt;/span&gt; should do them.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Six days shall work be done, but on the seventh day there shall be to you an holy day, a sabbath of rest to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: whosoever doeth work therein shall be put to death.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Ye shall kindle no fire throughout your habitations upon the sabbath day.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And Moses spake unto all the congregation of the children of Israel, saying, This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the thing which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Take ye from among you an offering unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: whosoever &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; of a willing heart, let him bring it, an offering of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; gold, and silver, and brass,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine linen, and goats' &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hair&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And rams' skins dyed red, and badgers' skins, and shittim wood,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And oil for the light, and spices for anointing oil, and for the sweet incense,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And onyx stones, and stones to be set for the ephod, and for the breastplate.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And every wise hearted among you shall come, and make all that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath commanded;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The tabernacle, his tent, and his covering, his taches, and his boards, his bars, his pillars, and his sockets,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The ark, and the staves thereof, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; the mercy seat, and the vail of the covering,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The table, and his staves, and all his vessels, and the shewbread,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The candlestick also for the light, and his furniture, and his lamps, with the oil for the light,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the incense altar, and his staves, and the anointing oil, and the sweet incense, and the hanging for the door at the entering in of the tabernacle,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The altar of burnt offering, with his brasen grate, his staves, and all his vessels, the laver and his foot,</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The hangings of the court, his pillars, and their sockets, and the hanging for the door of the court,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The pins of the tabernacle, and the pins of the court, and their cords,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The cloths of service, to do service in the holy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;, the holy garments for Aaron the priest, and the garments of his sons, to minister in the priest's office.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And all the congregation of the children of Israel departed from the presence of Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they came, every one whose heart stirred him up, and every one whom his spirit made willing, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; they brought the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s offering to the work of the tabernacle of the congregation, and for all his service, and for the holy garments.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And they came, both men and women, as many as were willing hearted, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; brought bracelets, and earrings, and rings, and tablets, all jewels of gold: and every man that offered &lt;span class="extra"&gt;offered&lt;/span&gt; an offering of gold unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And every man, with whom was found blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine linen, and goats' &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hair&lt;/span&gt;, and red skins of rams, and badgers' skins, brought &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Every one that did offer an offering of silver and brass brought the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s offering: and every man, with whom was found shittim wood for any work of the service, brought &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And all the women that were wise hearted did spin with their hands, and brought that which they had spun, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; of blue, and of purple, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; of scarlet, and of fine linen.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And all the women whose heart stirred them up in wisdom spun goats' &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hair&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And the rulers brought onyx stones, and stones to be set, for the ephod, and for the breastplate;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And spice, and oil for the light, and for the anointing oil, and for the sweet incense.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The children of Israel brought a willing offering unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, every man and woman, whose heart made them willing to bring for all manner of work, which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had commanded to be made by the hand of Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">And Moses said unto the children of Israel, See, the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath called by name Bezaleel the son of Uri, the son of Hur, of the tribe of Judah;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And he hath filled him with the spirit of God, in wisdom, in understanding, and in knowledge, and in all manner of workmanship;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And to devise curious works, to work in gold, and in silver, and in brass,</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And in the cutting of stones, to set &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, and in carving of wood, to make any manner of cunning work.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And he hath put in his heart that he may teach, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; he, and Aholiab, the son of Ahisamach, of the tribe of Dan.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Them hath he filled with wisdom of heart, to work all manner of work, of the engraver, and of the cunning workman, and of the embroiderer, in blue, and in purple, in scarlet, and in fine linen, and of the weaver, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of them that do any work, and of those that devise cunning work.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>