<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="25" nextChapter="exodus_8.html" nextTitle="Exodus 8" prevChapter="exodus_6.html" prevTitle="Exodus 6" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, See, I have made thee a god to Pharaoh: and Aaron thy brother shall be thy prophet.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thou shalt speak all that I command thee: and Aaron thy brother shall speak unto Pharaoh, that he send the children of Israel out of his land.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I will harden Pharaoh's heart, and multiply my signs and my wonders in the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But Pharaoh shall not hearken unto you, that I may lay my hand upon Egypt, and bring forth mine armies, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; my people the children of Israel, out of the land of Egypt by great judgments.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the Egyptians shall know that I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, when I stretch forth mine hand upon Egypt, and bring out the children of Israel from among them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Moses and Aaron did as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded them, so did they.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Moses &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; fourscore years old, and Aaron fourscore and three years old, when they spake unto Pharaoh.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses and unto Aaron, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">When Pharaoh shall speak unto you, saying, Shew a miracle for you: then thou shalt say unto Aaron, Take thy rod, and cast &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; before Pharaoh, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; it shall become a serpent.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And Moses and Aaron went in unto Pharaoh, and they did so as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had commanded: and Aaron cast down his rod before Pharaoh, and before his servants, and it became a serpent.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then Pharaoh also called the wise men and the sorcerers: now the magicians of Egypt, they also did in like manner with their enchantments.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For they cast down every man his rod, and they became serpents: but Aaron's rod swallowed up their rods.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he hardened Pharaoh's heart, that he hearkened not unto them; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had said.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Pharaoh's heart &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; hardened, he refuseth to let the people go.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Get thee unto Pharaoh in the morning; lo, he goeth out unto the water; and thou shalt stand by the river's brink against he come; and the rod which was turned to a serpent shalt thou take in thine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And thou shalt say unto him, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of the Hebrews hath sent me unto thee, saying, Let my people go, that they may serve me in the wilderness: and, behold, hitherto thou wouldest not hear.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, In this thou shalt know that I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: behold, I will smite with the rod that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in mine hand upon the waters which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in the river, and they shall be turned to blood.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the fish that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the river shall die, and the river shall stink; and the Egyptians shall lothe to drink of the water of the river.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, Say unto Aaron, Take thy rod, and stretch out thine hand upon the waters of Egypt, upon their streams, upon their rivers, and upon their ponds, and upon all their pools of water, that they may become blood; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; there may be blood throughout all the land of Egypt, both in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;vessels of&lt;/span&gt; wood, and in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;vessels of&lt;/span&gt; stone.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Moses and Aaron did so, as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded; and he lifted up the rod, and smote the waters that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the river, in the sight of Pharaoh, and in the sight of his servants; and all the waters that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the river were turned to blood.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the fish that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the river died; and the river stank, and the Egyptians could not drink of the water of the river; and there was blood throughout all the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the magicians of Egypt did so with their enchantments: and Pharaoh's heart was hardened, neither did he hearken unto them; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had said.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Pharaoh turned and went into his house, neither did he set his heart to this also.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And all the Egyptians digged round about the river for water to drink; for they could not drink of the water of the river.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And seven days were fulfilled, after that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had smitten the river.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>