<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="27" verseCount="21" nextChapter="exodus_28.html" nextTitle="Exodus 28" prevChapter="exodus_26.html" prevTitle="Exodus 26" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And thou shalt make an altar &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; shittim wood, five cubits long, and five cubits broad; the altar shall be foursquare: and the height thereof &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; three cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And thou shalt make the horns of it upon the four corners thereof: his horns shall be of the same: and thou shalt overlay it with brass.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And thou shalt make his pans to receive his ashes, and his shovels, and his basons, and his fleshhooks, and his firepans: all the vessels thereof thou shalt make &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; brass.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And thou shalt make for it a grate of network &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; brass; and upon the net shalt thou make four brasen rings in the four corners thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And thou shalt put it under the compass of the altar beneath, that the net may be even to the midst of the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And thou shalt make staves for the altar, staves &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; shittim wood, and overlay them with brass.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the staves shall be put into the rings, and the staves shall be upon the two sides of the altar, to bear it.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Hollow with boards shalt thou make it: as it was shewed thee in the mount, so shall they make &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And thou shalt make the court of the tabernacle: for the south side southward &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; hangings for the court &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; fine twined linen of an hundred cubits long for one side:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the twenty pillars thereof and their twenty sockets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be of&lt;/span&gt; brass; the hooks of the pillars and their fillets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be of&lt;/span&gt; silver.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And likewise for the north side in length &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; hangings of an hundred &lt;span class='extra'&gt;cubits&lt;/span&gt; long, and his twenty pillars and their twenty sockets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; brass; the hooks of the pillars and their fillets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; silver.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the breadth of the court on the west side &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; hangings of fifty cubits: their pillars ten, and their sockets ten.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the breadth of the court on the east side eastward &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; fifty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The hangings of one side &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of the gate shall be&lt;/span&gt; fifteen cubits: their pillars three, and their sockets three.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And on the other side &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; hangings fifteen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;cubits&lt;/span&gt;: their pillars three, and their sockets three.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And for the gate of the court &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; an hanging of twenty cubits, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine twined linen, wrought with needlework: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; their pillars &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; four, and their sockets four.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">All the pillars round about the court &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; filleted with silver; their hooks &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be of&lt;/span&gt; silver, and their sockets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; brass.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">The length of the court &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; an hundred cubits, and the breadth fifty every where, and the height five cubits &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; fine twined linen, and their sockets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; brass.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">All the vessels of the tabernacle in all the service thereof, and all the pins thereof, and all the pins of the court, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be of&lt;/span&gt; brass.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And thou shalt command the children of Israel, that they bring thee pure oil olive beaten for the light, to cause the lamp to burn always.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">In the tabernacle of the congregation without the vail, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; before the testimony, Aaron and his sons shall order it from evening to morning before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it shall be&lt;/span&gt; a statute for ever unto their generations on the behalf of the children of Israel.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>