<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="40" verseCount="38" nextChapter="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 1" prevChapter="exodus_39.html" prevTitle="Exodus 39" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">On the first day of the first month shalt thou set up the tabernacle of the tent of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And thou shalt put therein the ark of the testimony, and cover the ark with the vail.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And thou shalt bring in the table, and set in order the things that are to be set in order upon it; and thou shalt bring in the candlestick, and light the lamps thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And thou shalt set the altar of gold for the incense before the ark of the testimony, and put the hanging of the door to the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And thou shalt set the altar of the burnt offering before the door of the tabernacle of the tent of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And thou shalt set the laver between the tent of the congregation and the altar, and shalt put water therein.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And thou shalt set up the court round about, and hang up the hanging at the court gate.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And thou shalt take the anointing oil, and anoint the tabernacle, and all that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; therein, and shalt hallow it, and all the vessels thereof: and it shall be holy.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And thou shalt anoint the altar of the burnt offering, and all his vessels, and sanctify the altar: and it shall be an altar most holy.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And thou shalt anoint the laver and his foot, and sanctify it.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And thou shalt bring Aaron and his sons unto the door of the tabernacle of the congregation, and wash them with water.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And thou shalt put upon Aaron the holy garments, and anoint him, and sanctify him; that he may minister unto me in the priest's office.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And thou shalt bring his sons, and clothe them with coats:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And thou shalt anoint them, as thou didst anoint their father, that they may minister unto me in the priest's office: for their anointing shall surely be an everlasting priesthood throughout their generations.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thus did Moses: according to all that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded him, so did he.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And it came to pass in the first month in the second year, on the first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the month, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the tabernacle was reared up.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Moses reared up the tabernacle, and fastened his sockets, and set up the boards thereof, and put in the bars thereof, and reared up his pillars.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he spread abroad the tent over the tabernacle, and put the covering of the tent above upon it; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And he took and put the testimony into the ark, and set the staves on the ark, and put the mercy seat above upon the ark:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he brought the ark into the tabernacle, and set up the vail of the covering, and covered the ark of the testimony; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And he put the table in the tent of the congregation, upon the side of the tabernacle northward, without the vail.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he set the bread in order upon it before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And he put the candlestick in the tent of the congregation, over against the table, on the side of the tabernacle southward.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And he lighted the lamps before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And he put the golden altar in the tent of the congregation before the vail:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And he burnt sweet incense thereon; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">And he set up the hanging &lt;span class="extra"&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; the door of the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And he put the altar of burnt offering &lt;span class="extra"&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; the door of the tabernacle of the tent of the congregation, and offered upon it the burnt offering and the meat offering; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">And he set the laver between the tent of the congregation and the altar, and put water there, to wash &lt;span class="extra"&gt;withal&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Moses and Aaron and his sons washed their hands and their feet thereat:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">When they went into the tent of the congregation, and when they came near unto the altar, they washed; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And he reared up the court round about the tabernacle and the altar, and set up the hanging of the court gate. So Moses finished the work.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">Then a cloud covered the tent of the congregation, and the glory of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; filled the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And Moses was not able to enter into the tent of the congregation, because the cloud abode thereon, and the glory of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; filled the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And when the cloud was taken up from over the tabernacle, the children of Israel went onward in all their journeys:</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">But if the cloud were not taken up, then they journeyed not till the day that it was taken up.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">For the cloud of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; upon the tabernacle by day, and fire was on it by night, in the sight of all the house of Israel, throughout all their journeys.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>