<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="27" nextChapter="exodus_19.html" nextTitle="Exodus 19" prevChapter="exodus_17.html" prevTitle="Exodus 17" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">When Jethro, the priest of Midian, Moses' father in law, heard of all that God had done for Moses, and for Israel his people, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had brought Israel out of Egypt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then Jethro, Moses' father in law, took Zipporah, Moses' wife, after he had sent her back,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And her two sons; of which the name of the one &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Gershom; for he said, I have been an alien in a strange land:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the name of the other &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Eliezer; for the God of my father, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;said he, was&lt;/span&gt; mine help, and delivered me from the sword of Pharaoh:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Jethro, Moses' father in law, came with his sons and his wife unto Moses into the wilderness, where he encamped at the mount of God:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he said unto Moses, I thy father in law Jethro am come unto thee, and thy wife, and her two sons with her.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And Moses went out to meet his father in law, and did obeisance, and kissed him; and they asked each other of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; welfare; and they came into the tent.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Moses told his father in law all that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had done unto Pharaoh and to the Egyptians for Israel's sake, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; all the travail that had come upon them by the way, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;how&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; delivered them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Jethro rejoiced for all the goodness which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had done to Israel, whom he had delivered out of the hand of the Egyptians.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Jethro said, Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, who hath delivered you out of the hand of the Egyptians, and out of the hand of Pharaoh, who hath delivered the people from under the hand of the Egyptians.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Now I know that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; greater than all gods: for in the thing wherein they dealt proudly &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he was&lt;/span&gt; above them.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Jethro, Moses' father in law, took a burnt offering and sacrifices for God: and Aaron came, and all the elders of Israel, to eat bread with Moses' father in law before God.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And it came to pass on the morrow, that Moses sat to judge the people: and the people stood by Moses from the morning unto the evening.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And when Moses' father in law saw all that he did to the people, he said, What &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this thing that thou doest to the people? why sittest thou thyself alone, and all the people stand by thee from morning unto even?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Moses said unto his father in law, Because the people come unto me to enquire of God:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">When they have a matter, they come unto me; and I judge between one and another, and I do make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; know the statutes of God, and his laws.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Moses' father in law said unto him, The thing that thou doest &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not good.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thou wilt surely wear away, both thou, and this people that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with thee: for this thing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; too heavy for thee; thou art not able to perform it thyself alone.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Hearken now unto my voice, I will give thee counsel, and God shall be with thee: Be thou for the people to God-ward, that thou mayest bring the causes unto God:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And thou shalt teach them ordinances and laws, and shalt shew them the way wherein they must walk, and the work that they must do.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Moreover thou shalt provide out of all the people able men, such as fear God, men of truth, hating covetousness; and place &lt;span class="extra"&gt;such&lt;/span&gt; over them, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; rulers of thousands, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; rulers of hundreds, rulers of fifties, and rulers of tens:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And let them judge the people at all seasons: and it shall be, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; every great matter they shall bring unto thee, but every small matter they shall judge: so shall it be easier for thyself, and they shall bear &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the burden&lt;/span&gt; with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">If thou shalt do this thing, and God command thee &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;, then thou shalt be able to endure, and all this people shall also go to their place in peace.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">So Moses hearkened to the voice of his father in law, and did all that he had said.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Moses chose able men out of all Israel, and made them heads over the people, rulers of thousands, rulers of hundreds, rulers of fifties, and rulers of tens.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And they judged the people at all seasons: the hard causes they brought unto Moses, but every small matter they judged themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And Moses let his father in law depart; and he went his way into his own land.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>