<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="22" nextChapter="exodus_14.html" nextTitle="Exodus 14" prevChapter="exodus_12.html" prevTitle="Exodus 12" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Sanctify unto me all the firstborn, whatsoever openeth the womb among the children of Israel, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; of man and of beast: it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And Moses said unto the people, Remember this day, in which ye came out from Egypt, out of the house of bondage; for by strength of hand the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought you out from this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;: there shall no leavened bread be eaten.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">This day came ye out in the month Abib.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And it shall be when the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall bring thee into the land of the Canaanites, and the Hittites, and the Amorites, and the Hivites, and the Jebusites, which he sware unto thy fathers to give thee, a land flowing with milk and honey, that thou shalt keep this service in this month.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Seven days thou shalt eat unleavened bread, and in the seventh day &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a feast to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Unleavened bread shall be eaten seven days; and there shall no leavened bread be seen with thee, neither shall there be leaven seen with thee in all thy quarters.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And thou shalt shew thy son in that day, saying, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;This is done&lt;/span&gt; because of that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did unto me when I came forth out of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And it shall be for a sign unto thee upon thine hand, and for a memorial between thine eyes, that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s law may be in thy mouth: for with a strong hand hath the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought thee out of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thou shalt therefore keep this ordinance in his season from year to year.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And it shall be when the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall bring thee into the land of the Canaanites, as he sware unto thee and to thy fathers, and shall give it thee,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">That thou shalt set apart unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; all that openeth the matrix, and every firstling that cometh of a beast which thou hast; the males &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And every firstling of an ass thou shalt redeem with a lamb; and if thou wilt not redeem it, then thou shalt break his neck: and all the firstborn of man among thy children shalt thou redeem.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And it shall be when thy son asketh thee in time to come, saying, What &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this? that thou shalt say unto him, By strength of hand the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought us out from Egypt, from the house of bondage:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And it came to pass, when Pharaoh would hardly let us go, that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; slew all the firstborn in the land of Egypt, both the firstborn of man, and the firstborn of beast: therefore I sacrifice to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; all that openeth the matrix, being males; but all the firstborn of my children I redeem.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And it shall be for a token upon thine hand, and for frontlets between thine eyes: for by strength of hand the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought us forth out of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when Pharaoh had let the people go, that God led them not &lt;span class="extra"&gt;through&lt;/span&gt; the way of the land of the Philistines, although that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; near; for God said, Lest peradventure the people repent when they see war, and they return to Egypt:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But God led the people about, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;through&lt;/span&gt; the way of the wilderness of the Red sea: and the children of Israel went up harnessed out of the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Moses took the bones of Joseph with him: for he had straitly sworn the children of Israel, saying, God will surely visit you; and ye shall carry up my bones away hence with you.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And they took their journey from Succoth, and encamped in Etham, in the edge of the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; went before them by day in a pillar of a cloud, to lead them the way; and by night in a pillar of fire, to give them light; to go by day and night:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">He took not away the pillar of the cloud by day, nor the pillar of fire by night, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; before the people.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>