<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="28" verseCount="43" nextChapter="exodus_29.html" nextTitle="Exodus 29" prevChapter="exodus_27.html" prevTitle="Exodus 27" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And take thou unto thee Aaron thy brother, and his sons with him, from among the children of Israel, that he may minister unto me in the priest's office, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; Aaron, Nadab and Abihu, Eleazar and Ithamar, Aaron's sons.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And thou shalt make holy garments for Aaron thy brother for glory and for beauty.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And thou shalt speak unto all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; wise hearted, whom I have filled with the spirit of wisdom, that they may make Aaron's garments to consecrate him, that he may minister unto me in the priest's office.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the garments which they shall make; a breastplate, and an ephod, and a robe, and a broidered coat, a mitre, and a girdle: and they shall make holy garments for Aaron thy brother, and his sons, that he may minister unto me in the priest's office.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they shall take gold, and blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine linen.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And they shall make the ephod &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; gold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; purple, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; scarlet, and fine twined linen, with cunning work.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">It shall have the two shoulderpieces thereof joined at the two edges thereof; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; it shall be joined together.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the curious girdle of the ephod, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon it, shall be of the same, according to the work thereof; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even of&lt;/span&gt; gold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine twined linen.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And thou shalt take two onyx stones, and grave on them the names of the children of Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Six of their names on one stone, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the other&lt;/span&gt; six names of the rest on the other stone, according to their birth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">With the work of an engraver in stone, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; the engravings of a signet, shalt thou engrave the two stones with the names of the children of Israel: thou shalt make them to be set in ouches of gold.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And thou shalt put the two stones upon the shoulders of the ephod &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; stones of memorial unto the children of Israel: and Aaron shall bear their names before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; upon his two shoulders for a memorial.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And thou shalt make ouches &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; gold;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And two chains &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; pure gold at the ends; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; wreathen work shalt thou make them, and fasten the wreathen chains to the ouches.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And thou shalt make the breastplate of judgment with cunning work; after the work of the ephod thou shalt make it; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; gold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; purple, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; scarlet, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; fine twined linen, shalt thou make it.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Foursquare it shall be &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; doubled; a span &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the length thereof, and a span &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the breadth thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And thou shalt set in it settings of stones, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; four rows of stones: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the first&lt;/span&gt; row &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a sardius, a topaz, and a carbuncle: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this shall be&lt;/span&gt; the first row.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the second row &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; an emerald, a sapphire, and a diamond.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the third row a ligure, an agate, and an amethyst.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the fourth row a beryl, and an onyx, and a jasper: they shall be set in gold in their inclosings.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the stones shall be with the names of the children of Israel, twelve, according to their names, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; the engravings of a signet; every one with his name shall they be according to the twelve tribes.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And thou shalt make upon the breastplate chains at the ends &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; wreathen work &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; pure gold.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And thou shalt make upon the breastplate two rings of gold, and shalt put the two rings on the two ends of the breastplate.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And thou shalt put the two wreathen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;chains&lt;/span&gt; of gold in the two rings &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which are&lt;/span&gt; on the ends of the breastplate.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the other&lt;/span&gt; two ends of the two wreathen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;chains&lt;/span&gt; thou shalt fasten in the two ouches, and put &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; on the shoulderpieces of the ephod before it.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And thou shalt make two rings of gold, and thou shalt put them upon the two ends of the breastplate in the border thereof, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the side of the ephod inward.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And two &lt;span class='extra'&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; rings of gold thou shalt make, and shalt put them on the two sides of the ephod underneath, toward the forepart thereof, over against the &lt;span class='extra'&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; coupling thereof, above the curious girdle of the ephod.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they shall bind the breastplate by the rings thereof unto the rings of the ephod with a lace of blue, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; may be above the curious girdle of the ephod, and that the breastplate be not loosed from the ephod.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Aaron shall bear the names of the children of Israel in the breastplate of judgment upon his heart, when he goeth in unto the holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;, for a memorial before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; continually.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">And thou shalt put in the breastplate of judgment the Urim and the Thummim; and they shall be upon Aaron's heart, when he goeth in before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and Aaron shall bear the judgment of the children of Israel upon his heart before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; continually.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And thou shalt make the robe of the ephod all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And there shall be an hole in the top of it, in the midst thereof: it shall have a binding of woven work round about the hole of it, as it were the hole of an habergeon, that it be not rent.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;beneath&lt;/span&gt; upon the hem of it thou shalt make pomegranates &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; purple, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; scarlet, round about the hem thereof; and bells of gold between them round about:</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">A golden bell and a pomegranate, a golden bell and a pomegranate, upon the hem of the robe round about.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And it shall be upon Aaron to minister: and his sound shall be heard when he goeth in unto the holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt; before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and when he cometh out, that he die not.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">And thou shalt make a plate &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; pure gold, and grave upon it, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; the engravings of a signet, HOLINESS TO THE &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And thou shalt put it on a blue lace, that it may be upon the mitre; upon the forefront of the mitre it shall be.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And it shall be upon Aaron's forehead, that Aaron may bear the iniquity of the holy things, which the children of Israel shall hallow in all their holy gifts; and it shall be always upon his forehead, that they may be accepted before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39" newPara="true">And thou shalt embroider the coat of fine linen, and thou shalt make the mitre &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; fine linen, and thou shalt make the girdle &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; needlework.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40" newPara="true">And for Aaron's sons thou shalt make coats, and thou shalt make for them girdles, and bonnets shalt thou make for them, for glory and for beauty.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And thou shalt put them upon Aaron thy brother, and his sons with him; and shalt anoint them, and consecrate them, and sanctify them, that they may minister unto me in the priest's office.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And thou shalt make them linen breeches to cover their nakedness; from the loins even unto the thighs they shall reach:</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And they shall be upon Aaron, and upon his sons, when they come in unto the tabernacle of the congregation, or when they come near unto the altar to minister in the holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;; that they bear not iniquity, and die: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it shall be&lt;/span&gt; a statute for ever unto him and his seed after him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>