<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="29" nextChapter="exodus_11.html" nextTitle="Exodus 11" prevChapter="exodus_9.html" prevTitle="Exodus 9" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Go in unto Pharaoh: for I have hardened his heart, and the heart of his servants, that I might shew these my signs before him:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And that thou mayest tell in the ears of thy son, and of thy son's son, what things I have wrought in Egypt, and my signs which I have done among them; that ye may know how that I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Moses and Aaron came in unto Pharaoh, and said unto him, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of the Hebrews, How long wilt thou refuse to humble thyself before me? let my people go, that they may serve me.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Else, if thou refuse to let my people go, behold, to morrow will I bring the locusts into thy coast:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they shall cover the face of the earth, that one cannot be able to see the earth: and they shall eat the residue of that which is escaped, which remaineth unto you from the hail, and shall eat every tree which groweth for you out of the field:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And they shall fill thy houses, and the houses of all thy servants, and the houses of all the Egyptians; which neither thy fathers, nor thy fathers' fathers have seen, since the day that they were upon the earth unto this day. And he turned himself, and went out from Pharaoh.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Pharaoh's servants said unto him, How long shall this man be a snare unto us? let the men go, that they may serve the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God: knowest thou not yet that Egypt is destroyed?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Moses and Aaron were brought again unto Pharaoh: and he said unto them, Go, serve the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they that shall go?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Moses said, We will go with our young and with our old, with our sons and with our daughters, with our flocks and with our herds will we go; for we &lt;span class="extra"&gt;must hold&lt;/span&gt; a feast unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he said unto them, Let the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be so with you, as I will let you go, and your little ones: look &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to it&lt;/span&gt;; for evil &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; before you.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Not so: go now ye &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; men, and serve the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for that ye did desire. And they were driven out from Pharaoh's presence.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Stretch out thine hand over the land of Egypt for the locusts, that they may come up upon the land of Egypt, and eat every herb of the land, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all that the hail hath left.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Moses stretched forth his rod over the land of Egypt, and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought an east wind upon the land all that day, and all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; night; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; when it was morning, the east wind brought the locusts.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the locusts went up over all the land of Egypt, and rested in all the coasts of Egypt: very grievous &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were they&lt;/span&gt;; before them there were no such locusts as they, neither after them shall be such.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For they covered the face of the whole earth, so that the land was darkened; and they did eat every herb of the land, and all the fruit of the trees which the hail had left: and there remained not any green thing in the trees, or in the herbs of the field, through all the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Then Pharaoh called for Moses and Aaron in haste; and he said, I have sinned against the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, and against you.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Now therefore forgive, I pray thee, my sin only this once, and intreat the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, that he may take away from me this death only.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And he went out from Pharaoh, and intreated the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; turned a mighty strong west wind, which took away the locusts, and cast them into the Red sea; there remained not one locust in all the coasts of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hardened Pharaoh's heart, so that he would not let the children of Israel go.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Stretch out thine hand toward heaven, that there may be darkness over the land of Egypt, even darkness &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; may be felt.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Moses stretched forth his hand toward heaven; and there was a thick darkness in all the land of Egypt three days:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">They saw not one another, neither rose any from his place for three days: but all the children of Israel had light in their dwellings.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And Pharaoh called unto Moses, and said, Go ye, serve the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; only let your flocks and your herds be stayed: let your little ones also go with you.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Moses said, Thou must give us also sacrifices and burnt offerings, that we may sacrifice unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Our cattle also shall go with us; there shall not an hoof be left behind; for thereof must we take to serve the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God; and we know not with what we must serve the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, until we come thither.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">But the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hardened Pharaoh's heart, and he would not let them go.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Pharaoh said unto him, Get thee from me, take heed to thyself, see my face no more; for in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; day thou seest my face thou shalt die.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Moses said, Thou hast spoken well, I will see thy face again no more.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>