<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="39" verseCount="43" nextChapter="exodus_40.html" nextTitle="Exodus 40" prevChapter="exodus_38.html" prevTitle="Exodus 38" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And of the blue, and purple, and scarlet, they made cloths of service, to do service in the holy &lt;i&gt;place&lt;/i&gt;, and made the holy garments for Aaron; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he made the ephod &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; gold, blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine twined linen.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they did beat the gold into thin plates, and cut &lt;i&gt;it into&lt;/i&gt; wires, to work &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; in the blue, and in the purple, and in the scarlet, and in the fine linen, &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; cunning work.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They made shoulderpieces for it, to couple &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; together: by the two edges was it coupled together.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the curious girdle of his ephod, that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; upon it, &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; of the same, according to the work thereof; &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; gold, blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine twined linen; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And they wrought onyx stones inclosed in ouches of gold, graven, as signets are graven, with the names of the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he put them on the shoulders of the ephod, &lt;i&gt;that they should be&lt;/i&gt; stones for a memorial to the children of Israel; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And he made the breastplate &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; cunning work, like the work of the ephod; &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; gold, blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine twined linen.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">It was foursquare; they made the breastplate double: a span &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the length thereof, and a span the breadth thereof, &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; doubled.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they set in it four rows of stones: &lt;i&gt;the first&lt;/i&gt; row &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a sardius, a topaz, and a carbuncle: this &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the first row.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the second row, an emerald, a sapphire, and a diamond.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the third row, a ligure, an agate, and an amethyst.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the fourth row, a beryl, an onyx, and a jasper: &lt;i&gt;they were&lt;/i&gt; inclosed in ouches of gold in their inclosings.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the stones &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; according to the names of the children of Israel, twelve, according to their names, &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; the engravings of a signet, every one with his name, according to the twelve tribes.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And they made upon the breastplate chains at the ends, &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; wreathen work &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; pure gold.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And they made two ouches &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; gold, and two gold rings; and put the two rings in the two ends of the breastplate.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And they put the two wreathen chains of gold in the two rings on the ends of the breastplate.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the two ends of the two wreathen chains they fastened in the two ouches, and put them on the shoulderpieces of the ephod, before it.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And they made two rings of gold, and put &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; on the two ends of the breastplate, upon the border of it, which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; on the side of the ephod inward.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And they made two &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; golden rings, and put them on the two sides of the ephod underneath, toward the forepart of it, over against the &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; coupling thereof, above the curious girdle of the ephod.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they did bind the breastplate by his rings unto the rings of the ephod with a lace of blue, that it might be above the curious girdle of the ephod, and that the breastplate might not be loosed from the ephod; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And he made the robe of the ephod &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; woven work, all &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; blue.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; an hole in the midst of the robe, as the hole of an habergeon, &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; a band round about the hole, that it should not rend.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they made upon the hems of the robe pomegranates &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; blue, and purple, and scarlet, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; twined &lt;i&gt;linen&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they made bells &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; pure gold, and put the bells between the pomegranates upon the hem of the robe, round about between the pomegranates;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">A bell and a pomegranate, a bell and a pomegranate, round about the hem of the robe to minister &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt;; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And they made coats &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; fine linen &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; woven work for Aaron, and for his sons,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And a mitre &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; fine linen, and goodly bonnets &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; fine linen, and linen breeches &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; fine twined linen,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And a girdle &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; fine twined linen, and blue, and purple, and scarlet, &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; needlework; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">And they made the plate of the holy crown &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; pure gold, and wrote upon it a writing, &lt;i&gt;like to&lt;/i&gt; the engravings of a signet, HOLINESS TO THE &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And they tied unto it a lace of blue, to fasten &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; on high upon the mitre; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">Thus was all the work of the tabernacle of the tent of the congregation finished: and the children of Israel did according to all that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses, so did they.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">And they brought the tabernacle unto Moses, the tent, and all his furniture, his taches, his boards, his bars, and his pillars, and his sockets,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And the covering of rams' skins dyed red, and the covering of badgers' skins, and the vail of the covering,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">The ark of the testimony, and the staves thereof, and the mercy seat,</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">The table, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; all the vessels thereof, and the shewbread,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">The pure candlestick, &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; the lamps thereof, &lt;i&gt;even with&lt;/i&gt; the lamps to be set in order, and all the vessels thereof, and the oil for light,</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And the golden altar, and the anointing oil, and the sweet incense, and the hanging for the tabernacle door,</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">The brasen altar, and his grate of brass, his staves, and all his vessels, the laver and his foot,</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">The hangings of the court, his pillars, and his sockets, and the hanging for the court gate, his cords, and his pins, and all the vessels of the service of the tabernacle, for the tent of the congregation,</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">The cloths of service to do service in the holy &lt;i&gt;place&lt;/i&gt;, and the holy garments for Aaron the priest, and his sons' garments, to minister in the priest's office.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">According to all that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses, so the children of Israel made all the work.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And Moses did look upon all the work, and, behold, they had done it as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had commanded, even so had they done it: and Moses blessed them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>