<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="35" nextChapter="exodus_10.html" nextTitle="Exodus 10" prevChapter="exodus_8.html" prevTitle="Exodus 8" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Go in unto Pharaoh, and tell him, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of the Hebrews, Let my people go, that they may serve me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For if thou refuse to let &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; go, and wilt hold them still,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Behold, the hand of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; is upon thy cattle which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the field, upon the horses, upon the asses, upon the camels, upon the oxen, and upon the sheep: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; a very grievous murrain.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall sever between the cattle of Israel and the cattle of Egypt: and there shall nothing die of all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; the children's of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appointed a set time, saying, To morrow the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall do this thing in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did that thing on the morrow, and all the cattle of Egypt died: but of the cattle of the children of Israel died not one.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Pharaoh sent, and, behold, there was not one of the cattle of the Israelites dead. And the heart of Pharaoh was hardened, and he did not let the people go.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses and unto Aaron, Take to you handfuls of ashes of the furnace, and let Moses sprinkle it toward the heaven in the sight of Pharaoh.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And it shall become small dust in all the land of Egypt, and shall be a boil breaking forth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; blains upon man, and upon beast, throughout all the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they took ashes of the furnace, and stood before Pharaoh; and Moses sprinkled it up toward heaven; and it became a boil breaking forth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; blains upon man, and upon beast.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the magicians could not stand before Moses because of the boils; for the boil was upon the magicians, and upon all the Egyptians.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hardened the heart of Pharaoh, and he hearkened not unto them; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had spoken unto Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Rise up early in the morning, and stand before Pharaoh, and say unto him, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of the Hebrews, Let my people go, that they may serve me.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For I will at this time send all my plagues upon thine heart, and upon thy servants, and upon thy people; that thou mayest know that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none like me in all the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For now I will stretch out my hand, that I may smite thee and thy people with pestilence; and thou shalt be cut off from the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And in very deed for this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;cause&lt;/span&gt; have I raised thee up, for to shew &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; thee my power; and that my name may be declared throughout all the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">As yet exaltest thou thyself against my people, that thou wilt not let them go?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Behold, to morrow about this time I will cause it to rain a very grievous hail, such as hath not been in Egypt since the foundation thereof even until now.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Send therefore now, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; gather thy cattle, and all that thou hast in the field; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for upon&lt;/span&gt; every man and beast which shall be found in the field, and shall not be brought home, the hail shall come down upon them, and they shall die.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He that feared the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; among the servants of Pharaoh made his servants and his cattle flee into the houses:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he that regarded not the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; left his servants and his cattle in the field.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Stretch forth thine hand toward heaven, that there may be hail in all the land of Egypt, upon man, and upon beast, and upon every herb of the field, throughout the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Moses stretched forth his rod toward heaven: and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent thunder and hail, and the fire ran along upon the ground; and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; rained hail upon the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">So there was hail, and fire mingled with the hail, very grievous, such as there was none like it in all the land of Egypt since it became a nation.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the hail smote throughout all the land of Egypt all that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the field, both man and beast; and the hail smote every herb of the field, and brake every tree of the field.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Only in the land of Goshen, where the children of Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, was there no hail.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And Pharaoh sent, and called for Moses and Aaron, and said unto them, I have sinned this time: the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; righteous, and I and my people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Intreat the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; (for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; enough) that there be no &lt;span class="extra"&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; mighty thunderings and hail; and I will let you go, and ye shall stay no longer.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Moses said unto him, As soon as I am gone out of the city, I will spread abroad my hands unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the thunder shall cease, neither shall there be any more hail; that thou mayest know how that the earth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">But as for thee and thy servants, I know that ye will not yet fear the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And the flax and the barley was smitten: for the barley &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the ear, and the flax &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; bolled.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">But the wheat and the rie were not smitten: for they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; not grown up.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And Moses went out of the city from Pharaoh, and spread abroad his hands unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and the thunders and hail ceased, and the rain was not poured upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And when Pharaoh saw that the rain and the hail and the thunders were ceased, he sinned yet more, and hardened his heart, he and his servants.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And the heart of Pharaoh was hardened, neither would he let the children of Israel go; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had spoken by Moses.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>