<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="38" verseCount="31" nextChapter="exodus_39.html" nextTitle="Exodus 39" prevChapter="exodus_37.html" prevTitle="Exodus 37" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he made the altar of burnt offering &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; shittim wood: five cubits &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the length thereof, and five cubits the breadth thereof; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it was&lt;/span&gt; foursquare; and three cubits the height thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he made the horns thereof on the four corners of it; the horns thereof were of the same: and he overlaid it with brass.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he made all the vessels of the altar, the pots, and the shovels, and the basons, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the fleshhooks, and the firepans: all the vessels thereof made he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; brass.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he made for the altar a brasen grate of network under the compass thereof beneath unto the midst of it.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he cast four rings for the four ends of the grate of brass, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; places for the staves.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he made the staves &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; shittim wood, and overlaid them with brass.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he put the staves into the rings on the sides of the altar, to bear it withal; he made the altar hollow with boards.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And he made the laver &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; brass, and the foot of it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; brass, of the lookingglasses of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the women&lt;/span&gt; assembling, which assembled &lt;span class='extra'&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; the door of the tabernacle of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And he made the court: on the south side southward the hangings of the court &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were of&lt;/span&gt; fine twined linen, an hundred cubits:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Their pillars &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; twenty, and their brasen sockets twenty; the hooks of the pillars and their fillets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were of&lt;/span&gt; silver.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And for the north side &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the hangings were&lt;/span&gt; an hundred cubits, their pillars &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; twenty, and their sockets of brass twenty; the hooks of the pillars and their fillets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; silver.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And for the west side &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; hangings of fifty cubits, their pillars ten, and their sockets ten; the hooks of the pillars and their fillets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; silver.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And for the east side eastward fifty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The hangings of the one side &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of the gate were&lt;/span&gt; fifteen cubits; their pillars three, and their sockets three.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And for the other side of the court gate, on this hand and that hand, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; hangings of fifteen cubits; their pillars three, and their sockets three.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">All the hangings of the court round about &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; of fine twined linen.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the sockets for the pillars &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were of&lt;/span&gt; brass; the hooks of the pillars and their fillets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; silver; and the overlaying of their chapiters &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; silver; and all the pillars of the court &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; filleted with silver.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the hanging for the gate of the court &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; needlework, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine twined linen: and twenty cubits &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the length, and the height in the breadth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; five cubits, answerable to the hangings of the court.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And their pillars &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; four, and their sockets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; brass four; their hooks &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; silver, and the overlaying of their chapiters and their fillets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; silver.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And all the pins of the tabernacle, and of the court round about, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were of&lt;/span&gt; brass.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">This is the sum of the tabernacle, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of the tabernacle of testimony, as it was counted, according to the commandment of Moses, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the service of the Levites, by the hand of Ithamar, son to Aaron the priest.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Bezaleel the son of Uri, the son of Hur, of the tribe of Judah, made all that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And with him &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Aholiab, son of Ahisamach, of the tribe of Dan, an engraver, and a cunning workman, and an embroiderer in blue, and in purple, and in scarlet, and fine linen.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">All the gold that was occupied for the work in all the work of the holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;, even the gold of the offering, was twenty and nine talents, and seven hundred and thirty shekels, after the shekel of the sanctuary.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the silver of them that were numbered of the congregation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; an hundred talents, and a thousand seven hundred and threescore and fifteen shekels, after the shekel of the sanctuary:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">A bekah for every man, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt;, half a shekel, after the shekel of the sanctuary, for every one that went to be numbered, from twenty years old and upward, for six hundred thousand and three thousand and five hundred and fifty &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And of the hundred talents of silver were cast the sockets of the sanctuary, and the sockets of the vail; an hundred sockets of the hundred talents, a talent for a socket.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And of the thousand seven hundred seventy and five &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shekels&lt;/span&gt; he made hooks for the pillars, and overlaid their chapiters, and filleted them.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And the brass of the offering &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; seventy talents, and two thousand and four hundred shekels.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And therewith he made the sockets to the door of the tabernacle of the congregation, and the brasen altar, and the brasen grate for it, and all the vessels of the altar,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And the sockets of the court round about, and the sockets of the court gate, and all the pins of the tabernacle, and all the pins of the court round about.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>