<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="27" nextChapter="exodus_16.html" nextTitle="Exodus 16" prevChapter="exodus_14.html" prevTitle="Exodus 14" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then sang Moses and the children of Israel this song unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and spake, saying, I will sing unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, for he hath triumphed gloriously: the horse and his rider hath he thrown into the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my strength and song, and he is become my salvation: he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my God, and I will prepare him an habitation; my father's God, and I will exalt him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a man of war: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his name.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Pharaoh's chariots and his host hath he cast into the sea: his chosen captains also are drowned in the Red sea.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The depths have covered them: they sank into the bottom as a stone.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thy right hand, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, is become glorious in power: thy right hand, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hath dashed in pieces the enemy.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And in the greatness of thine excellency thou hast overthrown them that rose up against thee: thou sentest forth thy wrath, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; consumed them as stubble.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And with the blast of thy nostrils the waters were gathered together, the floods stood upright as an heap, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the depths were congealed in the heart of the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The enemy said, I will pursue, I will overtake, I will divide the spoil; my lust shall be satisfied upon them; I will draw my sword, my hand shall destroy them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thou didst blow with thy wind, the sea covered them: they sank as lead in the mighty waters.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; like unto thee, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, among the gods? who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; like thee, glorious in holiness, fearful &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; praises, doing wonders?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Thou stretchedst out thy right hand, the earth swallowed them.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thou in thy mercy hast led forth the people &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; thou hast redeemed: thou hast guided &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in thy strength unto thy holy habitation.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The people shall hear, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; be afraid: sorrow shall take hold on the inhabitants of Palestina.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Then the dukes of Edom shall be amazed; the mighty men of Moab, trembling shall take hold upon them; all the inhabitants of Canaan shall melt away.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Fear and dread shall fall upon them; by the greatness of thine arm they shall be &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; still as a stone; till thy people pass over, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, till the people pass over, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; thou hast purchased.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thou shalt bring them in, and plant them in the mountain of thine inheritance, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the place, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; thou hast made for thee to dwell in, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the Sanctuary, O Lord, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; thy hands have established.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall reign for ever and ever.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For the horse of Pharaoh went in with his chariots and with his horsemen into the sea, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought again the waters of the sea upon them; but the children of Israel went on dry &lt;i&gt;land&lt;/i&gt; in the midst of the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And Miriam the prophetess, the sister of Aaron, took a timbrel in her hand; and all the women went out after her with timbrels and with dances.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Miriam answered them, Sing ye to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, for he hath triumphed gloriously; the horse and his rider hath he thrown into the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">So Moses brought Israel from the Red sea, and they went out into the wilderness of Shur; and they went three days in the wilderness, and found no water.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And when they came to Marah, they could not drink of the waters of Marah, for they &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; bitter: therefore the name of it was called Marah.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the people murmured against Moses, saying, What shall we drink?</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And he cried unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shewed him a tree, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; when he had cast into the waters, the waters were made sweet: there he made for them a statute and an ordinance, and there he proved them,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And said, If thou wilt diligently hearken to the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, and wilt do that which is right in his sight, and wilt give ear to his commandments, and keep all his statutes, I will put none of these diseases upon thee, which I have brought upon the Egyptians: for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that healeth thee.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And they came to Elim, where &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve wells of water, and threescore and ten palm trees: and they encamped there by the waters.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>