<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="25" verseCount="40" nextChapter="exodus_26.html" nextTitle="Exodus 26" prevChapter="exodus_24.html" prevTitle="Exodus 24" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto the children of Israel, that they bring me an offering: of every man that giveth it willingly with his heart ye shall take my offering.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the offering which ye shall take of them; gold, and silver, and brass,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine linen, and goats' &lt;i&gt;hair&lt;/i&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And rams' skins dyed red, and badgers' skins, and shittim wood,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Oil for the light, spices for anointing oil, and for sweet incense,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Onyx stones, and stones to be set in the ephod, and in the breastplate.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And let them make me a sanctuary; that I may dwell among them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">According to all that I shew thee, &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; the pattern of the tabernacle, and the pattern of all the instruments thereof, even so shall ye make &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And they shall make an ark &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; shittim wood: two cubits and a half &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the length thereof, and a cubit and a half the breadth thereof, and a cubit and a half the height thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And thou shalt overlay it with pure gold, within and without shalt thou overlay it, and shalt make upon it a crown of gold round about.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And thou shalt cast four rings of gold for it, and put &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in the four corners thereof; and two rings &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; in the one side of it, and two rings in the other side of it.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And thou shalt make staves &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; shittim wood, and overlay them with gold.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And thou shalt put the staves into the rings by the sides of the ark, that the ark may be borne with them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The staves shall be in the rings of the ark: they shall not be taken from it.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And thou shalt put into the ark the testimony which I shall give thee.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And thou shalt make a mercy seat &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; pure gold: two cubits and a half &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the length thereof, and a cubit and a half the breadth thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And thou shalt make two cherubims &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; gold, &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; beaten work shalt thou make them, in the two ends of the mercy seat.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And make one cherub on the one end, and the other cherub on the other end: &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; of the mercy seat shall ye make the cherubims on the two ends thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the cherubims shall stretch forth &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; wings on high, covering the mercy seat with their wings, and their faces &lt;i&gt;shall look&lt;/i&gt; one to another; toward the mercy seat shall the faces of the cherubims be.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And thou shalt put the mercy seat above upon the ark; and in the ark thou shalt put the testimony that I shall give thee.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And there I will meet with thee, and I will commune with thee from above the mercy seat, from between the two cherubims which &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; upon the ark of the testimony, of all &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; which I will give thee in commandment unto the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">Thou shalt also make a table &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; shittim wood: two cubits &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the length thereof, and a cubit the breadth thereof, and a cubit and a half the height thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And thou shalt overlay it with pure gold, and make thereto a crown of gold round about.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And thou shalt make unto it a border of an hand breadth round about, and thou shalt make a golden crown to the border thereof round about.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And thou shalt make for it four rings of gold, and put the rings in the four corners that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; on the four feet thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Over against the border shall the rings be for places of the staves to bear the table.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And thou shalt make the staves &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; shittim wood, and overlay them with gold, that the table may be borne with them.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And thou shalt make the dishes thereof, and spoons thereof, and covers thereof, and bowls thereof, to cover withal: &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; pure gold shalt thou make them.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And thou shalt set upon the table shewbread before me alway.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And thou shalt make a candlestick &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; pure gold: &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; beaten work shall the candlestick be made: his shaft, and his branches, his bowls, his knops, and his flowers, shall be of the same.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And six branches shall come out of the sides of it; three branches of the candlestick out of the one side, and three branches of the candlestick out of the other side:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Three bowls made like unto almonds, &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; a knop and a flower in one branch; and three bowls made like almonds in the other branch, &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; a knop and a flower: so in the six branches that come out of the candlestick.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And in the candlestick &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; four bowls made like unto almonds, &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; their knops and their flowers.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And &lt;i&gt;there shall be&lt;/i&gt; a knop under two branches of the same, and a knop under two branches of the same, and a knop under two branches of the same, according to the six branches that proceed out of the candlestick.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Their knops and their branches shall be of the same: all it &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; one beaten work &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; pure gold.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And thou shalt make the seven lamps thereof: and they shall light the lamps thereof, that they may give light over against it.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And the tongs thereof, and the snuffdishes thereof, &lt;i&gt;shall be of&lt;/i&gt; pure gold.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">&lt;i&gt;Of&lt;/i&gt; a talent of pure gold shall he make it, with all these vessels.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And look that thou make &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; after their pattern, which was shewed thee in the mount.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>