<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="19" verseCount="25" nextChapter="exodus_20.html" nextTitle="Exodus 20" prevChapter="exodus_18.html" prevTitle="Exodus 18" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In the third month, when the children of Israel were gone forth out of the land of Egypt, the same day came they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;into&lt;/span&gt; the wilderness of Sinai.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For they were departed from Rephidim, and were come &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the desert of Sinai, and had pitched in the wilderness; and there Israel camped before the mount.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Moses went up unto God, and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; called unto him out of the mountain, saying, Thus shalt thou say to the house of Jacob, and tell the children of Israel;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Ye have seen what I did unto the Egyptians, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;how&lt;/span&gt; I bare you on eagles' wings, and brought you unto myself.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Now therefore, if ye will obey my voice indeed, and keep my covenant, then ye shall be a peculiar treasure unto me above all people: for all the earth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And ye shall be unto me a kingdom of priests, and an holy nation. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the words which thou shalt speak unto the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And Moses came and called for the elders of the people, and laid before their faces all these words which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded him.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And all the people answered together, and said, All that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken we will do. And Moses returned the words of the people unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Lo, I come unto thee in a thick cloud, that the people may hear when I speak with thee, and believe thee for ever. And Moses told the words of the people unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Go unto the people, and sanctify them to day and to morrow, and let them wash their clothes,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And be ready against the third day: for the third day the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will come down in the sight of all the people upon mount Sinai.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And thou shalt set bounds unto the people round about, saying, Take heed to yourselves, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that ye&lt;/span&gt; go &lt;span class="extra"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; up into the mount, or touch the border of it: whosoever toucheth the mount shall be surely put to death:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">There shall not an hand touch it, but he shall surely be stoned, or shot through; whether &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt; beast or man, it shall not live: when the trumpet soundeth long, they shall come up to the mount.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And Moses went down from the mount unto the people, and sanctified the people; and they washed their clothes.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he said unto the people, Be ready against the third day: come not at &lt;span class="extra"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; wives.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And it came to pass on the third day in the morning, that there were thunders and lightnings, and a thick cloud upon the mount, and the voice of the trumpet exceeding loud; so that all the people that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the camp trembled.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Moses brought forth the people out of the camp to meet with God; and they stood at the nether part of the mount.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And mount Sinai was altogether on a smoke, because the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; descended upon it in fire: and the smoke thereof ascended as the smoke of a furnace, and the whole mount quaked greatly.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And when the voice of the trumpet sounded long, and waxed louder and louder, Moses spake, and God answered him by a voice.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came down upon mount Sinai, on the top of the mount: and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; called Moses &lt;span class="extra"&gt;up&lt;/span&gt; to the top of the mount; and Moses went up.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Go down, charge the people, lest they break through unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to gaze, and many of them perish.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And let the priests also, which come near to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, sanctify themselves, lest the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; break forth upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Moses said unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, The people cannot come up to mount Sinai: for thou chargedst us, saying, Set bounds about the mount, and sanctify it.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, Away, get thee down, and thou shalt come up, thou, and Aaron with thee: but let not the priests and the people break through to come up unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, lest he break forth upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">So Moses went down unto the people, and spake unto them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>