<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="17" verseCount="16" nextChapter="exodus_18.html" nextTitle="Exodus 18" prevChapter="exodus_16.html" prevTitle="Exodus 16" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And all the congregation of the children of Israel journeyed from the wilderness of Sin, after their journeys, according to the commandment of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and pitched in Rephidim: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; no water for the people to drink.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Wherefore the people did chide with Moses, and said, Give us water that we may drink. And Moses said unto them, Why chide ye with me? wherefore do ye tempt the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the people thirsted there for water; and the people murmured against Moses, and said, Wherefore &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thou hast brought us up out of Egypt, to kill us and our children and our cattle with thirst?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Moses cried unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, saying, What shall I do unto this people? they be almost ready to stone me.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Go on before the people, and take with thee of the elders of Israel; and thy rod, wherewith thou smotest the river, take in thine hand, and go.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Behold, I will stand before thee there upon the rock in Horeb; and thou shalt smite the rock, and there shall come water out of it, that the people may drink. And Moses did so in the sight of the elders of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he called the name of the place Massah, and Meribah, because of the chiding of the children of Israel, and because they tempted the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, saying, Is the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; among us, or not?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Then came Amalek, and fought with Israel in Rephidim.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Moses said unto Joshua, Choose us out men, and go out, fight with Amalek: to morrow I will stand on the top of the hill with the rod of God in mine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">So Joshua did as Moses had said to him, and fought with Amalek: and Moses, Aaron, and Hur went up to the top of the hill.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And it came to pass, when Moses held up his hand, that Israel prevailed: and when he let down his hand, Amalek prevailed.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But Moses' hands &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; heavy; and they took a stone, and put &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; under him, and he sat thereon; and Aaron and Hur stayed up his hands, the one on the one side, and the other on the other side; and his hands were steady until the going down of the sun.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Joshua discomfited Amalek and his people with the edge of the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Write this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a memorial in a book, and rehearse &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; in the ears of Joshua: for I will utterly put out the remembrance of Amalek from under heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Moses built an altar, and called the name of it Jehovah-nissi:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For he said, Because the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath sworn &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;will have&lt;/span&gt; war with Amalek from generation to generation.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>