<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="24" verseCount="18" nextChapter="exodus_25.html" nextTitle="Exodus 25" prevChapter="exodus_23.html" prevTitle="Exodus 23" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he said unto Moses, Come up unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou, and Aaron, Nadab, and Abihu, and seventy of the elders of Israel; and worship ye afar off.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Moses alone shall come near the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but they shall not come nigh; neither shall the people go up with him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And Moses came and told the people all the words of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and all the judgments: and all the people answered with one voice, and said, All the words which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath said will we do.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Moses wrote all the words of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and rose up early in the morning, and builded an altar under the hill, and twelve pillars, according to the twelve tribes of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he sent young men of the children of Israel, which offered burnt offerings, and sacrificed peace offerings of oxen unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Moses took half of the blood, and put &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; in basons; and half of the blood he sprinkled on the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he took the book of the covenant, and read in the audience of the people: and they said, All that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath said will we do, and be obedient.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Moses took the blood, and sprinkled &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on the people, and said, Behold the blood of the covenant, which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath made with you concerning all these words.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Then went up Moses, and Aaron, Nadab, and Abihu, and seventy of the elders of Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they saw the God of Israel: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; under his feet as it were a paved work of a sapphire stone, and as it were the body of heaven in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; clearness.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And upon the nobles of the children of Israel he laid not his hand: also they saw God, and did eat and drink.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Come up to me into the mount, and be there: and I will give thee tables of stone, and a law, and commandments which I have written; that thou mayest teach them.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Moses rose up, and his minister Joshua: and Moses went up into the mount of God.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he said unto the elders, Tarry ye here for us, until we come again unto you: and, behold, Aaron and Hur &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; with you: if any man have any matters to do, let him come unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Moses went up into the mount, and a cloud covered the mount.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the glory of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; abode upon mount Sinai, and the cloud covered it six days: and the seventh day he called unto Moses out of the midst of the cloud.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the sight of the glory of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; like devouring fire on the top of the mount in the eyes of the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Moses went into the midst of the cloud, and gat him up into the mount: and Moses was in the mount forty days and forty nights.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>