<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="26" verseCount="37" nextChapter="exodus_27.html" nextTitle="Exodus 27" prevChapter="exodus_25.html" prevTitle="Exodus 25" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover thou shalt make the tabernacle &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; ten curtains &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; fine twined linen, and blue, and purple, and scarlet: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; cherubims of cunning work shalt thou make them.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The length of one curtain &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; eight and twenty cubits, and the breadth of one curtain four cubits: and every one of the curtains shall have one measure.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The five curtains shall be coupled together one to another; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; five curtains &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; coupled one to another.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And thou shalt make loops of blue upon the edge of the one curtain from the selvedge in the coupling; and likewise shalt thou make in the uttermost edge of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;another&lt;/span&gt; curtain, in the coupling of the second.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Fifty loops shalt thou make in the one curtain, and fifty loops shalt thou make in the edge of the curtain that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the coupling of the second; that the loops may take hold one of another.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And thou shalt make fifty taches of gold, and couple the curtains together with the taches: and it shall be one tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And thou shalt make curtains &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; goats' &lt;span class='extra'&gt;hair&lt;/span&gt; to be a covering upon the tabernacle: eleven curtains shalt thou make.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The length of one curtain &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; thirty cubits, and the breadth of one curtain four cubits: and the eleven curtains &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be all&lt;/span&gt; of one measure.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And thou shalt couple five curtains by themselves, and six curtains by themselves, and shalt double the sixth curtain in the forefront of the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And thou shalt make fifty loops on the edge of the one curtain &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; outmost in the coupling, and fifty loops in the edge of the curtain which coupleth the second.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And thou shalt make fifty taches of brass, and put the taches into the loops, and couple the tent together, that it may be one.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the remnant that remaineth of the curtains of the tent, the half curtain that remaineth, shall hang over the backside of the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And a cubit on the one side, and a cubit on the other side of that which remaineth in the length of the curtains of the tent, it shall hang over the sides of the tabernacle on this side and on that side, to cover it.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And thou shalt make a covering for the tent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; rams' skins dyed red, and a covering above &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; badgers' skins.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And thou shalt make boards for the tabernacle &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; shittim wood standing up.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Ten cubits &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the length of a board, and a cubit and a half &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the breadth of one board.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Two tenons &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall there be&lt;/span&gt; in one board, set in order one against another: thus shalt thou make for all the boards of the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And thou shalt make the boards for the tabernacle, twenty boards on the south side southward.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And thou shalt make forty sockets of silver under the twenty boards; two sockets under one board for his two tenons, and two sockets under another board for his two tenons.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And for the second side of the tabernacle on the north side &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; twenty boards:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And their forty sockets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; silver; two sockets under one board, and two sockets under another board.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And for the sides of the tabernacle westward thou shalt make six boards.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And two boards shalt thou make for the corners of the tabernacle in the two sides.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they shall be coupled together beneath, and they shall be coupled together above the head of it unto one ring: thus shall it be for them both; they shall be for the two corners.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they shall be eight boards, and their sockets &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; silver, sixteen sockets; two sockets under one board, and two sockets under another board.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And thou shalt make bars &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; shittim wood; five for the boards of the one side of the tabernacle,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And five bars for the boards of the other side of the tabernacle, and five bars for the boards of the side of the tabernacle, for the two sides westward.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the middle bar in the midst of the boards shall reach from end to end.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And thou shalt overlay the boards with gold, and make their rings &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; gold &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; places for the bars: and thou shalt overlay the bars with gold.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And thou shalt rear up the tabernacle according to the fashion thereof which was shewed thee in the mount.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And thou shalt make a vail &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine twined linen of cunning work: with cherubims shall it be made:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And thou shalt hang it upon four pillars of shittim &lt;span class='extra'&gt;wood&lt;/span&gt; overlaid with gold: their hooks &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be of&lt;/span&gt; gold, upon the four sockets of silver.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">And thou shalt hang up the vail under the taches, that thou mayest bring in thither within the vail the ark of the testimony: and the vail shall divide unto you between the holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt; and the most holy.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And thou shalt put the mercy seat upon the ark of the testimony in the most holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And thou shalt set the table without the vail, and the candlestick over against the table on the side of the tabernacle toward the south: and thou shalt put the table on the north side.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And thou shalt make an hanging for the door of the tent, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; blue, and purple, and scarlet, and fine twined linen, wrought with needlework.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And thou shalt make for the hanging five pillars &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; shittim &lt;span class='extra'&gt;wood&lt;/span&gt;, and overlay them with gold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; their hooks &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be of&lt;/span&gt; gold: and thou shalt cast five sockets of brass for them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>