<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="51" nextChapter="exodus_13.html" nextTitle="Exodus 13" prevChapter="exodus_11.html" prevTitle="Exodus 11" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses and Aaron in the land of Egypt, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">This month &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; unto you the beginning of months: it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the first month of the year to you.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Speak ye unto all the congregation of Israel, saying, In the tenth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of this month they shall take to them every man a lamb, according to the house of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; fathers, a lamb for an house:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And if the household be too little for the lamb, let him and his neighbour next unto his house take &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; according to the number of the souls; every man according to his eating shall make your count for the lamb.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Your lamb shall be without blemish, a male of the first year: ye shall take &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; out from the sheep, or from the goats:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And ye shall keep it up until the fourteenth day of the same month: and the whole assembly of the congregation of Israel shall kill it in the evening.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they shall take of the blood, and strike &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on the two side posts and on the upper door post of the houses, wherein they shall eat it.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And they shall eat the flesh in that night, roast with fire, and unleavened bread; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; with bitter &lt;span class="extra"&gt;herbs&lt;/span&gt; they shall eat it.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Eat not of it raw, nor sodden at all with water, but roast &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; fire; his head with his legs, and with the purtenance thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And ye shall let nothing of it remain until the morning; and that which remaineth of it until the morning ye shall burn with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And thus shall ye eat it; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; your loins girded, your shoes on your feet, and your staff in your hand; and ye shall eat it in haste: it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s passover.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For I will pass through the land of Egypt this night, and will smite all the firstborn in the land of Egypt, both man and beast; and against all the gods of Egypt I will execute judgment: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the blood shall be to you for a token upon the houses where ye &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt;: and when I see the blood, I will pass over you, and the plague shall not be upon you to destroy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;you&lt;/span&gt;, when I smite the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And this day shall be unto you for a memorial; and ye shall keep it a feast to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; throughout your generations; ye shall keep it a feast by an ordinance for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Seven days shall ye eat unleavened bread; even the first day ye shall put away leaven out of your houses: for whosoever eateth leavened bread from the first day until the seventh day, that soul shall be cut off from Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And in the first day &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; an holy convocation, and in the seventh day there shall be an holy convocation to you; no manner of work shall be done in them, save &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which every man must eat, that only may be done of you.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And ye shall observe &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the feast of&lt;/span&gt; unleavened bread; for in this selfsame day have I brought your armies out of the land of Egypt: therefore shall ye observe this day in your generations by an ordinance for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">In the first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;month&lt;/span&gt;, on the fourteenth day of the month at even, ye shall eat unleavened bread, until the one and twentieth day of the month at even.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Seven days shall there be no leaven found in your houses: for whosoever eateth that which is leavened, even that soul shall be cut off from the congregation of Israel, whether he be a stranger, or born in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Ye shall eat nothing leavened; in all your habitations shall ye eat unleavened bread.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Then Moses called for all the elders of Israel, and said unto them, Draw out and take you a lamb according to your families, and kill the passover.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And ye shall take a bunch of hyssop, and dip &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; in the blood that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the bason, and strike the lintel and the two side posts with the blood that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the bason; and none of you shall go out at the door of his house until the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will pass through to smite the Egyptians; and when he seeth the blood upon the lintel, and on the two side posts, the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will pass over the door, and will not suffer the destroyer to come in unto your houses to smite &lt;span class="extra"&gt;you&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And ye shall observe this thing for an ordinance to thee and to thy sons for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And it shall come to pass, when ye be come to the land which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will give you, according as he hath promised, that ye shall keep this service.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And it shall come to pass, when your children shall say unto you, What mean ye by this service?</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">That ye shall say, It &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the sacrifice of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s passover, who passed over the houses of the children of Israel in Egypt, when he smote the Egyptians, and delivered our houses. And the people bowed the head and worshipped.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the children of Israel went away, and did as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had commanded Moses and Aaron, so did they.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">And it came to pass, that at midnight the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; smote all the firstborn in the land of Egypt, from the firstborn of Pharaoh that sat on his throne unto the firstborn of the captive that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the dungeon; and all the firstborn of cattle.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Pharaoh rose up in the night, he, and all his servants, and all the Egyptians; and there was a great cry in Egypt; for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; not a house where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; not one dead.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And he called for Moses and Aaron by night, and said, Rise up, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; get you forth from among my people, both ye and the children of Israel; and go, serve the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as ye have said.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Also take your flocks and your herds, as ye have said, and be gone; and bless me also.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And the Egyptians were urgent upon the people, that they might send them out of the land in haste; for they said, We &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; all dead &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And the people took their dough before it was leavened, their kneadingtroughs being bound up in their clothes upon their shoulders.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And the children of Israel did according to the word of Moses; and they borrowed of the Egyptians jewels of silver, and jewels of gold, and raiment:</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; gave the people favour in the sight of the Egyptians, so that they lent unto them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;such things as they required&lt;/span&gt;. And they spoiled the Egyptians.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37" newPara="true">And the children of Israel journeyed from Rameses to Succoth, about six hundred thousand on foot &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that were&lt;/span&gt; men, beside children.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And a mixed multitude went up also with them; and flocks, and herds, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; very much cattle.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And they baked unleavened cakes of the dough which they brought forth out of Egypt, for it was not leavened; because they were thrust out of Egypt, and could not tarry, neither had they prepared for themselves any victual.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40" newPara="true">Now the sojourning of the children of Israel, who dwelt in Egypt, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; four hundred and thirty years.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And it came to pass at the end of the four hundred and thirty years, even the selfsame day it came to pass, that all the hosts of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; went out from the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">It &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a night to be much observed unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for bringing them out from the land of Egypt: this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; that night of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to be observed of all the children of Israel in their generations.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses and Aaron, This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the ordinance of the passover: There shall no stranger eat thereof:</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">But every man's servant that is bought for money, when thou hast circumcised him, then shall he eat thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">A foreigner and an hired servant shall not eat thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">In one house shall it be eaten; thou shalt not carry forth ought of the flesh abroad out of the house; neither shall ye break a bone thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">All the congregation of Israel shall keep it.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">And when a stranger shall sojourn with thee, and will keep the passover to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, let all his males be circumcised, and then let him come near and keep it; and he shall be as one that is born in the land: for no uncircumcised person shall eat thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">One law shall be to him that is homeborn, and unto the stranger that sojourneth among you.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">Thus did all the children of Israel; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses and Aaron, so did they.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And it came to pass the selfsame day, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did bring the children of Israel out of the land of Egypt by their armies.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>