<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="34" verseCount="35" nextChapter="exodus_35.html" nextTitle="Exodus 35" prevChapter="exodus_33.html" prevTitle="Exodus 33" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Hew thee two tables of stone like unto the first: and I will write upon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;these&lt;/span&gt; tables the words that were in the first tables, which thou brakest.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And be ready in the morning, and come up in the morning unto mount Sinai, and present thyself there to me in the top of the mount.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And no man shall come up with thee, neither let any man be seen throughout all the mount; neither let the flocks nor herds feed before that mount.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And he hewed two tables of stone like unto the first; and Moses rose up early in the morning, and went up unto mount Sinai, as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had commanded him, and took in his hand the two tables of stone.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; descended in the cloud, and stood with him there, and proclaimed the name of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; passed by before him, and proclaimed, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God, merciful and gracious, longsuffering, and abundant in goodness and truth,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Keeping mercy for thousands, forgiving iniquity and transgression and sin, and that will by no means clear &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the guilty&lt;/span&gt;; visiting the iniquity of the fathers upon the children, and upon the children's children, unto the third and to the fourth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;generation&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Moses made haste, and bowed his head toward the earth, and worshipped.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he said, If now I have found grace in thy sight, O Lord, let my Lord, I pray thee, go among us; for it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a stiffnecked people; and pardon our iniquity and our sin, and take us for thine inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And he said, Behold, I make a covenant: before all thy people I will do marvels, such as have not been done in all the earth, nor in any nation: and all the people among which thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; shall see the work of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a terrible thing that I will do with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Observe thou that which I command thee this day: behold, I drive out before thee the Amorite, and the Canaanite, and the Hittite, and the Perizzite, and the Hivite, and the Jebusite.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Take heed to thyself, lest thou make a covenant with the inhabitants of the land whither thou goest, lest it be for a snare in the midst of thee:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But ye shall destroy their altars, break their images, and cut down their groves:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For thou shalt worship no other god: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, whose name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Jealous, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a jealous God:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Lest thou make a covenant with the inhabitants of the land, and they go a whoring after their gods, and do sacrifice unto their gods, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; call thee, and thou eat of his sacrifice;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And thou take of their daughters unto thy sons, and their daughters go a whoring after their gods, and make thy sons go a whoring after their gods.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thou shalt make thee no molten gods.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">The feast of unleavened bread shalt thou keep. Seven days thou shalt eat unleavened bread, as I commanded thee, in the time of the month Abib: for in the month Abib thou camest out from Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">All that openeth the matrix &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine; and every firstling among thy cattle, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;whether&lt;/span&gt; ox or sheep, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is male&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But the firstling of an ass thou shalt redeem with a lamb: and if thou redeem &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; not, then shalt thou break his neck. All the firstborn of thy sons thou shalt redeem. And none shall appear before me empty.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Six days thou shalt work, but on the seventh day thou shalt rest: in earing time and in harvest thou shalt rest.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And thou shalt observe the feast of weeks, of the firstfruits of wheat harvest, and the feast of ingathering at the year's end.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">Thrice in the year shall all your men children appear before the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, the God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For I will cast out the nations before thee, and enlarge thy borders: neither shall any man desire thy land, when thou shalt go up to appear before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God thrice in the year.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Thou shalt not offer the blood of my sacrifice with leaven; neither shall the sacrifice of the feast of the passover be left unto the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The first of the firstfruits of thy land thou shalt bring unto the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God. Thou shalt not seethe a kid in his mother's milk.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Write thou these words: for after the tenor of these words I have made a covenant with thee and with Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he was there with the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; forty days and forty nights; he did neither eat bread, nor drink water. And he wrote upon the tables the words of the covenant, the ten commandments.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when Moses came down from mount Sinai with the two tables of testimony in Moses' hand, when he came down from the mount, that Moses wist not that the skin of his face shone while he talked with him.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And when Aaron and all the children of Israel saw Moses, behold, the skin of his face shone; and they were afraid to come nigh him.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Moses called unto them; and Aaron and all the rulers of the congregation returned unto him: and Moses talked with them.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And afterward all the children of Israel came nigh: and he gave them in commandment all that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had spoken with him in mount Sinai.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;till&lt;/span&gt; Moses had done speaking with them, he put a vail on his face.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">But when Moses went in before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to speak with him, he took the vail off, until he came out. And he came out, and spake unto the children of Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which he was commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And the children of Israel saw the face of Moses, that the skin of Moses' face shone: and Moses put the vail upon his face again, until he went in to speak with him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>