<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="26" nextChapter="exodus_21.html" nextTitle="Exodus 21" prevChapter="exodus_19.html" prevTitle="Exodus 19" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And God spake all these words, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, which have brought thee out of the land of Egypt, out of the house of bondage.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou shalt have no other gods before me.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven image, or any likeness &lt;i&gt;of any thing&lt;/i&gt; that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in heaven above, or that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the earth beneath, or that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the water under the earth:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them, nor serve them: for I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; a jealous God, visiting the iniquity of the fathers upon the children unto the third and fourth &lt;i&gt;generation&lt;/i&gt; of them that hate me;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And shewing mercy unto thousands of them that love me, and keep my commandments.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thou shalt not take the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God in vain; for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will not hold him guiltless that taketh his name in vain.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Remember the sabbath day, to keep it holy.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Six days shalt thou labour, and do all thy work:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But the seventh day &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the sabbath of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God: &lt;i&gt;in it&lt;/i&gt; thou shalt not do any work, thou, nor thy son, nor thy daughter, thy manservant, nor thy maidservant, nor thy cattle, nor thy stranger that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; within thy gates:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; six days the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made heaven and earth, the sea, and all that in them &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt;, and rested the seventh day: wherefore the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; blessed the sabbath day, and hallowed it.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Honour thy father and thy mother: that thy days may be long upon the land which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thou shalt not kill.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou shalt not commit adultery.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Thou shalt not steal.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thou shalt not bear false witness against thy neighbour.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thou shalt not covet thy neighbour's house, thou shalt not covet thy neighbour's wife, nor his manservant, nor his maidservant, nor his ox, nor his ass, nor any thing that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy neighbour's.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And all the people saw the thunderings, and the lightnings, and the noise of the trumpet, and the mountain smoking: and when the people saw &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, they removed, and stood afar off.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And they said unto Moses, Speak thou with us, and we will hear: but let not God speak with us, lest we die.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Moses said unto the people, Fear not: for God is come to prove you, and that his fear may be before your faces, that ye sin not.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the people stood afar off, and Moses drew near unto the thick darkness where God &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Thus thou shalt say unto the children of Israel, Ye have seen that I have talked with you from heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Ye shall not make with me gods of silver, neither shall ye make unto you gods of gold.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">An altar of earth thou shalt make unto me, and shalt sacrifice thereon thy burnt offerings, and thy peace offerings, thy sheep, and thine oxen: in all places where I record my name I will come unto thee, and I will bless thee.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And if thou wilt make me an altar of stone, thou shalt not build it of hewn stone: for if thou lift up thy tool upon it, thou hast polluted it.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Neither shalt thou go up by steps unto mine altar, that thy nakedness be not discovered thereon.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>