<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="31" nextChapter="exodus_23.html" nextTitle="Exodus 23" prevChapter="exodus_21.html" prevTitle="Exodus 21" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">If a man shall steal an ox, or a sheep, and kill it, or sell it; he shall restore five oxen for an ox, and four sheep for a sheep.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">If a thief be found breaking up, and be smitten that he die, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there shall&lt;/span&gt; no blood &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be shed&lt;/span&gt; for him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">If the sun be risen upon him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; blood &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shed&lt;/span&gt; for him; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; he should make full restitution; if he have nothing, then he shall be sold for his theft.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">If the theft be certainly found in his hand alive, whether it be ox, or ass, or sheep; he shall restore double.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">If a man shall cause a field or vineyard to be eaten, and shall put in his beast, and shall feed in another man's field; of the best of his own field, and of the best of his own vineyard, shall he make restitution.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">If fire break out, and catch in thorns, so that the stacks of corn, or the standing corn, or the field, be consumed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;therewith&lt;/span&gt;; he that kindled the fire shall surely make restitution.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">If a man shall deliver unto his neighbour money or stuff to keep, and it be stolen out of the man's house; if the thief be found, let him pay double.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">If the thief be not found, then the master of the house shall be brought unto the judges, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to see&lt;/span&gt; whether he have put his hand unto his neighbour's goods.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For all manner of trespass, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;whether it be&lt;/span&gt; for ox, for ass, for sheep, for raiment, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; for any manner of lost thing, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;another&lt;/span&gt; challengeth to be his, the cause of both parties shall come before the judges; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; whom the judges shall condemn, he shall pay double unto his neighbour.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">If a man deliver unto his neighbour an ass, or an ox, or a sheep, or any beast, to keep; and it die, or be hurt, or driven away, no man seeing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; shall an oath of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be between them both, that he hath not put his hand unto his neighbour's goods; and the owner of it shall accept &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thereof&lt;/span&gt;, and he shall not make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; good.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And if it be stolen from him, he shall make restitution unto the owner thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">If it be torn in pieces, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; let him bring it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; witness, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he shall not make good that which was torn.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And if a man borrow &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ought&lt;/span&gt; of his neighbour, and it be hurt, or die, the owner thereof &lt;span class="extra"&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; not with it, he shall surely make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; good.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;But&lt;/span&gt; if the owner thereof &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; with it, he shall not make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; good: if it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; an hired &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thing&lt;/span&gt;, it came for his hire.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And if a man entice a maid that is not betrothed, and lie with her, he shall surely endow her to be his wife.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">If her father utterly refuse to give her unto him, he shall pay money according to the dowry of virgins.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Thou shalt not suffer a witch to live.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">Whosoever lieth with a beast shall surely be put to death.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">He that sacrificeth unto &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; god, save unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; only, he shall be utterly destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Thou shalt neither vex a stranger, nor oppress him: for ye were strangers in the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">Ye shall not afflict any widow, or fatherless child.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">If thou afflict them in any wise, and they cry at all unto me, I will surely hear their cry;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And my wrath shall wax hot, and I will kill you with the sword; and your wives shall be widows, and your children fatherless.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">If thou lend money to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any of&lt;/span&gt; my people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; poor by thee, thou shalt not be to him as an usurer, neither shalt thou lay upon him usury.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">If thou at all take thy neighbour's raiment to pledge, thou shalt deliver it unto him by that the sun goeth down:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his covering only, it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his raiment for his skin: wherein shall he sleep? and it shall come to pass, when he crieth unto me, that I will hear; for I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; gracious.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">Thou shalt not revile the gods, nor curse the ruler of thy people.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">Thou shalt not delay &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to offer&lt;/span&gt; the first of thy ripe fruits, and of thy liquors: the firstborn of thy sons shalt thou give unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Likewise shalt thou do with thine oxen, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; with thy sheep: seven days it shall be with his dam; on the eighth day thou shalt give it me.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And ye shall be holy men unto me: neither shall ye eat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; flesh &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; torn of beasts in the field; ye shall cast it to the dogs.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>