<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="10" nextChapter="exodus_12.html" nextTitle="Exodus 12" prevChapter="exodus_10.html" prevTitle="Exodus 10" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Yet will I bring one plague &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; upon Pharaoh, and upon Egypt; afterwards he will let you go hence: when he shall let &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; go, he shall surely thrust you out hence altogether.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak now in the ears of the people, and let every man borrow of his neighbour, and every woman of her neighbour, jewels of silver, and jewels of gold.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; gave the people favour in the sight of the Egyptians. Moreover the man Moses &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; very great in the land of Egypt, in the sight of Pharaoh's servants, and in the sight of the people.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Moses said, Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, About midnight will I go out into the midst of Egypt:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And all the firstborn in the land of Egypt shall die, from the firstborn of Pharaoh that sitteth upon his throne, even unto the firstborn of the maidservant that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; behind the mill; and all the firstborn of beasts.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And there shall be a great cry throughout all the land of Egypt, such as there was none like it, nor shall be like it any more.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But against any of the children of Israel shall not a dog move his tongue, against man or beast: that ye may know how that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; doth put a difference between the Egyptians and Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And all these thy servants shall come down unto me, and bow down themselves unto me, saying, Get thee out, and all the people that follow thee: and after that I will go out. And he went out from Pharaoh in a great anger.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Pharaoh shall not hearken unto you; that my wonders may be multiplied in the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Moses and Aaron did all these wonders before Pharaoh: and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hardened Pharaoh's heart, so that he would not let the children of Israel go out of his land.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>