<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="32" nextChapter="exodus_9.html" nextTitle="Exodus 9" prevChapter="exodus_7.html" prevTitle="Exodus 7" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, Go unto Pharaoh, and say unto him, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Let my people go, that they may serve me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And if thou refuse to let &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; go, behold, I will smite all thy borders with frogs:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the river shall bring forth frogs abundantly, which shall go up and come into thine house, and into thy bedchamber, and upon thy bed, and into the house of thy servants, and upon thy people, and into thine ovens, and into thy kneadingtroughs:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the frogs shall come up both on thee, and upon thy people, and upon all thy servants.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, Say unto Aaron, Stretch forth thine hand with thy rod over the streams, over the rivers, and over the ponds, and cause frogs to come up upon the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Aaron stretched out his hand over the waters of Egypt; and the frogs came up, and covered the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the magicians did so with their enchantments, and brought up frogs upon the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Then Pharaoh called for Moses and Aaron, and said, Intreat the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that he may take away the frogs from me, and from my people; and I will let the people go, that they may do sacrifice unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Moses said unto Pharaoh, Glory over me: when shall I intreat for thee, and for thy servants, and for thy people, to destroy the frogs from thee and thy houses, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; they may remain in the river only?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he said, To morrow. And he said, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Be it&lt;/span&gt; according to thy word: that thou mayest know that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none like unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the frogs shall depart from thee, and from thy houses, and from thy servants, and from thy people; they shall remain in the river only.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Moses and Aaron went out from Pharaoh: and Moses cried unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; because of the frogs which he had brought against Pharaoh.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did according to the word of Moses; and the frogs died out of the houses, out of the villages, and out of the fields.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they gathered them together upon heaps: and the land stank.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But when Pharaoh saw that there was respite, he hardened his heart, and hearkened not unto them; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had said.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Say unto Aaron, Stretch out thy rod, and smite the dust of the land, that it may become lice throughout all the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And they did so; for Aaron stretched out his hand with his rod, and smote the dust of the earth, and it became lice in man, and in beast; all the dust of the land became lice throughout all the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the magicians did so with their enchantments to bring forth lice, but they could not: so there were lice upon man, and upon beast.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Then the magicians said unto Pharaoh, This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the finger of God: and Pharaoh's heart was hardened, and he hearkened not unto them; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had said.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Rise up early in the morning, and stand before Pharaoh; lo, he cometh forth to the water; and say unto him, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Let my people go, that they may serve me.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Else, if thou wilt not let my people go, behold, I will send swarms &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of flies&lt;/span&gt; upon thee, and upon thy servants, and upon thy people, and into thy houses: and the houses of the Egyptians shall be full of swarms &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of flies&lt;/span&gt;, and also the ground whereon they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And I will sever in that day the land of Goshen, in which my people dwell, that no swarms &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of flies&lt;/span&gt; shall be there; to the end thou mayest know that I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the midst of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And I will put a division between my people and thy people: to morrow shall this sign be.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did so; and there came a grievous swarm &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of flies&lt;/span&gt; into the house of Pharaoh, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;into&lt;/span&gt; his servants' houses, and into all the land of Egypt: the land was corrupted by reason of the swarm &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of flies&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And Pharaoh called for Moses and for Aaron, and said, Go ye, sacrifice to your God in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Moses said, It is not meet so to do; for we shall sacrifice the abomination of the Egyptians to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God: lo, shall we sacrifice the abomination of the Egyptians before their eyes, and will they not stone us?</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">We will go three days' journey into the wilderness, and sacrifice to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, as he shall command us.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Pharaoh said, I will let you go, that ye may sacrifice to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God in the wilderness; only ye shall not go very far away: intreat for me.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Moses said, Behold, I go out from thee, and I will intreat the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that the swarms &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of flies&lt;/span&gt; may depart from Pharaoh, from his servants, and from his people, to morrow: but let not Pharaoh deal deceitfully any more in not letting the people go to sacrifice to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Moses went out from Pharaoh, and intreated the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did according to the word of Moses; and he removed the swarms &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of flies&lt;/span&gt; from Pharaoh, from his servants, and from his people; there remained not one.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And Pharaoh hardened his heart at this time also, neither would he let the people go.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>