<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="2" name="Exodus" bookPage="exodus.html" title="Exodus" chapterCount="40" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="leviticus_1.html" nextTitle="Leviticus" prevBook="genesis_1.html" prevTitle="Genesis">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="30" nextChapter="exodus_7.html" nextTitle="Exodus 7" prevChapter="exodus_5.html" prevTitle="Exodus 5" chapterPage="exodus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Now shalt thou see what I will do to Pharaoh: for with a strong hand shall he let them go, and with a strong hand shall he drive them out of his land.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And God spake unto Moses, and said unto him, I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I appeared unto Abraham, unto Isaac, and unto Jacob, by &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the name of&lt;/span&gt; God Almighty, but by my name JEHOVAH was I not known to them.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And I have also established my covenant with them, to give them the land of Canaan, the land of their pilgrimage, wherein they were strangers.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And I have also heard the groaning of the children of Israel, whom the Egyptians keep in bondage; and I have remembered my covenant.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Wherefore say unto the children of Israel, I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and I will bring you out from under the burdens of the Egyptians, and I will rid you out of their bondage, and I will redeem you with a stretched out arm, and with great judgments:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And I will take you to me for a people, and I will be to you a God: and ye shall know that I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, which bringeth you out from under the burdens of the Egyptians.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I will bring you in unto the land, concerning the which I did swear to give it to Abraham, to Isaac, and to Jacob; and I will give it you for an heritage: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And Moses spake so unto the children of Israel: but they hearkened not unto Moses for anguish of spirit, and for cruel bondage.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Go in, speak unto Pharaoh king of Egypt, that he let the children of Israel go out of his land.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Moses spake before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, saying, Behold, the children of Israel have not hearkened unto me; how then shall Pharaoh hear me, who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; of uncircumcised lips?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses and unto Aaron, and gave them a charge unto the children of Israel, and unto Pharaoh king of Egypt, to bring the children of Israel out of the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the heads of their fathers' houses: The sons of Reuben the firstborn of Israel; Hanoch, and Pallu, Hezron, and Carmi: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the families of Reuben.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the sons of Simeon; Jemuel, and Jamin, and Ohad, and Jachin, and Zohar, and Shaul the son of a Canaanitish woman: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the families of Simeon.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the names of the sons of Levi according to their generations; Gershon, and Kohath, and Merari: and the years of the life of Levi &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; an hundred thirty and seven years.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The sons of Gershon; Libni, and Shimi, according to their families.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the sons of Kohath; Amram, and Izhar, and Hebron, and Uzziel: and the years of the life of Kohath &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; an hundred thirty and three years.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the sons of Merari; Mahali and Mushi: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the families of Levi according to their generations.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Amram took him Jochebed his father's sister to wife; and she bare him Aaron and Moses: and the years of the life of Amram &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; an hundred and thirty and seven years.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">And the sons of Izhar; Korah, and Nepheg, and Zichri.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the sons of Uzziel; Mishael, and Elzaphan, and Zithri.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Aaron took him Elisheba, daughter of Amminadab, sister of Naashon, to wife; and she bare him Nadab, and Abihu, Eleazar, and Ithamar.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the sons of Korah; Assir, and Elkanah, and Abiasaph: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the families of the Korhites.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Eleazar Aaron's son took him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; of the daughters of Putiel to wife; and she bare him Phinehas: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the heads of the fathers of the Levites according to their families.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; that Aaron and Moses, to whom the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said, Bring out the children of Israel from the land of Egypt according to their armies.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they which spake to Pharaoh king of Egypt, to bring out the children of Israel from Egypt: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; that Moses and Aaron.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">And it came to pass on the day &lt;span class="extra"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses in the land of Egypt,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">That the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying, I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: speak thou unto Pharaoh king of Egypt all that I say unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Moses said before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Behold, I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; of uncircumcised lips, and how shall Pharaoh hearken unto me?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>