<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="47" nextChapter="leviticus_12.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 12" prevChapter="leviticus_10.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 10" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses and to Aaron, saying unto them,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto the children of Israel, saying, These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the beasts which ye shall eat among all the beasts that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; on the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Whatsoever parteth the hoof, and is clovenfooted, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; cheweth the cud, among the beasts, that shall ye eat.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Nevertheless these shall ye not eat of them that chew the cud, or of them that divide the hoof: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the camel, because he cheweth the cud, but divideth not the hoof; he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the coney, because he cheweth the cud, but divideth not the hoof; he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the hare, because he cheweth the cud, but divideth not the hoof; he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the swine, though he divide the hoof, and be clovenfooted, yet he cheweth not the cud; he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean to you.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Of their flesh shall ye not eat, and their carcase shall ye not touch; they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; unclean to you.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">These shall ye eat of all that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in the waters: whatsoever hath fins and scales in the waters, in the seas, and in the rivers, them shall ye eat.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And all that have not fins and scales in the seas, and in the rivers, of all that move in the waters, and of any living thing which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the waters, they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; an abomination unto you:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">They shall be even an abomination unto you; ye shall not eat of their flesh, but ye shall have their carcases in abomination.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Whatsoever hath no fins nor scales in the waters, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; an abomination unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are they which&lt;/span&gt; ye shall have in abomination among the fowls; they shall not be eaten, they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; an abomination: the eagle, and the ossifrage, and the ospray,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the vulture, and the kite after his kind;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Every raven after his kind;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the owl, and the night hawk, and the cuckow, and the hawk after his kind,</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the little owl, and the cormorant, and the great owl,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the swan, and the pelican, and the gier eagle,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the stork, the heron after her kind, and the lapwing, and the bat.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">All fowls that creep, going upon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; four, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; an abomination unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Yet these may ye eat of every flying creeping thing that goeth upon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; four, which have legs above their feet, to leap withal upon the earth;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Even&lt;/span&gt; these of them ye may eat; the locust after his kind, and the bald locust after his kind, and the beetle after his kind, and the grasshopper after his kind.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; flying creeping things, which have four feet, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; an abomination unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And for these ye shall be unclean: whosoever toucheth the carcase of them shall be unclean until the even.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And whosoever beareth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ought&lt;/span&gt; of the carcase of them shall wash his clothes, and be unclean until the even.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;The carcases&lt;/span&gt; of every beast which divideth the hoof, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not clovenfooted, nor cheweth the cud, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; unclean unto you: every one that toucheth them shall be unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And whatsoever goeth upon his paws, among all manner of beasts that go on &lt;span class="extra"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; four, those &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; unclean unto you: whoso toucheth their carcase shall be unclean until the even.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he that beareth the carcase of them shall wash his clothes, and be unclean until the even: they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; unclean unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">These also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; unclean unto you among the creeping things that creep upon the earth; the weasel, and the mouse, and the tortoise after his kind,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the ferret, and the chameleon, and the lizard, and the snail, and the mole.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; unclean to you among all that creep: whosoever doth touch them, when they be dead, shall be unclean until the even.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And upon whatsoever &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; of them, when they are dead, doth fall, it shall be unclean; whether &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt; any vessel of wood, or raiment, or skin, or sack, whatsoever vessel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt;, wherein &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; work is done, it must be put into water, and it shall be unclean until the even; so it shall be cleansed.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And every earthen vessel, whereinto &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; of them falleth, whatsoever &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in it shall be unclean; and ye shall break it.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Of all meat which may be eaten, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; on which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;such&lt;/span&gt; water cometh shall be unclean: and all drink that may be drunk in every &lt;span class="extra"&gt;such&lt;/span&gt; vessel shall be unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And every &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thing&lt;/span&gt; whereupon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any part&lt;/span&gt; of their carcase falleth shall be unclean; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;whether it be&lt;/span&gt; oven, or ranges for pots, they shall be broken down: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; unclean, and shall be unclean unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Nevertheless a fountain or pit, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;wherein there is&lt;/span&gt; plenty of water, shall be clean: but that which toucheth their carcase shall be unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And if &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any part&lt;/span&gt; of their carcase fall upon any sowing seed which is to be sown, it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; clean.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">But if &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; water be put upon the seed, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any part&lt;/span&gt; of their carcase fall thereon, it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; unclean unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And if any beast, of which ye may eat, die; he that toucheth the carcase thereof shall be unclean until the even.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And he that eateth of the carcase of it shall wash his clothes, and be unclean until the even: he also that beareth the carcase of it shall wash his clothes, and be unclean until the even.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And every creeping thing that creepeth upon the earth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; an abomination; it shall not be eaten.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Whatsoever goeth upon the belly, and whatsoever goeth upon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; four, or whatsoever hath more feet among all creeping things that creep upon the earth, them ye shall not eat; for they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; an abomination.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Ye shall not make yourselves abominable with any creeping thing that creepeth, neither shall ye make yourselves unclean with them, that ye should be defiled thereby.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">For I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God: ye shall therefore sanctify yourselves, and ye shall be holy; for I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; holy: neither shall ye defile yourselves with any manner of creeping thing that creepeth upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">For I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that bringeth you up out of the land of Egypt, to be your God: ye shall therefore be holy, for I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; holy.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law of the beasts, and of the fowl, and of every living creature that moveth in the waters, and of every creature that creepeth upon the earth:</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">To make a difference between the unclean and the clean, and between the beast that may be eaten and the beast that may not be eaten.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>