<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="8" nextChapter="leviticus_13.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 13" prevChapter="leviticus_11.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 11" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto the children of Israel, saying, If a woman have conceived seed, and born a man child: then she shall be unclean seven days; according to the days of the separation for her infirmity shall she be unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And in the eighth day the flesh of his foreskin shall be circumcised.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And she shall then continue in the blood of her purifying three and thirty days; she shall touch no hallowed thing, nor come into the sanctuary, until the days of her purifying be fulfilled.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But if she bear a maid child, then she shall be unclean two weeks, as in her separation: and she shall continue in the blood of her purifying threescore and six days.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And when the days of her purifying are fulfilled, for a son, or for a daughter, she shall bring a lamb of the first year for a burnt offering, and a young pigeon, or a turtledove, for a sin offering, unto the door of the tabernacle of the congregation, unto the priest:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Who shall offer it before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and make an atonement for her; and she shall be cleansed from the issue of her blood. This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law for her that hath born a male or a female.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And if she be not able to bring a lamb, then she shall bring two turtles, or two young pigeons; the one for the burnt offering, and the other for a sin offering: and the priest shall make an atonement for her, and she shall be clean.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>