<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="27" nextChapter="leviticus_21.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 21" prevChapter="leviticus_19.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 19" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Again, thou shalt say to the children of Israel, Whosoever &lt;i&gt;he be&lt;/i&gt; of the children of Israel, or of the strangers that sojourn in Israel, that giveth &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; of his seed unto Molech; he shall surely be put to death: the people of the land shall stone him with stones.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I will set my face against that man, and will cut him off from among his people; because he hath given of his seed unto Molech, to defile my sanctuary, and to profane my holy name.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And if the people of the land do any ways hide their eyes from the man, when he giveth of his seed unto Molech, and kill him not:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then I will set my face against that man, and against his family, and will cut him off, and all that go a whoring after him, to commit whoredom with Molech, from among their people.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And the soul that turneth after such as have familiar spirits, and after wizards, to go a whoring after them, I will even set my face against that soul, and will cut him off from among his people.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Sanctify yourselves therefore, and be ye holy: for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And ye shall keep my statutes, and do them: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which sanctify you.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">For every one that curseth his father or his mother shall be surely put to death: he hath cursed his father or his mother; his blood &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And the man that committeth adultery with &lt;i&gt;another&lt;/i&gt; man's wife, &lt;i&gt;even he&lt;/i&gt; that committeth adultery with his neighbour's wife, the adulterer and the adulteress shall surely be put to death.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the man that lieth with his father's wife hath uncovered his father's nakedness: both of them shall surely be put to death; their blood &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And if a man lie with his daughter in law, both of them shall surely be put to death: they have wrought confusion; their blood &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">If a man also lie with mankind, as he lieth with a woman, both of them have committed an abomination: they shall surely be put to death; their blood &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And if a man take a wife and her mother, it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; wickedness: they shall be burnt with fire, both he and they; that there be no wickedness among you.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And if a man lie with a beast, he shall surely be put to death: and ye shall slay the beast.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And if a woman approach unto any beast, and lie down thereto, thou shalt kill the woman, and the beast: they shall surely be put to death; their blood &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And if a man shall take his sister, his father's daughter, or his mother's daughter, and see her nakedness, and she see his nakedness; it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a wicked thing; and they shall be cut off in the sight of their people: he hath uncovered his sister's nakedness; he shall bear his iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And if a man shall lie with a woman having her sickness, and shall uncover her nakedness; he hath discovered her fountain, and she hath uncovered the fountain of her blood: and both of them shall be cut off from among their people.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And thou shalt not uncover the nakedness of thy mother's sister, nor of thy father's sister: for he uncovereth his near kin: they shall bear their iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And if a man shall lie with his uncle's wife, he hath uncovered his uncle's nakedness: they shall bear their sin; they shall die childless.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And if a man shall take his brother's wife, it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an unclean thing: he hath uncovered his brother's nakedness; they shall be childless.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">Ye shall therefore keep all my statutes, and all my judgments, and do them: that the land, whither I bring you to dwell therein, spue you not out.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And ye shall not walk in the manners of the nation, which I cast out before you: for they committed all these things, and therefore I abhorred them.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But I have said unto you, Ye shall inherit their land, and I will give it unto you to possess it, a land that floweth with milk and honey: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, which have separated you from &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; people.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Ye shall therefore put difference between clean beasts and unclean, and between unclean fowls and clean: and ye shall not make your souls abominable by beast, or by fowl, or by any manner of living thing that creepeth on the ground, which I have separated from you as unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And ye shall be holy unto me: for I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; holy, and have severed you from &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; people, that ye should be mine.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">A man also or woman that hath a familiar spirit, or that is a wizard, shall surely be put to death: they shall stone them with stones: their blood &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; upon them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>