<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="17" nextChapter="leviticus_2.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 2" prevChapter="exodus_40.html" prevTitle="Exodus 40" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; called unto Moses, and spake unto him out of the tabernacle of the congregation, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto the children of Israel, and say unto them, If any man of you bring an offering unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, ye shall bring your offering of the cattle, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of the herd, and of the flock.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">If his offering &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; a burnt sacrifice of the herd, let him offer a male without blemish: he shall offer it of his own voluntary will at the door of the tabernacle of the congregation before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he shall put his hand upon the head of the burnt offering; and it shall be accepted for him to make atonement for him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he shall kill the bullock before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and the priests, Aaron's sons, shall bring the blood, and sprinkle the blood round about upon the altar that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is by&lt;/span&gt; the door of the tabernacle of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he shall flay the burnt offering, and cut it into his pieces.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the sons of Aaron the priest shall put fire upon the altar, and lay the wood in order upon the fire:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the priests, Aaron's sons, shall lay the parts, the head, and the fat, in order upon the wood that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; on the fire which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the altar:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But his inwards and his legs shall he wash in water: and the priest shall burn all on the altar, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; a burnt sacrifice, an offering made by fire, of a sweet savour unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And if his offering &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; of the flocks, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;namely&lt;/span&gt;, of the sheep, or of the goats, for a burnt sacrifice; he shall bring it a male without blemish.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he shall kill it on the side of the altar northward before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and the priests, Aaron's sons, shall sprinkle his blood round about upon the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he shall cut it into his pieces, with his head and his fat: and the priest shall lay them in order on the wood that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; on the fire which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the altar:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But he shall wash the inwards and the legs with water: and the priest shall bring &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; all, and burn &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon the altar: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a burnt sacrifice, an offering made by fire, of a sweet savour unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And if the burnt sacrifice for his offering to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; of fowls, then he shall bring his offering of turtledoves, or of young pigeons.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the priest shall bring it unto the altar, and wring off his head, and burn &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on the altar; and the blood thereof shall be wrung out at the side of the altar:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he shall pluck away his crop with his feathers, and cast it beside the altar on the east part, by the place of the ashes:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he shall cleave it with the wings thereof, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; shall not divide &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; asunder: and the priest shall burn it upon the altar, upon the wood that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the fire: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a burnt sacrifice, an offering made by fire, of a sweet savour unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>