<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="17" verseCount="16" nextChapter="leviticus_18.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 18" prevChapter="leviticus_16.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 16" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto Aaron, and unto his sons, and unto all the children of Israel, and say unto them; This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the thing which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath commanded, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">What man soever &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; of the house of Israel, that killeth an ox, or lamb, or goat, in the camp, or that killeth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; out of the camp,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And bringeth it not unto the door of the tabernacle of the congregation, to offer an offering unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; before the tabernacle of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; blood shall be imputed unto that man; he hath shed blood; and that man shall be cut off from among his people:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">To the end that the children of Israel may bring their sacrifices, which they offer in the open field, even that they may bring them unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, unto the door of the tabernacle of the congregation, unto the priest, and offer them &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; peace offerings unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the priest shall sprinkle the blood upon the altar of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; the door of the tabernacle of the congregation, and burn the fat for a sweet savour unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they shall no more offer their sacrifices unto devils, after whom they have gone a whoring. This shall be a statute for ever unto them throughout their generations.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And thou shalt say unto them, Whatsoever man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; of the house of Israel, or of the strangers which sojourn among you, that offereth a burnt offering or sacrifice,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And bringeth it not unto the door of the tabernacle of the congregation, to offer it unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; even that man shall be cut off from among his people.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And whatsoever man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; of the house of Israel, or of the strangers that sojourn among you, that eateth any manner of blood; I will even set my face against that soul that eateth blood, and will cut him off from among his people.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For the life of the flesh &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the blood: and I have given it to you upon the altar to make an atonement for your souls: for it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the blood &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; maketh an atonement for the soul.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore I said unto the children of Israel, No soul of you shall eat blood, neither shall any stranger that sojourneth among you eat blood.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And whatsoever man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; of the children of Israel, or of the strangers that sojourn among you, which hunteth and catcheth any beast or fowl that may be eaten; he shall even pour out the blood thereof, and cover it with dust.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; the life of all flesh; the blood of it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; for the life thereof: therefore I said unto the children of Israel, Ye shall eat the blood of no manner of flesh: for the life of all flesh &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the blood thereof: whosoever eateth it shall be cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And every soul that eateth that which died &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of itself&lt;/span&gt;, or that which was torn &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with beasts, whether it be&lt;/span&gt; one of your own country, or a stranger, he shall both wash his clothes, and bathe &lt;span class='extra'&gt;himself&lt;/span&gt; in water, and be unclean until the even: then shall he be clean.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But if he wash &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; not, nor bathe his flesh; then he shall bear his iniquity.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>