<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="26" verseCount="46" nextChapter="leviticus_27.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 27" prevChapter="leviticus_25.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 25" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Ye shall make you no idols nor graven image, neither rear you up a standing image, neither shall ye set up &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; image of stone in your land, to bow down unto it: for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">Ye shall keep my sabbaths, and reverence my sanctuary: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">If ye walk in my statutes, and keep my commandments, and do them;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Then I will give you rain in due season, and the land shall yield her increase, and the trees of the field shall yield their fruit.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And your threshing shall reach unto the vintage, and the vintage shall reach unto the sowing time: and ye shall eat your bread to the full, and dwell in your land safely.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I will give peace in the land, and ye shall lie down, and none shall make &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; afraid: and I will rid evil beasts out of the land, neither shall the sword go through your land.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And ye shall chase your enemies, and they shall fall before you by the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And five of you shall chase an hundred, and an hundred of you shall put ten thousand to flight: and your enemies shall fall before you by the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For I will have respect unto you, and make you fruitful, and multiply you, and establish my covenant with you.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And ye shall eat old store, and bring forth the old because of the new.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I will set my tabernacle among you: and my soul shall not abhor you.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I will walk among you, and will be your God, and ye shall be my people.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, which brought you forth out of the land of Egypt, that ye should not be their bondmen; and I have broken the bands of your yoke, and made you go upright.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">But if ye will not hearken unto me, and will not do all these commandments;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And if ye shall despise my statutes, or if your soul abhor my judgments, so that ye will not do all my commandments, &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; that ye break my covenant:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I also will do this unto you; I will even appoint over you terror, consumption, and the burning ague, that shall consume the eyes, and cause sorrow of heart: and ye shall sow your seed in vain, for your enemies shall eat it.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And I will set my face against you, and ye shall be slain before your enemies: they that hate you shall reign over you; and ye shall flee when none pursueth you.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And if ye will not yet for all this hearken unto me, then I will punish you seven times more for your sins.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And I will break the pride of your power; and I will make your heaven as iron, and your earth as brass:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And your strength shall be spent in vain: for your land shall not yield her increase, neither shall the trees of the land yield their fruits.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">And if ye walk contrary unto me, and will not hearken unto me; I will bring seven times more plagues upon you according to your sins.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">I will also send wild beasts among you, which shall rob you of your children, and destroy your cattle, and make you few in number; and your &lt;i&gt;high&lt;/i&gt; ways shall be desolate.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And if ye will not be reformed by me by these things, but will walk contrary unto me;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Then will I also walk contrary unto you, and will punish you yet seven times for your sins.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And I will bring a sword upon you, that shall avenge the quarrel of &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; covenant: and when ye are gathered together within your cities, I will send the pestilence among you; and ye shall be delivered into the hand of the enemy.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;i&gt;And&lt;/i&gt; when I have broken the staff of your bread, ten women shall bake your bread in one oven, and they shall deliver &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; your bread again by weight: and ye shall eat, and not be satisfied.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And if ye will not for all this hearken unto me, but walk contrary unto me;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Then I will walk contrary unto you also in fury; and I, even I, will chastise you seven times for your sins.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And ye shall eat the flesh of your sons, and the flesh of your daughters shall ye eat.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And I will destroy your high places, and cut down your images, and cast your carcases upon the carcases of your idols, and my soul shall abhor you.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And I will make your cities waste, and bring your sanctuaries unto desolation, and I will not smell the savour of your sweet odours.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And I will bring the land into desolation: and your enemies which dwell therein shall be astonished at it.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And I will scatter you among the heathen, and will draw out a sword after you: and your land shall be desolate, and your cities waste.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Then shall the land enjoy her sabbaths, as long as it lieth desolate, and ye &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; in your enemies' land; &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; then shall the land rest, and enjoy her sabbaths.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">As long as it lieth desolate it shall rest; because it did not rest in your sabbaths, when ye dwelt upon it.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And upon them that are left &lt;i&gt;alive&lt;/i&gt; of you I will send a faintness into their hearts in the lands of their enemies; and the sound of a shaken leaf shall chase them; and they shall flee, as fleeing from a sword; and they shall fall when none pursueth.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And they shall fall one upon another, as it were before a sword, when none pursueth: and ye shall have no power to stand before your enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And ye shall perish among the heathen, and the land of your enemies shall eat you up.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And they that are left of you shall pine away in their iniquity in your enemies' lands; and also in the iniquities of their fathers shall they pine away with them.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">If they shall confess their iniquity, and the iniquity of their fathers, with their trespass which they trespassed against me, and that also they have walked contrary unto me;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I also have walked contrary unto them, and have brought them into the land of their enemies; if then their uncircumcised hearts be humbled, and they then accept of the punishment of their iniquity:</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Then will I remember my covenant with Jacob, and also my covenant with Isaac, and also my covenant with Abraham will I remember; and I will remember the land.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">The land also shall be left of them, and shall enjoy her sabbaths, while she lieth desolate without them: and they shall accept of the punishment of their iniquity: because, even because they despised my judgments, and because their soul abhorred my statutes.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And yet for all that, when they be in the land of their enemies, I will not cast them away, neither will I abhor them, to destroy them utterly, and to break my covenant with them: for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">But I will for their sakes remember the covenant of their ancestors, whom I brought forth out of the land of Egypt in the sight of the heathen, that I might be their God: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the statutes and judgments and laws, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made between him and the children of Israel in mount Sinai by the hand of Moses.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>