<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="30" nextChapter="leviticus_7.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 7" prevChapter="leviticus_5.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 5" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">If a soul sin, and commit a trespass against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and lie unto his neighbour in that which was delivered him to keep, or in fellowship, or in a thing taken away by violence, or hath deceived his neighbour;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Or have found that which was lost, and lieth concerning it, and sweareth falsely; in any of all these that a man doeth, sinning therein:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Then it shall be, because he hath sinned, and is guilty, that he shall restore that which he took violently away, or the thing which he hath deceitfully gotten, or that which was delivered him to keep, or the lost thing which he found,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Or all that about which he hath sworn falsely; he shall even restore it in the principal, and shall add the fifth part more thereto, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; give it unto him to whom it appertaineth, in the day of his trespass offering.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he shall bring his trespass offering unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, a ram without blemish out of the flock, with thy estimation, for a trespass offering, unto the priest:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the priest shall make an atonement for him before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and it shall be forgiven him for any thing of all that he hath done in trespassing therein.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Command Aaron and his sons, saying, This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law of the burnt offering: It &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the burnt offering, because of the burning upon the altar all night unto the morning, and the fire of the altar shall be burning in it.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the priest shall put on his linen garment, and his linen breeches shall he put upon his flesh, and take up the ashes which the fire hath consumed with the burnt offering on the altar, and he shall put them beside the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he shall put off his garments, and put on other garments, and carry forth the ashes without the camp unto a clean place.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the fire upon the altar shall be burning in it; it shall not be put out: and the priest shall burn wood on it every morning, and lay the burnt offering in order upon it; and he shall burn thereon the fat of the peace offerings.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The fire shall ever be burning upon the altar; it shall never go out.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law of the meat offering: the sons of Aaron shall offer it before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, before the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he shall take of it his handful, of the flour of the meat offering, and of the oil thereof, and all the frankincense which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the meat offering, and shall burn &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon the altar &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a sweet savour, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the memorial of it, unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the remainder thereof shall Aaron and his sons eat: with unleavened bread shall it be eaten in the holy place; in the court of the tabernacle of the congregation they shall eat it.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">It shall not be baken with leaven. I have given it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;unto them for&lt;/span&gt; their portion of my offerings made by fire; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; most holy, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the sin offering, and as the trespass offering.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">All the males among the children of Aaron shall eat of it. &lt;span class='extra'&gt;It shall be&lt;/span&gt; a statute for ever in your generations concerning the offerings of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made by fire: every one that toucheth them shall be holy.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the offering of Aaron and of his sons, which they shall offer unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the day when he is anointed; the tenth part of an ephah of fine flour for a meat offering perpetual, half of it in the morning, and half thereof at night.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">In a pan it shall be made with oil; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and when it is&lt;/span&gt; baken, thou shalt bring it in: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the baken pieces of the meat offering shalt thou offer &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a sweet savour unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the priest of his sons that is anointed in his stead shall offer it: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; a statute for ever unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; it shall be wholly burnt.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For every meat offering for the priest shall be wholly burnt: it shall not be eaten.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Speak unto Aaron and to his sons, saying, This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law of the sin offering: In the place where the burnt offering is killed shall the sin offering be killed before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; most holy.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The priest that offereth it for sin shall eat it: in the holy place shall it be eaten, in the court of the tabernacle of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Whatsoever shall touch the flesh thereof shall be holy: and when there is sprinkled of the blood thereof upon any garment, thou shalt wash that whereon it was sprinkled in the holy place.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">But the earthen vessel wherein it is sodden shall be broken: and if it be sodden in a brasen pot, it shall be both scoured, and rinsed in water.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">All the males among the priests shall eat thereof: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; most holy.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And no sin offering, whereof &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; of the blood is brought into the tabernacle of the congregation to reconcile &lt;span class='extra'&gt;withal&lt;/span&gt; in the holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;, shall be eaten: it shall be burnt in the fire.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>