<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="33" nextChapter="leviticus_23.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 23" prevChapter="leviticus_21.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 21" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto Aaron and to his sons, that they separate themselves from the holy things of the children of Israel, and that they profane not my holy name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in those things&lt;/span&gt; which they hallow unto me: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Say unto them, Whosoever &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he be&lt;/span&gt; of all your seed among your generations, that goeth unto the holy things, which the children of Israel hallow unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, having his uncleanness upon him, that soul shall be cut off from my presence: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">What man soever of the seed of Aaron &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a leper, or hath a running issue; he shall not eat of the holy things, until he be clean. And whoso toucheth any thing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; unclean &lt;span class="extra"&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; the dead, or a man whose seed goeth from him;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Or whosoever toucheth any creeping thing, whereby he may be made unclean, or a man of whom he may take uncleanness, whatsoever uncleanness he hath;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The soul which hath touched any such shall be unclean until even, and shall not eat of the holy things, unless he wash his flesh with water.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when the sun is down, he shall be clean, and shall afterward eat of the holy things; because it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his food.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">That which dieth of itself, or is torn &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with beasts&lt;/span&gt;, he shall not eat to defile himself therewith: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">They shall therefore keep mine ordinance, lest they bear sin for it, and die therefore, if they profane it: I the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; do sanctify them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">There shall no stranger eat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; the holy thing: a sojourner of the priest, or an hired servant, shall not eat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; the holy thing.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But if the priest buy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; soul with his money, he shall eat of it, and he that is born in his house: they shall eat of his meat.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">If the priest's daughter also be &lt;span class="extra"&gt;married&lt;/span&gt; unto a stranger, she may not eat of an offering of the holy things.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But if the priest's daughter be a widow, or divorced, and have no child, and is returned unto her father's house, as in her youth, she shall eat of her father's meat: but there shall no stranger eat thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And if a man eat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; the holy thing unwittingly, then he shall put the fifth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;part&lt;/span&gt; thereof unto it, and shall give &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; unto the priest with the holy thing.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And they shall not profane the holy things of the children of Israel, which they offer unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Or suffer them to bear the iniquity of trespass, when they eat their holy things: for I the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; do sanctify them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Speak unto Aaron, and to his sons, and unto all the children of Israel, and say unto them, Whatsoever &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he be&lt;/span&gt; of the house of Israel, or of the strangers in Israel, that will offer his oblation for all his vows, and for all his freewill offerings, which they will offer unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for a burnt offering;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Ye shall offer&lt;/span&gt; at your own will a male without blemish, of the beeves, of the sheep, or of the goats.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;But&lt;/span&gt; whatsoever hath a blemish, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shall ye not offer: for it shall not be acceptable for you.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And whosoever offereth a sacrifice of peace offerings unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to accomplish &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; vow, or a freewill offering in beeves or sheep, it shall be perfect to be accepted; there shall be no blemish therein.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Blind, or broken, or maimed, or having a wen, or scurvy, or scabbed, ye shall not offer these unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, nor make an offering by fire of them upon the altar unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Either a bullock or a lamb that hath any thing superfluous or lacking in his parts, that mayest thou offer &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a freewill offering; but for a vow it shall not be accepted.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Ye shall not offer unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that which is bruised, or crushed, or broken, or cut; neither shall ye make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any offering thereof&lt;/span&gt; in your land.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Neither from a stranger's hand shall ye offer the bread of your God of any of these; because their corruption &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in them, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; blemishes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in them: they shall not be accepted for you.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">When a bullock, or a sheep, or a goat, is brought forth, then it shall be seven days under the dam; and from the eighth day and thenceforth it shall be accepted for an offering made by fire unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;whether it be&lt;/span&gt; cow or ewe, ye shall not kill it and her young both in one day.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And when ye will offer a sacrifice of thanksgiving unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, offer &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; at your own will.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">On the same day it shall be eaten up; ye shall leave none of it until the morrow: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Therefore shall ye keep my commandments, and do them: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Neither shall ye profane my holy name; but I will be hallowed among the children of Israel: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which hallow you,</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">That brought you out of the land of Egypt, to be your God: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>