<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="35" nextChapter="leviticus_5.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 5" prevChapter="leviticus_3.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 3" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto the children of Israel, saying, If a soul shall sin through ignorance against any of the commandments of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;concerning things&lt;/span&gt; which ought not to be done, and shall do against any of them:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">If the priest that is anointed do sin according to the sin of the people; then let him bring for his sin, which he hath sinned, a young bullock without blemish unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for a sin offering.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he shall bring the bullock unto the door of the tabernacle of the congregation before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and shall lay his hand upon the bullock's head, and kill the bullock before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the priest that is anointed shall take of the bullock's blood, and bring it to the tabernacle of the congregation:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the priest shall dip his finger in the blood, and sprinkle of the blood seven times before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, before the vail of the sanctuary.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the priest shall put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of the blood upon the horns of the altar of sweet incense before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the tabernacle of the congregation; and shall pour all the blood of the bullock at the bottom of the altar of the burnt offering, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is at&lt;/span&gt; the door of the tabernacle of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he shall take off from it all the fat of the bullock for the sin offering; the fat that covereth the inwards, and all the fat that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the inwards,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the two kidneys, and the fat that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon them, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the flanks, and the caul above the liver, with the kidneys, it shall he take away,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">As it was taken off from the bullock of the sacrifice of peace offerings: and the priest shall burn them upon the altar of the burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the skin of the bullock, and all his flesh, with his head, and with his legs, and his inwards, and his dung,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Even the whole bullock shall he carry forth without the camp unto a clean place, where the ashes are poured out, and burn him on the wood with fire: where the ashes are poured out shall he be burnt.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And if the whole congregation of Israel sin through ignorance, and the thing be hid from the eyes of the assembly, and they have done &lt;span class="extra"&gt;somewhat against&lt;/span&gt; any of the commandments of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;concerning things&lt;/span&gt; which should not be done, and are guilty;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">When the sin, which they have sinned against it, is known, then the congregation shall offer a young bullock for the sin, and bring him before the tabernacle of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the elders of the congregation shall lay their hands upon the head of the bullock before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and the bullock shall be killed before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the priest that is anointed shall bring of the bullock's blood to the tabernacle of the congregation:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the priest shall dip his finger &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in some&lt;/span&gt; of the blood, and sprinkle &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; seven times before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; before the vail.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And he shall put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of the blood upon the horns of the altar which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the tabernacle of the congregation, and shall pour out all the blood at the bottom of the altar of the burnt offering, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is at&lt;/span&gt; the door of the tabernacle of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he shall take all his fat from him, and burn &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And he shall do with the bullock as he did with the bullock for a sin offering, so shall he do with this: and the priest shall make an atonement for them, and it shall be forgiven them.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he shall carry forth the bullock without the camp, and burn him as he burned the first bullock: it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a sin offering for the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">When a ruler hath sinned, and done &lt;span class="extra"&gt;somewhat&lt;/span&gt; through ignorance &lt;span class="extra"&gt;against&lt;/span&gt; any of the commandments of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;concerning things&lt;/span&gt; which should not be done, and is guilty;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Or if his sin, wherein he hath sinned, come to his knowledge; he shall bring his offering, a kid of the goats, a male without blemish:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And he shall lay his hand upon the head of the goat, and kill it in the place where they kill the burnt offering before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a sin offering.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the priest shall take of the blood of the sin offering with his finger, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon the horns of the altar of burnt offering, and shall pour out his blood at the bottom of the altar of burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And he shall burn all his fat upon the altar, as the fat of the sacrifice of peace offerings: and the priest shall make an atonement for him as concerning his sin, and it shall be forgiven him.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And if any one of the common people sin through ignorance, while he doeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;somewhat against&lt;/span&gt; any of the commandments of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;concerning things&lt;/span&gt; which ought not to be done, and be guilty;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Or if his sin, which he hath sinned, come to his knowledge: then he shall bring his offering, a kid of the goats, a female without blemish, for his sin which he hath sinned.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And he shall lay his hand upon the head of the sin offering, and slay the sin offering in the place of the burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the priest shall take of the blood thereof with his finger, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon the horns of the altar of burnt offering, and shall pour out all the blood thereof at the bottom of the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And he shall take away all the fat thereof, as the fat is taken away from off the sacrifice of peace offerings; and the priest shall burn &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon the altar for a sweet savour unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and the priest shall make an atonement for him, and it shall be forgiven him.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And if he bring a lamb for a sin offering, he shall bring it a female without blemish.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And he shall lay his hand upon the head of the sin offering, and slay it for a sin offering in the place where they kill the burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And the priest shall take of the blood of the sin offering with his finger, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon the horns of the altar of burnt offering, and shall pour out all the blood thereof at the bottom of the altar:</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And he shall take away all the fat thereof, as the fat of the lamb is taken away from the sacrifice of the peace offerings; and the priest shall burn them upon the altar, according to the offerings made by fire unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and the priest shall make an atonement for his sin that he hath committed, and it shall be forgiven him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>