<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="59" nextChapter="leviticus_14.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 14" prevChapter="leviticus_12.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 12" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses and Aaron, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">When a man shall have in the skin of his flesh a rising, a scab, or bright spot, and it be in the skin of his flesh &lt;span class='extra'&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; the plague of leprosy; then he shall be brought unto Aaron the priest, or unto one of his sons the priests:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the priest shall look on the plague in the skin of the flesh: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; the hair in the plague is turned white, and the plague in sight &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; deeper than the skin of his flesh, it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a plague of leprosy: and the priest shall look on him, and pronounce him unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">If the bright spot &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; white in the skin of his flesh, and in sight &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; not deeper than the skin, and the hair thereof be not turned white; then the priest shall shut up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him that hath&lt;/span&gt; the plague seven days:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the priest shall look on him the seventh day: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the plague in his sight be at a stay, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the plague spread not in the skin; then the priest shall shut him up seven days more:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the priest shall look on him again the seventh day: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the plague &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; somewhat dark, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the plague spread not in the skin, the priest shall pronounce him clean: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is but&lt;/span&gt; a scab: and he shall wash his clothes, and be clean.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But if the scab spread much abroad in the skin, after that he hath been seen of the priest for his cleansing, he shall be seen of the priest again:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the priest see that, behold, the scab spreadeth in the skin, then the priest shall pronounce him unclean: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a leprosy.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">When the plague of leprosy is in a man, then he shall be brought unto the priest;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the priest shall see &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the rising &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; white in the skin, and it have turned the hair white, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; quick raw flesh in the rising;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">It &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an old leprosy in the skin of his flesh, and the priest shall pronounce him unclean, and shall not shut him up: for he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And if a leprosy break out abroad in the skin, and the leprosy cover all the skin of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him that hath&lt;/span&gt; the plague from his head even to his foot, wheresoever the priest looketh;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then the priest shall consider: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the leprosy have covered all his flesh, he shall pronounce &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; clean &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that hath&lt;/span&gt; the plague: it is all turned white: he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; clean.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But when raw flesh appeareth in him, he shall be unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the priest shall see the raw flesh, and pronounce him to be unclean: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the raw flesh &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a leprosy.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Or if the raw flesh turn again, and be changed unto white, he shall come unto the priest;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the priest shall see him: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the plague be turned into white; then the priest shall pronounce &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; clean &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that hath&lt;/span&gt; the plague: he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; clean.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">The flesh also, in which, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; in the skin thereof, was a boil, and is healed,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And in the place of the boil there be a white rising, or a bright spot, white, and somewhat reddish, and it be shewed to the priest;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And if, when the priest seeth it, behold, it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in sight lower than the skin, and the hair thereof be turned white; the priest shall pronounce him unclean: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a plague of leprosy broken out of the boil.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But if the priest look on it, and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; no white hairs therein, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; not lower than the skin, but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; somewhat dark; then the priest shall shut him up seven days:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And if it spread much abroad in the skin, then the priest shall pronounce him unclean: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a plague.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But if the bright spot stay in his place, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; spread not, it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a burning boil; and the priest shall pronounce him clean.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">Or if there be &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; flesh, in the skin whereof &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; a hot burning, and the quick &lt;span class='extra'&gt;flesh&lt;/span&gt; that burneth have a white bright spot, somewhat reddish, or white;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then the priest shall look upon it: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the hair in the bright spot be turned white, and it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be in&lt;/span&gt; sight deeper than the skin; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a leprosy broken out of the burning: wherefore the priest shall pronounce him unclean: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the plague of leprosy.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">But if the priest look on it, and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; no white hair in the bright spot, and it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; no lower than the &lt;span class='extra'&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; skin, but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; somewhat dark; then the priest shall shut him up seven days:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And the priest shall look upon him the seventh day: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; if it be spread much abroad in the skin, then the priest shall pronounce him unclean: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the plague of leprosy.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And if the bright spot stay in his place, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; spread not in the skin, but it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; somewhat dark; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a rising of the burning, and the priest shall pronounce him clean: for it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an inflammation of the burning.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">If a man or woman have a plague upon the head or the beard;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Then the priest shall see the plague: and, behold, if it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in sight deeper than the skin; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and there be&lt;/span&gt; in it a yellow thin hair; then the priest shall pronounce him unclean: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a dry scall, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; a leprosy upon the head or beard.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And if the priest look on the plague of the scall, and, behold, it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; not in sight deeper than the skin, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that there is&lt;/span&gt; no black hair in it; then the priest shall shut up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him that hath&lt;/span&gt; the plague of the scall seven days:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And in the seventh day the priest shall look on the plague: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the scall spread not, and there be in it no yellow hair, and the scall &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; not in sight deeper than the skin;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">He shall be shaven, but the scall shall he not shave; and the priest shall shut up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him that hath&lt;/span&gt; the scall seven days more:</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And in the seventh day the priest shall look on the scall: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the scall be not spread in the skin, nor &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in sight deeper than the skin; then the priest shall pronounce him clean: and he shall wash his clothes, and be clean.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">But if the scall spread much in the skin after his cleansing;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Then the priest shall look on him: and, behold, if the scall be spread in the skin, the priest shall not seek for yellow hair; he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">But if the scall be in his sight at a stay, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; there is black hair grown up therein; the scall is healed, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; clean: and the priest shall pronounce him clean.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38" newPara="true">If a man also or a woman have in the skin of their flesh bright spots, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; white bright spots;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Then the priest shall look: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the bright spots in the skin of their flesh &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; darkish white; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a freckled spot &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; groweth in the skin; he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; clean.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And the man whose hair is fallen off his head, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; bald; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;yet is&lt;/span&gt; he clean.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And he that hath his hair fallen off from the part of his head toward his face, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; forehead bald: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;yet is&lt;/span&gt; he clean.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And if there be in the bald head, or bald forehead, a white reddish sore; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a leprosy sprung up in his bald head, or his bald forehead.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Then the priest shall look upon it: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the rising of the sore &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; white reddish in his bald head, or in his bald forehead, as the leprosy appeareth in the skin of the flesh;</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">He is a leprous man, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean: the priest shall pronounce him utterly unclean; his plague &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in his head.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And the leper in whom the plague &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;, his clothes shall be rent, and his head bare, and he shall put a covering upon his upper lip, and shall cry, Unclean, unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">All the days wherein the plague &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; in him he shall be defiled; he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean: he shall dwell alone; without the camp &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall&lt;/span&gt; his habitation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47" newPara="true">The garment also that the plague of leprosy is in, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;whether it be&lt;/span&gt; a woollen garment, or a linen garment;</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">Whether &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt; in the warp, or woof; of linen, or of woollen; whether in a skin, or in any thing made of skin;</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And if the plague be greenish or reddish in the garment, or in the skin, either in the warp, or in the woof, or in any thing of skin; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a plague of leprosy, and shall be shewed unto the priest:</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">And the priest shall look upon the plague, and shut up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it that hath&lt;/span&gt; the plague seven days:</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And he shall look on the plague on the seventh day: if the plague be spread in the garment, either in the warp, or in the woof, or in a skin, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; in any work that is made of skin; the plague &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a fretting leprosy; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">He shall therefore burn that garment, whether warp or woof, in woollen or in linen, or any thing of skin, wherein the plague is: for it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a fretting leprosy; it shall be burnt in the fire.</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">And if the priest shall look, and, behold, the plague be not spread in the garment, either in the warp, or in the woof, or in any thing of skin;</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">Then the priest shall command that they wash &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the thing&lt;/span&gt; wherein the plague &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;, and he shall shut it up seven days more:</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">And the priest shall look on the plague, after that it is washed: and, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the plague have not changed his colour, and the plague be not spread; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unclean; thou shalt burn it in the fire; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; fret inward, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;whether&lt;/span&gt; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; bare within or without.</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">And if the priest look, and, behold, the plague &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; somewhat dark after the washing of it; then he shall rend it out of the garment, or out of the skin, or out of the warp, or out of the woof:</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">And if it appear still in the garment, either in the warp, or in the woof, or in any thing of skin; it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a spreading &lt;span class='extra'&gt;plague&lt;/span&gt;: thou shalt burn that wherein the plague &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">And the garment, either warp, or woof, or whatsoever thing of skin &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt;, which thou shalt wash, if the plague be departed from them, then it shall be washed the second time, and shall be clean.</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law of the plague of leprosy in a garment of woollen or linen, either in the warp, or woof, or any thing of skins, to pronounce it clean, or to pronounce it unclean.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>