<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="24" verseCount="23" nextChapter="leviticus_25.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 25" prevChapter="leviticus_23.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 23" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Command the children of Israel, that they bring unto thee pure oil olive beaten for the light, to cause the lamps to burn continually.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Without the vail of the testimony, in the tabernacle of the congregation, shall Aaron order it from the evening unto the morning before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; continually: &lt;i&gt;it shall be&lt;/i&gt; a statute for ever in your generations.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He shall order the lamps upon the pure candlestick before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; continually.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And thou shalt take fine flour, and bake twelve cakes thereof: two tenth deals shall be in one cake.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And thou shalt set them in two rows, six on a row, upon the pure table before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And thou shalt put pure frankincense upon &lt;i&gt;each&lt;/i&gt; row, that it may be on the bread for a memorial, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; an offering made by fire unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Every sabbath he shall set it in order before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; continually, &lt;i&gt;being taken&lt;/i&gt; from the children of Israel by an everlasting covenant.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And it shall be Aaron's and his sons'; and they shall eat it in the holy place: for it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; most holy unto him of the offerings of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made by fire by a perpetual statute.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And the son of an Israelitish woman, whose father &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; an Egyptian, went out among the children of Israel: and this son of the Israelitish &lt;i&gt;woman&lt;/i&gt; and a man of Israel strove together in the camp;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the Israelitish woman's son blasphemed the name &lt;i&gt;of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, and cursed. And they brought him unto Moses: (and his mother's name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Shelomith, the daughter of Dibri, of the tribe of Dan:)</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And they put him in ward, that the mind of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; might be shewed them.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Bring forth him that hath cursed without the camp; and let all that heard &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; lay their hands upon his head, and let all the congregation stone him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And thou shalt speak unto the children of Israel, saying, Whosoever curseth his God shall bear his sin.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he that blasphemeth the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, he shall surely be put to death, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; all the congregation shall certainly stone him: as well the stranger, as he that is born in the land, when he blasphemeth the name &lt;i&gt;of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, shall be put to death.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And he that killeth any man shall surely be put to death.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And he that killeth a beast shall make it good; beast for beast.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And if a man cause a blemish in his neighbour; as he hath done, so shall it be done to him;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Breach for breach, eye for eye, tooth for tooth: as he hath caused a blemish in a man, so shall it be done to him &lt;i&gt;again&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he that killeth a beast, he shall restore it: and he that killeth a man, he shall be put to death.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Ye shall have one manner of law, as well for the stranger, as for one of your own country: for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And Moses spake to the children of Israel, that they should bring forth him that had cursed out of the camp, and stone him with stones. And the children of Israel did as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>