<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="24" nextChapter="leviticus_10.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 10" prevChapter="leviticus_8.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 8" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass on the eighth day, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; Moses called Aaron and his sons, and the elders of Israel;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he said unto Aaron, Take thee a young calf for a sin offering, and a ram for a burnt offering, without blemish, and offer &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And unto the children of Israel thou shalt speak, saying, Take ye a kid of the goats for a sin offering; and a calf and a lamb, &lt;i&gt;both&lt;/i&gt; of the first year, without blemish, for a burnt offering;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Also a bullock and a ram for peace offerings, to sacrifice before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and a meat offering mingled with oil: for to day the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will appear unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And they brought &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; which Moses commanded before the tabernacle of the congregation: and all the congregation drew near and stood before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Moses said, This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the thing which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded that ye should do: and the glory of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall appear unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Moses said unto Aaron, Go unto the altar, and offer thy sin offering, and thy burnt offering, and make an atonement for thyself, and for the people: and offer the offering of the people, and make an atonement for them; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Aaron therefore went unto the altar, and slew the calf of the sin offering, which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; for himself.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the sons of Aaron brought the blood unto him: and he dipped his finger in the blood, and put &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; upon the horns of the altar, and poured out the blood at the bottom of the altar:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But the fat, and the kidneys, and the caul above the liver of the sin offering, he burnt upon the altar; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the flesh and the hide he burnt with fire without the camp.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he slew the burnt offering; and Aaron's sons presented unto him the blood, which he sprinkled round about upon the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And they presented the burnt offering unto him, with the pieces thereof, and the head: and he burnt &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; upon the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he did wash the inwards and the legs, and burnt &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; upon the burnt offering on the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And he brought the people's offering, and took the goat, which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the sin offering for the people, and slew it, and offered it for sin, as the first.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he brought the burnt offering, and offered it according to the manner.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he brought the meat offering, and took an handful thereof, and burnt &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; upon the altar, beside the burnt sacrifice of the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He slew also the bullock and the ram &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a sacrifice of peace offerings, which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; for the people: and Aaron's sons presented unto him the blood, which he sprinkled upon the altar round about,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the fat of the bullock and of the ram, the rump, and that which covereth &lt;i&gt;the inwards&lt;/i&gt;, and the kidneys, and the caul &lt;i&gt;above&lt;/i&gt; the liver:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And they put the fat upon the breasts, and he burnt the fat upon the altar:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the breasts and the right shoulder Aaron waved &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a wave offering before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; as Moses commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Aaron lifted up his hand toward the people, and blessed them, and came down from offering of the sin offering, and the burnt offering, and peace offerings.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Moses and Aaron went into the tabernacle of the congregation, and came out, and blessed the people: and the glory of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared unto all the people.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And there came a fire out from before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and consumed upon the altar the burnt offering and the fat: &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; when all the people saw, they shouted, and fell on their faces.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>