<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="38" nextChapter="leviticus_8.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 8" prevChapter="leviticus_6.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 6" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Likewise this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the law of the trespass offering: it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; most holy.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">In the place where they kill the burnt offering shall they kill the trespass offering: and the blood thereof shall he sprinkle round about upon the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he shall offer of it all the fat thereof; the rump, and the fat that covereth the inwards,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the two kidneys, and the fat that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; on them, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; by the flanks, and the caul &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; above the liver, with the kidneys, it shall he take away:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the priest shall burn them upon the altar &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an offering made by fire unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a trespass offering.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Every male among the priests shall eat thereof: it shall be eaten in the holy place: it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; most holy.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">As the sin offering &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt;, so &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the trespass offering: &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; one law for them: the priest that maketh atonement therewith shall have &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the priest that offereth any man's burnt offering, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the priest shall have to himself the skin of the burnt offering which he hath offered.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And all the meat offering that is baken in the oven, and all that is dressed in the fryingpan, and in the pan, shall be the priest's that offereth it.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And every meat offering, mingled with oil, and dry, shall all the sons of Aaron have, one &lt;i&gt;as much&lt;/i&gt; as another.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the law of the sacrifice of peace offerings, which he shall offer unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">If he offer it for a thanksgiving, then he shall offer with the sacrifice of thanksgiving unleavened cakes mingled with oil, and unleavened wafers anointed with oil, and cakes mingled with oil, of fine flour, fried.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Besides the cakes, he shall offer &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; his offering leavened bread with the sacrifice of thanksgiving of his peace offerings.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And of it he shall offer one out of the whole oblation &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an heave offering unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; it shall be the priest's that sprinkleth the blood of the peace offerings.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the flesh of the sacrifice of his peace offerings for thanksgiving shall be eaten the same day that it is offered; he shall not leave any of it until the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But if the sacrifice of his offering &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; a vow, or a voluntary offering, it shall be eaten the same day that he offereth his sacrifice: and on the morrow also the remainder of it shall be eaten:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But the remainder of the flesh of the sacrifice on the third day shall be burnt with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And if &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; of the flesh of the sacrifice of his peace offerings be eaten at all on the third day, it shall not be accepted, neither shall it be imputed unto him that offereth it: it shall be an abomination, and the soul that eateth of it shall bear his iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the flesh that toucheth any unclean &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; shall not be eaten; it shall be burnt with fire: and as for the flesh, all that be clean shall eat thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But the soul that eateth &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; the flesh of the sacrifice of peace offerings, that &lt;i&gt;pertain&lt;/i&gt; unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, having his uncleanness upon him, even that soul shall be cut off from his people.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Moreover the soul that shall touch any unclean &lt;i&gt;thing, as&lt;/i&gt; the uncleanness of man, or &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; unclean beast, or any abominable unclean &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt;, and eat of the flesh of the sacrifice of peace offerings, which &lt;i&gt;pertain&lt;/i&gt; unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, even that soul shall be cut off from his people.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Speak unto the children of Israel, saying, Ye shall eat no manner of fat, of ox, or of sheep, or of goat.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the fat of the beast that dieth of itself, and the fat of that which is torn with beasts, may be used in any other use: but ye shall in no wise eat of it.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For whosoever eateth the fat of the beast, of which men offer an offering made by fire unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, even the soul that eateth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; shall be cut off from his people.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Moreover ye shall eat no manner of blood, &lt;i&gt;whether it be&lt;/i&gt; of fowl or of beast, in any of your dwellings.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Whatsoever soul &lt;i&gt;it be&lt;/i&gt; that eateth any manner of blood, even that soul shall be cut off from his people.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Speak unto the children of Israel, saying, He that offereth the sacrifice of his peace offerings unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall bring his oblation unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of the sacrifice of his peace offerings.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">His own hands shall bring the offerings of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made by fire, the fat with the breast, it shall he bring, that the breast may be waved &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a wave offering before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And the priest shall burn the fat upon the altar: but the breast shall be Aaron's and his sons'.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And the right shoulder shall ye give unto the priest &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an heave offering of the sacrifices of your peace offerings.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">He among the sons of Aaron, that offereth the blood of the peace offerings, and the fat, shall have the right shoulder for &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; part.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">For the wave breast and the heave shoulder have I taken of the children of Israel from off the sacrifices of their peace offerings, and have given them unto Aaron the priest and unto his sons by a statute for ever from among the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35" newPara="true">This &lt;i&gt;is the portion&lt;/i&gt; of the anointing of Aaron, and of the anointing of his sons, out of the offerings of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made by fire, in the day &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; he presented them to minister unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the priest's office;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded to be given them of the children of Israel, in the day that he anointed them, &lt;i&gt;by&lt;/i&gt; a statute for ever throughout their generations.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the law of the burnt offering, of the meat offering, and of the sin offering, and of the trespass offering, and of the consecrations, and of the sacrifice of the peace offerings;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">Which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses in mount Sinai, in the day that he commanded the children of Israel to offer their oblations unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in the wilderness of Sinai.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>