<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="30" nextChapter="leviticus_19.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 19" prevChapter="leviticus_17.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 17" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto the children of Israel, and say unto them, I am the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">After the doings of the land of Egypt, wherein ye dwelt, shall ye not do: and after the doings of the land of Canaan, whither I bring you, shall ye not do: neither shall ye walk in their ordinances.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Ye shall do my judgments, and keep mine ordinances, to walk therein: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Ye shall therefore keep my statutes, and my judgments: which if a man do, he shall live in them: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">None of you shall approach to any that is near of kin to him, to uncover &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; nakedness: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The nakedness of thy father, or the nakedness of thy mother, shalt thou not uncover: she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy mother; thou shalt not uncover her nakedness.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The nakedness of thy father's wife shalt thou not uncover: it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy father's nakedness.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The nakedness of thy sister, the daughter of thy father, or daughter of thy mother, &lt;i&gt;whether she be&lt;/i&gt; born at home, or born abroad, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; their nakedness thou shalt not uncover.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The nakedness of thy son's daughter, or of thy daughter's daughter, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; their nakedness thou shalt not uncover: for theirs &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thine own nakedness.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The nakedness of thy father's wife's daughter, begotten of thy father, she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy sister, thou shalt not uncover her nakedness.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Thou shalt not uncover the nakedness of thy father's sister: she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy father's near kinswoman.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thou shalt not uncover the nakedness of thy mother's sister: for she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy mother's near kinswoman.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou shalt not uncover the nakedness of thy father's brother, thou shalt not approach to his wife: she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thine aunt.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Thou shalt not uncover the nakedness of thy daughter in law: she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy son's wife; thou shalt not uncover her nakedness.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thou shalt not uncover the nakedness of thy brother's wife: it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy brother's nakedness.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thou shalt not uncover the nakedness of a woman and her daughter, neither shalt thou take her son's daughter, or her daughter's daughter, to uncover her nakedness; &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; her near kinswomen: it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; wickedness.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Neither shalt thou take a wife to her sister, to vex &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt;, to uncover her nakedness, beside the other in her life &lt;i&gt;time&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Also thou shalt not approach unto a woman to uncover her nakedness, as long as she is put apart for her uncleanness.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Moreover thou shalt not lie carnally with thy neighbour's wife, to defile thyself with her.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And thou shalt not let any of thy seed pass through &lt;i&gt;the fire&lt;/i&gt; to Molech, neither shalt thou profane the name of thy God: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Thou shalt not lie with mankind, as with womankind: it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; abomination.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Neither shalt thou lie with any beast to defile thyself therewith: neither shall any woman stand before a beast to lie down thereto: it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; confusion.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Defile not ye yourselves in any of these things: for in all these the nations are defiled which I cast out before you:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the land is defiled: therefore I do visit the iniquity thereof upon it, and the land itself vomiteth out her inhabitants.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Ye shall therefore keep my statutes and my judgments, and shall not commit &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; of these abominations; &lt;i&gt;neither&lt;/i&gt; any of your own nation, nor any stranger that sojourneth among you:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">(For all these abominations have the men of the land done, which &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; before you, and the land is defiled;)</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">That the land spue not you out also, when ye defile it, as it spued out the nations that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; before you.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For whosoever shall commit any of these abominations, even the souls that commit &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; shall be cut off from among their people.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Therefore shall ye keep mine ordinance, that &lt;i&gt;ye&lt;/i&gt; commit not &lt;i&gt;any one&lt;/i&gt; of these abominable customs, which were committed before you, and that ye defile not yourselves therein: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>