<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="17" nextChapter="leviticus_4.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 4" prevChapter="leviticus_2.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 2" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And if his oblation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; a sacrifice of peace offering, if he offer &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; of the herd; whether &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt; a male or female, he shall offer it without blemish before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he shall lay his hand upon the head of his offering, and kill it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; the door of the tabernacle of the congregation: and Aaron's sons the priests shall sprinkle the blood upon the altar round about.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he shall offer of the sacrifice of the peace offering an offering made by fire unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; the fat that covereth the inwards, and all the fat that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the inwards,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the two kidneys, and the fat that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; on them, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the flanks, and the caul above the liver, with the kidneys, it shall he take away.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Aaron's sons shall burn it on the altar upon the burnt sacrifice, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the wood that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; on the fire: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; an offering made by fire, of a sweet savour unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And if his offering for a sacrifice of peace offering unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; of the flock; male or female, he shall offer it without blemish.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">If he offer a lamb for his offering, then shall he offer it before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he shall lay his hand upon the head of his offering, and kill it before the tabernacle of the congregation: and Aaron's sons shall sprinkle the blood thereof round about upon the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he shall offer of the sacrifice of the peace offering an offering made by fire unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; the fat thereof, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the whole rump, it shall he take off hard by the backbone; and the fat that covereth the inwards, and all the fat that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the inwards,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the two kidneys, and the fat that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon them, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the flanks, and the caul above the liver, with the kidneys, it shall he take away.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the priest shall burn it upon the altar: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; the food of the offering made by fire unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And if his offering &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; a goat, then he shall offer it before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he shall lay his hand upon the head of it, and kill it before the tabernacle of the congregation: and the sons of Aaron shall sprinkle the blood thereof upon the altar round about.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he shall offer thereof his offering, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; an offering made by fire unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; the fat that covereth the inwards, and all the fat that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the inwards,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the two kidneys, and the fat that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon them, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the flanks, and the caul above the liver, with the kidneys, it shall he take away.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the priest shall burn them upon the altar: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; the food of the offering made by fire for a sweet savour: all the fat &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;It shall be&lt;/span&gt; a perpetual statute for your generations throughout all your dwellings, that ye eat neither fat nor blood.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>