<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="16" nextChapter="leviticus_3.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 3" prevChapter="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 1" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And when any will offer a meat offering unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, his offering shall be &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; fine flour; and he shall pour oil upon it, and put frankincense thereon:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he shall bring it to Aaron's sons the priests: and he shall take thereout his handful of the flour thereof, and of the oil thereof, with all the frankincense thereof; and the priest shall burn the memorial of it upon the altar, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; an offering made by fire, of a sweet savour unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the remnant of the meat offering &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; Aaron's and his sons': &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; a thing most holy of the offerings of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made by fire.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And if thou bring an oblation of a meat offering baken in the oven, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it shall be&lt;/span&gt; unleavened cakes of fine flour mingled with oil, or unleavened wafers anointed with oil.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And if thy oblation &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; a meat offering &lt;span class="extra"&gt;baken&lt;/span&gt; in a pan, it shall be &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; fine flour unleavened, mingled with oil.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thou shalt part it in pieces, and pour oil thereon: it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a meat offering.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And if thy oblation &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; a meat offering &lt;span class="extra"&gt;baken&lt;/span&gt; in the fryingpan, it shall be made &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; fine flour with oil.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And thou shalt bring the meat offering that is made of these things unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and when it is presented unto the priest, he shall bring it unto the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the priest shall take from the meat offering a memorial thereof, and shall burn &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon the altar: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; an offering made by fire, of a sweet savour unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And that which is left of the meat offering &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; Aaron's and his sons': &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; a thing most holy of the offerings of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made by fire.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">No meat offering, which ye shall bring unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, shall be made with leaven: for ye shall burn no leaven, nor any honey, in any offering of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made by fire.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">As for the oblation of the firstfruits, ye shall offer them unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but they shall not be burnt on the altar for a sweet savour.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And every oblation of thy meat offering shalt thou season with salt; neither shalt thou suffer the salt of the covenant of thy God to be lacking from thy meat offering: with all thine offerings thou shalt offer salt.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And if thou offer a meat offering of thy firstfruits unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou shalt offer for the meat offering of thy firstfruits green ears of corn dried by the fire, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; corn beaten out of full ears.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And thou shalt put oil upon it, and lay frankincense thereon: it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a meat offering.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the priest shall burn the memorial of it, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;part&lt;/span&gt; of the beaten corn thereof, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;part&lt;/span&gt; of the oil thereof, with all the frankincense thereof: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; an offering made by fire unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>