<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="3" name="Leviticus" bookPage="leviticus.html" title="Leviticus" chapterCount="27" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="numbers_1.html" nextTitle="Numbers" prevBook="exodus_1.html" prevTitle="Exodus">
    <chapter number="19" verseCount="37" nextChapter="leviticus_20.html" nextTitle="Leviticus 20" prevChapter="leviticus_18.html" prevTitle="Leviticus 18" chapterPage="leviticus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto all the congregation of the children of Israel, and say unto them, Ye shall be holy: for I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; holy.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Ye shall fear every man his mother, and his father, and keep my sabbaths: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Turn ye not unto idols, nor make to yourselves molten gods: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And if ye offer a sacrifice of peace offerings unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, ye shall offer it at your own will.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">It shall be eaten the same day ye offer it, and on the morrow: and if ought remain until the third day, it shall be burnt in the fire.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And if it be eaten at all on the third day, it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; abominable; it shall not be accepted.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Therefore &lt;i&gt;every one&lt;/i&gt; that eateth it shall bear his iniquity, because he hath profaned the hallowed thing of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and that soul shall be cut off from among his people.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And when ye reap the harvest of your land, thou shalt not wholly reap the corners of thy field, neither shalt thou gather the gleanings of thy harvest.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And thou shalt not glean thy vineyard, neither shalt thou gather &lt;i&gt;every&lt;/i&gt; grape of thy vineyard; thou shalt leave them for the poor and stranger: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Ye shall not steal, neither deal falsely, neither lie one to another.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And ye shall not swear by my name falsely, neither shalt thou profane the name of thy God: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Thou shalt not defraud thy neighbour, neither rob &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;: the wages of him that is hired shall not abide with thee all night until the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Thou shalt not curse the deaf, nor put a stumblingblock before the blind, but shalt fear thy God: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Ye shall do no unrighteousness in judgment: thou shalt not respect the person of the poor, nor honour the person of the mighty: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; in righteousness shalt thou judge thy neighbour.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Thou shalt not go up and down &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; a talebearer among thy people: neither shalt thou stand against the blood of thy neighbour: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Thou shalt not hate thy brother in thine heart: thou shalt in any wise rebuke thy neighbour, and not suffer sin upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Thou shalt not avenge, nor bear any grudge against the children of thy people, but thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">Ye shall keep my statutes. Thou shalt not let thy cattle gender with a diverse kind: thou shalt not sow thy field with mingled seed: neither shall a garment mingled of linen and woollen come upon thee.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And whosoever lieth carnally with a woman, that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a bondmaid, betrothed to an husband, and not at all redeemed, nor freedom given her; she shall be scourged; they shall not be put to death, because she was not free.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he shall bring his trespass offering unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, unto the door of the tabernacle of the congregation, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; a ram for a trespass offering.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the priest shall make an atonement for him with the ram of the trespass offering before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for his sin which he hath done: and the sin which he hath done shall be forgiven him.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And when ye shall come into the land, and shall have planted all manner of trees for food, then ye shall count the fruit thereof as uncircumcised: three years shall it be as uncircumcised unto you: it shall not be eaten of.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But in the fourth year all the fruit thereof shall be holy to praise the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;withal&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And in the fifth year shall ye eat of the fruit thereof, that it may yield unto you the increase thereof: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">Ye shall not eat &lt;i&gt;any thing&lt;/i&gt; with the blood: neither shall ye use enchantment, nor observe times.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Ye shall not round the corners of your heads, neither shalt thou mar the corners of thy beard.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Ye shall not make any cuttings in your flesh for the dead, nor print any marks upon you: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">Do not prostitute thy daughter, to cause her to be a whore; lest the land fall to whoredom, and the land become full of wickedness.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">Ye shall keep my sabbaths, and reverence my sanctuary: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">Regard not them that have familiar spirits, neither seek after wizards, to be defiled by them: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">Thou shalt rise up before the hoary head, and honour the face of the old man, and fear thy God: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">And if a stranger sojourn with thee in your land, ye shall not vex him.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">&lt;i&gt;But&lt;/i&gt; the stranger that dwelleth with you shall be unto you as one born among you, and thou shalt love him as thyself; for ye were strangers in the land of Egypt: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35" newPara="true">Ye shall do no unrighteousness in judgment, in meteyard, in weight, or in measure.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Just balances, just weights, a just ephah, and a just hin, shall ye have: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, which brought you out of the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Therefore shall ye observe all my statutes, and all my judgments, and do them: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>