<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="41" nextChapter="numbers_23.html" nextTitle="Numbers 23" prevChapter="numbers_21.html" prevTitle="Numbers 21" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the children of Israel set forward, and pitched in the plains of Moab on this side Jordan &lt;i&gt;by&lt;/i&gt; Jericho.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">And Balak the son of Zippor saw all that Israel had done to the Amorites.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Moab was sore afraid of the people, because they &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; many: and Moab was distressed because of the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Moab said unto the elders of Midian, Now shall this company lick up all &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; round about us, as the ox licketh up the grass of the field. And Balak the son of Zippor &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; king of the Moabites at that time.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">He sent messengers therefore unto Balaam the son of Beor to Pethor, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; by the river of the land of the children of his people, to call him, saying, Behold, there is a people come out from Egypt: behold, they cover the face of the earth, and they abide over against me:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Come now therefore, I pray thee, curse me this people; for they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; too mighty for me: peradventure I shall prevail, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; we may smite them, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I may drive them out of the land: for I wot that he whom thou blessest &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; blessed, and he whom thou cursest is cursed.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the elders of Moab and the elders of Midian departed with the rewards of divination in their hand; and they came unto Balaam, and spake unto him the words of Balak.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he said unto them, Lodge here this night, and I will bring you word again, as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall speak unto me: and the princes of Moab abode with Balaam.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And God came unto Balaam, and said, What men &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; these with thee?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Balaam said unto God, Balak the son of Zippor, king of Moab, hath sent unto me, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Behold, &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; a people come out of Egypt, which covereth the face of the earth: come now, curse me them; peradventure I shall be able to overcome them, and drive them out.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And God said unto Balaam, Thou shalt not go with them; thou shalt not curse the people: for they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; blessed.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Balaam rose up in the morning, and said unto the princes of Balak, Get you into your land: for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; refuseth to give me leave to go with you.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the princes of Moab rose up, and they went unto Balak, and said, Balaam refuseth to come with us.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And Balak sent yet again princes, more, and more honourable than they.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And they came to Balaam, and said to him, Thus saith Balak the son of Zippor, Let nothing, I pray thee, hinder thee from coming unto me:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For I will promote thee unto very great honour, and I will do whatsoever thou sayest unto me: come therefore, I pray thee, curse me this people.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Balaam answered and said unto the servants of Balak, If Balak would give me his house full of silver and gold, I cannot go beyond the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, to do less or more.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Now therefore, I pray you, tarry ye also here this night, that I may know what the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will say unto me more.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And God came unto Balaam at night, and said unto him, If the men come to call thee, rise up, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; go with them; but yet the word which I shall say unto thee, that shalt thou do.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Balaam rose up in the morning, and saddled his ass, and went with the princes of Moab.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And God's anger was kindled because he went: and the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; stood in the way for an adversary against him. Now he was riding upon his ass, and his two servants &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the ass saw the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; standing in the way, and his sword drawn in his hand: and the ass turned aside out of the way, and went into the field: and Balaam smote the ass, to turn her into the way.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; stood in a path of the vineyards, a wall &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; on this side, and a wall on that side.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And when the ass saw the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, she thrust herself unto the wall, and crushed Balaam's foot against the wall: and he smote her again.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; went further, and stood in a narrow place, where &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; no way to turn either to the right hand or to the left.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And when the ass saw the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, she fell down under Balaam: and Balaam's anger was kindled, and he smote the ass with a staff.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; opened the mouth of the ass, and she said unto Balaam, What have I done unto thee, that thou hast smitten me these three times?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Balaam said unto the ass, Because thou hast mocked me: I would there were a sword in mine hand, for now would I kill thee.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the ass said unto Balaam, &lt;i&gt;Am&lt;/i&gt; not I thine ass, upon which thou hast ridden ever since &lt;i&gt;I was&lt;/i&gt; thine unto this day? was I ever wont to do so unto thee? And he said, Nay.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Then the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; opened the eyes of Balaam, and he saw the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; standing in the way, and his sword drawn in his hand: and he bowed down his head, and fell flat on his face.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, Wherefore hast thou smitten thine ass these three times? behold, I went out to withstand thee, because &lt;i&gt;thy&lt;/i&gt; way is perverse before me:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And the ass saw me, and turned from me these three times: unless she had turned from me, surely now also I had slain thee, and saved her alive.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And Balaam said unto the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I have sinned; for I knew not that thou stoodest in the way against me: now therefore, if it displease thee, I will get me back again.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Balaam, Go with the men: but only the word that I shall speak unto thee, that thou shalt speak. So Balaam went with the princes of Balak.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">And when Balak heard that Balaam was come, he went out to meet him unto a city of Moab, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the border of Arnon, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the utmost coast.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And Balak said unto Balaam, Did I not earnestly send unto thee to call thee? wherefore camest thou not unto me? am I not able indeed to promote thee to honour?</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And Balaam said unto Balak, Lo, I am come unto thee: have I now any power at all to say any thing? the word that God putteth in my mouth, that shall I speak.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And Balaam went with Balak, and they came unto Kirjath-huzoth.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And Balak offered oxen and sheep, and sent to Balaam, and to the princes that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And it came to pass on the morrow, that Balak took Balaam, and brought him up into the high places of Baal, that thence he might see the utmost &lt;i&gt;part&lt;/i&gt; of the people.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>