<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="34" nextChapter="numbers_3.html" nextTitle="Numbers 3" prevChapter="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers 1" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses and unto Aaron, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Every man of the children of Israel shall pitch by his own standard, with the ensign of their father's house: far off about the tabernacle of the congregation shall they pitch.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And on the east side toward the rising of the sun shall they of the standard of the camp of Judah pitch throughout their armies: and Nahshon the son of Amminadab &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; captain of the children of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And his host, and those that were numbered of them, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; threescore and fourteen thousand and six hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And those that do pitch next unto him &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the tribe of Issachar: and Nethaneel the son of Zuar &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; captain of the children of Issachar.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And his host, and those that were numbered thereof, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; fifty and four thousand and four hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;i&gt;Then&lt;/i&gt; the tribe of Zebulun: and Eliab the son of Helon &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; captain of the children of Zebulun.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And his host, and those that were numbered thereof, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; fifty and seven thousand and four hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">All that were numbered in the camp of Judah &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; an hundred thousand and fourscore thousand and six thousand and four hundred, throughout their armies. These shall first set forth.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">On the south side &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the standard of the camp of Reuben according to their armies: and the captain of the children of Reuben &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; Elizur the son of Shedeur.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And his host, and those that were numbered thereof, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; forty and six thousand and five hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And those which pitch by him &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the tribe of Simeon: and the captain of the children of Simeon &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; Shelumiel the son of Zurishaddai.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And his host, and those that were numbered of them, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; fifty and nine thousand and three hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then the tribe of Gad: and the captain of the sons of Gad &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; Eliasaph the son of Reuel.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And his host, and those that were numbered of them, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; forty and five thousand and six hundred and fifty.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">All that were numbered in the camp of Reuben &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; an hundred thousand and fifty and one thousand and four hundred and fifty, throughout their armies. And they shall set forth in the second rank.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Then the tabernacle of the congregation shall set forward with the camp of the Levites in the midst of the camp: as they encamp, so shall they set forward, every man in his place by their standards.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">On the west side &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the standard of the camp of Ephraim according to their armies: and the captain of the sons of Ephraim &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; Elishama the son of Ammihud.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And his host, and those that were numbered of them, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; forty thousand and five hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And by him &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the tribe of Manasseh: and the captain of the children of Manasseh &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; Gamaliel the son of Pedahzur.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And his host, and those that were numbered of them, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thirty and two thousand and two hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then the tribe of Benjamin: and the captain of the sons of Benjamin &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; Abidan the son of Gideoni.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And his host, and those that were numbered of them, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thirty and five thousand and four hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">All that were numbered of the camp of Ephraim &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; an hundred thousand and eight thousand and an hundred, throughout their armies. And they shall go forward in the third rank.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">The standard of the camp of Dan &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; on the north side by their armies: and the captain of the children of Dan &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; Ahiezer the son of Ammishaddai.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And his host, and those that were numbered of them, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; threescore and two thousand and seven hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And those that encamp by him &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the tribe of Asher: and the captain of the children of Asher &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; Pagiel the son of Ocran.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And his host, and those that were numbered of them, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; forty and one thousand and five hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">Then the tribe of Naphtali: and the captain of the children of Naphtali &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; Ahira the son of Enan.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And his host, and those that were numbered of them, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; fifty and three thousand and four hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">All they that were numbered in the camp of Dan &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; an hundred thousand and fifty and seven thousand and six hundred. They shall go hindmost with their standards.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; those which were numbered of the children of Israel by the house of their fathers: all those that were numbered of the camps throughout their hosts &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; six hundred thousand and three thousand and five hundred and fifty.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">But the Levites were not numbered among the children of Israel; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And the children of Israel did according to all that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses: so they pitched by their standards, and so they set forward, every one after their families, according to the house of their fathers.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>