<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="51" nextChapter="numbers_4.html" nextTitle="Numbers 4" prevChapter="numbers_2.html" prevTitle="Numbers 2" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">These also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the generations of Aaron and Moses in the day &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake with Moses in mount Sinai.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the names of the sons of Aaron; Nadab the firstborn, and Abihu, Eleazar, and Ithamar.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the names of the sons of Aaron, the priests which were anointed, whom he consecrated to minister in the priest's office.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Nadab and Abihu died before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, when they offered strange fire before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in the wilderness of Sinai, and they had no children: and Eleazar and Ithamar ministered in the priest's office in the sight of Aaron their father.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Bring the tribe of Levi near, and present them before Aaron the priest, that they may minister unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they shall keep his charge, and the charge of the whole congregation before the tabernacle of the congregation, to do the service of the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And they shall keep all the instruments of the tabernacle of the congregation, and the charge of the children of Israel, to do the service of the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And thou shalt give the Levites unto Aaron and to his sons: they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; wholly given unto him out of the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And thou shalt appoint Aaron and his sons, and they shall wait on their priest's office: and the stranger that cometh nigh shall be put to death.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I, behold, I have taken the Levites from among the children of Israel instead of all the firstborn that openeth the matrix among the children of Israel: therefore the Levites shall be mine;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Because all the firstborn &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; mine; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; on the day that I smote all the firstborn in the land of Egypt I hallowed unto me all the firstborn in Israel, both man and beast: mine shall they be: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses in the wilderness of Sinai, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Number the children of Levi after the house of their fathers, by their families: every male from a month old and upward shalt thou number them.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Moses numbered them according to the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as he was commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And these were the sons of Levi by their names; Gershon, and Kohath, and Merari.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the names of the sons of Gershon by their families; Libni, and Shimei.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the sons of Kohath by their families; Amram, and Izehar, Hebron, and Uzziel.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the sons of Merari by their families; Mahli, and Mushi. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the families of the Levites according to the house of their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Of Gershon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the family of the Libnites, and the family of the Shimites: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the families of the Gershonites.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Those that were numbered of them, according to the number of all the males, from a month old and upward, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; those that were numbered of them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; seven thousand and five hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The families of the Gershonites shall pitch behind the tabernacle westward.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the chief of the house of the father of the Gershonites &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; Eliasaph the son of Lael.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the charge of the sons of Gershon in the tabernacle of the congregation &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the tabernacle, and the tent, the covering thereof, and the hanging for the door of the tabernacle of the congregation,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And the hangings of the court, and the curtain for the door of the court, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the tabernacle, and by the altar round about, and the cords of it for all the service thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And of Kohath &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the family of the Amramites, and the family of the Izeharites, and the family of the Hebronites, and the family of the Uzzielites: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the families of the Kohathites.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">In the number of all the males, from a month old and upward, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; eight thousand and six hundred, keeping the charge of the sanctuary.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The families of the sons of Kohath shall pitch on the side of the tabernacle southward.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the chief of the house of the father of the families of the Kohathites &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; Elizaphan the son of Uzziel.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And their charge &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the ark, and the table, and the candlestick, and the altars, and the vessels of the sanctuary wherewith they minister, and the hanging, and all the service thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And Eleazar the son of Aaron the priest &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; chief over the chief of the Levites, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and have&lt;/span&gt; the oversight of them that keep the charge of the sanctuary.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">Of Merari &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the family of the Mahlites, and the family of the Mushites: these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the families of Merari.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And those that were numbered of them, according to the number of all the males, from a month old and upward, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; six thousand and two hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And the chief of the house of the father of the families of Merari &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Zuriel the son of Abihail: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;these&lt;/span&gt; shall pitch on the side of the tabernacle northward.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;under&lt;/span&gt; the custody and charge of the sons of Merari &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the boards of the tabernacle, and the bars thereof, and the pillars thereof, and the sockets thereof, and all the vessels thereof, and all that serveth thereto,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And the pillars of the court round about, and their sockets, and their pins, and their cords.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38" newPara="true">But those that encamp before the tabernacle toward the east, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; before the tabernacle of the congregation eastward, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; Moses, and Aaron and his sons, keeping the charge of the sanctuary for the charge of the children of Israel; and the stranger that cometh nigh shall be put to death.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">All that were numbered of the Levites, which Moses and Aaron numbered at the commandment of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, throughout their families, all the males from a month old and upward, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; twenty and two thousand.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Number all the firstborn of the males of the children of Israel from a month old and upward, and take the number of their names.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And thou shalt take the Levites for me (I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;) instead of all the firstborn among the children of Israel; and the cattle of the Levites instead of all the firstlings among the cattle of the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And Moses numbered, as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded him, all the firstborn among the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And all the firstborn males by the number of names, from a month old and upward, of those that were numbered of them, were twenty and two thousand two hundred and threescore and thirteen.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">Take the Levites instead of all the firstborn among the children of Israel, and the cattle of the Levites instead of their cattle; and the Levites shall be mine: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And for those that are to be redeemed of the two hundred and threescore and thirteen of the firstborn of the children of Israel, which are more than the Levites;</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">Thou shalt even take five shekels apiece by the poll, after the shekel of the sanctuary shalt thou take &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;: (the shekel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; twenty gerahs:)</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">And thou shalt give the money, wherewith the odd number of them is to be redeemed, unto Aaron and to his sons.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And Moses took the redemption money of them that were over and above them that were redeemed by the Levites:</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">Of the firstborn of the children of Israel took he the money; a thousand three hundred and threescore and five &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shekels&lt;/span&gt;, after the shekel of the sanctuary:</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And Moses gave the money of them that were redeemed unto Aaron and to his sons, according to the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>