<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="33" verseCount="56" nextChapter="numbers_34.html" nextTitle="Numbers 34" prevChapter="numbers_32.html" prevTitle="Numbers 32" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the journeys of the children of Israel, which went forth out of the land of Egypt with their armies under the hand of Moses and Aaron.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Moses wrote their goings out according to their journeys by the commandment of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; their journeys according to their goings out.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they departed from Rameses in the first month, on the fifteenth day of the first month; on the morrow after the passover the children of Israel went out with an high hand in the sight of all the Egyptians.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For the Egyptians buried all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; firstborn, which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had smitten among them: upon their gods also the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; executed judgments.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the children of Israel removed from Rameses, and pitched in Succoth.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And they departed from Succoth, and pitched in Etham, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the edge of the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they removed from Etham, and turned again unto Pi-hahiroth, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; before Baal-zephon: and they pitched before Migdol.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And they departed from before Pi-hahiroth, and passed through the midst of the sea into the wilderness, and went three days' journey in the wilderness of Etham, and pitched in Marah.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And they removed from Marah, and came unto Elim: and in Elim &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; twelve fountains of water, and threescore and ten palm trees; and they pitched there.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they removed from Elim, and encamped by the Red sea.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And they removed from the Red sea, and encamped in the wilderness of Sin.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And they took their journey out of the wilderness of Sin, and encamped in Dophkah.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And they departed from Dophkah, and encamped in Alush.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they removed from Alush, and encamped at Rephidim, where was no water for the people to drink.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And they departed from Rephidim, and pitched in the wilderness of Sinai.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And they removed from the desert of Sinai, and pitched at Kibroth-hattaavah.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And they departed from Kibroth-hattaavah, and encamped at Hazeroth.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And they departed from Hazeroth, and pitched in Rithmah.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And they departed from Rithmah, and pitched at Rimmon-parez.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And they departed from Rimmon-parez, and pitched in Libnah.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they removed from Libnah, and pitched at Rissah.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And they journeyed from Rissah, and pitched in Kehelathah.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And they went from Kehelathah, and pitched in mount Shapher.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they removed from mount Shapher, and encamped in Haradah.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they removed from Haradah, and pitched in Makheloth.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And they removed from Makheloth, and encamped at Tahath.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And they departed from Tahath, and pitched at Tarah.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they removed from Tarah, and pitched in Mithcah.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And they went from Mithcah, and pitched in Hashmonah.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And they departed from Hashmonah, and encamped at Moseroth.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And they departed from Moseroth, and pitched in Bene-jaakan.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And they removed from Bene-jaakan, and encamped at Hor-hagidgad.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And they went from Hor-hagidgad, and pitched in Jotbathah.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And they removed from Jotbathah, and encamped at Ebronah.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And they departed from Ebronah, and encamped at Ezion-gaber.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And they removed from Ezion-gaber, and pitched in the wilderness of Zin, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Kadesh.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And they removed from Kadesh, and pitched in mount Hor, in the edge of the land of Edom.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And Aaron the priest went up into mount Hor at the commandment of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and died there, in the fortieth year after the children of Israel were come out of the land of Egypt, in the first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the fifth month.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And Aaron &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; an hundred and twenty and three years old when he died in mount Hor.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And king Arad the Canaanite, which dwelt in the south in the land of Canaan, heard of the coming of the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And they departed from mount Hor, and pitched in Zalmonah.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And they departed from Zalmonah, and pitched in Punon.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And they departed from Punon, and pitched in Oboth.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And they departed from Oboth, and pitched in Ije-abarim, in the border of Moab.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And they departed from Iim, and pitched in Dibon-gad.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And they removed from Dibon-gad, and encamped in Almon-diblathaim.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">And they removed from Almon-diblathaim, and pitched in the mountains of Abarim, before Nebo.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">And they departed from the mountains of Abarim, and pitched in the plains of Moab by Jordan &lt;span class="extra"&gt;near&lt;/span&gt; Jericho.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And they pitched by Jordan, from Beth-jesimoth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto Abel-shittim in the plains of Moab.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses in the plains of Moab by Jordan &lt;span class="extra"&gt;near&lt;/span&gt; Jericho, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">Speak unto the children of Israel, and say unto them, When ye are passed over Jordan into the land of Canaan;</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">Then ye shall drive out all the inhabitants of the land from before you, and destroy all their pictures, and destroy all their molten images, and quite pluck down all their high places:</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">And ye shall dispossess &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the inhabitants&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; the land, and dwell therein: for I have given you the land to possess it.</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">And ye shall divide the land by lot for an inheritance among your families: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to the more ye shall give the more inheritance, and to the fewer ye shall give the less inheritance: every man's &lt;span class="extra"&gt;inheritance&lt;/span&gt; shall be in the place where his lot falleth; according to the tribes of your fathers ye shall inherit.</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">But if ye will not drive out the inhabitants of the land from before you; then it shall come to pass, that those which ye let remain of them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; pricks in your eyes, and thorns in your sides, and shall vex you in the land wherein ye dwell.</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">Moreover it shall come to pass, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; I shall do unto you, as I thought to do unto them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>