<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="31" verseCount="54" nextChapter="numbers_32.html" nextTitle="Numbers 32" prevChapter="numbers_30.html" prevTitle="Numbers 30" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Avenge the children of Israel of the Midianites: afterward shalt thou be gathered unto thy people.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Moses spake unto the people, saying, Arm some of yourselves unto the war, and let them go against the Midianites, and avenge the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of Midian.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Of every tribe a thousand, throughout all the tribes of Israel, shall ye send to the war.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">So there were delivered out of the thousands of Israel, a thousand of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;every&lt;/span&gt; tribe, twelve thousand armed for war.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Moses sent them to the war, a thousand of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;every&lt;/span&gt; tribe, them and Phinehas the son of Eleazar the priest, to the war, with the holy instruments, and the trumpets to blow in his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they warred against the Midianites, as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses; and they slew all the males.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And they slew the kings of Midian, beside the rest of them that were slain; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;namely&lt;/span&gt;, Evi, and Rekem, and Zur, and Hur, and Reba, five kings of Midian: Balaam also the son of Beor they slew with the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the children of Israel took &lt;span class="extra"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; the women of Midian captives, and their little ones, and took the spoil of all their cattle, and all their flocks, and all their goods.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they burnt all their cities wherein they dwelt, and all their goodly castles, with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And they took all the spoil, and all the prey, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; of men and of beasts.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And they brought the captives, and the prey, and the spoil, unto Moses, and Eleazar the priest, and unto the congregation of the children of Israel, unto the camp at the plains of Moab, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; by Jordan &lt;span class="extra"&gt;near&lt;/span&gt; Jericho.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And Moses, and Eleazar the priest, and all the princes of the congregation, went forth to meet them without the camp.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Moses was wroth with the officers of the host, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; the captains over thousands, and captains over hundreds, which came from the battle.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Moses said unto them, Have ye saved all the women alive?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Behold, these caused the children of Israel, through the counsel of Balaam, to commit trespass against the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the matter of Peor, and there was a plague among the congregation of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Now therefore kill every male among the little ones, and kill every woman that hath known man by lying with him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But all the women children, that have not known a man by lying with him, keep alive for yourselves.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And do ye abide without the camp seven days: whosoever hath killed any person, and whosoever hath touched any slain, purify &lt;span class="extra"&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; yourselves and your captives on the third day, and on the seventh day.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And purify all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; raiment, and all that is made of skins, and all work of goats' &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hair&lt;/span&gt;, and all things made of wood.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">And Eleazar the priest said unto the men of war which went to the battle, This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the ordinance of the law which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Only the gold, and the silver, the brass, the iron, the tin, and the lead,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Every thing that may abide the fire, ye shall make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; go through the fire, and it shall be clean: nevertheless it shall be purified with the water of separation: and all that abideth not the fire ye shall make go through the water.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And ye shall wash your clothes on the seventh day, and ye shall be clean, and afterward ye shall come into the camp.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Take the sum of the prey that was taken, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; of man and of beast, thou, and Eleazar the priest, and the chief fathers of the congregation:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And divide the prey into two parts; between them that took the war upon them, who went out to battle, and between all the congregation:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And levy a tribute unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of the men of war which went out to battle: one soul of five hundred, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; of the persons, and of the beeves, and of the asses, and of the sheep:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Take &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; of their half, and give it unto Eleazar the priest, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; an heave offering of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And of the children of Israel's half, thou shalt take one portion of fifty, of the persons, of the beeves, of the asses, and of the flocks, of all manner of beasts, and give them unto the Levites, which keep the charge of the tabernacle of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Moses and Eleazar the priest did as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And the booty, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; the rest of the prey which the men of war had caught, was six hundred thousand and seventy thousand and five thousand sheep,</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And threescore and twelve thousand beeves,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And threescore and one thousand asses,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And thirty and two thousand persons in all, of women that had not known man by lying with him.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And the half, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which was&lt;/span&gt; the portion of them that went out to war, was in number three hundred thousand and seven and thirty thousand and five hundred sheep:</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s tribute of the sheep was six hundred and threescore and fifteen.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And the beeves &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; thirty and six thousand; of which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s tribute &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; threescore and twelve.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And the asses &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; thirty thousand and five hundred; of which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s tribute &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; threescore and one.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And the persons &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; sixteen thousand; of which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s tribute &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; thirty and two persons.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And Moses gave the tribute, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which was&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s heave offering, unto Eleazar the priest, as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And of the children of Israel's half, which Moses divided from the men that warred,</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">(Now the half &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that pertained unto&lt;/span&gt; the congregation was three hundred thousand and thirty thousand &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; seven thousand and five hundred sheep,</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And thirty and six thousand beeves,</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And thirty thousand asses and five hundred,</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And sixteen thousand persons;)</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">Even of the children of Israel's half, Moses took one portion of fifty, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; of man and of beast, and gave them unto the Levites, which kept the charge of the tabernacle of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48" newPara="true">And the officers which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; over thousands of the host, the captains of thousands, and captains of hundreds, came near unto Moses:</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And they said unto Moses, Thy servants have taken the sum of the men of war which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; under our charge, and there lacketh not one man of us.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">We have therefore brought an oblation for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, what every man hath gotten, of jewels of gold, chains, and bracelets, rings, earrings, and tablets, to make an atonement for our souls before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And Moses and Eleazar the priest took the gold of them, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all wrought jewels.</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">And all the gold of the offering that they offered up to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, of the captains of thousands, and of the captains of hundreds, was sixteen thousand seven hundred and fifty shekels.</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">(&lt;span class="extra"&gt;For&lt;/span&gt; the men of war had taken spoil, every man for himself.)</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">And Moses and Eleazar the priest took the gold of the captains of thousands and of hundreds, and brought it into the tabernacle of the congregation, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a memorial for the children of Israel before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>