<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="30" verseCount="16" nextChapter="numbers_31.html" nextTitle="Numbers 31" prevChapter="numbers_29.html" prevTitle="Numbers 29" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Moses spake unto the heads of the tribes concerning the children of Israel, saying, This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the thing which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">If a man vow a vow unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, or swear an oath to bind his soul with a bond; he shall not break his word, he shall do according to all that proceedeth out of his mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">If a woman also vow a vow unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and bind &lt;span class='extra'&gt;herself&lt;/span&gt; by a bond, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; in her father's house in her youth;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And her father hear her vow, and her bond wherewith she hath bound her soul, and her father shall hold his peace at her: then all her vows shall stand, and every bond wherewith she hath bound her soul shall stand.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But if her father disallow her in the day that he heareth; not any of her vows, or of her bonds wherewith she hath bound her soul, shall stand: and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall forgive her, because her father disallowed her.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And if she had at all an husband, when she vowed, or uttered ought out of her lips, wherewith she bound her soul;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And her husband heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it,&lt;/span&gt; and held his peace at her in the day that he heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;: then her vows shall stand, and her bonds wherewith she bound her soul shall stand.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But if her husband disallowed her on the day that he heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;; then he shall make her vow which she vowed, and that which she uttered with her lips, wherewith she bound her soul, of none effect: and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall forgive her.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But every vow of a widow, and of her that is divorced, wherewith they have bound their souls, shall stand against her.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And if she vowed in her husband's house, or bound her soul by a bond with an oath;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And her husband heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and held his peace at her, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; disallowed her not: then all her vows shall stand, and every bond wherewith she bound her soul shall stand.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But if her husband hath utterly made them void on the day he heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them; then&lt;/span&gt; whatsoever proceeded out of her lips concerning her vows, or concerning the bond of her soul, shall not stand: her husband hath made them void; and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall forgive her.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Every vow, and every binding oath to afflict the soul, her husband may establish it, or her husband may make it void.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But if her husband altogether hold his peace at her from day to day; then he establisheth all her vows, or all her bonds, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; upon her: he confirmeth them, because he held his peace at her in the day that he heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But if he shall any ways make them void after that he hath heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;; then he shall bear her iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the statutes, which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses, between a man and his wife, between the father and his daughter, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being yet&lt;/span&gt; in her youth in her father's house.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>