<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="28" verseCount="31" nextChapter="numbers_29.html" nextTitle="Numbers 29" prevChapter="numbers_27.html" prevTitle="Numbers 27" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Command the children of Israel, and say unto them, My offering, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; my bread for my sacrifices made by fire, &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a sweet savour unto me, shall ye observe to offer unto me in their due season.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And thou shalt say unto them, This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the offering made by fire which ye shall offer unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; two lambs of the first year without spot day by day, &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a continual burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The one lamb shalt thou offer in the morning, and the other lamb shalt thou offer at even;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And a tenth &lt;i&gt;part&lt;/i&gt; of an ephah of flour for a meat offering, mingled with the fourth &lt;i&gt;part&lt;/i&gt; of an hin of beaten oil.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; a continual burnt offering, which was ordained in mount Sinai for a sweet savour, a sacrifice made by fire unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the drink offering thereof &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the fourth &lt;i&gt;part&lt;/i&gt; of an hin for the one lamb: in the holy &lt;i&gt;place&lt;/i&gt; shalt thou cause the strong wine to be poured unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a drink offering.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the other lamb shalt thou offer at even: as the meat offering of the morning, and as the drink offering thereof, thou shalt offer &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, a sacrifice made by fire, of a sweet savour unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And on the sabbath day two lambs of the first year without spot, and two tenth deals of flour &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a meat offering, mingled with oil, and the drink offering thereof:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;i&gt;This is&lt;/i&gt; the burnt offering of every sabbath, beside the continual burnt offering, and his drink offering.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And in the beginnings of your months ye shall offer a burnt offering unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; two young bullocks, and one ram, seven lambs of the first year without spot;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And three tenth deals of flour &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a meat offering, mingled with oil, for one bullock; and two tenth deals of flour &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a meat offering, mingled with oil, for one ram;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And a several tenth deal of flour mingled with oil &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a meat offering unto one lamb; &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a burnt offering of a sweet savour, a sacrifice made by fire unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And their drink offerings shall be half an hin of wine unto a bullock, and the third &lt;i&gt;part&lt;/i&gt; of an hin unto a ram, and a fourth &lt;i&gt;part&lt;/i&gt; of an hin unto a lamb: this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the burnt offering of every month throughout the months of the year.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And one kid of the goats for a sin offering unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be offered, beside the continual burnt offering, and his drink offering.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And in the fourteenth day of the first month &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the passover of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And in the fifteenth day of this month &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the feast: seven days shall unleavened bread be eaten.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">In the first day &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; an holy convocation; ye shall do no manner of servile work &lt;i&gt;therein&lt;/i&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But ye shall offer a sacrifice made by fire &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a burnt offering unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; two young bullocks, and one ram, and seven lambs of the first year: they shall be unto you without blemish:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And their meat offering &lt;i&gt;shall be of&lt;/i&gt; flour mingled with oil: three tenth deals shall ye offer for a bullock, and two tenth deals for a ram;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">A several tenth deal shalt thou offer for every lamb, throughout the seven lambs:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And one goat &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a sin offering, to make an atonement for you.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Ye shall offer these beside the burnt offering in the morning, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; for a continual burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">After this manner ye shall offer daily, throughout the seven days, the meat of the sacrifice made by fire, of a sweet savour unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: it shall be offered beside the continual burnt offering, and his drink offering.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And on the seventh day ye shall have an holy convocation; ye shall do no servile work.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">Also in the day of the firstfruits, when ye bring a new meat offering unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, after your weeks &lt;i&gt;be out&lt;/i&gt;, ye shall have an holy convocation; ye shall do no servile work:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">But ye shall offer the burnt offering for a sweet savour unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; two young bullocks, one ram, seven lambs of the first year;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And their meat offering of flour mingled with oil, three tenth deals unto one bullock, two tenth deals unto one ram,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">A several tenth deal unto one lamb, throughout the seven lambs;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;i&gt;And&lt;/i&gt; one kid of the goats, to make an atonement for you.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Ye shall offer &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; beside the continual burnt offering, and his meat offering, (they shall be unto you without blemish) and their drink offerings.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>