<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="33" nextChapter="numbers_14.html" nextTitle="Numbers 14" prevChapter="numbers_12.html" prevTitle="Numbers 12" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Send thou men, that they may search the land of Canaan, which I give unto the children of Israel: of every tribe of their fathers shall ye send a man, every one a ruler among them.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Moses by the commandment of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent them from the wilderness of Paran: all those men &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; heads of the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; their names: of the tribe of Reuben, Shammua the son of Zaccur.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Of the tribe of Simeon, Shaphat the son of Hori.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Of the tribe of Judah, Caleb the son of Jephunneh.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Of the tribe of Issachar, Igal the son of Joseph.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Of the tribe of Ephraim, Oshea the son of Nun.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Of the tribe of Benjamin, Palti the son of Raphu.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Of the tribe of Zebulun, Gaddiel the son of Sodi.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Of the tribe of Joseph, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;namely&lt;/span&gt;, of the tribe of Manasseh, Gaddi the son of Susi.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Of the tribe of Dan, Ammiel the son of Gemalli.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Of the tribe of Asher, Sethur the son of Michael.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Of the tribe of Naphtali, Nahbi the son of Vophsi.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Of the tribe of Gad, Geuel the son of Machi.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the names of the men which Moses sent to spy out the land. And Moses called Oshea the son of Nun Jehoshua.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And Moses sent them to spy out the land of Canaan, and said unto them, Get you up this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;way&lt;/span&gt; southward, and go up into the mountain:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And see the land, what it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;; and the people that dwelleth therein, whether they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; strong or weak, few or many;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And what the land &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; that they dwell in, whether it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; good or bad; and what cities &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they be&lt;/span&gt; that they dwell in, whether in tents, or in strong holds;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And what the land &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;, whether it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; fat or lean, whether there be wood therein, or not. And be ye of good courage, and bring of the fruit of the land. Now the time &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the time of the firstripe grapes.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">So they went up, and searched the land from the wilderness of Zin unto Rehob, as men come to Hamath.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And they ascended by the south, and came unto Hebron; where Ahiman, Sheshai, and Talmai, the children of Anak, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;. (Now Hebron was built seven years before Zoan in Egypt.)</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And they came unto the brook of Eshcol, and cut down from thence a branch with one cluster of grapes, and they bare it between two upon a staff; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they brought&lt;/span&gt; of the pomegranates, and of the figs.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The place was called the brook Eshcol, because of the cluster of grapes which the children of Israel cut down from thence.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they returned from searching of the land after forty days.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And they went and came to Moses, and to Aaron, and to all the congregation of the children of Israel, unto the wilderness of Paran, to Kadesh; and brought back word unto them, and unto all the congregation, and shewed them the fruit of the land.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And they told him, and said, We came unto the land whither thou sentest us, and surely it floweth with milk and honey; and this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the fruit of it.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Nevertheless the people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; strong that dwell in the land, and the cities &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; walled, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; very great: and moreover we saw the children of Anak there.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The Amalekites dwell in the land of the south: and the Hittites, and the Jebusites, and the Amorites, dwell in the mountains: and the Canaanites dwell by the sea, and by the coast of Jordan.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Caleb stilled the people before Moses, and said, Let us go up at once, and possess it; for we are well able to overcome it.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">But the men that went up with him said, We be not able to go up against the people; for they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; stronger than we.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And they brought up an evil report of the land which they had searched unto the children of Israel, saying, The land, through which we have gone to search it, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a land that eateth up the inhabitants thereof; and all the people that we saw in it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; men of a great stature.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And there we saw the giants, the sons of Anak, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which come&lt;/span&gt; of the giants: and we were in our own sight as grasshoppers, and so we were in their sight.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>