<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="23" verseCount="30" nextChapter="numbers_24.html" nextTitle="Numbers 24" prevChapter="numbers_22.html" prevTitle="Numbers 22" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Balaam said unto Balak, Build me here seven altars, and prepare me here seven oxen and seven rams.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Balak did as Balaam had spoken; and Balak and Balaam offered on &lt;span class="extra"&gt;every&lt;/span&gt; altar a bullock and a ram.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Balaam said unto Balak, Stand by thy burnt offering, and I will go: peradventure the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will come to meet me: and whatsoever he sheweth me I will tell thee. And he went to an high place.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And God met Balaam: and he said unto him, I have prepared seven altars, and I have offered upon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;every&lt;/span&gt; altar a bullock and a ram.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; put a word in Balaam's mouth, and said, Return unto Balak, and thus thou shalt speak.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he returned unto him, and, lo, he stood by his burnt sacrifice, he, and all the princes of Moab.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he took up his parable, and said, Balak the king of Moab hath brought me from Aram, out of the mountains of the east, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Come, curse me Jacob, and come, defy Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">How shall I curse, whom God hath not cursed? or how shall I defy, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;whom&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath not defied?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For from the top of the rocks I see him, and from the hills I behold him: lo, the people shall dwell alone, and shall not be reckoned among the nations.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Who can count the dust of Jacob, and the number of the fourth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;part&lt;/span&gt; of Israel? Let me die the death of the righteous, and let my last end be like his!</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Balak said unto Balaam, What hast thou done unto me? I took thee to curse mine enemies, and, behold, thou hast blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; altogether.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he answered and said, Must I not take heed to speak that which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath put in my mouth?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Balak said unto him, Come, I pray thee, with me unto another place, from whence thou mayest see them: thou shalt see but the utmost part of them, and shalt not see them all: and curse me them from thence.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And he brought him into the field of Zophim, to the top of Pisgah, and built seven altars, and offered a bullock and a ram on &lt;span class="extra"&gt;every&lt;/span&gt; altar.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he said unto Balak, Stand here by thy burnt offering, while I meet &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; yonder.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; met Balaam, and put a word in his mouth, and said, Go again unto Balak, and say thus.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And when he came to him, behold, he stood by his burnt offering, and the princes of Moab with him. And Balak said unto him, What hath the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spoken?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And he took up his parable, and said, Rise up, Balak, and hear; hearken unto me, thou son of Zippor:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not a man, that he should lie; neither the son of man, that he should repent: hath he said, and shall he not do &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;? or hath he spoken, and shall he not make it good?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Behold, I have received &lt;span class="extra"&gt;commandment&lt;/span&gt; to bless: and he hath blessed; and I cannot reverse it.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">He hath not beheld iniquity in Jacob, neither hath he seen perverseness in Israel: the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with him, and the shout of a king &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; among them.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">God brought them out of Egypt; he hath as it were the strength of an unicorn.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Surely &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no enchantment against Jacob, neither &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; any divination against Israel: according to this time it shall be said of Jacob and of Israel, What hath God wrought!</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Behold, the people shall rise up as a great lion, and lift up himself as a young lion: he shall not lie down until he eat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; the prey, and drink the blood of the slain.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And Balak said unto Balaam, Neither curse them at all, nor bless them at all.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">But Balaam answered and said unto Balak, Told not I thee, saying, All that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; speaketh, that I must do?</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And Balak said unto Balaam, Come, I pray thee, I will bring thee unto another place; peradventure it will please God that thou mayest curse me them from thence.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Balak brought Balaam unto the top of Peor, that looketh toward Jeshimon.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Balaam said unto Balak, Build me here seven altars, and prepare me here seven bullocks and seven rams.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Balak did as Balaam had said, and offered a bullock and a ram on &lt;span class="extra"&gt;every&lt;/span&gt; altar.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>