<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="17" verseCount="13" nextChapter="numbers_18.html" nextTitle="Numbers 18" prevChapter="numbers_16.html" prevTitle="Numbers 16" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto the children of Israel, and take of every one of them a rod according to the house of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; fathers, of all their princes according to the house of their fathers twelve rods: write thou every man's name upon his rod.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And thou shalt write Aaron's name upon the rod of Levi: for one rod &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; for the head of the house of their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And thou shalt lay them up in the tabernacle of the congregation before the testimony, where I will meet with you.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And it shall come to pass, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the man's rod, whom I shall choose, shall blossom: and I will make to cease from me the murmurings of the children of Israel, whereby they murmur against you.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And Moses spake unto the children of Israel, and every one of their princes gave him a rod apiece, for each prince one, according to their fathers' houses, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; twelve rods: and the rod of Aaron &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; among their rods.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Moses laid up the rods before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the tabernacle of witness.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And it came to pass, that on the morrow Moses went into the tabernacle of witness; and, behold, the rod of Aaron for the house of Levi was budded, and brought forth buds, and bloomed blossoms, and yielded almonds.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Moses brought out all the rods from before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto all the children of Israel: and they looked, and took every man his rod.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Bring Aaron's rod again before the testimony, to be kept for a token against the rebels; and thou shalt quite take away their murmurings from me, that they die not.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Moses did &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;: as the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded him, so did he.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the children of Israel spake unto Moses, saying, Behold, we die, we perish, we all perish.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Whosoever cometh any thing near unto the tabernacle of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall die: shall we be consumed with dying?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>