<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="27" nextChapter="numbers_7.html" nextTitle="Numbers 7" prevChapter="numbers_5.html" prevTitle="Numbers 5" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak unto the children of Israel, and say unto them, When either man or woman shall separate &lt;span class="extra"&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt; to vow a vow of a Nazarite, to separate &lt;span class="extra"&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt; unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">He shall separate &lt;span class="extra"&gt;himself&lt;/span&gt; from wine and strong drink, and shall drink no vinegar of wine, or vinegar of strong drink, neither shall he drink any liquor of grapes, nor eat moist grapes, or dried.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">All the days of his separation shall he eat nothing that is made of the vine tree, from the kernels even to the husk.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">All the days of the vow of his separation there shall no razor come upon his head: until the days be fulfilled, in the which he separateth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;himself&lt;/span&gt; unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, he shall be holy, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; shall let the locks of the hair of his head grow.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">All the days that he separateth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;himself&lt;/span&gt; unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; he shall come at no dead body.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He shall not make himself unclean for his father, or for his mother, for his brother, or for his sister, when they die: because the consecration of his God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon his head.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">All the days of his separation he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; holy unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And if any man die very suddenly by him, and he hath defiled the head of his consecration; then he shall shave his head in the day of his cleansing, on the seventh day shall he shave it.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And on the eighth day he shall bring two turtles, or two young pigeons, to the priest, to the door of the tabernacle of the congregation:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the priest shall offer the one for a sin offering, and the other for a burnt offering, and make an atonement for him, for that he sinned by the dead, and shall hallow his head that same day.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he shall consecrate unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; the days of his separation, and shall bring a lamb of the first year for a trespass offering: but the days that were before shall be lost, because his separation was defiled.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law of the Nazarite, when the days of his separation are fulfilled: he shall be brought unto the door of the tabernacle of the congregation:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he shall offer his offering unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, one he lamb of the first year without blemish for a burnt offering, and one ewe lamb of the first year without blemish for a sin offering, and one ram without blemish for peace offerings,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And a basket of unleavened bread, cakes of fine flour mingled with oil, and wafers of unleavened bread anointed with oil, and their meat offering, and their drink offerings.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the priest shall bring &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and shall offer his sin offering, and his burnt offering:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he shall offer the ram &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a sacrifice of peace offerings unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, with the basket of unleavened bread: the priest shall offer also his meat offering, and his drink offering.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the Nazarite shall shave the head of his separation &lt;span class="extra"&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; the door of the tabernacle of the congregation, and shall take the hair of the head of his separation, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; in the fire which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; under the sacrifice of the peace offerings.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the priest shall take the sodden shoulder of the ram, and one unleavened cake out of the basket, and one unleavened wafer, and shall put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; upon the hands of the Nazarite, after &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the hair of&lt;/span&gt; his separation is shaven:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the priest shall wave them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a wave offering before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; holy for the priest, with the wave breast and heave shoulder: and after that the Nazarite may drink wine.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law of the Nazarite who hath vowed, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and of&lt;/span&gt; his offering unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for his separation, beside &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; that his hand shall get: according to the vow which he vowed, so he must do after the law of his separation.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Speak unto Aaron and unto his sons, saying, On this wise ye shall bless the children of Israel, saying unto them,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; bless thee, and keep thee:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; make his face shine upon thee, and be gracious unto thee:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; lift up his countenance upon thee, and give thee peace.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And they shall put my name upon the children of Israel; and I will bless them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>