<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="4" name="Numbers" bookPage="numbers.html" title="Numbers" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="deuteronomy_1.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy" prevBook="leviticus_1.html" prevTitle="Leviticus">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="45" nextChapter="numbers_15.html" nextTitle="Numbers 15" prevChapter="numbers_13.html" prevTitle="Numbers 13" chapterPage="numbers_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And all the congregation lifted up their voice, and cried; and the people wept that night.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And all the children of Israel murmured against Moses and against Aaron: and the whole congregation said unto them, Would God that we had died in the land of Egypt! or would God we had died in this wilderness!</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And wherefore hath the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought us unto this land, to fall by the sword, that our wives and our children should be a prey? were it not better for us to return into Egypt?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they said one to another, Let us make a captain, and let us return into Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then Moses and Aaron fell on their faces before all the assembly of the congregation of the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And Joshua the son of Nun, and Caleb the son of Jephunneh, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which were&lt;/span&gt; of them that searched the land, rent their clothes:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they spake unto all the company of the children of Israel, saying, The land, which we passed through to search it, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an exceeding good land.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">If the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; delight in us, then he will bring us into this land, and give it us; a land which floweth with milk and honey.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Only rebel not ye against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, neither fear ye the people of the land; for they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; bread for us: their defence is departed from them, and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with us: fear them not.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But all the congregation bade stone them with stones. And the glory of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared in the tabernacle of the congregation before all the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, How long will this people provoke me? and how long will it be ere they believe me, for all the signs which I have shewed among them?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I will smite them with the pestilence, and disinherit them, and will make of thee a greater nation and mightier than they.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And Moses said unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Then the Egyptians shall hear &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, (for thou broughtest up this people in thy might from among them;)</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they will tell &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to the inhabitants of this land: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; they have heard that thou &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; among this people, that thou &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; art seen face to face, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thy cloud standeth over them, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thou goest before them, by day time in a pillar of a cloud, and in a pillar of fire by night.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Now &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; thou shalt kill &lt;span class='extra'&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; this people as one man, then the nations which have heard the fame of thee will speak, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Because the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was not able to bring this people into the land which he sware unto them, therefore he hath slain them in the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And now, I beseech thee, let the power of my Lord be great, according as thou hast spoken, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; longsuffering, and of great mercy, forgiving iniquity and transgression, and by no means clearing &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the guilty&lt;/span&gt;, visiting the iniquity of the fathers upon the children unto the third and fourth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;generation&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Pardon, I beseech thee, the iniquity of this people according unto the greatness of thy mercy, and as thou hast forgiven this people, from Egypt even until now.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said, I have pardoned according to thy word:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; truly &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; I live, all the earth shall be filled with the glory of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Because all those men which have seen my glory, and my miracles, which I did in Egypt and in the wilderness, and have tempted me now these ten times, and have not hearkened to my voice;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Surely they shall not see the land which I sware unto their fathers, neither shall any of them that provoked me see it:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But my servant Caleb, because he had another spirit with him, and hath followed me fully, him will I bring into the land whereinto he went; and his seed shall possess it.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">(Now the Amalekites and the Canaanites dwelt in the valley.) To morrow turn you, and get you into the wilderness by the way of the Red sea.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Moses and unto Aaron, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">How long &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall I bear with&lt;/span&gt; this evil congregation, which murmur against me? I have heard the murmurings of the children of Israel, which they murmur against me.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Say unto them, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;As truly as&lt;/span&gt; I live, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as ye have spoken in mine ears, so will I do to you:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Your carcases shall fall in this wilderness; and all that were numbered of you, according to your whole number, from twenty years old and upward, which have murmured against me,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Doubtless ye shall not come into the land, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;concerning&lt;/span&gt; which I sware to make you dwell therein, save Caleb the son of Jephunneh, and Joshua the son of Nun.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">But your little ones, which ye said should be a prey, them will I bring in, and they shall know the land which ye have despised.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">But &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; you, your carcases, they shall fall in this wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And your children shall wander in the wilderness forty years, and bear your whoredoms, until your carcases be wasted in the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">After the number of the days in which ye searched the land, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; forty days, each day for a year, shall ye bear your iniquities, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; forty years, and ye shall know my breach of promise.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">I the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have said, I will surely do it unto all this evil congregation, that are gathered together against me: in this wilderness they shall be consumed, and there they shall die.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And the men, which Moses sent to search the land, who returned, and made all the congregation to murmur against him, by bringing up a slander upon the land,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Even those men that did bring up the evil report upon the land, died by the plague before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">But Joshua the son of Nun, and Caleb the son of Jephunneh, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which were&lt;/span&gt; of the men that went to search the land, lived &lt;span class='extra'&gt;still&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And Moses told these sayings unto all the children of Israel: and the people mourned greatly.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40" newPara="true">And they rose up early in the morning, and gat them up into the top of the mountain, saying, Lo, we &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be here&lt;/span&gt;, and will go up unto the place which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath promised: for we have sinned.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And Moses said, Wherefore now do ye transgress the commandment of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? but it shall not prosper.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Go not up, for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not among you; that ye be not smitten before your enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">For the Amalekites and the Canaanites &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; there before you, and ye shall fall by the sword: because ye are turned away from the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, therefore the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will not be with you.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">But they presumed to go up unto the hill top: nevertheless the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and Moses, departed not out of the camp.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">Then the Amalekites came down, and the Canaanites which dwelt in that hill, and smote them, and discomfited them, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto Hormah.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>