<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="29" nextChapter="deuteronomy_15.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 15" prevChapter="deuteronomy_13.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 13" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the children of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God: ye shall not cut yourselves, nor make any baldness between your eyes for the dead.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; an holy people unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath chosen thee to be a peculiar people unto himself, above all the nations that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Thou shalt not eat any abominable thing.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the beasts which ye shall eat: the ox, the sheep, and the goat,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The hart, and the roebuck, and the fallow deer, and the wild goat, and the pygarg, and the wild ox, and the chamois.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And every beast that parteth the hoof, and cleaveth the cleft into two claws, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; cheweth the cud among the beasts, that ye shall eat.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Nevertheless these ye shall not eat of them that chew the cud, or of them that divide the cloven hoof; &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; the camel, and the hare, and the coney: for they chew the cud, but divide not the hoof; &lt;i&gt;therefore&lt;/i&gt; they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; unclean unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the swine, because it divideth the hoof, yet cheweth not the cud, it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; unclean unto you: ye shall not eat of their flesh, nor touch their dead carcase.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">These ye shall eat of all that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in the waters: all that have fins and scales shall ye eat:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And whatsoever hath not fins and scales ye may not eat; it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; unclean unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">&lt;i&gt;Of&lt;/i&gt; all clean birds ye shall eat.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But these &lt;i&gt;are they&lt;/i&gt; of which ye shall not eat: the eagle, and the ossifrage, and the ospray,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the glede, and the kite, and the vulture after his kind,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And every raven after his kind,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the owl, and the night hawk, and the cuckow, and the hawk after his kind,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The little owl, and the great owl, and the swan,</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the pelican, and the gier eagle, and the cormorant,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the stork, and the heron after her kind, and the lapwing, and the bat.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And every creeping thing that flieth &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; unclean unto you: they shall not be eaten.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;i&gt;But of&lt;/i&gt; all clean fowls ye may eat.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Ye shall not eat &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; any thing that dieth of itself: thou shalt give it unto the stranger that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in thy gates, that he may eat it; or thou mayest sell it unto an alien: for thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; an holy people unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God. Thou shalt not seethe a kid in his mother's milk.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Thou shalt truly tithe all the increase of thy seed, that the field bringeth forth year by year.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And thou shalt eat before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, in the place which he shall choose to place his name there, the tithe of thy corn, of thy wine, and of thine oil, and the firstlings of thy herds and of thy flocks; that thou mayest learn to fear the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God always.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And if the way be too long for thee, so that thou art not able to carry it; &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; if the place be too far from thee, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall choose to set his name there, when the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath blessed thee:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then shalt thou turn &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; into money, and bind up the money in thine hand, and shalt go unto the place which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall choose:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And thou shalt bestow that money for whatsoever thy soul lusteth after, for oxen, or for sheep, or for wine, or for strong drink, or for whatsoever thy soul desireth: and thou shalt eat there before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, and thou shalt rejoice, thou, and thine household,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And the Levite that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; within thy gates; thou shalt not forsake him; for he hath no part nor inheritance with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">At the end of three years thou shalt bring forth all the tithe of thine increase the same year, and shalt lay &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; up within thy gates:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And the Levite, (because he hath no part nor inheritance with thee,) and the stranger, and the fatherless, and the widow, which &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; within thy gates, shall come, and shall eat and be satisfied; that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God may bless thee in all the work of thine hand which thou doest.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>