<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="26" verseCount="19" nextChapter="deuteronomy_27.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 27" prevChapter="deuteronomy_25.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 25" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it shall be, when thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; come in unto the land which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an inheritance, and possessest it, and dwellest therein;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That thou shalt take of the first of all the fruit of the earth, which thou shalt bring of thy land that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee, and shalt put &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; in a basket, and shalt go unto the place which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall choose to place his name there.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And thou shalt go unto the priest that shall be in those days, and say unto him, I profess this day unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, that I am come unto the country which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sware unto our fathers for to give us.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the priest shall take the basket out of thine hand, and set it down before the altar of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And thou shalt speak and say before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, A Syrian ready to perish &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; my father, and he went down into Egypt, and sojourned there with a few, and became there a nation, great, mighty, and populous:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the Egyptians evil entreated us, and afflicted us, and laid upon us hard bondage:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when we cried unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of our fathers, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; heard our voice, and looked on our affliction, and our labour, and our oppression:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought us forth out of Egypt with a mighty hand, and with an outstretched arm, and with great terribleness, and with signs, and with wonders:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he hath brought us into this place, and hath given us this land, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; a land that floweth with milk and honey.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And now, behold, I have brought the firstfruits of the land, which thou, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hast given me. And thou shalt set it before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, and worship before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And thou shalt rejoice in every good &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath given unto thee, and unto thine house, thou, and the Levite, and the stranger that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; among you.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">When thou hast made an end of tithing all the tithes of thine increase the third year, &lt;i&gt;which is&lt;/i&gt; the year of tithing, and hast given &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; unto the Levite, the stranger, the fatherless, and the widow, that they may eat within thy gates, and be filled;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then thou shalt say before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, I have brought away the hallowed things out of &lt;i&gt;mine&lt;/i&gt; house, and also have given them unto the Levite, and unto the stranger, to the fatherless, and to the widow, according to all thy commandments which thou hast commanded me: I have not transgressed thy commandments, neither have I forgotten &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I have not eaten thereof in my mourning, neither have I taken away &lt;i&gt;ought&lt;/i&gt; thereof for &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; unclean &lt;i&gt;use&lt;/i&gt;, nor given &lt;i&gt;ought&lt;/i&gt; thereof for the dead: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; I have hearkened to the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; have done according to all that thou hast commanded me.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Look down from thy holy habitation, from heaven, and bless thy people Israel, and the land which thou hast given us, as thou swarest unto our fathers, a land that floweth with milk and honey.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">This day the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath commanded thee to do these statutes and judgments: thou shalt therefore keep and do them with all thine heart, and with all thy soul.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thou hast avouched the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; this day to be thy God, and to walk in his ways, and to keep his statutes, and his commandments, and his judgments, and to hearken unto his voice:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath avouched thee this day to be his peculiar people, as he hath promised thee, and that &lt;i&gt;thou&lt;/i&gt; shouldest keep all his commandments;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And to make thee high above all nations which he hath made, in praise, and in name, and in honour; and that thou mayest be an holy people unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, as he hath spoken.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>