<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="21" verseCount="23" nextChapter="deuteronomy_22.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 22" prevChapter="deuteronomy_20.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 20" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">If &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; be found slain in the land which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee to possess it, lying in the field, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; it be not known who hath slain him:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then thy elders and thy judges shall come forth, and they shall measure unto the cities which &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; round about him that is slain:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And it shall be, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the city &lt;i&gt;which is&lt;/i&gt; next unto the slain man, even the elders of that city shall take an heifer, which hath not been wrought with, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; which hath not drawn in the yoke;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the elders of that city shall bring down the heifer unto a rough valley, which is neither eared nor sown, and shall strike off the heifer's neck there in the valley:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the priests the sons of Levi shall come near; for them the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath chosen to minister unto him, and to bless in the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and by their word shall every controversy and every stroke be &lt;i&gt;tried&lt;/i&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And all the elders of that city, &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; next unto the slain &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;, shall wash their hands over the heifer that is beheaded in the valley:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they shall answer and say, Our hands have not shed this blood, neither have our eyes seen &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Be merciful, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, unto thy people Israel, whom thou hast redeemed, and lay not innocent blood unto thy people of Israel's charge. And the blood shall be forgiven them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">So shalt thou put away the &lt;i&gt;guilt of&lt;/i&gt; innocent blood from among you, when thou shalt do &lt;i&gt;that which is&lt;/i&gt; right in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">When thou goest forth to war against thine enemies, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath delivered them into thine hands, and thou hast taken them captive,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And seest among the captives a beautiful woman, and hast a desire unto her, that thou wouldest have her to thy wife;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Then thou shalt bring her home to thine house; and she shall shave her head, and pare her nails;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And she shall put the raiment of her captivity from off her, and shall remain in thine house, and bewail her father and her mother a full month: and after that thou shalt go in unto her, and be her husband, and she shall be thy wife.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And it shall be, if thou have no delight in her, then thou shalt let her go whither she will; but thou shalt not sell her at all for money, thou shalt not make merchandise of her, because thou hast humbled her.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">If a man have two wives, one beloved, and another hated, and they have born him children, &lt;i&gt;both&lt;/i&gt; the beloved and the hated; and &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; the firstborn son be hers that was hated:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Then it shall be, when he maketh his sons to inherit &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; which he hath, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; he may not make the son of the beloved firstborn before the son of the hated, &lt;i&gt;which is indeed&lt;/i&gt; the firstborn:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But he shall acknowledge the son of the hated &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; the firstborn, by giving him a double portion of all that he hath: for he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the beginning of his strength; the right of the firstborn &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">If a man have a stubborn and rebellious son, which will not obey the voice of his father, or the voice of his mother, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt;, when they have chastened him, will not hearken unto them:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Then shall his father and his mother lay hold on him, and bring him out unto the elders of his city, and unto the gate of his place;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And they shall say unto the elders of his city, This our son &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; stubborn and rebellious, he will not obey our voice; &lt;i&gt;he is&lt;/i&gt; a glutton, and a drunkard.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And all the men of his city shall stone him with stones, that he die: so shalt thou put evil away from among you; and all Israel shall hear, and fear.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And if a man have committed a sin worthy of death, and he be to be put to death, and thou hang him on a tree:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">His body shall not remain all night upon the tree, but thou shalt in any wise bury him that day; (for he that is hanged &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; accursed of God;) that thy land be not defiled, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an inheritance.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>