<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="37" nextChapter="deuteronomy_3.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 3" prevChapter="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 1" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then we turned, and took our journey into the wilderness by the way of the Red sea, as the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto me: and we compassed mount Seir many days.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Ye have compassed this mountain long enough: turn you northward.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And command thou the people, saying, Ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; to pass through the coast of your brethren the children of Esau, which dwell in Seir; and they shall be afraid of you: take ye good heed unto yourselves therefore:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Meddle not with them; for I will not give you of their land, no, not so much as a foot breadth; because I have given mount Seir unto Esau &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a possession.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Ye shall buy meat of them for money, that ye may eat; and ye shall also buy water of them for money, that ye may drink.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath blessed thee in all the works of thy hand: he knoweth thy walking through this great wilderness: these forty years the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;hath been&lt;/span&gt; with thee; thou hast lacked nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And when we passed by from our brethren the children of Esau, which dwelt in Seir, through the way of the plain from Elath, and from Ezion-gaber, we turned and passed by the way of the wilderness of Moab.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, Distress not the Moabites, neither contend with them in battle: for I will not give thee of their land &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a possession; because I have given Ar unto the children of Lot &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a possession.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The Emims dwelt therein in times past, a people great, and many, and tall, as the Anakims;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Which also were accounted giants, as the Anakims; but the Moabites call them Emims.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The Horims also dwelt in Seir beforetime; but the children of Esau succeeded them, when they had destroyed them from before them, and dwelt in their stead; as Israel did unto the land of his possession, which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; gave unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Now rise up, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;said I&lt;/span&gt;, and get you over the brook Zered. And we went over the brook Zered.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the space in which we came from Kadesh-barnea, until we were come over the brook Zered, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; thirty and eight years; until all the generation of the men of war were wasted out from among the host, as the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sware unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For indeed the hand of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was against them, to destroy them from among the host, until they were consumed.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">So it came to pass, when all the men of war were consumed and dead from among the people,</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">That the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thou art to pass over through Ar, the coast of Moab, this day:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; thou comest nigh over against the children of Ammon, distress them not, nor meddle with them: for I will not give thee of the land of the children of Ammon &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; possession; because I have given it unto the children of Lot &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a possession.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">(That also was accounted a land of giants: giants dwelt therein in old time; and the Ammonites call them Zamzummims;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">A people great, and many, and tall, as the Anakims; but the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; destroyed them before them; and they succeeded them, and dwelt in their stead:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">As he did to the children of Esau, which dwelt in Seir, when he destroyed the Horims from before them; and they succeeded them, and dwelt in their stead even unto this day:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the Avims which dwelt in Hazerim, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto Azzah, the Caphtorims, which came forth out of Caphtor, destroyed them, and dwelt in their stead.)</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">Rise ye up, take your journey, and pass over the river Arnon: behold, I have given into thine hand Sihon the Amorite, king of Heshbon, and his land: begin to possess &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and contend with him in battle.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">This day will I begin to put the dread of thee and the fear of thee upon the nations &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; under the whole heaven, who shall hear report of thee, and shall tremble, and be in anguish because of thee.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And I sent messengers out of the wilderness of Kedemoth unto Sihon king of Heshbon with words of peace, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Let me pass through thy land: I will go along by the high way, I will neither turn unto the right hand nor to the left.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Thou shalt sell me meat for money, that I may eat; and give me water for money, that I may drink: only I will pass through on my feet;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">(As the children of Esau which dwell in Seir, and the Moabites which dwell in Ar, did unto me;) until I shall pass over Jordan into the land which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God giveth us.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">But Sihon king of Heshbon would not let us pass by him: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hardened his spirit, and made his heart obstinate, that he might deliver him into thy hand, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;appeareth&lt;/span&gt; this day.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, Behold, I have begun to give Sihon and his land before thee: begin to possess, that thou mayest inherit his land.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Then Sihon came out against us, he and all his people, to fight at Jahaz.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God delivered him before us; and we smote him, and his sons, and all his people.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And we took all his cities at that time, and utterly destroyed the men, and the women, and the little ones, of every city, we left none to remain:</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Only the cattle we took for a prey unto ourselves, and the spoil of the cities which we took.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">From Aroer, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the brink of the river of Arnon, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the city that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the river, even unto Gilead, there was not one city too strong for us: the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God delivered all unto us:</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Only unto the land of the children of Ammon thou camest not, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;nor&lt;/span&gt; unto any place of the river Jabbok, nor unto the cities in the mountains, nor unto whatsoever the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God forbad us.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>