<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="20" nextChapter="deuteronomy_21.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 21" prevChapter="deuteronomy_19.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 19" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">When thou goest out to battle against thine enemies, and seest horses, and chariots, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; a people more than thou, be not afraid of them: for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with thee, which brought thee up out of the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And it shall be, when ye are come nigh unto the battle, that the priest shall approach and speak unto the people,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And shall say unto them, Hear, O Israel, ye approach this day unto battle against your enemies: let not your hearts faint, fear not, and do not tremble, neither be ye terrified because of them;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he that goeth with you, to fight for you against your enemies, to save you.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And the officers shall speak unto the people, saying, What man &lt;i&gt;is there&lt;/i&gt; that hath built a new house, and hath not dedicated it? let him go and return to his house, lest he die in the battle, and another man dedicate it.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And what man &lt;i&gt;is he&lt;/i&gt; that hath planted a vineyard, and hath not &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; eaten of it? let him &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; go and return unto his house, lest he die in the battle, and another man eat of it.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And what man &lt;i&gt;is there&lt;/i&gt; that hath betrothed a wife, and hath not taken her? let him go and return unto his house, lest he die in the battle, and another man take her.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the officers shall speak further unto the people, and they shall say, What man &lt;i&gt;is there that is&lt;/i&gt; fearful and fainthearted? let him go and return unto his house, lest his brethren's heart faint as well as his heart.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And it shall be, when the officers have made an end of speaking unto the people, that they shall make captains of the armies to lead the people.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">When thou comest nigh unto a city to fight against it, then proclaim peace unto it.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And it shall be, if it make thee answer of peace, and open unto thee, then it shall be, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; all the people &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; found therein shall be tributaries unto thee, and they shall serve thee.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And if it will make no peace with thee, but will make war against thee, then thou shalt besiege it:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And when the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath delivered it into thine hands, thou shalt smite every male thereof with the edge of the sword:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But the women, and the little ones, and the cattle, and all that is in the city, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; all the spoil thereof, shalt thou take unto thyself; and thou shalt eat the spoil of thine enemies, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath given thee.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Thus shalt thou do unto all the cities &lt;i&gt;which are&lt;/i&gt; very far off from thee, which &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; not of the cities of these nations.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But of the cities of these people, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God doth give thee &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an inheritance, thou shalt save alive nothing that breatheth:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But thou shalt utterly destroy them; &lt;i&gt;namely&lt;/i&gt;, the Hittites, and the Amorites, the Canaanites, and the Perizzites, the Hivites, and the Jebusites; as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath commanded thee:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">That they teach you not to do after all their abominations, which they have done unto their gods; so should ye sin against the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">When thou shalt besiege a city a long time, in making war against it to take it, thou shalt not destroy the trees thereof by forcing an axe against them: for thou mayest eat of them, and thou shalt not cut them down (for the tree of the field &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; man's &lt;i&gt;life&lt;/i&gt;) to employ &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in the siege:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Only the trees which thou knowest that they &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; not trees for meat, thou shalt destroy and cut them down; and thou shalt build bulwarks against the city that maketh war with thee, until it be subdued.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>