<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="33" verseCount="29" nextChapter="deuteronomy_34.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 34" prevChapter="deuteronomy_32.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 32" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the blessing, wherewith Moses the man of God blessed the children of Israel before his death.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he said, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came from Sinai, and rose up from Seir unto them; he shined forth from mount Paran, and he came with ten thousands of saints: from his right hand &lt;span class="extra"&gt;went&lt;/span&gt; a fiery law for them.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Yea, he loved the people; all his saints &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in thy hand: and they sat down at thy feet; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;every one&lt;/span&gt; shall receive of thy words.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Moses commanded us a law, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the inheritance of the congregation of Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he was king in Jeshurun, when the heads of the people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the tribes of Israel were gathered together.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Let Reuben live, and not die; and let &lt;span class="extra"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; his men be few.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is the blessing&lt;/span&gt; of Judah: and he said, Hear, &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the voice of Judah, and bring him unto his people: let his hands be sufficient for him; and be thou an help &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to him&lt;/span&gt; from his enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And of Levi he said, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Let&lt;/span&gt; thy Thummim and thy Urim &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; with thy holy one, whom thou didst prove at Massah, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and with&lt;/span&gt; whom thou didst strive at the waters of Meribah;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Who said unto his father and to his mother, I have not seen him; neither did he acknowledge his brethren, nor knew his own children: for they have observed thy word, and kept thy covenant.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">They shall teach Jacob thy judgments, and Israel thy law: they shall put incense before thee, and whole burnt sacrifice upon thine altar.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Bless, &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, his substance, and accept the work of his hands: smite through the loins of them that rise against him, and of them that hate him, that they rise not again.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; of Benjamin he said, The beloved of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall dwell in safety by him; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; shall cover him all the day long, and he shall dwell between his shoulders.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And of Joseph he said, Blessed of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; his land, for the precious things of heaven, for the dew, and for the deep that coucheth beneath,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And for the precious fruits &lt;span class="extra"&gt;brought forth&lt;/span&gt; by the sun, and for the precious things put forth by the moon,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And for the chief things of the ancient mountains, and for the precious things of the lasting hills,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And for the precious things of the earth and fulness thereof, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the good will of him that dwelt in the bush: let &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the blessing&lt;/span&gt; come upon the head of Joseph, and upon the top of the head of him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that was&lt;/span&gt; separated from his brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">His glory &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is like&lt;/span&gt; the firstling of his bullock, and his horns &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are like&lt;/span&gt; the horns of unicorns: with them he shall push the people together to the ends of the earth: and they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the ten thousands of Ephraim, and they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the thousands of Manasseh.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And of Zebulun he said, Rejoice, Zebulun, in thy going out; and, Issachar, in thy tents.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">They shall call the people unto the mountain; there they shall offer sacrifices of righteousness: for they shall suck &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; the abundance of the seas, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; treasures hid in the sand.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And of Gad he said, Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; he that enlargeth Gad: he dwelleth as a lion, and teareth the arm with the crown of the head.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he provided the first part for himself, because there, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; a portion of the lawgiver, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was he&lt;/span&gt; seated; and he came with the heads of the people, he executed the justice of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and his judgments with Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And of Dan he said, Dan &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a lion's whelp: he shall leap from Bashan.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And of Naphtali he said, O Naphtali, satisfied with favour, and full with the blessing of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: possess thou the west and the south.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And of Asher he said, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Let&lt;/span&gt; Asher &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; blessed with children; let him be acceptable to his brethren, and let him dip his foot in oil.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Thy shoes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; iron and brass; and as thy days, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so shall&lt;/span&gt; thy strength &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;There is&lt;/span&gt; none like unto the God of Jeshurun, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;who&lt;/span&gt; rideth upon the heaven in thy help, and in his excellency on the sky.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The eternal God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is thy&lt;/span&gt; refuge, and underneath &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the everlasting arms: and he shall thrust out the enemy from before thee; and shall say, Destroy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Israel then shall dwell in safety alone: the fountain of Jacob &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; upon a land of corn and wine; also his heavens shall drop down dew.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Happy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; thou, O Israel: who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; like unto thee, O people saved by the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the shield of thy help, and who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the sword of thy excellency! and thine enemies shall be found liars unto thee; and thou shalt tread upon their high places.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>