<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="25" nextChapter="deuteronomy_7.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 7" prevChapter="deuteronomy_5.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 5" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the commandments, the statutes, and the judgments, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God commanded to teach you, that ye might do &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in the land whither ye go to possess it:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That thou mightest fear the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, to keep all his statutes and his commandments, which I command thee, thou, and thy son, and thy son's son, all the days of thy life; and that thy days may be prolonged.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Hear therefore, O Israel, and observe to do &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;; that it may be well with thee, and that ye may increase mightily, as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of thy fathers hath promised thee, in the land that floweth with milk and honey.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Hear, O Israel: The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; one &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And thou shalt love the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God with all thine heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy might.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And these words, which I command thee this day, shall be in thine heart:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And thou shalt teach them diligently unto thy children, and shalt talk of them when thou sittest in thine house, and when thou walkest by the way, and when thou liest down, and when thou risest up.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And thou shalt bind them for a sign upon thine hand, and they shall be as frontlets between thine eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And thou shalt write them upon the posts of thy house, and on thy gates.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And it shall be, when the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall have brought thee into the land which he sware unto thy fathers, to Abraham, to Isaac, and to Jacob, to give thee great and goodly cities, which thou buildedst not,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And houses full of all good &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt;, which thou filledst not, and wells digged, which thou diggedst not, vineyards and olive trees, which thou plantedst not; when thou shalt have eaten and be full;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;i&gt;Then&lt;/i&gt; beware lest thou forget the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which brought thee forth out of the land of Egypt, from the house of bondage.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thou shalt fear the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, and serve him, and shalt swear by his name.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Ye shall not go after other gods, of the gods of the people which &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; round about you;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">(For the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a jealous God among you) lest the anger of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God be kindled against thee, and destroy thee from off the face of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Ye shall not tempt the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, as ye tempted &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; in Massah.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Ye shall diligently keep the commandments of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, and his testimonies, and his statutes, which he hath commanded thee.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And thou shalt do &lt;i&gt;that which is&lt;/i&gt; right and good in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: that it may be well with thee, and that thou mayest go in and possess the good land which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sware unto thy fathers,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">To cast out all thine enemies from before thee, as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;i&gt;And&lt;/i&gt; when thy son asketh thee in time to come, saying, What &lt;i&gt;mean&lt;/i&gt; the testimonies, and the statutes, and the judgments, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God hath commanded you?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then thou shalt say unto thy son, We were Pharaoh's bondmen in Egypt; and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought us out of Egypt with a mighty hand:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shewed signs and wonders, great and sore, upon Egypt, upon Pharaoh, and upon all his household, before our eyes:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he brought us out from thence, that he might bring us in, to give us the land which he sware unto our fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded us to do all these statutes, to fear the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, for our good always, that he might preserve us alive, as &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; at this day.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And it shall be our righteousness, if we observe to do all these commandments before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, as he hath commanded us.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>