<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="22" nextChapter="deuteronomy_17.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 17" prevChapter="deuteronomy_15.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 15" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Observe the month of Abib, and keep the passover unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God: for in the month of Abib the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God brought thee forth out of Egypt by night.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thou shalt therefore sacrifice the passover unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, of the flock and the herd, in the place which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall choose to place his name there.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou shalt eat no leavened bread with it; seven days shalt thou eat unleavened bread therewith, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the bread of affliction; for thou camest forth out of the land of Egypt in haste: that thou mayest remember the day when thou camest forth out of the land of Egypt all the days of thy life.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And there shall be no leavened bread seen with thee in all thy coast seven days; neither shall there &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any thing&lt;/span&gt; of the flesh, which thou sacrificedst the first day at even, remain all night until the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thou mayest not sacrifice the passover within any of thy gates, which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But at the place which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall choose to place his name in, there thou shalt sacrifice the passover at even, at the going down of the sun, at the season that thou camest forth out of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And thou shalt roast and eat &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; in the place which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall choose: and thou shalt turn in the morning, and go unto thy tents.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Six days thou shalt eat unleavened bread: and on the seventh day &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a solemn assembly to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God: thou shalt do no work &lt;span class='extra'&gt;therein&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Seven weeks shalt thou number unto thee: begin to number the seven weeks from &lt;span class='extra'&gt;such time as&lt;/span&gt; thou beginnest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to put&lt;/span&gt; the sickle to the corn.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And thou shalt keep the feast of weeks unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God with a tribute of a freewill offering of thine hand, which thou shalt give &lt;span class='extra'&gt;unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God&lt;/span&gt;, according as the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath blessed thee:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And thou shalt rejoice before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, thou, and thy son, and thy daughter, and thy manservant, and thy maidservant, and the Levite that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; within thy gates, and the stranger, and the fatherless, and the widow, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; among you, in the place which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath chosen to place his name there.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And thou shalt remember that thou wast a bondman in Egypt: and thou shalt observe and do these statutes.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Thou shalt observe the feast of tabernacles seven days, after that thou hast gathered in thy corn and thy wine:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And thou shalt rejoice in thy feast, thou, and thy son, and thy daughter, and thy manservant, and thy maidservant, and the Levite, the stranger, and the fatherless, and the widow, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; within thy gates.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Seven days shalt thou keep a solemn feast unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God in the place which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall choose: because the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall bless thee in all thine increase, and in all the works of thine hands, therefore thou shalt surely rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Three times in a year shall all thy males appear before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God in the place which he shall choose; in the feast of unleavened bread, and in the feast of weeks, and in the feast of tabernacles: and they shall not appear before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; empty:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Every man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall give&lt;/span&gt; as he is able, according to the blessing of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God which he hath given thee.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Judges and officers shalt thou make thee in all thy gates, which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee, throughout thy tribes: and they shall judge the people with just judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thou shalt not wrest judgment; thou shalt not respect persons, neither take a gift: for a gift doth blind the eyes of the wise, and pervert the words of the righteous.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">That which is altogether just shalt thou follow, that thou mayest live, and inherit the land which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Thou shalt not plant thee a grove of any trees near unto the altar of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, which thou shalt make thee.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Neither shalt thou set thee up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; image; which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hateth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>