<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="34" verseCount="12" nextChapter="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua 1" prevChapter="deuteronomy_33.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 33" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Moses went up from the plains of Moab unto the mountain of Nebo, to the top of Pisgah, that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; over against Jericho. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shewed him all the land of Gilead, unto Dan,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And all Naphtali, and the land of Ephraim, and Manasseh, and all the land of Judah, unto the utmost sea,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the south, and the plain of the valley of Jericho, the city of palm trees, unto Zoar.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the land which I sware unto Abraham, unto Isaac, and unto Jacob, saying, I will give it unto thy seed: I have caused thee to see &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; with thine eyes, but thou shalt not go over thither.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">So Moses the servant of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; died there in the land of Moab, according to the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he buried him in a valley in the land of Moab, over against Beth-peor: but no man knoweth of his sepulchre unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And Moses &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; an hundred and twenty years old when he died: his eye was not dim, nor his natural force abated.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And the children of Israel wept for Moses in the plains of Moab thirty days: so the days of weeping &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; mourning for Moses were ended.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And Joshua the son of Nun was full of the spirit of wisdom; for Moses had laid his hands upon him: and the children of Israel hearkened unto him, and did as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And there arose not a prophet since in Israel like unto Moses, whom the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; knew face to face,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">In all the signs and the wonders, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent him to do in the land of Egypt to Pharaoh, and to all his servants, and to all his land,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And in all that mighty hand, and in all the great terror which Moses shewed in the sight of all Israel.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>