<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="31" verseCount="30" nextChapter="deuteronomy_32.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 32" prevChapter="deuteronomy_30.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 30" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Moses went and spake these words unto all Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he said unto them, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; an hundred and twenty years old this day; I can no more go out and come in: also the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath said unto me, Thou shalt not go over this Jordan.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, he will go over before thee, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he will destroy these nations from before thee, and thou shalt possess them: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Joshua, he shall go over before thee, as the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath said.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall do unto them as he did to Sihon and to Og, kings of the Amorites, and unto the land of them, whom he destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall give them up before your face, that ye may do unto them according unto all the commandments which I have commanded you.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Be strong and of a good courage, fear not, nor be afraid of them: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; that doth go with thee; he will not fail thee, nor forsake thee.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And Moses called unto Joshua, and said unto him in the sight of all Israel, Be strong and of a good courage: for thou must go with this people unto the land which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath sworn unto their fathers to give them; and thou shalt cause them to inherit it.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; that doth go before thee; he will be with thee, he will not fail thee, neither forsake thee: fear not, neither be dismayed.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And Moses wrote this law, and delivered it unto the priests the sons of Levi, which bare the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and unto all the elders of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Moses commanded them, saying, At the end of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;every&lt;/span&gt; seven years, in the solemnity of the year of release, in the feast of tabernacles,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">When all Israel is come to appear before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God in the place which he shall choose, thou shalt read this law before all Israel in their hearing.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Gather the people together, men, and women, and children, and thy stranger that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; within thy gates, that they may hear, and that they may learn, and fear the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, and observe to do all the words of this law:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; their children, which have not known &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any thing&lt;/span&gt;, may hear, and learn to fear the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, as long as ye live in the land whither ye go over Jordan to possess it.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Behold, thy days approach that thou must die: call Joshua, and present yourselves in the tabernacle of the congregation, that I may give him a charge. And Moses and Joshua went, and presented themselves in the tabernacle of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared in the tabernacle in a pillar of a cloud: and the pillar of the cloud stood over the door of the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Moses, Behold, thou shalt sleep with thy fathers; and this people will rise up, and go a whoring after the gods of the strangers of the land, whither they go &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; among them, and will forsake me, and break my covenant which I have made with them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then my anger shall be kindled against them in that day, and I will forsake them, and I will hide my face from them, and they shall be devoured, and many evils and troubles shall befall them; so that they will say in that day, Are not these evils come upon us, because our God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not among us?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And I will surely hide my face in that day for all the evils which they shall have wrought, in that they are turned unto other gods.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Now therefore write ye this song for you, and teach it the children of Israel: put it in their mouths, that this song may be a witness for me against the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For when I shall have brought them into the land which I sware unto their fathers, that floweth with milk and honey; and they shall have eaten and filled themselves, and waxen fat; then will they turn unto other gods, and serve them, and provoke me, and break my covenant.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And it shall come to pass, when many evils and troubles are befallen them, that this song shall testify against them as a witness; for it shall not be forgotten out of the mouths of their seed: for I know their imagination which they go about, even now, before I have brought them into the land which I sware.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">Moses therefore wrote this song the same day, and taught it the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he gave Joshua the son of Nun a charge, and said, Be strong and of a good courage: for thou shalt bring the children of Israel into the land which I sware unto them: and I will be with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when Moses had made an end of writing the words of this law in a book, until they were finished,</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">That Moses commanded the Levites, which bare the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Take this book of the law, and put it in the side of the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, that it may be there for a witness against thee.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For I know thy rebellion, and thy stiff neck: behold, while I am yet alive with you this day, ye have been rebellious against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and how much more after my death?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">Gather unto me all the elders of your tribes, and your officers, that I may speak these words in their ears, and call heaven and earth to record against them.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For I know that after my death ye will utterly corrupt &lt;span class='extra'&gt;yourselves&lt;/span&gt;, and turn aside from the way which I have commanded you; and evil will befall you in the latter days; because ye will do evil in the sight of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to provoke him to anger through the work of your hands.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Moses spake in the ears of all the congregation of Israel the words of this song, until they were ended.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>