<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="23" nextChapter="deuteronomy_16.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 16" prevChapter="deuteronomy_14.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 14" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">At the end of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;every&lt;/span&gt; seven years thou shalt make a release.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the manner of the release: Every creditor that lendeth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;ought&lt;/span&gt; unto his neighbour shall release &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;; he shall not exact &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; of his neighbour, or of his brother; because it is called the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s release.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Of a foreigner thou mayest exact &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it again&lt;/span&gt;: but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which is thine with thy brother thine hand shall release;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Save when there shall be no poor among you; for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall greatly bless thee in the land which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; an inheritance to possess it:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Only if thou carefully hearken unto the voice of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, to observe to do all these commandments which I command thee this day.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God blesseth thee, as he promised thee: and thou shalt lend unto many nations, but thou shalt not borrow; and thou shalt reign over many nations, but they shall not reign over thee.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">If there be among you a poor man of one of thy brethren within any of thy gates in thy land which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee, thou shalt not harden thine heart, nor shut thine hand from thy poor brother:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But thou shalt open thine hand wide unto him, and shalt surely lend him sufficient for his need, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in that&lt;/span&gt; which he wanteth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Beware that there be not a thought in thy wicked heart, saying, The seventh year, the year of release, is at hand; and thine eye be evil against thy poor brother, and thou givest him nought; and he cry unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; against thee, and it be sin unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thou shalt surely give him, and thine heart shall not be grieved when thou givest unto him: because that for this thing the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall bless thee in all thy works, and in all that thou puttest thine hand unto.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For the poor shall never cease out of the land: therefore I command thee, saying, Thou shalt open thine hand wide unto thy brother, to thy poor, and to thy needy, in thy land.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; if thy brother, an Hebrew man, or an Hebrew woman, be sold unto thee, and serve thee six years; then in the seventh year thou shalt let him go free from thee.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And when thou sendest him out free from thee, thou shalt not let him go away empty:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou shalt furnish him liberally out of thy flock, and out of thy floor, and out of thy winepress: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of that&lt;/span&gt; wherewith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath blessed thee thou shalt give unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And thou shalt remember that thou wast a bondman in the land of Egypt, and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God redeemed thee: therefore I command thee this thing to day.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And it shall be, if he say unto thee, I will not go away from thee; because he loveth thee and thine house, because he is well with thee;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then thou shalt take an aul, and thrust &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; through his ear unto the door, and he shall be thy servant for ever. And also unto thy maidservant thou shalt do likewise.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">It shall not seem hard unto thee, when thou sendest him away free from thee; for he hath been worth a double hired servant &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to thee&lt;/span&gt;, in serving thee six years: and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall bless thee in all that thou doest.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">All the firstling males that come of thy herd and of thy flock thou shalt sanctify unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God: thou shalt do no work with the firstling of thy bullock, nor shear the firstling of thy sheep.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Thou shalt eat &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God year by year in the place which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall choose, thou and thy household.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And if there be &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; blemish therein, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as if it be&lt;/span&gt; lame, or blind, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or have&lt;/span&gt; any ill blemish, thou shalt not sacrifice it unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Thou shalt eat it within thy gates: the unclean and the clean &lt;span class='extra'&gt;person shall eat it&lt;/span&gt; alike, as the roebuck, and as the hart.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Only thou shalt not eat the blood thereof; thou shalt pour it upon the ground as water.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>