<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="24" verseCount="22" nextChapter="deuteronomy_25.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 25" prevChapter="deuteronomy_23.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 23" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">When a man hath taken a wife, and married her, and it come to pass that she find no favour in his eyes, because he hath found some uncleanness in her: then let him write her a bill of divorcement, and give &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; in her hand, and send her out of his house.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And when she is departed out of his house, she may go and be another man's &lt;i&gt;wife&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; the latter husband hate her, and write her a bill of divorcement, and giveth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; in her hand, and sendeth her out of his house; or if the latter husband die, which took her &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; his wife;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Her former husband, which sent her away, may not take her again to be his wife, after that she is defiled; for that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; abomination before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and thou shalt not cause the land to sin, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">When a man hath taken a new wife, he shall not go out to war, neither shall he be charged with any business: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; he shall be free at home one year, and shall cheer up his wife which he hath taken.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">No man shall take the nether or the upper millstone to pledge: for he taketh &lt;i&gt;a man's&lt;/i&gt; life to pledge.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">If a man be found stealing any of his brethren of the children of Israel, and maketh merchandise of him, or selleth him; then that thief shall die; and thou shalt put evil away from among you.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Take heed in the plague of leprosy, that thou observe diligently, and do according to all that the priests the Levites shall teach you: as I commanded them, &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; ye shall observe to do.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Remember what the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God did unto Miriam by the way, after that ye were come forth out of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">When thou dost lend thy brother any thing, thou shalt not go into his house to fetch his pledge.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thou shalt stand abroad, and the man to whom thou dost lend shall bring out the pledge abroad unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And if the man &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; poor, thou shalt not sleep with his pledge:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">In any case thou shalt deliver him the pledge again when the sun goeth down, that he may sleep in his own raiment, and bless thee: and it shall be righteousness unto thee before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Thou shalt not oppress an hired servant &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; poor and needy, &lt;i&gt;whether he be&lt;/i&gt; of thy brethren, or of thy strangers that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in thy land within thy gates:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">At his day thou shalt give &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; his hire, neither shall the sun go down upon it; for he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; poor, and setteth his heart upon it: lest he cry against thee unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and it be sin unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The fathers shall not be put to death for the children, neither shall the children be put to death for the fathers: every man shall be put to death for his own sin.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Thou shalt not pervert the judgment of the stranger, &lt;i&gt;nor&lt;/i&gt; of the fatherless; nor take a widow's raiment to pledge:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But thou shalt remember that thou wast a bondman in Egypt, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God redeemed thee thence: therefore I command thee to do this thing.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">When thou cuttest down thine harvest in thy field, and hast forgot a sheaf in the field, thou shalt not go again to fetch it: it shall be for the stranger, for the fatherless, and for the widow: that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God may bless thee in all the work of thine hands.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">When thou beatest thine olive tree, thou shalt not go over the boughs again: it shall be for the stranger, for the fatherless, and for the widow.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">When thou gatherest the grapes of thy vineyard, thou shalt not glean &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; afterward: it shall be for the stranger, for the fatherless, and for the widow.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And thou shalt remember that thou wast a bondman in the land of Egypt: therefore I command thee to do this thing.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>