<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="26" nextChapter="deuteronomy_8.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 8" prevChapter="deuteronomy_6.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 6" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">When the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall bring thee into the land whither thou goest to possess it, and hath cast out many nations before thee, the Hittites, and the Girgashites, and the Amorites, and the Canaanites, and the Perizzites, and the Hivites, and the Jebusites, seven nations greater and mightier than thou;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And when the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall deliver them before thee; thou shalt smite them, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; utterly destroy them; thou shalt make no covenant with them, nor shew mercy unto them:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Neither shalt thou make marriages with them; thy daughter thou shalt not give unto his son, nor his daughter shalt thou take unto thy son.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For they will turn away thy son from following me, that they may serve other gods: so will the anger of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be kindled against you, and destroy thee suddenly.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But thus shall ye deal with them; ye shall destroy their altars, and break down their images, and cut down their groves, and burn their graven images with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; an holy people unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God: the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath chosen thee to be a special people unto himself, above all people that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; upon the face of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did not set his love upon you, nor choose you, because ye were more in number than any people; for ye &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the fewest of all people:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But because the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; loved you, and because he would keep the oath which he had sworn unto your fathers, hath the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought you out with a mighty hand, and redeemed you out of the house of bondmen, from the hand of Pharaoh king of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Know therefore that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; God, the faithful God, which keepeth covenant and mercy with them that love him and keep his commandments to a thousand generations;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And repayeth them that hate him to their face, to destroy them: he will not be slack to him that hateth him, he will repay him to his face.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thou shalt therefore keep the commandments, and the statutes, and the judgments, which I command thee this day, to do them.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Wherefore it shall come to pass, if ye hearken to these judgments, and keep, and do them, that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall keep unto thee the covenant and the mercy which he sware unto thy fathers:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he will love thee, and bless thee, and multiply thee: he will also bless the fruit of thy womb, and the fruit of thy land, thy corn, and thy wine, and thine oil, the increase of thy kine, and the flocks of thy sheep, in the land which he sware unto thy fathers to give thee.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou shalt be blessed above all people: there shall not be male or female barren among you, or among your cattle.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will take away from thee all sickness, and will put none of the evil diseases of Egypt, which thou knowest, upon thee; but will lay them upon all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; that hate thee.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And thou shalt consume all the people which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall deliver thee; thine eye shall have no pity upon them: neither shalt thou serve their gods; for that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;will be&lt;/span&gt; a snare unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">If thou shalt say in thine heart, These nations &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; more than I; how can I dispossess them?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thou shalt not be afraid of them: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; shalt well remember what the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God did unto Pharaoh, and unto all Egypt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The great temptations which thine eyes saw, and the signs, and the wonders, and the mighty hand, and the stretched out arm, whereby the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God brought thee out: so shall the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God do unto all the people of whom thou art afraid.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Moreover the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God will send the hornet among them, until they that are left, and hide themselves from thee, be destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Thou shalt not be affrighted at them: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; among you, a mighty God and terrible.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God will put out those nations before thee by little and little: thou mayest not consume them at once, lest the beasts of the field increase upon thee.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall deliver them unto thee, and shall destroy them with a mighty destruction, until they be destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And he shall deliver their kings into thine hand, and thou shalt destroy their name from under heaven: there shall no man be able to stand before thee, until thou have destroyed them.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The graven images of their gods shall ye burn with fire: thou shalt not desire the silver or gold &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; on them, nor take &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; unto thee, lest thou be snared therein: for it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an abomination to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Neither shalt thou bring an abomination into thine house, lest thou be a cursed thing like it: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; thou shalt utterly detest it, and thou shalt utterly abhor it; for it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a cursed thing.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>