<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="29" verseCount="29" nextChapter="deuteronomy_30.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 30" prevChapter="deuteronomy_28.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 28" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the words of the covenant, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses to make with the children of Israel in the land of Moab, beside the covenant which he made with them in Horeb.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">And Moses called unto all Israel, and said unto them, Ye have seen all that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did before your eyes in the land of Egypt unto Pharaoh, and unto all his servants, and unto all his land;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The great temptations which thine eyes have seen, the signs, and those great miracles:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Yet the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath not given you an heart to perceive, and eyes to see, and ears to hear, unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And I have led you forty years in the wilderness: your clothes are not waxen old upon you, and thy shoe is not waxen old upon thy foot.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Ye have not eaten bread, neither have ye drunk wine or strong drink: that ye might know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when ye came unto this place, Sihon the king of Heshbon, and Og the king of Bashan, came out against us unto battle, and we smote them:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And we took their land, and gave it for an inheritance unto the Reubenites, and to the Gadites, and to the half tribe of Manasseh.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Keep therefore the words of this covenant, and do them, that ye may prosper in all that ye do.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Ye stand this day all of you before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God; your captains of your tribes, your elders, and your officers, &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; all the men of Israel,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Your little ones, your wives, and thy stranger that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in thy camp, from the hewer of thy wood unto the drawer of thy water:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">That thou shouldest enter into covenant with the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, and into his oath, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God maketh with thee this day:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">That he may establish thee to day for a people unto himself, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; he may be unto thee a God, as he hath said unto thee, and as he hath sworn unto thy fathers, to Abraham, to Isaac, and to Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Neither with you only do I make this covenant and this oath;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But with &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; that standeth here with us this day before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, and also with &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not here with us this day:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">(For ye know how we have dwelt in the land of Egypt; and how we came through the nations which ye passed by;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And ye have seen their abominations, and their idols, wood and stone, silver and gold, which &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; among them:)</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Lest there should be among you man, or woman, or family, or tribe, whose heart turneth away this day from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, to go &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; serve the gods of these nations; lest there should be among you a root that beareth gall and wormwood;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And it come to pass, when he heareth the words of this curse, that he bless himself in his heart, saying, I shall have peace, though I walk in the imagination of mine heart, to add drunkenness to thirst:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will not spare him, but then the anger of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; and his jealousy shall smoke against that man, and all the curses that are written in this book shall lie upon him, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall blot out his name from under heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall separate him unto evil out of all the tribes of Israel, according to all the curses of the covenant that are written in this book of the law:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">So that the generation to come of your children that shall rise up after you, and the stranger that shall come from a far land, shall say, when they see the plagues of that land, and the sicknesses which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath laid upon it;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;i&gt;And that&lt;/i&gt; the whole land thereof &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; brimstone, and salt, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; burning, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; it is not sown, nor beareth, nor any grass groweth therein, like the overthrow of Sodom, and Gomorrah, Admah, and Zeboim, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; overthrew in his anger, and in his wrath:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Even all nations shall say, Wherefore hath the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; done thus unto this land? what &lt;i&gt;meaneth&lt;/i&gt; the heat of this great anger?</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then men shall say, Because they have forsaken the covenant of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of their fathers, which he made with them when he brought them forth out of the land of Egypt:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For they went and served other gods, and worshipped them, gods whom they knew not, and &lt;i&gt;whom&lt;/i&gt; he had not given unto them:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And the anger of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was kindled against this land, to bring upon it all the curses that are written in this book:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; rooted them out of their land in anger, and in wrath, and in great indignation, and cast them into another land, as &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; this day.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The secret &lt;i&gt;things belong&lt;/i&gt; unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God: but those &lt;i&gt;things which are&lt;/i&gt; revealed &lt;i&gt;belong&lt;/i&gt; unto us and to our children for ever, that &lt;i&gt;we&lt;/i&gt; may do all the words of this law.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>