<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="28" verseCount="68" nextChapter="deuteronomy_29.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 29" prevChapter="deuteronomy_27.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 27" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it shall come to pass, if thou shalt hearken diligently unto the voice of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, to observe &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to do all his commandments which I command thee this day, that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God will set thee on high above all nations of the earth:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And all these blessings shall come on thee, and overtake thee, if thou shalt hearken unto the voice of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shalt&lt;/span&gt; thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in the city, and blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shalt&lt;/span&gt; thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in the field.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the fruit of thy body, and the fruit of thy ground, and the fruit of thy cattle, the increase of thy kine, and the flocks of thy sheep.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; thy basket and thy store.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shalt&lt;/span&gt; thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; when thou comest in, and blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shalt&lt;/span&gt; thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; when thou goest out.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall cause thine enemies that rise up against thee to be smitten before thy face: they shall come out against thee one way, and flee before thee seven ways.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall command the blessing upon thee in thy storehouses, and in all that thou settest thine hand unto; and he shall bless thee in the land which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God giveth thee.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall establish thee an holy people unto himself, as he hath sworn unto thee, if thou shalt keep the commandments of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, and walk in his ways.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And all people of the earth shall see that thou art called by the name of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and they shall be afraid of thee.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall make thee plenteous in goods, in the fruit of thy body, and in the fruit of thy cattle, and in the fruit of thy ground, in the land which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sware unto thy fathers to give thee.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall open unto thee his good treasure, the heaven to give the rain unto thy land in his season, and to bless all the work of thine hand: and thou shalt lend unto many nations, and thou shalt not borrow.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall make thee the head, and not the tail; and thou shalt be above only, and thou shalt not be beneath; if that thou hearken unto the commandments of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, which I command thee this day, to observe and to do &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And thou shalt not go aside from any of the words which I command thee this day, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the right hand, or &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the left, to go after other gods to serve them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">But it shall come to pass, if thou wilt not hearken unto the voice of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, to observe to do all his commandments and his statutes which I command thee this day; that all these curses shall come upon thee, and overtake thee:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Cursed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shalt&lt;/span&gt; thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in the city, and cursed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shalt&lt;/span&gt; thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in the field.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Cursed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; thy basket and thy store.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Cursed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the fruit of thy body, and the fruit of thy land, the increase of thy kine, and the flocks of thy sheep.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Cursed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shalt&lt;/span&gt; thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; when thou comest in, and cursed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shalt&lt;/span&gt; thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; when thou goest out.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall send upon thee cursing, vexation, and rebuke, in all that thou settest thine hand unto for to do, until thou be destroyed, and until thou perish quickly; because of the wickedness of thy doings, whereby thou hast forsaken me.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall make the pestilence cleave unto thee, until he have consumed thee from off the land, whither thou goest to possess it.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall smite thee with a consumption, and with a fever, and with an inflammation, and with an extreme burning, and with the sword, and with blasting, and with mildew; and they shall pursue thee until thou perish.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And thy heaven that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; over thy head shall be brass, and the earth that is under thee &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; iron.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall make the rain of thy land powder and dust: from heaven shall it come down upon thee, until thou be destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall cause thee to be smitten before thine enemies: thou shalt go out one way against them, and flee seven ways before them: and shalt be removed into all the kingdoms of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And thy carcase shall be meat unto all fowls of the air, and unto the beasts of the earth, and no man shall fray &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; away.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will smite thee with the botch of Egypt, and with the emerods, and with the scab, and with the itch, whereof thou canst not be healed.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall smite thee with madness, and blindness, and astonishment of heart:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And thou shalt grope at noonday, as the blind gropeth in darkness, and thou shalt not prosper in thy ways: and thou shalt be only oppressed and spoiled evermore, and no man shall save &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Thou shalt betroth a wife, and another man shall lie with her: thou shalt build an house, and thou shalt not dwell therein: thou shalt plant a vineyard, and shalt not gather the grapes thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Thine ox &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; slain before thine eyes, and thou shalt not eat thereof: thine ass &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; violently taken away from before thy face, and shall not be restored to thee: thy sheep &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; given unto thine enemies, and thou shalt have none to rescue &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Thy sons and thy daughters &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; given unto another people, and thine eyes shall look, and fail &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with longing&lt;/span&gt; for them all the day long: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; no might in thine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">The fruit of thy land, and all thy labours, shall a nation which thou knowest not eat up; and thou shalt be only oppressed and crushed alway:</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">So that thou shalt be mad for the sight of thine eyes which thou shalt see.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall smite thee in the knees, and in the legs, with a sore botch that cannot be healed, from the sole of thy foot unto the top of thy head.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall bring thee, and thy king which thou shalt set over thee, unto a nation which neither thou nor thy fathers have known; and there shalt thou serve other gods, wood and stone.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And thou shalt become an astonishment, a proverb, and a byword, among all nations whither the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall lead thee.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">Thou shalt carry much seed out into the field, and shalt gather &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; little in; for the locust shall consume it.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Thou shalt plant vineyards, and dress &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, but shalt neither drink &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; the wine, nor gather &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the grapes&lt;/span&gt;; for the worms shall eat them.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Thou shalt have olive trees throughout all thy coasts, but thou shalt not anoint &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thyself&lt;/span&gt; with the oil; for thine olive shall cast &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his fruit&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Thou shalt beget sons and daughters, but thou shalt not enjoy them; for they shall go into captivity.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">All thy trees and fruit of thy land shall the locust consume.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">The stranger that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; within thee shall get up above thee very high; and thou shalt come down very low.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">He shall lend to thee, and thou shalt not lend to him: he shall be the head, and thou shalt be the tail.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">Moreover all these curses shall come upon thee, and shall pursue thee, and overtake thee, till thou be destroyed; because thou hearkenedst not unto the voice of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, to keep his commandments and his statutes which he commanded thee:</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And they shall be upon thee for a sign and for a wonder, and upon thy seed for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">Because thou servedst not the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God with joyfulness, and with gladness of heart, for the abundance of all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">Therefore shalt thou serve thine enemies which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall send against thee, in hunger, and in thirst, and in nakedness, and in want of all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;: and he shall put a yoke of iron upon thy neck, until he have destroyed thee.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall bring a nation against thee from far, from the end of the earth, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as swift&lt;/span&gt; as the eagle flieth; a nation whose tongue thou shalt not understand;</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">A nation of fierce countenance, which shall not regard the person of the old, nor shew favour to the young:</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And he shall eat the fruit of thy cattle, and the fruit of thy land, until thou be destroyed: which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;also&lt;/span&gt; shall not leave thee &lt;span class="extra"&gt;either&lt;/span&gt; corn, wine, or oil, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; the increase of thy kine, or flocks of thy sheep, until he have destroyed thee.</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">And he shall besiege thee in all thy gates, until thy high and fenced walls come down, wherein thou trustedst, throughout all thy land: and he shall besiege thee in all thy gates throughout all thy land, which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath given thee.</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">And thou shalt eat the fruit of thine own body, the flesh of thy sons and of thy daughters, which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath given thee, in the siege, and in the straitness, wherewith thine enemies shall distress thee:</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;So that&lt;/span&gt; the man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; tender among you, and very delicate, his eye shall be evil toward his brother, and toward the wife of his bosom, and toward the remnant of his children which he shall leave:</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">So that he will not give to any of them of the flesh of his children whom he shall eat: because he hath nothing left him in the siege, and in the straitness, wherewith thine enemies shall distress thee in all thy gates.</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">The tender and delicate woman among you, which would not adventure to set the sole of her foot upon the ground for delicateness and tenderness, her eye shall be evil toward the husband of her bosom, and toward her son, and toward her daughter,</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">And toward her young one that cometh out from between her feet, and toward her children which she shall bear: for she shall eat them for want of all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; secretly in the siege and straitness, wherewith thine enemy shall distress thee in thy gates.</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">If thou wilt not observe to do all the words of this law that are written in this book, that thou mayest fear this glorious and fearful name, THE &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; THY GOD;</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">Then the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will make thy plagues wonderful, and the plagues of thy seed, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; great plagues, and of long continuance, and sore sicknesses, and of long continuance.</verse>
      <verse number="60" id="v60">Moreover he will bring upon thee all the diseases of Egypt, which thou wast afraid of; and they shall cleave unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="61" id="v61">Also every sickness, and every plague, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not written in the book of this law, them will the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; bring upon thee, until thou be destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="62" id="v62">And ye shall be left few in number, whereas ye were as the stars of heaven for multitude; because thou wouldest not obey the voice of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="63" id="v63">And it shall come to pass, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; rejoiced over you to do you good, and to multiply you; so the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will rejoice over you to destroy you, and to bring you to nought; and ye shall be plucked from off the land whither thou goest to possess it.</verse>
      <verse number="64" id="v64">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall scatter thee among all people, from the one end of the earth even unto the other; and there thou shalt serve other gods, which neither thou nor thy fathers have known, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; wood and stone.</verse>
      <verse number="65" id="v65">And among these nations shalt thou find no ease, neither shall the sole of thy foot have rest: but the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall give thee there a trembling heart, and failing of eyes, and sorrow of mind:</verse>
      <verse number="66" id="v66">And thy life shall hang in doubt before thee; and thou shalt fear day and night, and shalt have none assurance of thy life:</verse>
      <verse number="67" id="v67">In the morning thou shalt say, Would God it were even! and at even thou shalt say, Would God it were morning! for the fear of thine heart wherewith thou shalt fear, and for the sight of thine eyes which thou shalt see.</verse>
      <verse number="68" id="v68">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall bring thee into Egypt again with ships, by the way whereof I spake unto thee, Thou shalt see it no more again: and there ye shall be sold unto your enemies for bondmen and bondwomen, and no man shall buy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;you&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>