<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="46" nextChapter="deuteronomy_2.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 2" prevChapter="numbers_36.html" prevTitle="Numbers 36" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the words which Moses spake unto all Israel on this side Jordan in the wilderness, in the plain over against the Red &lt;span class='extra'&gt;sea&lt;/span&gt;, between Paran, and Tophel, and Laban, and Hazeroth, and Dizahab.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">(&lt;span class='extra'&gt;There are&lt;/span&gt; eleven days' &lt;span class='extra'&gt;journey&lt;/span&gt; from Horeb by the way of mount Seir unto Kadesh-barnea.)</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And it came to pass in the fortieth year, in the eleventh month, on the first &lt;span class='extra'&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the month, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; Moses spake unto the children of Israel, according unto all that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had given him in commandment unto them;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">After he had slain Sihon the king of the Amorites, which dwelt in Heshbon, and Og the king of Bashan, which dwelt at Astaroth in Edrei:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">On this side Jordan, in the land of Moab, began Moses to declare this law, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God spake unto us in Horeb, saying, Ye have dwelt long enough in this mount:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Turn you, and take your journey, and go to the mount of the Amorites, and unto all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the places&lt;/span&gt; nigh thereunto, in the plain, in the hills, and in the vale, and in the south, and by the sea side, to the land of the Canaanites, and unto Lebanon, unto the great river, the river Euphrates.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Behold, I have set the land before you: go in and possess the land which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sware unto your fathers, Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, to give unto them and to their seed after them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And I spake unto you at that time, saying, I am not able to bear you myself alone:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God hath multiplied you, and, behold, ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; this day as the stars of heaven for multitude.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">(The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of your fathers make you a thousand times so many more as ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt;, and bless you, as he hath promised you!)</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">How can I myself alone bear your cumbrance, and your burden, and your strife?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Take you wise men, and understanding, and known among your tribes, and I will make them rulers over you.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And ye answered me, and said, The thing which thou hast spoken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; good &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for us&lt;/span&gt; to do.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So I took the chief of your tribes, wise men, and known, and made them heads over you, captains over thousands, and captains over hundreds, and captains over fifties, and captains over tens, and officers among your tribes.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And I charged your judges at that time, saying, Hear &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the causes&lt;/span&gt; between your brethren, and judge righteously between &lt;span class='extra'&gt;every&lt;/span&gt; man and his brother, and the stranger &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Ye shall not respect persons in judgment; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; ye shall hear the small as well as the great; ye shall not be afraid of the face of man; for the judgment &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; God's: and the cause that is too hard for you, bring &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; unto me, and I will hear it.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And I commanded you at that time all the things which ye should do.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And when we departed from Horeb, we went through all that great and terrible wilderness, which ye saw by the way of the mountain of the Amorites, as the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God commanded us; and we came to Kadesh-barnea.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And I said unto you, Ye are come unto the mountain of the Amorites, which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God doth give unto us.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Behold, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath set the land before thee: go up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; possess &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, as the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of thy fathers hath said unto thee; fear not, neither be discouraged.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And ye came near unto me every one of you, and said, We will send men before us, and they shall search us out the land, and bring us word again by what way we must go up, and into what cities we shall come.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the saying pleased me well: and I took twelve men of you, one of a tribe:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they turned and went up into the mountain, and came unto the valley of Eshcol, and searched it out.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they took of the fruit of the land in their hands, and brought &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; down unto us, and brought us word again, and said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; a good land which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God doth give us.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Notwithstanding ye would not go up, but rebelled against the commandment of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And ye murmured in your tents, and said, Because the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hated us, he hath brought us forth out of the land of Egypt, to deliver us into the hand of the Amorites, to destroy us.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Whither shall we go up? our brethren have discouraged our heart, saying, The people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; greater and taller than we; the cities &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; great and walled up to heaven; and moreover we have seen the sons of the Anakims there.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Then I said unto you, Dread not, neither be afraid of them.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God which goeth before you, he shall fight for you, according to all that he did for you in Egypt before your eyes;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And in the wilderness, where thou hast seen how that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God bare thee, as a man doth bear his son, in all the way that ye went, until ye came into this place.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Yet in this thing ye did not believe the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God,</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Who went in the way before you, to search you out a place to pitch your tents &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;, in fire by night, to shew you by what way ye should go, and in a cloud by day.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; heard the voice of your words, and was wroth, and sware, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Surely there shall not one of these men of this evil generation see that good land, which I sware to give unto your fathers,</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Save Caleb the son of Jephunneh; he shall see it, and to him will I give the land that he hath trodden upon, and to his children, because he hath wholly followed the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Also the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was angry with me for your sakes, saying, Thou also shalt not go in thither.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;But&lt;/span&gt; Joshua the son of Nun, which standeth before thee, he shall go in thither: encourage him: for he shall cause Israel to inherit it.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Moreover your little ones, which ye said should be a prey, and your children, which in that day had no knowledge between good and evil, they shall go in thither, and unto them will I give it, and they shall possess it.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">But &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; you, turn you, and take your journey into the wilderness by the way of the Red sea.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Then ye answered and said unto me, We have sinned against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, we will go up and fight, according to all that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God commanded us. And when ye had girded on every man his weapons of war, ye were ready to go up into the hill.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, Say unto them, Go not up, neither fight; for I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; not among you; lest ye be smitten before your enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">So I spake unto you; and ye would not hear, but rebelled against the commandment of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and went presumptuously up into the hill.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And the Amorites, which dwelt in that mountain, came out against you, and chased you, as bees do, and destroyed you in Seir, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto Hormah.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And ye returned and wept before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; but the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; would not hearken to your voice, nor give ear unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">So ye abode in Kadesh many days, according unto the days that ye abode &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>