<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="5" name="Deuteronomy" bookPage="deuteronomy.html" title="Deuteronomy" chapterCount="34" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joshua_1.html" nextTitle="Joshua" prevBook="numbers_1.html" prevTitle="Numbers">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="20" nextChapter="deuteronomy_9.html" nextTitle="Deuteronomy 9" prevChapter="deuteronomy_7.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 7" chapterPage="deuteronomy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">All the commandments which I command thee this day shall ye observe to do, that ye may live, and multiply, and go in and possess the land which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sware unto your fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And thou shalt remember all the way which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God led thee these forty years in the wilderness, to humble thee, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; to prove thee, to know what &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in thine heart, whether thou wouldest keep his commandments, or no.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he humbled thee, and suffered thee to hunger, and fed thee with manna, which thou knewest not, neither did thy fathers know; that he might make thee know that man doth not live by bread only, but by every &lt;i&gt;word&lt;/i&gt; that proceedeth out of the mouth of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; doth man live.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thy raiment waxed not old upon thee, neither did thy foot swell, these forty years.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thou shalt also consider in thine heart, that, as a man chasteneth his son, &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God chasteneth thee.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Therefore thou shalt keep the commandments of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, to walk in his ways, and to fear him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God bringeth thee into a good land, a land of brooks of water, of fountains and depths that spring out of valleys and hills;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">A land of wheat, and barley, and vines, and fig trees, and pomegranates; a land of oil olive, and honey;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">A land wherein thou shalt eat bread without scarceness, thou shalt not lack any &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; in it; a land whose stones &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; iron, and out of whose hills thou mayest dig brass.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">When thou hast eaten and art full, then thou shalt bless the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God for the good land which he hath given thee.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Beware that thou forget not the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, in not keeping his commandments, and his judgments, and his statutes, which I command thee this day:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Lest &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; thou hast eaten and art full, and hast built goodly houses, and dwelt &lt;i&gt;therein&lt;/i&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; thy herds and thy flocks multiply, and thy silver and thy gold is multiplied, and all that thou hast is multiplied;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then thine heart be lifted up, and thou forget the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, which brought thee forth out of the land of Egypt, from the house of bondage;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Who led thee through that great and terrible wilderness, &lt;i&gt;wherein were&lt;/i&gt; fiery serpents, and scorpions, and drought, where &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; no water; who brought thee forth water out of the rock of flint;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Who fed thee in the wilderness with manna, which thy fathers knew not, that he might humble thee, and that he might prove thee, to do thee good at thy latter end;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And thou say in thine heart, My power and the might of &lt;i&gt;mine&lt;/i&gt; hand hath gotten me this wealth.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But thou shalt remember the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God: for &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; he that giveth thee power to get wealth, that he may establish his covenant which he sware unto thy fathers, as &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; this day.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And it shall be, if thou do at all forget the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, and walk after other gods, and serve them, and worship them, I testify against you this day that ye shall surely perish.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">As the nations which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; destroyeth before your face, so shall ye perish; because ye would not be obedient unto the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>