<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="27" nextChapter="joshua_7.html" nextTitle="Joshua 7" prevChapter="joshua_5.html" prevTitle="Joshua 5" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now Jericho was straitly shut up because of the children of Israel: none went out, and none came in.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Joshua, See, I have given into thine hand Jericho, and the king thereof, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the mighty men of valour.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And ye shall compass the city, all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ye&lt;/span&gt; men of war, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; go round about the city once. Thus shalt thou do six days.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And seven priests shall bear before the ark seven trumpets of rams' horns: and the seventh day ye shall compass the city seven times, and the priests shall blow with the trumpets.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And it shall come to pass, that when they make a long &lt;span class="extra"&gt;blast&lt;/span&gt; with the ram's horn, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; when ye hear the sound of the trumpet, all the people shall shout with a great shout; and the wall of the city shall fall down flat, and the people shall ascend up every man straight before him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And Joshua the son of Nun called the priests, and said unto them, Take up the ark of the covenant, and let seven priests bear seven trumpets of rams' horns before the ark of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he said unto the people, Pass on, and compass the city, and let him that is armed pass on before the ark of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when Joshua had spoken unto the people, that the seven priests bearing the seven trumpets of rams' horns passed on before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and blew with the trumpets: and the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; followed them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And the armed men went before the priests that blew with the trumpets, and the rereward came after the ark, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the priests&lt;/span&gt; going on, and blowing with the trumpets.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Joshua had commanded the people, saying, Ye shall not shout, nor make any noise with your voice, neither shall &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; word proceed out of your mouth, until the day I bid you shout; then shall ye shout.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">So the ark of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; compassed the city, going about &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; once: and they came into the camp, and lodged in the camp.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And Joshua rose early in the morning, and the priests took up the ark of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And seven priests bearing seven trumpets of rams' horns before the ark of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; went on continually, and blew with the trumpets: and the armed men went before them; but the rereward came after the ark of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the priests&lt;/span&gt; going on, and blowing with the trumpets.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the second day they compassed the city once, and returned into the camp: so they did six days.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And it came to pass on the seventh day, that they rose early about the dawning of the day, and compassed the city after the same manner seven times: only on that day they compassed the city seven times.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And it came to pass at the seventh time, when the priests blew with the trumpets, Joshua said unto the people, Shout; for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath given you the city.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And the city shall be accursed, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; it, and all that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; therein, to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: only Rahab the harlot shall live, she and all that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; with her in the house, because she hid the messengers that we sent.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And ye, in any wise keep &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yourselves&lt;/span&gt; from the accursed thing, lest ye make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yourselves&lt;/span&gt; accursed, when ye take of the accursed thing, and make the camp of Israel a curse, and trouble it.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But all the silver, and gold, and vessels of brass and iron, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; consecrated unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: they shall come into the treasury of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">So the people shouted when &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the priests&lt;/span&gt; blew with the trumpets: and it came to pass, when the people heard the sound of the trumpet, and the people shouted with a great shout, that the wall fell down flat, so that the people went up into the city, every man straight before him, and they took the city.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they utterly destroyed all that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the city, both man and woman, young and old, and ox, and sheep, and ass, with the edge of the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But Joshua had said unto the two men that had spied out the country, Go into the harlot's house, and bring out thence the woman, and all that she hath, as ye sware unto her.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the young men that were spies went in, and brought out Rahab, and her father, and her mother, and her brethren, and all that she had; and they brought out all her kindred, and left them without the camp of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they burnt the city with fire, and all that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; therein: only the silver, and the gold, and the vessels of brass and of iron, they put into the treasury of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Joshua saved Rahab the harlot alive, and her father's household, and all that she had; and she dwelleth in Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto this day; because she hid the messengers, which Joshua sent to spy out Jericho.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And Joshua adjured &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; at that time, saying, Cursed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the man before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that riseth up and buildeth this city Jericho: he shall lay the foundation thereof in his firstborn, and in his youngest &lt;span class="extra"&gt;son&lt;/span&gt; shall he set up the gates of it.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">So the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was with Joshua; and his fame was &lt;span class="extra"&gt;noised&lt;/span&gt; throughout all the country.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>