<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="24" nextChapter="joshua_3.html" nextTitle="Joshua 3" prevChapter="joshua_1.html" prevTitle="Joshua 1" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Joshua the son of Nun sent out of Shittim two men to spy secretly, saying, Go view the land, even Jericho. And they went, and came into an harlot's house, named Rahab, and lodged there.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And it was told the king of Jericho, saying, Behold, there came men in hither to night of the children of Israel to search out the country.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the king of Jericho sent unto Rahab, saying, Bring forth the men that are come to thee, which are entered into thine house: for they be come to search out all the country.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the woman took the two men, and hid them, and said thus, There came men unto me, but I wist not whence they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And it came to pass &lt;span class='extra'&gt;about the time&lt;/span&gt; of shutting of the gate, when it was dark, that the men went out: whither the men went I wot not: pursue after them quickly; for ye shall overtake them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But she had brought them up to the roof of the house, and hid them with the stalks of flax, which she had laid in order upon the roof.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the men pursued after them the way to Jordan unto the fords: and as soon as they which pursued after them were gone out, they shut the gate.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And before they were laid down, she came up unto them upon the roof;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And she said unto the men, I know that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath given you the land, and that your terror is fallen upon us, and that all the inhabitants of the land faint because of you.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For we have heard how the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; dried up the water of the Red sea for you, when ye came out of Egypt; and what ye did unto the two kings of the Amorites, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; on the other side Jordan, Sihon and Og, whom ye utterly destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And as soon as we had heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;these things&lt;/span&gt;, our hearts did melt, neither did there remain any more courage in any man, because of you: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; God in heaven above, and in earth beneath.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Now therefore, I pray you, swear unto me by the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, since I have shewed you kindness, that ye will also shew kindness unto my father's house, and give me a true token:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; ye will save alive my father, and my mother, and my brethren, and my sisters, and all that they have, and deliver our lives from death.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the men answered her, Our life for yours, if ye utter not this our business. And it shall be, when the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath given us the land, that we will deal kindly and truly with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Then she let them down by a cord through the window: for her house &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; upon the town wall, and she dwelt upon the wall.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And she said unto them, Get you to the mountain, lest the pursuers meet you; and hide yourselves there three days, until the pursuers be returned: and afterward may ye go your way.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the men said unto her, We &lt;span class='extra'&gt;will be&lt;/span&gt; blameless of this thine oath which thou hast made us swear.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; we come into the land, thou shalt bind this line of scarlet thread in the window which thou didst let us down by: and thou shalt bring thy father, and thy mother, and thy brethren, and all thy father's household, home unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And it shall be, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; whosoever shall go out of the doors of thy house into the street, his blood &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; upon his head, and we &lt;span class='extra'&gt;will be&lt;/span&gt; guiltless: and whosoever shall be with thee in the house, his blood &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; on our head, if &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; hand be upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And if thou utter this our business, then we will be quit of thine oath which thou hast made us to swear.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And she said, According unto your words, so &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; it. And she sent them away, and they departed: and she bound the scarlet line in the window.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And they went, and came unto the mountain, and abode there three days, until the pursuers were returned: and the pursuers sought &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; throughout all the way, but found &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; not.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">So the two men returned, and descended from the mountain, and passed over, and came to Joshua the son of Nun, and told him all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; that befell them:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they said unto Joshua, Truly the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath delivered into our hands all the land; for even all the inhabitants of the country do faint because of us.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>