<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="23" verseCount="16" nextChapter="joshua_24.html" nextTitle="Joshua 24" prevChapter="joshua_22.html" prevTitle="Joshua 22" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass a long time after that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had given rest unto Israel from all their enemies round about, that Joshua waxed old &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; stricken in age.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Joshua called for all Israel, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; for their elders, and for their heads, and for their judges, and for their officers, and said unto them, I am old &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; stricken in age:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And ye have seen all that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God hath done unto all these nations because of you; for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he that hath fought for you.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Behold, I have divided unto you by lot these nations that remain, to be an inheritance for your tribes, from Jordan, with all the nations that I have cut off, even unto the great sea westward.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, he shall expel them from before you, and drive them from out of your sight; and ye shall possess their land, as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God hath promised unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Be ye therefore very courageous to keep and to do all that is written in the book of the law of Moses, that ye turn not aside therefrom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the right hand or &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the left;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">That ye come not among these nations, these that remain among you; neither make mention of the name of their gods, nor cause to swear &lt;span class="extra"&gt;by them&lt;/span&gt;, neither serve them, nor bow yourselves unto them:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But cleave unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, as ye have done unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath driven out from before you great nations and strong: but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; you, no man hath been able to stand before you unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">One man of you shall chase a thousand: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; that fighteth for you, as he hath promised you.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Take good heed therefore unto yourselves, that ye love the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Else if ye do in any wise go back, and cleave unto the remnant of these nations, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; these that remain among you, and shall make marriages with them, and go in unto them, and they to you:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Know for a certainty that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God will no more drive out &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any of&lt;/span&gt; these nations from before you; but they shall be snares and traps unto you, and scourges in your sides, and thorns in your eyes, until ye perish from off this good land which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God hath given you.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And, behold, this day I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; going the way of all the earth: and ye know in all your hearts and in all your souls, that not one thing hath failed of all the good things which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God spake concerning you; all are come to pass unto you, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; not one thing hath failed thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Therefore it shall come to pass, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; as all good things are come upon you, which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God promised you; so shall the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; bring upon you all evil things, until he have destroyed you from off this good land which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God hath given you.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">When ye have transgressed the covenant of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, which he commanded you, and have gone and served other gods, and bowed yourselves to them; then shall the anger of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be kindled against you, and ye shall perish quickly from off the good land which he hath given unto you.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>