<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="21" verseCount="45" nextChapter="joshua_22.html" nextTitle="Joshua 22" prevChapter="joshua_20.html" prevTitle="Joshua 20" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then came near the heads of the fathers of the Levites unto Eleazar the priest, and unto Joshua the son of Nun, and unto the heads of the fathers of the tribes of the children of Israel;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And they spake unto them at Shiloh in the land of Canaan, saying, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded by the hand of Moses to give us cities to dwell in, with the suburbs thereof for our cattle.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the children of Israel gave unto the Levites out of their inheritance, at the commandment of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, these cities and their suburbs.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the lot came out for the families of the Kohathites: and the children of Aaron the priest, &lt;i&gt;which were&lt;/i&gt; of the Levites, had by lot out of the tribe of Judah, and out of the tribe of Simeon, and out of the tribe of Benjamin, thirteen cities.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the rest of the children of Kohath &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; by lot out of the families of the tribe of Ephraim, and out of the tribe of Dan, and out of the half tribe of Manasseh, ten cities.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the children of Gershon &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; by lot out of the families of the tribe of Issachar, and out of the tribe of Asher, and out of the tribe of Naphtali, and out of the half tribe of Manasseh in Bashan, thirteen cities.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The children of Merari by their families &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; out of the tribe of Reuben, and out of the tribe of Gad, and out of the tribe of Zebulun, twelve cities.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the children of Israel gave by lot unto the Levites these cities with their suburbs, as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded by the hand of Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And they gave out of the tribe of the children of Judah, and out of the tribe of the children of Simeon, these cities which are &lt;i&gt;here&lt;/i&gt; mentioned by name,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Which the children of Aaron, &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; of the families of the Kohathites, &lt;i&gt;who were&lt;/i&gt; of the children of Levi, had: for theirs was the first lot.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And they gave them the city of Arba the father of Anak, which &lt;i&gt;city is&lt;/i&gt; Hebron, in the hill &lt;i&gt;country&lt;/i&gt; of Judah, with the suburbs thereof round about it.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But the fields of the city, and the villages thereof, gave they to Caleb the son of Jephunneh for his possession.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Thus they gave to the children of Aaron the priest Hebron with her suburbs, &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; a city of refuge for the slayer; and Libnah with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Jattir with her suburbs, and Eshtemoa with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Holon with her suburbs, and Debir with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Ain with her suburbs, and Juttah with her suburbs, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Beth-shemesh with her suburbs; nine cities out of those two tribes.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And out of the tribe of Benjamin, Gibeon with her suburbs, Geba with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Anathoth with her suburbs, and Almon with her suburbs; four cities.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">All the cities of the children of Aaron, the priests, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thirteen cities with their suburbs.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And the families of the children of Kohath, the Levites which remained of the children of Kohath, even they had the cities of their lot out of the tribe of Ephraim.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For they gave them Shechem with her suburbs in mount Ephraim, &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; a city of refuge for the slayer; and Gezer with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Kibzaim with her suburbs, and Beth-horon with her suburbs; four cities.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And out of the tribe of Dan, Eltekeh with her suburbs, Gibbethon with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Aijalon with her suburbs, Gath-rimmon with her suburbs; four cities.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And out of the half tribe of Manasseh, Tanach with her suburbs, and Gath-rimmon with her suburbs; two cities.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">All the cities &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; ten with their suburbs for the families of the children of Kohath that remained.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And unto the children of Gershon, of the families of the Levites, out of the &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; half tribe of Manasseh &lt;i&gt;they gave&lt;/i&gt; Golan in Bashan with her suburbs, &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; a city of refuge for the slayer; and Beesh-terah with her suburbs; two cities.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And out of the tribe of Issachar, Kishon with her suburbs, Dabareh with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Jarmuth with her suburbs, En-gannim with her suburbs; four cities.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And out of the tribe of Asher, Mishal with her suburbs, Abdon with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Helkath with her suburbs, and Rehob with her suburbs; four cities.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And out of the tribe of Naphtali, Kedesh in Galilee with her suburbs, &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; a city of refuge for the slayer; and Hammoth-dor with her suburbs, and Kartan with her suburbs; three cities.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">All the cities of the Gershonites according to their families &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thirteen cities with their suburbs.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">And unto the families of the children of Merari, the rest of the Levites, out of the tribe of Zebulun, Jokneam with her suburbs, and Kartah with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Dimnah with her suburbs, Nahalal with her suburbs; four cities.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And out of the tribe of Reuben, Bezer with her suburbs, and Jahazah with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Kedemoth with her suburbs, and Mephaath with her suburbs; four cities.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And out of the tribe of Gad, Ramoth in Gilead with her suburbs, &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; a city of refuge for the slayer; and Mahanaim with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Heshbon with her suburbs, Jazer with her suburbs; four cities in all.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">So all the cities for the children of Merari by their families, which were remaining of the families of the Levites, were &lt;i&gt;by&lt;/i&gt; their lot twelve cities.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">All the cities of the Levites within the possession of the children of Israel &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; forty and eight cities with their suburbs.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">These cities were every one with their suburbs round about them: thus &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; all these cities.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43" newPara="true">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; gave unto Israel all the land which he sware to give unto their fathers; and they possessed it, and dwelt therein.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; gave them rest round about, according to all that he sware unto their fathers: and there stood not a man of all their enemies before them; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; delivered all their enemies into their hand.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">There failed not ought of any good thing which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had spoken unto the house of Israel; all came to pass.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>