<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="63" nextChapter="joshua_16.html" nextTitle="Joshua 16" prevChapter="joshua_14.html" prevTitle="Joshua 14" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;i&gt;This&lt;/i&gt; then was the lot of the tribe of the children of Judah by their families; &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to the border of Edom the wilderness of Zin southward &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the uttermost part of the south coast.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And their south border was from the shore of the salt sea, from the bay that looketh southward:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And it went out to the south side to Maaleh-acrabbim, and passed along to Zin, and ascended up on the south side unto Kadesh-barnea, and passed along to Hezron, and went up to Adar, and fetched a compass to Karkaa:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;i&gt;From thence&lt;/i&gt; it passed toward Azmon, and went out unto the river of Egypt; and the goings out of that coast were at the sea: this shall be your south coast.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the east border &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the salt sea, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; unto the end of Jordan. And &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; border in the north quarter &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; from the bay of the sea at the uttermost part of Jordan:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the border went up to Beth-hogla, and passed along by the north of Beth-arabah; and the border went up to the stone of Bohan the son of Reuben:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the border went up toward Debir from the valley of Achor, and so northward, looking toward Gilgal, that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; before the going up to Adummim, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; on the south side of the river: and the border passed toward the waters of En-shemesh, and the goings out thereof were at En-rogel:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the border went up by the valley of the son of Hinnom unto the south side of the Jebusite; the same &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Jerusalem: and the border went up to the top of the mountain that &lt;i&gt;lieth&lt;/i&gt; before the valley of Hinnom westward, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; at the end of the valley of the giants northward:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the border was drawn from the top of the hill unto the fountain of the water of Nephtoah, and went out to the cities of mount Ephron; and the border was drawn to Baalah, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Kirjath-jearim:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the border compassed from Baalah westward unto mount Seir, and passed along unto the side of mount Jearim, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Chesalon, on the north side, and went down to Beth-shemesh, and passed on to Timnah:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the border went out unto the side of Ekron northward: and the border was drawn to Shicron, and passed along to mount Baalah, and went out unto Jabneel; and the goings out of the border were at the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the west border &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; to the great sea, and the coast &lt;i&gt;thereof&lt;/i&gt;. This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the coast of the children of Judah round about according to their families.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And unto Caleb the son of Jephunneh he gave a part among the children of Judah, according to the commandment of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to Joshua, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the city of Arba the father of Anak, which &lt;i&gt;city is&lt;/i&gt; Hebron.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Caleb drove thence the three sons of Anak, Sheshai, and Ahiman, and Talmai, the children of Anak.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he went up thence to the inhabitants of Debir: and the name of Debir before &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Kirjath-sepher.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And Caleb said, He that smiteth Kirjath-sepher, and taketh it, to him will I give Achsah my daughter to wife.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Othniel the son of Kenaz, the brother of Caleb, took it: and he gave him Achsah his daughter to wife.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And it came to pass, as she came &lt;i&gt;unto him&lt;/i&gt;, that she moved him to ask of her father a field: and she lighted off &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; ass; and Caleb said unto her, What wouldest thou?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Who answered, Give me a blessing; for thou hast given me a south land; give me also springs of water. And he gave her the upper springs, and the nether springs.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Judah according to their families.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the uttermost cities of the tribe of the children of Judah toward the coast of Edom southward were Kabzeel, and Eder, and Jagur,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Kinah, and Dimonah, and Adadah,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Kedesh, and Hazor, and Ithnan,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Ziph, and Telem, and Bealoth,</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Hazor, Hadattah, and Kerioth, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Hezron, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Hazor,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Amam, and Shema, and Moladah,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Hazar-gaddah, and Heshmon, and Beth-palet,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Hazar-shual, and Beer-sheba, and Bizjothjah,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Baalah, and Iim, and Azem,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Eltolad, and Chesil, and Hormah,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Ziklag, and Madmannah, and Sansannah,</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And Lebaoth, and Shilhim, and Ain, and Rimmon: all the cities &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; twenty and nine, with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;i&gt;And&lt;/i&gt; in the valley, Eshtaol, and Zoreah, and Ashnah,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And Zanoah, and En-gannim, Tappuah, and Enam,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Jarmuth, and Adullam, Socoh, and Azekah,</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And Sharaim, and Adithaim, and Gederah, and Gederothaim; fourteen cities with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Zenan, and Hadashah, and Migdal-gad,</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And Dilean, and Mizpeh, and Joktheel,</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Lachish, and Bozkath, and Eglon,</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And Cabbon, and Lahmam, and Kithlish,</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And Gederoth, Beth-dagon, and Naamah, and Makkedah; sixteen cities with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Libnah, and Ether, and Ashan,</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And Jiphtah, and Ashnah, and Nezib,</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And Keilah, and Achzib, and Mareshah; nine cities with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">Ekron, with her towns and her villages:</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">From Ekron even unto the sea, all that &lt;i&gt;lay&lt;/i&gt; near Ashdod, with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">Ashdod with her towns and her villages, Gaza with her towns and her villages, unto the river of Egypt, and the great sea, and the border &lt;i&gt;thereof&lt;/i&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48" newPara="true">And in the mountains, Shamir, and Jattir, and Socoh,</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And Dannah, and Kirjath-sannah, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Debir,</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">And Anab, and Eshtemoh, and Anim,</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And Goshen, and Holon, and Giloh; eleven cities with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">Arab, and Dumah, and Eshean,</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">And Janum, and Beth-tappuah, and Aphekah,</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">And Humtah, and Kirjath-arba, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Hebron, and Zior; nine cities with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">Maon, Carmel, and Ziph, and Juttah,</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">And Jezreel, and Jokdeam, and Zanoah,</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">Cain, Gibeah, and Timnah; ten cities with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">Halhul, Beth-zur, and Gedor,</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">And Maarath, and Beth-anoth, and Eltekon; six cities with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="60" id="v60">Kirjath-baal, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Kirjath-jearim, and Rabbah; two cities with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="61" id="v61">In the wilderness, Beth-arabah, Middin, and Secacah,</verse>
      <verse number="62" id="v62">And Nibshan, and the city of Salt, and En-gedi; six cities with their villages.</verse>
      <verse number="63" id="v63" newPara="true">As for the Jebusites the inhabitants of Jerusalem, the children of Judah could not drive them out: but the Jebusites dwell with the children of Judah at Jerusalem unto this day.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>