<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="15" nextChapter="joshua_6.html" nextTitle="Joshua 6" prevChapter="joshua_4.html" prevTitle="Joshua 4" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, when all the kings of the Amorites, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; on the side of Jordan westward, and all the kings of the Canaanites, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; by the sea, heard that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had dried up the waters of Jordan from before the children of Israel, until we were passed over, that their heart melted, neither was there spirit in them any more, because of the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">At that time the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Joshua, Make thee sharp knives, and circumcise again the children of Israel the second time.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Joshua made him sharp knives, and circumcised the children of Israel at the hill of the foreskins.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the cause why Joshua did circumcise: All the people that came out of Egypt, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that were&lt;/span&gt; males, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all the men of war, died in the wilderness by the way, after they came out of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Now all the people that came out were circumcised: but all the people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that were&lt;/span&gt; born in the wilderness by the way as they came forth out of Egypt, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; they had not circumcised.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For the children of Israel walked forty years in the wilderness, till all the people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that were&lt;/span&gt; men of war, which came out of Egypt, were consumed, because they obeyed not the voice of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: unto whom the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sware that he would not shew them the land, which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sware unto their fathers that he would give us, a land that floweth with milk and honey.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And their children, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;whom&lt;/span&gt; he raised up in their stead, them Joshua circumcised: for they were uncircumcised, because they had not circumcised them by the way.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And it came to pass, when they had done circumcising all the people, that they abode in their places in the camp, till they were whole.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Joshua, This day have I rolled away the reproach of Egypt from off you. Wherefore the name of the place is called Gilgal unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And the children of Israel encamped in Gilgal, and kept the passover on the fourteenth day of the month at even in the plains of Jericho.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And they did eat of the old corn of the land on the morrow after the passover, unleavened cakes, and parched &lt;span class="extra"&gt;corn&lt;/span&gt; in the selfsame day.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And the manna ceased on the morrow after they had eaten of the old corn of the land; neither had the children of Israel manna any more; but they did eat of the fruit of the land of Canaan that year.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when Joshua was by Jericho, that he lifted up his eyes and looked, and, behold, there stood a man over against him with his sword drawn in his hand: and Joshua went unto him, and said unto him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Art&lt;/span&gt; thou for us, or for our adversaries?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he said, Nay; but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; captain of the host of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; am I now come. And Joshua fell on his face to the earth, and did worship, and said unto him, What saith my lord unto his servant?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the captain of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s host said unto Joshua, Loose thy shoe from off thy foot; for the place whereon thou standest &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; holy. And Joshua did so.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>