<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="28" nextChapter="joshua_19.html" nextTitle="Joshua 19" prevChapter="joshua_17.html" prevTitle="Joshua 17" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the whole congregation of the children of Israel assembled together at Shiloh, and set up the tabernacle of the congregation there. And the land was subdued before them.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And there remained among the children of Israel seven tribes, which had not yet received their inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Joshua said unto the children of Israel, How long &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; ye slack to go to possess the land, which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of your fathers hath given you?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Give out from among you three men for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; tribe: and I will send them, and they shall rise, and go through the land, and describe it according to the inheritance of them; and they shall come &lt;span class="extra"&gt;again&lt;/span&gt; to me.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they shall divide it into seven parts: Judah shall abide in their coast on the south, and the house of Joseph shall abide in their coasts on the north.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Ye shall therefore describe the land &lt;span class="extra"&gt;into&lt;/span&gt; seven parts, and bring &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the description&lt;/span&gt; hither to me, that I may cast lots for you here before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But the Levites have no part among you; for the priesthood of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; their inheritance: and Gad, and Reuben, and half the tribe of Manasseh, have received their inheritance beyond Jordan on the east, which Moses the servant of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; gave them.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And the men arose, and went away: and Joshua charged them that went to describe the land, saying, Go and walk through the land, and describe it, and come again to me, that I may here cast lots for you before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in Shiloh.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the men went and passed through the land, and described it by cities into seven parts in a book, and came &lt;span class="extra"&gt;again&lt;/span&gt; to Joshua to the host at Shiloh.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And Joshua cast lots for them in Shiloh before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and there Joshua divided the land unto the children of Israel according to their divisions.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And the lot of the tribe of the children of Benjamin came up according to their families: and the coast of their lot came forth between the children of Judah and the children of Joseph.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And their border on the north side was from Jordan; and the border went up to the side of Jericho on the north side, and went up through the mountains westward; and the goings out thereof were at the wilderness of Beth-aven.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the border went over from thence toward Luz, to the side of Luz, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Beth-el, southward; and the border descended to Ataroth-adar, near the hill that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;lieth&lt;/span&gt; on the south side of the nether Beth-horon.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the border was drawn &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thence&lt;/span&gt;, and compassed the corner of the sea southward, from the hill that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;lieth&lt;/span&gt; before Beth-horon southward; and the goings out thereof were at Kirjath-baal, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Kirjath-jearim, a city of the children of Judah: this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the west quarter.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the south quarter &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; from the end of Kirjath-jearim, and the border went out on the west, and went out to the well of waters of Nephtoah:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the border came down to the end of the mountain that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;lieth&lt;/span&gt; before the valley of the son of Hinnom, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the valley of the giants on the north, and descended to the valley of Hinnom, to the side of Jebusi on the south, and descended to En-rogel,</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And was drawn from the north, and went forth to En-shemesh, and went forth toward Geliloth, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; over against the going up of Adummim, and descended to the stone of Bohan the son of Reuben,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And passed along toward the side over against Arabah northward, and went down unto Arabah:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the border passed along to the side of Beth-hoglah northward: and the outgoings of the border were at the north bay of the salt sea at the south end of Jordan: this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the south coast.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Jordan was the border of it on the east side. This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the inheritance of the children of Benjamin, by the coasts thereof round about, according to their families.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Now the cities of the tribe of the children of Benjamin according to their families were Jericho, and Beth-hoglah, and the valley of Keziz,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Beth-arabah, and Zemaraim, and Beth-el,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Avim, and Parah, and Ophrah,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Chephar-haammonai, and Ophni, and Gaba; twelve cities with their villages:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Gibeon, and Ramah, and Beeroth,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Mizpeh, and Chephirah, and Mozah,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Rekem, and Irpeel, and Taralah,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Zelah, Eleph, and Jebusi, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Jerusalem, Gibeath, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Kirjath; fourteen cities with their villages. This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the inheritance of the children of Benjamin according to their families.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>