<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="18" nextChapter="joshua_2.html" nextTitle="Joshua 2" prevChapter="deuteronomy_34.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy 34" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now after the death of Moses the servant of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; it came to pass, that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto Joshua the son of Nun, Moses' minister, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Moses my servant is dead; now therefore arise, go over this Jordan, thou, and all this people, unto the land which I do give to them, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Every place that the sole of your foot shall tread upon, that have I given unto you, as I said unto Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">From the wilderness and this Lebanon even unto the great river, the river Euphrates, all the land of the Hittites, and unto the great sea toward the going down of the sun, shall be your coast.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">There shall not any man be able to stand before thee all the days of thy life: as I was with Moses, &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; I will be with thee: I will not fail thee, nor forsake thee.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Be strong and of a good courage: for unto this people shalt thou divide for an inheritance the land, which I sware unto their fathers to give them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Only be thou strong and very courageous, that thou mayest observe to do according to all the law, which Moses my servant commanded thee: turn not from it &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; the right hand or &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; the left, that thou mayest prosper whithersoever thou goest.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">This book of the law shall not depart out of thy mouth; but thou shalt meditate therein day and night, that thou mayest observe to do according to all that is written therein: for then thou shalt make thy way prosperous, and then thou shalt have good success.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Have not I commanded thee? Be strong and of a good courage; be not afraid, neither be thou dismayed: for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with thee whithersoever thou goest.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Then Joshua commanded the officers of the people, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Pass through the host, and command the people, saying, Prepare you victuals; for within three days ye shall pass over this Jordan, to go in to possess the land, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God giveth you to possess it.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And to the Reubenites, and to the Gadites, and to half the tribe of Manasseh, spake Joshua, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Remember the word which Moses the servant of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded you, saying, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God hath given you rest, and hath given you this land.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Your wives, your little ones, and your cattle, shall remain in the land which Moses gave you on this side Jordan; but ye shall pass before your brethren armed, all the mighty men of valour, and help them;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Until the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have given your brethren rest, as &lt;i&gt;he hath given&lt;/i&gt; you, and they also have possessed the land which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God giveth them: then ye shall return unto the land of your possession, and enjoy it, which Moses the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s servant gave you on this side Jordan toward the sunrising.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And they answered Joshua, saying, All that thou commandest us we will do, and whithersoever thou sendest us, we will go.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">According as we hearkened unto Moses in all things, so will we hearken unto thee: only the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God be with thee, as he was with Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Whosoever &lt;i&gt;he be&lt;/i&gt; that doth rebel against thy commandment, and will not hearken unto thy words in all that thou commandest him, he shall be put to death: only be strong and of a good courage.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>