<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="35" nextChapter="joshua_9.html" nextTitle="Joshua 9" prevChapter="joshua_7.html" prevTitle="Joshua 7" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Joshua, Fear not, neither be thou dismayed: take all the people of war with thee, and arise, go up to Ai: see, I have given into thy hand the king of Ai, and his people, and his city, and his land:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And thou shalt do to Ai and her king as thou didst unto Jericho and her king: only the spoil thereof, and the cattle thereof, shall ye take for a prey unto yourselves: lay thee an ambush for the city behind it.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">So Joshua arose, and all the people of war, to go up against Ai: and Joshua chose out thirty thousand mighty men of valour, and sent them away by night.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he commanded them, saying, Behold, ye shall lie in wait against the city, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; behind the city: go not very far from the city, but be ye all ready:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And I, and all the people that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; with me, will approach unto the city: and it shall come to pass, when they come out against us, as at the first, that we will flee before them,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">(For they will come out after us) till we have drawn them from the city; for they will say, They flee before us, as at the first: therefore we will flee before them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then ye shall rise up from the ambush, and seize upon the city: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God will deliver it into your hand.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And it shall be, when ye have taken the city, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; ye shall set the city on fire: according to the commandment of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall ye do. See, I have commanded you.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Joshua therefore sent them forth: and they went to lie in ambush, and abode between Beth-el and Ai, on the west side of Ai: but Joshua lodged that night among the people.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Joshua rose up early in the morning, and numbered the people, and went up, he and the elders of Israel, before the people to Ai.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And all the people, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even the people&lt;/span&gt; of war that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him, went up, and drew nigh, and came before the city, and pitched on the north side of Ai: now &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; a valley between them and Ai.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he took about five thousand men, and set them to lie in ambush between Beth-el and Ai, on the west side of the city.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And when they had set the people, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all the host that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; on the north of the city, and their liers in wait on the west of the city, Joshua went that night into the midst of the valley.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when the king of Ai saw &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, that they hasted and rose up early, and the men of the city went out against Israel to battle, he and all his people, at a time appointed, before the plain; but he wist not that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there were&lt;/span&gt; liers in ambush against him behind the city.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Joshua and all Israel made as if they were beaten before them, and fled by the way of the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And all the people that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Ai were called together to pursue after them: and they pursued after Joshua, and were drawn away from the city.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And there was not a man left in Ai or Beth-el, that went not out after Israel: and they left the city open, and pursued after Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Joshua, Stretch out the spear that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in thy hand toward Ai; for I will give it into thine hand. And Joshua stretched out the spear that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he had&lt;/span&gt; in his hand toward the city.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the ambush arose quickly out of their place, and they ran as soon as he had stretched out his hand: and they entered into the city, and took it, and hasted and set the city on fire.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And when the men of Ai looked behind them, they saw, and, behold, the smoke of the city ascended up to heaven, and they had no power to flee this way or that way: and the people that fled to the wilderness turned back upon the pursuers.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And when Joshua and all Israel saw that the ambush had taken the city, and that the smoke of the city ascended, then they turned again, and slew the men of Ai.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the other issued out of the city against them; so they were in the midst of Israel, some on this side, and some on that side: and they smote them, so that they let none of them remain or escape.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the king of Ai they took alive, and brought him to Joshua.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And it came to pass, when Israel had made an end of slaying all the inhabitants of Ai in the field, in the wilderness wherein they chased them, and when they were all fallen on the edge of the sword, until they were consumed, that all the Israelites returned unto Ai, and smote it with the edge of the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; it was, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; all that fell that day, both of men and women, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; twelve thousand, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all the men of Ai.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For Joshua drew not his hand back, wherewith he stretched out the spear, until he had utterly destroyed all the inhabitants of Ai.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Only the cattle and the spoil of that city Israel took for a prey unto themselves, according unto the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which he commanded Joshua.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Joshua burnt Ai, and made it an heap for ever, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; a desolation unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And the king of Ai he hanged on a tree until eventide: and as soon as the sun was down, Joshua commanded that they should take his carcase down from the tree, and cast it at the entering of the gate of the city, and raise thereon a great heap of stones, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that remaineth&lt;/span&gt; unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">Then Joshua built an altar unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel in mount Ebal,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">As Moses the servant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded the children of Israel, as it is written in the book of the law of Moses, an altar of whole stones, over which no man hath lift up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; iron: and they offered thereon burnt offerings unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and sacrificed peace offerings.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">And he wrote there upon the stones a copy of the law of Moses, which he wrote in the presence of the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And all Israel, and their elders, and officers, and their judges, stood on this side the ark and on that side before the priests the Levites, which bare the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as well the stranger, as he that was born among them; half of them over against mount Gerizim, and half of them over against mount Ebal; as Moses the servant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had commanded before, that they should bless the people of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And afterward he read all the words of the law, the blessings and cursings, according to all that is written in the book of the law.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">There was not a word of all that Moses commanded, which Joshua read not before all the congregation of Israel, with the women, and the little ones, and the strangers that were conversant among them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>