<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="10" nextChapter="joshua_17.html" nextTitle="Joshua 17" prevChapter="joshua_15.html" prevTitle="Joshua 15" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the lot of the children of Joseph fell from Jordan by Jericho, unto the water of Jericho on the east, to the wilderness that goeth up from Jericho throughout mount Beth-el,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And goeth out from Beth-el to Luz, and passeth along unto the borders of Archi to Ataroth,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And goeth down westward to the coast of Japhleti, unto the coast of Beth-horon the nether, and to Gezer: and the goings out thereof are at the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">So the children of Joseph, Manasseh and Ephraim, took their inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And the border of the children of Ephraim according to their families was &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thus&lt;/span&gt;: even the border of their inheritance on the east side was Ataroth-addar, unto Beth-horon the upper;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the border went out toward the sea to Michmethah on the north side; and the border went about eastward unto Taanath-shiloh, and passed by it on the east to Janohah;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And it went down from Janohah to Ataroth, and to Naarath, and came to Jericho, and went out at Jordan.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The border went out from Tappuah westward unto the river Kanah; and the goings out thereof were at the sea. This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the inheritance of the tribe of the children of Ephraim by their families.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the separate cities for the children of Ephraim &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; among the inheritance of the children of Manasseh, all the cities with their villages.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they drave not out the Canaanites that dwelt in Gezer: but the Canaanites dwell among the Ephraimites unto this day, and serve under tribute.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>