<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="6" name="Joshua" bookPage="joshua.html" title="Joshua" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges" prevBook="deuteronomy_1.html" prevTitle="Deuteronomy">
    <chapter number="24" verseCount="33" nextChapter="judges_1.html" nextTitle="Judges 1" prevChapter="joshua_23.html" prevTitle="Joshua 23" chapterPage="joshua_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Joshua gathered all the tribes of Israel to Shechem, and called for the elders of Israel, and for their heads, and for their judges, and for their officers; and they presented themselves before God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Joshua said unto all the people, Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, Your fathers dwelt on the other side of the flood in old time, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; Terah, the father of Abraham, and the father of Nachor: and they served other gods.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I took your father Abraham from the other side of the flood, and led him throughout all the land of Canaan, and multiplied his seed, and gave him Isaac.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And I gave unto Isaac Jacob and Esau: and I gave unto Esau mount Seir, to possess it; but Jacob and his children went down into Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I sent Moses also and Aaron, and I plagued Egypt, according to that which I did among them: and afterward I brought you out.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I brought your fathers out of Egypt: and ye came unto the sea; and the Egyptians pursued after your fathers with chariots and horsemen unto the Red sea.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when they cried unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, he put darkness between you and the Egyptians, and brought the sea upon them, and covered them; and your eyes have seen what I have done in Egypt: and ye dwelt in the wilderness a long season.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I brought you into the land of the Amorites, which dwelt on the other side Jordan; and they fought with you: and I gave them into your hand, that ye might possess their land; and I destroyed them from before you.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then Balak the son of Zippor, king of Moab, arose and warred against Israel, and sent and called Balaam the son of Beor to curse you:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But I would not hearken unto Balaam; therefore he blessed you still: so I delivered you out of his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And ye went over Jordan, and came unto Jericho: and the men of Jericho fought against you, the Amorites, and the Perizzites, and the Canaanites, and the Hittites, and the Girgashites, the Hivites, and the Jebusites; and I delivered them into your hand.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I sent the hornet before you, which drave them out from before you, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the two kings of the Amorites; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; not with thy sword, nor with thy bow.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And I have given you a land for which ye did not labour, and cities which ye built not, and ye dwell in them; of the vineyards and oliveyards which ye planted not do ye eat.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Now therefore fear the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and serve him in sincerity and in truth: and put away the gods which your fathers served on the other side of the flood, and in Egypt; and serve ye the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And if it seem evil unto you to serve the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, choose you this day whom ye will serve; whether the gods which your fathers served that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; on the other side of the flood, or the gods of the Amorites, in whose land ye dwell: but as for me and my house, we will serve the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the people answered and said, God forbid that we should forsake the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to serve other gods;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; that brought us up and our fathers out of the land of Egypt, from the house of bondage, and which did those great signs in our sight, and preserved us in all the way wherein we went, and among all the people through whom we passed:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; drave out from before us all the people, even the Amorites which dwelt in the land: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;therefore&lt;/span&gt; will we also serve the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our God.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Joshua said unto the people, Ye cannot serve the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an holy God; he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a jealous God; he will not forgive your transgressions nor your sins.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">If ye forsake the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and serve strange gods, then he will turn and do you hurt, and consume you, after that he hath done you good.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the people said unto Joshua, Nay; but we will serve the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Joshua said unto the people, Ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; witnesses against yourselves that ye have chosen you the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to serve him. And they said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;We are&lt;/span&gt; witnesses.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Now therefore put away, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;said he&lt;/span&gt;, the strange gods which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; among you, and incline your heart unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the people said unto Joshua, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God will we serve, and his voice will we obey.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">So Joshua made a covenant with the people that day, and set them a statute and an ordinance in Shechem.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And Joshua wrote these words in the book of the law of God, and took a great stone, and set it up there under an oak, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; by the sanctuary of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Joshua said unto all the people, Behold, this stone shall be a witness unto us; for it hath heard all the words of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which he spake unto us: it shall be therefore a witness unto you, lest ye deny your God.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">So Joshua let the people depart, every man unto his inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">And it came to pass after these things, that Joshua the son of Nun, the servant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, died, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; an hundred and ten years old.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And they buried him in the border of his inheritance in Timnath-serah, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in mount Ephraim, on the north side of the hill of Gaash.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Israel served the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; all the days of Joshua, and all the days of the elders that overlived Joshua, and which had known all the works of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that he had done for Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">And the bones of Joseph, which the children of Israel brought up out of Egypt, buried they in Shechem, in a parcel of ground which Jacob bought of the sons of Hamor the father of Shechem for an hundred pieces of silver: and it became the inheritance of the children of Joseph.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And Eleazar the son of Aaron died; and they buried him in a hill &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that pertained to&lt;/span&gt; Phinehas his son, which was given him in mount Ephraim.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>