<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="7" name="Judges" bookPage="judges.html" title="Judges" chapterCount="21" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ruth_1.html" nextTitle="Ruth" prevBook="joshua_1.html" prevTitle="Joshua">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="31" nextChapter="judges_6.html" nextTitle="Judges 6" prevChapter="judges_4.html" prevTitle="Judges 4" chapterPage="judges_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then sang Deborah and Barak the son of Abinoam on that day, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Praise ye the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for the avenging of Israel, when the people willingly offered themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Hear, O ye kings; give ear, O ye princes; I, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; I, will sing unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; I will sing &lt;i&gt;praise&lt;/i&gt; to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, when thou wentest out of Seir, when thou marchedst out of the field of Edom, the earth trembled, and the heavens dropped, the clouds also dropped water.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The mountains melted from before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; that Sinai from before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">In the days of Shamgar the son of Anath, in the days of Jael, the highways were unoccupied, and the travellers walked through byways.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;i&gt;The inhabitants of&lt;/i&gt; the villages ceased, they ceased in Israel, until that I Deborah arose, that I arose a mother in Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">They chose new gods; then &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; war in the gates: was there a shield or spear seen among forty thousand in Israel?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">My heart &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; toward the governors of Israel, that offered themselves willingly among the people. Bless ye the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Speak, ye that ride on white asses, ye that sit in judgment, and walk by the way.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;i&gt;They that are delivered&lt;/i&gt; from the noise of archers in the places of drawing water, there shall they rehearse the righteous acts of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the righteous acts &lt;i&gt;toward the inhabitants&lt;/i&gt; of his villages in Israel: then shall the people of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; go down to the gates.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Awake, awake, Deborah: awake, awake, utter a song: arise, Barak, and lead thy captivity captive, thou son of Abinoam.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then he made him that remaineth have dominion over the nobles among the people: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made me have dominion over the mighty.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Out of Ephraim &lt;i&gt;was there&lt;/i&gt; a root of them against Amalek; after thee, Benjamin, among thy people; out of Machir came down governors, and out of Zebulun they that handle the pen of the writer.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the princes of Issachar &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with Deborah; even Issachar, and also Barak: he was sent on foot into the valley. For the divisions of Reuben &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; great thoughts of heart.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Why abodest thou among the sheepfolds, to hear the bleatings of the flocks? For the divisions of Reuben &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; great searchings of heart.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Gilead abode beyond Jordan: and why did Dan remain in ships? Asher continued on the sea shore, and abode in his breaches.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Zebulun and Naphtali &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; a people &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; jeoparded their lives unto the death in the high places of the field.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The kings came &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; fought, then fought the kings of Canaan in Taanach by the waters of Megiddo; they took no gain of money.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">They fought from heaven; the stars in their courses fought against Sisera.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The river of Kishon swept them away, that ancient river, the river Kishon. O my soul, thou hast trodden down strength.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then were the horsehoofs broken by the means of the pransings, the pransings of their mighty ones.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Curse ye Meroz, said the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, curse ye bitterly the inhabitants thereof; because they came not to the help of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to the help of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; against the mighty.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Blessed above women shall Jael the wife of Heber the Kenite be, blessed shall she be above women in the tent.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">He asked water, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; she gave &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; milk; she brought forth butter in a lordly dish.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">She put her hand to the nail, and her right hand to the workmen's hammer; and with the hammer she smote Sisera, she smote off his head, when she had pierced and stricken through his temples.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">At her feet he bowed, he fell, he lay down: at her feet he bowed, he fell: where he bowed, there he fell down dead.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The mother of Sisera looked out at a window, and cried through the lattice, Why is his chariot &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; long in coming? why tarry the wheels of his chariots?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Her wise ladies answered her, yea, she returned answer to herself,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Have they not sped? have they &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; divided the prey; to every man a damsel &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; two; to Sisera a prey of divers colours, a prey of divers colours of needlework, of divers colours of needlework on both sides, &lt;i&gt;meet&lt;/i&gt; for the necks of &lt;i&gt;them that take&lt;/i&gt; the spoil?</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">So let all thine enemies perish, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but &lt;i&gt;let&lt;/i&gt; them that love him &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; as the sun when he goeth forth in his might. And the land had rest forty years.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>