<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="7" name="Judges" bookPage="judges.html" title="Judges" chapterCount="21" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ruth_1.html" nextTitle="Ruth" prevBook="joshua_1.html" prevTitle="Joshua">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="31" nextChapter="judges_4.html" nextTitle="Judges 4" prevChapter="judges_2.html" prevTitle="Judges 2" chapterPage="judges_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the nations which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; left, to prove Israel by them, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; as many &lt;i&gt;of Israel&lt;/i&gt; as had not known all the wars of Canaan;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Only that the generations of the children of Israel might know, to teach them war, at the least such as before knew nothing thereof;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;i&gt;Namely&lt;/i&gt;, five lords of the Philistines, and all the Canaanites, and the Sidonians, and the Hivites that dwelt in mount Lebanon, from mount Baal-hermon unto the entering in of Hamath.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they were to prove Israel by them, to know whether they would hearken unto the commandments of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which he commanded their fathers by the hand of Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And the children of Israel dwelt among the Canaanites, Hittites, and Amorites, and Perizzites, and Hivites, and Jebusites:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And they took their daughters to be their wives, and gave their daughters to their sons, and served their gods.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the children of Israel did evil in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and forgat the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God, and served Baalim and the groves.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Therefore the anger of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was hot against Israel, and he sold them into the hand of Chushan-rishathaim king of Mesopotamia: and the children of Israel served Chushan-rishathaim eight years.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And when the children of Israel cried unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; raised up a deliverer to the children of Israel, who delivered them, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; Othniel the son of Kenaz, Caleb's younger brother.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the Spirit of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came upon him, and he judged Israel, and went out to war: and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; delivered Chushan-rishathaim king of Mesopotamia into his hand; and his hand prevailed against Chushan-rishathaim.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the land had rest forty years. And Othniel the son of Kenaz died.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And the children of Israel did evil again in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; strengthened Eglon the king of Moab against Israel, because they had done evil in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he gathered unto him the children of Ammon and Amalek, and went and smote Israel, and possessed the city of palm trees.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">So the children of Israel served Eglon the king of Moab eighteen years.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But when the children of Israel cried unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; raised them up a deliverer, Ehud the son of Gera, a Benjamite, a man lefthanded: and by him the children of Israel sent a present unto Eglon the king of Moab.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But Ehud made him a dagger which had two edges, of a cubit length; and he did gird it under his raiment upon his right thigh.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he brought the present unto Eglon king of Moab: and Eglon &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a very fat man.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And when he had made an end to offer the present, he sent away the people that bare the present.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But he himself turned again from the quarries that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; by Gilgal, and said, I have a secret errand unto thee, O king: who said, Keep silence. And all that stood by him went out from him.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Ehud came unto him; and he was sitting in a summer parlour, which he had for himself alone. And Ehud said, I have a message from God unto thee. And he arose out of &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; seat.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Ehud put forth his left hand, and took the dagger from his right thigh, and thrust it into his belly:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the haft also went in after the blade; and the fat closed upon the blade, so that he could not draw the dagger out of his belly; and the dirt came out.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Then Ehud went forth through the porch, and shut the doors of the parlour upon him, and locked them.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">When he was gone out, his servants came; and when they saw that, behold, the doors of the parlour &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; locked, they said, Surely he covereth his feet in his summer chamber.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they tarried till they were ashamed: and, behold, he opened not the doors of the parlour; therefore they took a key, and opened &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;: and, behold, their lord &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; fallen down dead on the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Ehud escaped while they tarried, and passed beyond the quarries, and escaped unto Seirath.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And it came to pass, when he was come, that he blew a trumpet in the mountain of Ephraim, and the children of Israel went down with him from the mount, and he before them.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he said unto them, Follow after me: for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath delivered your enemies the Moabites into your hand. And they went down after him, and took the fords of Jordan toward Moab, and suffered not a man to pass over.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And they slew of Moab at that time about ten thousand men, all lusty, and all men of valour; and there escaped not a man.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">So Moab was subdued that day under the hand of Israel. And the land had rest fourscore years.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And after him was Shamgar the son of Anath, which slew of the Philistines six hundred men with an ox goad: and he also delivered Israel.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>