<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="7" name="Judges" bookPage="judges.html" title="Judges" chapterCount="21" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ruth_1.html" nextTitle="Ruth" prevBook="joshua_1.html" prevTitle="Joshua">
    <chapter number="17" verseCount="13" nextChapter="judges_18.html" nextTitle="Judges 18" prevChapter="judges_16.html" prevTitle="Judges 16" chapterPage="judges_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And there was a man of mount Ephraim, whose name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Micah.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he said unto his mother, The eleven hundred &lt;i&gt;shekels&lt;/i&gt; of silver that were taken from thee, about which thou cursedst, and spakest of also in mine ears, behold, the silver &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with me; I took it. And his mother said, Blessed &lt;i&gt;be thou&lt;/i&gt; of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, my son.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And when he had restored the eleven hundred &lt;i&gt;shekels&lt;/i&gt; of silver to his mother, his mother said, I had wholly dedicated the silver unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; from my hand for my son, to make a graven image and a molten image: now therefore I will restore it unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Yet he restored the money unto his mother; and his mother took two hundred &lt;i&gt;shekels&lt;/i&gt; of silver, and gave them to the founder, who made thereof a graven image and a molten image: and they were in the house of Micah.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the man Micah had an house of gods, and made an ephod, and teraphim, and consecrated one of his sons, who became his priest.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">In those days &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; no king in Israel, &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; every man did &lt;i&gt;that which was&lt;/i&gt; right in his own eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And there was a young man out of Beth-lehem-judah of the family of Judah, who &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a Levite, and he sojourned there.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the man departed out of the city from Beth-lehem-judah to sojourn where he could find &lt;i&gt;a place&lt;/i&gt;: and he came to mount Ephraim to the house of Micah, as he journeyed.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Micah said unto him, Whence comest thou? And he said unto him, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; a Levite of Beth-lehem-judah, and I go to sojourn where I may find &lt;i&gt;a place&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Micah said unto him, Dwell with me, and be unto me a father and a priest, and I will give thee ten &lt;i&gt;shekels&lt;/i&gt; of silver by the year, and a suit of apparel, and thy victuals. So the Levite went in.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the Levite was content to dwell with the man; and the young man was unto him as one of his sons.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Micah consecrated the Levite; and the young man became his priest, and was in the house of Micah.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then said Micah, Now know I that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will do me good, seeing I have a Levite to &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; priest.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>