<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="7" name="Judges" bookPage="judges.html" title="Judges" chapterCount="21" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ruth_1.html" nextTitle="Ruth" prevBook="joshua_1.html" prevTitle="Joshua">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="25" nextChapter="judges_14.html" nextTitle="Judges 14" prevChapter="judges_12.html" prevTitle="Judges 12" chapterPage="judges_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the children of Israel did evil again in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; delivered them into the hand of the Philistines forty years.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">And there was a certain man of Zorah, of the family of the Danites, whose name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Manoah; and his wife &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; barren, and bare not.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared unto the woman, and said unto her, Behold now, thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; barren, and bearest not: but thou shalt conceive, and bear a son.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Now therefore beware, I pray thee, and drink not wine nor strong drink, and eat not any unclean &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For, lo, thou shalt conceive, and bear a son; and no razor shall come on his head: for the child shall be a Nazarite unto God from the womb: and he shall begin to deliver Israel out of the hand of the Philistines.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Then the woman came and told her husband, saying, A man of God came unto me, and his countenance &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; like the countenance of an angel of God, very terrible: but I asked him not whence he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt;, neither told he me his name:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But he said unto me, Behold, thou shalt conceive, and bear a son; and now drink no wine nor strong drink, neither eat any unclean &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt;: for the child shall be a Nazarite to God from the womb to the day of his death.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Then Manoah intreated the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and said, O my Lord, let the man of God which thou didst send come again unto us, and teach us what we shall do unto the child that shall be born.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And God hearkened to the voice of Manoah; and the angel of God came again unto the woman as she sat in the field: but Manoah her husband &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; not with her.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the woman made haste, and ran, and shewed her husband, and said unto him, Behold, the man hath appeared unto me, that came unto me the &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; day.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Manoah arose, and went after his wife, and came to the man, and said unto him, &lt;i&gt;Art&lt;/i&gt; thou the man that spakest unto the woman? And he said, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Manoah said, Now let thy words come to pass. How shall we order the child, and &lt;i&gt;how&lt;/i&gt; shall we do unto him?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Manoah, Of all that I said unto the woman let her beware.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">She may not eat of any &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; that cometh of the vine, neither let her drink wine or strong drink, nor eat any unclean &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt;: all that I commanded her let her observe.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And Manoah said unto the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I pray thee, let us detain thee, until we shall have made ready a kid for thee.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Manoah, Though thou detain me, I will not eat of thy bread: and if thou wilt offer a burnt offering, thou must offer it unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. For Manoah knew not that he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; an angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Manoah said unto the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, What &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy name, that when thy sayings come to pass we may do thee honour?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, Why askest thou thus after my name, seeing it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; secret?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">So Manoah took a kid with a meat offering, and offered &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; upon a rock unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and &lt;i&gt;the angel&lt;/i&gt; did wondrously; and Manoah and his wife looked on.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For it came to pass, when the flame went up toward heaven from off the altar, that the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; ascended in the flame of the altar. And Manoah and his wife looked on &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and fell on their faces to the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did no more appear to Manoah and to his wife. Then Manoah knew that he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; an angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Manoah said unto his wife, We shall surely die, because we have seen God.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But his wife said unto him, If the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; were pleased to kill us, he would not have received a burnt offering and a meat offering at our hands, neither would he have shewed us all these &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt;, nor would as at this time have told us &lt;i&gt;such things&lt;/i&gt; as these.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And the woman bare a son, and called his name Samson: and the child grew, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; blessed him.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the Spirit of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; began to move him at times in the camp of Dan between Zorah and Eshtaol.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>