<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="7" name="Judges" bookPage="judges.html" title="Judges" chapterCount="21" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ruth_1.html" nextTitle="Ruth" prevBook="joshua_1.html" prevTitle="Joshua">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="40" nextChapter="judges_7.html" nextTitle="Judges 7" prevChapter="judges_5.html" prevTitle="Judges 5" chapterPage="judges_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the children of Israel did evil in the sight of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; delivered them into the hand of Midian seven years.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the hand of Midian prevailed against Israel: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; because of the Midianites the children of Israel made them the dens which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in the mountains, and caves, and strong holds.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; it was, when Israel had sown, that the Midianites came up, and the Amalekites, and the children of the east, even they came up against them;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they encamped against them, and destroyed the increase of the earth, till thou come unto Gaza, and left no sustenance for Israel, neither sheep, nor ox, nor ass.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For they came up with their cattle and their tents, and they came as grasshoppers for multitude; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; both they and their camels were without number: and they entered into the land to destroy it.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Israel was greatly impoverished because of the Midianites; and the children of Israel cried unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when the children of Israel cried unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; because of the Midianites,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">That the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent a prophet unto the children of Israel, which said unto them, Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, I brought you up from Egypt, and brought you forth out of the house of bondage;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And I delivered you out of the hand of the Egyptians, and out of the hand of all that oppressed you, and drave them out from before you, and gave you their land;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And I said unto you, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God; fear not the gods of the Amorites, in whose land ye dwell: but ye have not obeyed my voice.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And there came an angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and sat under an oak which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in Ophrah, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;pertained&lt;/span&gt; unto Joash the Abi-ezrite: and his son Gideon threshed wheat by the winepress, to hide &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; from the Midianites.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared unto him, and said unto him, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with thee, thou mighty man of valour.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Gideon said unto him, Oh my Lord, if the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be with us, why then is all this befallen us? and where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; all his miracles which our fathers told us of, saying, Did not the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; bring us up from Egypt? but now the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath forsaken us, and delivered us into the hands of the Midianites.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; looked upon him, and said, Go in this thy might, and thou shalt save Israel from the hand of the Midianites: have not I sent thee?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he said unto him, Oh my Lord, wherewith shall I save Israel? behold, my family &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; poor in Manasseh, and I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the least in my father's house.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, Surely I will be with thee, and thou shalt smite the Midianites as one man.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he said unto him, If now I have found grace in thy sight, then shew me a sign that thou talkest with me.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Depart not hence, I pray thee, until I come unto thee, and bring forth my present, and set &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; before thee. And he said, I will tarry until thou come again.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And Gideon went in, and made ready a kid, and unleavened cakes of an ephah of flour: the flesh he put in a basket, and he put the broth in a pot, and brought &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; out unto him under the oak, and presented &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the angel of God said unto him, Take the flesh and the unleavened cakes, and lay &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; upon this rock, and pour out the broth. And he did so.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Then the angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; put forth the end of the staff that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in his hand, and touched the flesh and the unleavened cakes; and there rose up fire out of the rock, and consumed the flesh and the unleavened cakes. Then the angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; departed out of his sight.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And when Gideon perceived that he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; an angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Gideon said, Alas, O Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;! for because I have seen an angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; face to face.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, Peace &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; unto thee; fear not: thou shalt not die.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Then Gideon built an altar there unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and called it Jehovah-shalom: unto this day it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; yet in Ophrah of the Abi-ezrites.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And it came to pass the same night, that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, Take thy father's young bullock, even the second bullock of seven years old, and throw down the altar of Baal that thy father hath, and cut down the grove that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by it:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And build an altar unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God upon the top of this rock, in the ordered place, and take the second bullock, and offer a burnt sacrifice with the wood of the grove which thou shalt cut down.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Then Gideon took ten men of his servants, and did as the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had said unto him: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; it was, because he feared his father's household, and the men of the city, that he could not do &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; by day, that he did &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; by night.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">And when the men of the city arose early in the morning, behold, the altar of Baal was cast down, and the grove was cut down that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; by it, and the second bullock was offered upon the altar &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that was&lt;/span&gt; built.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And they said one to another, Who hath done this thing? And when they enquired and asked, they said, Gideon the son of Joash hath done this thing.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Then the men of the city said unto Joash, Bring out thy son, that he may die: because he hath cast down the altar of Baal, and because he hath cut down the grove that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; by it.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Joash said unto all that stood against him, Will ye plead for Baal? will ye save him? he that will plead for him, let him be put to death whilst &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is yet&lt;/span&gt; morning: if he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; a god, let him plead for himself, because &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; hath cast down his altar.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Therefore on that day he called him Jerubbaal, saying, Let Baal plead against him, because he hath thrown down his altar.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">Then all the Midianites and the Amalekites and the children of the east were gathered together, and went over, and pitched in the valley of Jezreel.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">But the Spirit of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came upon Gideon, and he blew a trumpet; and Abi-ezer was gathered after him.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And he sent messengers throughout all Manasseh; who also was gathered after him: and he sent messengers unto Asher, and unto Zebulun, and unto Naphtali; and they came up to meet them.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">And Gideon said unto God, If thou wilt save Israel by mine hand, as thou hast said,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Behold, I will put a fleece of wool in the floor; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; if the dew be on the fleece only, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt; dry upon all the earth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;beside&lt;/span&gt;, then shall I know that thou wilt save Israel by mine hand, as thou hast said.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And it was so: for he rose up early on the morrow, and thrust the fleece together, and wringed the dew out of the fleece, a bowl full of water.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And Gideon said unto God, Let not thine anger be hot against me, and I will speak but this once: let me prove, I pray thee, but this once with the fleece; let it now be dry only upon the fleece, and upon all the ground let there be dew.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And God did so that night: for it was dry upon the fleece only, and there was dew on all the ground.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>