<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="8" name="Ruth" bookPage="ruth.html" title="Ruth" chapterCount="4" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1samuel_1.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel" prevBook="judges_1.html" prevTitle="Judges">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="22" nextChapter="ruth_2.html" nextTitle="Ruth 2" prevChapter="judges_21.html" prevTitle="Judges 21" chapterPage="ruth_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now it came to pass in the days when the judges ruled, that there was a famine in the land. And a certain man of Beth-lehem-judah went to sojourn in the country of Moab, he, and his wife, and his two sons.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the name of the man &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Elimelech, and the name of his wife Naomi, and the name of his two sons Mahlon and Chilion, Ephrathites of Beth-lehem-judah. And they came into the country of Moab, and continued there.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Elimelech Naomi's husband died; and she was left, and her two sons.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they took them wives of the women of Moab; the name of the one &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Orpah, and the name of the other Ruth: and they dwelled there about ten years.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Mahlon and Chilion died also both of them; and the woman was left of her two sons and her husband.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Then she arose with her daughters in law, that she might return from the country of Moab: for she had heard in the country of Moab how that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had visited his people in giving them bread.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Wherefore she went forth out of the place where she was, and her two daughters in law with her; and they went on the way to return unto the land of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Naomi said unto her two daughters in law, Go, return each to her mother's house: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; deal kindly with you, as ye have dealt with the dead, and with me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; grant you that ye may find rest, each &lt;i&gt;of you&lt;/i&gt; in the house of her husband. Then she kissed them; and they lifted up their voice, and wept.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they said unto her, Surely we will return with thee unto thy people.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Naomi said, Turn again, my daughters: why will ye go with me? &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; there yet &lt;i&gt;any more&lt;/i&gt; sons in my womb, that they may be your husbands?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Turn again, my daughters, go &lt;i&gt;your way&lt;/i&gt;; for I am too old to have an husband. If I should say, I have hope, &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; I should have an husband also to night, and should also bear sons;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Would ye tarry for them till they were grown? would ye stay for them from having husbands? nay, my daughters; for it grieveth me much for your sakes that the hand of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; is gone out against me.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they lifted up their voice, and wept again: and Orpah kissed her mother in law; but Ruth clave unto her.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And she said, Behold, thy sister in law is gone back unto her people, and unto her gods: return thou after thy sister in law.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Ruth said, Intreat me not to leave thee, &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; to return from following after thee: for whither thou goest, I will go; and where thou lodgest, I will lodge: thy people &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; my people, and thy God my God:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Where thou diest, will I die, and there will I be buried: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; do so to me, and more also, &lt;i&gt;if ought&lt;/i&gt; but death part thee and me.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">When she saw that she was stedfastly minded to go with her, then she left speaking unto her.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">So they two went until they came to Beth-lehem. And it came to pass, when they were come to Beth-lehem, that all the city was moved about them, and they said, &lt;i&gt;Is&lt;/i&gt; this Naomi?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And she said unto them, Call me not Naomi, call me Mara: for the Almighty hath dealt very bitterly with me.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">I went out full, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath brought me home again empty: why &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; call ye me Naomi, seeing the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath testified against me, and the Almighty hath afflicted me?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">So Naomi returned, and Ruth the Moabitess, her daughter in law, with her, which returned out of the country of Moab: and they came to Beth-lehem in the beginning of barley harvest.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>