<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="52" nextChapter="1samuel_15.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 15" prevChapter="1samuel_13.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 13" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now it came to pass upon a day, that Jonathan the son of Saul said unto the young man that bare his armour, Come, and let us go over to the Philistines' garrison, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; on the other side. But he told not his father.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Saul tarried in the uttermost part of Gibeah under a pomegranate tree which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in Migron: and the people that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; about six hundred men;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Ahiah, the son of Ahitub, I-chabod's brother, the son of Phinehas, the son of Eli, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s priest in Shiloh, wearing an ephod. And the people knew not that Jonathan was gone.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And between the passages, by which Jonathan sought to go over unto the Philistines' garrison, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; a sharp rock on the one side, and a sharp rock on the other side: and the name of the one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Bozez, and the name of the other Seneh.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The forefront of the one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; situate northward over against Michmash, and the other southward over against Gibeah.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Jonathan said to the young man that bare his armour, Come, and let us go over unto the garrison of these uncircumcised: it may be that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will work for us: for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no restraint to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to save by many or by few.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And his armourbearer said unto him, Do all that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in thine heart: turn thee; behold, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; with thee according to thy heart.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then said Jonathan, Behold, we will pass over unto &lt;span class='extra'&gt;these&lt;/span&gt; men, and we will discover ourselves unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">If they say thus unto us, Tarry until we come to you; then we will stand still in our place, and will not go up unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But if they say thus, Come up unto us; then we will go up: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath delivered them into our hand: and this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a sign unto us.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And both of them discovered themselves unto the garrison of the Philistines: and the Philistines said, Behold, the Hebrews come forth out of the holes where they had hid themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the men of the garrison answered Jonathan and his armourbearer, and said, Come up to us, and we will shew you a thing. And Jonathan said unto his armourbearer, Come up after me: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath delivered them into the hand of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Jonathan climbed up upon his hands and upon his feet, and his armourbearer after him: and they fell before Jonathan; and his armourbearer slew after him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And that first slaughter, which Jonathan and his armourbearer made, was about twenty men, within as it were an half acre of land, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; a yoke &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of oxen might plow&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And there was trembling in the host, in the field, and among all the people: the garrison, and the spoilers, they also trembled, and the earth quaked: so it was a very great trembling.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the watchmen of Saul in Gibeah of Benjamin looked; and, behold, the multitude melted away, and they went on beating down &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one another&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then said Saul unto the people that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him, Number now, and see who is gone from us. And when they had numbered, behold, Jonathan and his armourbearer &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Saul said unto Ahiah, Bring hither the ark of God. For the ark of God was at that time with the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And it came to pass, while Saul talked unto the priest, that the noise that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the host of the Philistines went on and increased: and Saul said unto the priest, Withdraw thine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Saul and all the people that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him assembled themselves, and they came to the battle: and, behold, every man's sword was against his fellow, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and there was&lt;/span&gt; a very great discomfiture.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Moreover the Hebrews &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; were with the Philistines before that time, which went up with them into the camp &lt;span class='extra'&gt;from the country&lt;/span&gt; round about, even they also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;turned&lt;/span&gt; to be with the Israelites that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with Saul and Jonathan.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Likewise all the men of Israel which had hid themselves in mount Ephraim, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; they heard that the Philistines fled, even they also followed hard after them in the battle.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">So the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; saved Israel that day: and the battle passed over unto Beth-aven.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And the men of Israel were distressed that day: for Saul had adjured the people, saying, Cursed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the man that eateth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; food until evening, that I may be avenged on mine enemies. So none of the people tasted &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; food.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they of&lt;/span&gt; the land came to a wood; and there was honey upon the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And when the people were come into the wood, behold, the honey dropped; but no man put his hand to his mouth: for the people feared the oath.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">But Jonathan heard not when his father charged the people with the oath: wherefore he put forth the end of the rod that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in his hand, and dipped it in an honeycomb, and put his hand to his mouth; and his eyes were enlightened.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Then answered one of the people, and said, Thy father straitly charged the people with an oath, saying, Cursed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the man that eateth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; food this day. And the people were faint.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Then said Jonathan, My father hath troubled the land: see, I pray you, how mine eyes have been enlightened, because I tasted a little of this honey.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">How much more, if haply the people had eaten freely to day of the spoil of their enemies which they found? for had there not been now a much greater slaughter among the Philistines?</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And they smote the Philistines that day from Michmash to Aijalon: and the people were very faint.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And the people flew upon the spoil, and took sheep, and oxen, and calves, and slew &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; on the ground: and the people did eat &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; with the blood.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">Then they told Saul, saying, Behold, the people sin against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in that they eat with the blood. And he said, Ye have transgressed: roll a great stone unto me this day.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And Saul said, Disperse yourselves among the people, and say unto them, Bring me hither every man his ox, and every man his sheep, and slay &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; here, and eat; and sin not against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in eating with the blood. And all the people brought every man his ox with him that night, and slew &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; there.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And Saul built an altar unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: the same was the first altar that he built unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">And Saul said, Let us go down after the Philistines by night, and spoil them until the morning light, and let us not leave a man of them. And they said, Do whatsoever seemeth good unto thee. Then said the priest, Let us draw near hither unto God.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And Saul asked counsel of God, Shall I go down after the Philistines? wilt thou deliver them into the hand of Israel? But he answered him not that day.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And Saul said, Draw ye near hither, all the chief of the people: and know and see wherein this sin hath been this day.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">For, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth, which saveth Israel, though it be in Jonathan my son, he shall surely die. But &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; not a man among all the people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; answered him.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Then said he unto all Israel, Be ye on one side, and I and Jonathan my son will be on the other side. And the people said unto Saul, Do what seemeth good unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Therefore Saul said unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, Give a perfect &lt;span class='extra'&gt;lot&lt;/span&gt;. And Saul and Jonathan were taken: but the people escaped.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And Saul said, Cast &lt;span class='extra'&gt;lots&lt;/span&gt; between me and Jonathan my son. And Jonathan was taken.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Then Saul said to Jonathan, Tell me what thou hast done. And Jonathan told him, and said, I did but taste a little honey with the end of the rod that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in mine hand, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;, lo, I must die.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And Saul answered, God do so and more also: for thou shalt surely die, Jonathan.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And the people said unto Saul, Shall Jonathan die, who hath wrought this great salvation in Israel? God forbid: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth, there shall not one hair of his head fall to the ground; for he hath wrought with God this day. So the people rescued Jonathan, that he died not.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">Then Saul went up from following the Philistines: and the Philistines went to their own place.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47" newPara="true">So Saul took the kingdom over Israel, and fought against all his enemies on every side, against Moab, and against the children of Ammon, and against Edom, and against the kings of Zobah, and against the Philistines: and whithersoever he turned himself, he vexed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">And he gathered an host, and smote the Amalekites, and delivered Israel out of the hands of them that spoiled them.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">Now the sons of Saul were Jonathan, and Ishui, and Melchi-shua: and the names of his two daughters &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were these&lt;/span&gt;; the name of the firstborn Merab, and the name of the younger Michal:</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">And the name of Saul's wife &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Ahinoam, the daughter of Ahimaaz: and the name of the captain of his host &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Abner, the son of Ner, Saul's uncle.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And Kish &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the father of Saul; and Ner the father of Abner &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the son of Abiel.</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">And there was sore war against the Philistines all the days of Saul: and when Saul saw any strong man, or any valiant man, he took him unto him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>