<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="23" nextChapter="1samuel_14.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 14" prevChapter="1samuel_12.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 12" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Saul reigned one year; and when he had reigned two years over Israel,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Saul chose him three thousand &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; of Israel; &lt;i&gt;whereof&lt;/i&gt; two thousand were with Saul in Michmash and in mount Beth-el, and a thousand were with Jonathan in Gibeah of Benjamin: and the rest of the people he sent every man to his tent.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Jonathan smote the garrison of the Philistines that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in Geba, and the Philistines heard &lt;i&gt;of it&lt;/i&gt;. And Saul blew the trumpet throughout all the land, saying, Let the Hebrews hear.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And all Israel heard say &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; Saul had smitten a garrison of the Philistines, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; Israel also was had in abomination with the Philistines. And the people were called together after Saul to Gilgal.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And the Philistines gathered themselves together to fight with Israel, thirty thousand chariots, and six thousand horsemen, and people as the sand which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; on the sea shore in multitude: and they came up, and pitched in Michmash, eastward from Beth-aven.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">When the men of Israel saw that they were in a strait, (for the people were distressed,) then the people did hide themselves in caves, and in thickets, and in rocks, and in high places, and in pits.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And &lt;i&gt;some of&lt;/i&gt; the Hebrews went over Jordan to the land of Gad and Gilead. As for Saul, he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; yet in Gilgal, and all the people followed him trembling.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And he tarried seven days, according to the set time that Samuel &lt;i&gt;had appointed&lt;/i&gt;: but Samuel came not to Gilgal; and the people were scattered from him.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Saul said, Bring hither a burnt offering to me, and peace offerings. And he offered the burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And it came to pass, that as soon as he had made an end of offering the burnt offering, behold, Samuel came; and Saul went out to meet him, that he might salute him.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And Samuel said, What hast thou done? And Saul said, Because I saw that the people were scattered from me, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thou camest not within the days appointed, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the Philistines gathered themselves together at Michmash;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore said I, The Philistines will come down now upon me to Gilgal, and I have not made supplication unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: I forced myself therefore, and offered a burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Samuel said to Saul, Thou hast done foolishly: thou hast not kept the commandment of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, which he commanded thee: for now would the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have established thy kingdom upon Israel for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But now thy kingdom shall not continue: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath sought him a man after his own heart, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath commanded him &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; captain over his people, because thou hast not kept &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded thee.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Samuel arose, and gat him up from Gilgal unto Gibeah of Benjamin. And Saul numbered the people &lt;i&gt;that were&lt;/i&gt; present with him, about six hundred men.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Saul, and Jonathan his son, and the people &lt;i&gt;that were&lt;/i&gt; present with them, abode in Gibeah of Benjamin: but the Philistines encamped in Michmash.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And the spoilers came out of the camp of the Philistines in three companies: one company turned unto the way &lt;i&gt;that leadeth to&lt;/i&gt; Ophrah, unto the land of Shual:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And another company turned the way &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; Beth-horon: and another company turned &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; the way of the border that looketh to the valley of Zeboim toward the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">Now there was no smith found throughout all the land of Israel: for the Philistines said, Lest the Hebrews make &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; swords or spears:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But all the Israelites went down to the Philistines, to sharpen every man his share, and his coulter, and his axe, and his mattock.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Yet they had a file for the mattocks, and for the coulters, and for the forks, and for the axes, and to sharpen the goads.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">So it came to pass in the day of battle, that there was neither sword nor spear found in the hand of any of the people that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with Saul and Jonathan: but with Saul and with Jonathan his son was there found.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the garrison of the Philistines went out to the passage of Michmash.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>