<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="27" nextChapter="1samuel_10.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 10" prevChapter="1samuel_8.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 8" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now there was a man of Benjamin, whose name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Kish, the son of Abiel, the son of Zeror, the son of Bechorath, the son of Aphiah, a Benjamite, a mighty man of power.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he had a son, whose name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Saul, a choice young man, and a goodly: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; not among the children of Israel a goodlier person than he: from his shoulders and upward &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he was&lt;/span&gt; higher than any of the people.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the asses of Kish Saul's father were lost. And Kish said to Saul his son, Take now one of the servants with thee, and arise, go seek the asses.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he passed through mount Ephraim, and passed through the land of Shalisha, but they found &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; not: then they passed through the land of Shalim, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there they were&lt;/span&gt; not: and he passed through the land of the Benjamites, but they found &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; not.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; when they were come to the land of Zuph, Saul said to his servant that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; with him, Come, and let us return; lest my father leave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;caring&lt;/span&gt; for the asses, and take thought for us.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he said unto him, Behold now, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; in this city a man of God, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; an honourable man; all that he saith cometh surely to pass: now let us go thither; peradventure he can shew us our way that we should go.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then said Saul to his servant, But, behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; we go, what shall we bring the man? for the bread is spent in our vessels, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; not a present to bring to the man of God: what have we?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the servant answered Saul again, and said, Behold, I have here at hand the fourth part of a shekel of silver: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; will I give to the man of God, to tell us our way.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">(Beforetime in Israel, when a man went to enquire of God, thus he spake, Come, and let us go to the seer: for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he that is&lt;/span&gt; now &lt;span class='extra'&gt;called&lt;/span&gt; a Prophet was beforetime called a Seer.)</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then said Saul to his servant, Well said; come, let us go. So they went unto the city where the man of God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; as they went up the hill to the city, they found young maidens going out to draw water, and said unto them, Is the seer here?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And they answered them, and said, He is; behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; before you: make haste now, for he came to day to the city; for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; a sacrifice of the people to day in the high place:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">As soon as ye be come into the city, ye shall straightway find him, before he go up to the high place to eat: for the people will not eat until he come, because he doth bless the sacrifice; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; afterwards they eat that be bidden. Now therefore get you up; for about this time ye shall find him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they went up into the city: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; when they were come into the city, behold, Samuel came out against them, for to go up to the high place.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Now the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had told Samuel in his ear a day before Saul came, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">To morrow about this time I will send thee a man out of the land of Benjamin, and thou shalt anoint him &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; captain over my people Israel, that he may save my people out of the hand of the Philistines: for I have looked upon my people, because their cry is come unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And when Samuel saw Saul, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, Behold the man whom I spake to thee of! this same shall reign over my people.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Then Saul drew near to Samuel in the gate, and said, Tell me, I pray thee, where the seer's house &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Samuel answered Saul, and said, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the seer: go up before me unto the high place; for ye shall eat with me to day, and to morrow I will let thee go, and will tell thee all that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in thine heart.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And as for thine asses that were lost three days ago, set not thy mind on them; for they are found. And on whom &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; all the desire of Israel? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is it&lt;/span&gt; not on thee, and on all thy father's house?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Saul answered and said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Am&lt;/span&gt; not I a Benjamite, of the smallest of the tribes of Israel? and my family the least of all the families of the tribe of Benjamin? wherefore then speakest thou so to me?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Samuel took Saul and his servant, and brought them into the parlour, and made them sit in the chiefest place among them that were bidden, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; about thirty persons.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Samuel said unto the cook, Bring the portion which I gave thee, of which I said unto thee, Set it by thee.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the cook took up the shoulder, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; upon it, and set &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; before Saul. And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Samuel&lt;/span&gt; said, Behold that which is left! set &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; before thee, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; eat: for unto this time hath it been kept for thee since I said, I have invited the people. So Saul did eat with Samuel that day.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And when they were come down from the high place into the city, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Samuel&lt;/span&gt; communed with Saul upon the top of the house.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And they arose early: and it came to pass about the spring of the day, that Samuel called Saul to the top of the house, saying, Up, that I may send thee away. And Saul arose, and they went out both of them, he and Samuel, abroad.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; as they were going down to the end of the city, Samuel said to Saul, Bid the servant pass on before us, (and he passed on,) but stand thou still a while, that I may shew thee the word of God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>