<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="21" nextChapter="1samuel_4.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 4" prevChapter="1samuel_2.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 2" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the child Samuel ministered unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; before Eli. And the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was precious in those days; &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; no open vision.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And it came to pass at that time, when Eli &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; laid down in his place, and his eyes began to wax dim, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; he could not see;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And ere the lamp of God went out in the temple of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, where the ark of God &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt;, and Samuel was laid down &lt;i&gt;to sleep&lt;/i&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">That the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; called Samuel: and he answered, Here &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he ran unto Eli, and said, Here &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I; for thou calledst me. And he said, I called not; lie down again. And he went and lay down.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; called yet again, Samuel. And Samuel arose and went to Eli, and said, Here &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I; for thou didst call me. And he answered, I called not, my son; lie down again.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Now Samuel did not yet know the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, neither was the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; yet revealed unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; called Samuel again the third time. And he arose and went to Eli, and said, Here &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I; for thou didst call me. And Eli perceived that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had called the child.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Therefore Eli said unto Samuel, Go, lie down: and it shall be, if he call thee, that thou shalt say, Speak, &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for thy servant heareth. So Samuel went and lay down in his place.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came, and stood, and called as at other times, Samuel, Samuel. Then Samuel answered, Speak; for thy servant heareth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said to Samuel, Behold, I will do a thing in Israel, at which both the ears of every one that heareth it shall tingle.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">In that day I will perform against Eli all &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; which I have spoken concerning his house: when I begin, I will also make an end.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For I have told him that I will judge his house for ever for the iniquity which he knoweth; because his sons made themselves vile, and he restrained them not.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And therefore I have sworn unto the house of Eli, that the iniquity of Eli's house shall not be purged with sacrifice nor offering for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And Samuel lay until the morning, and opened the doors of the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. And Samuel feared to shew Eli the vision.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Then Eli called Samuel, and said, Samuel, my son. And he answered, Here &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he said, What &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the thing that &lt;i&gt;the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt; hath said unto thee? I pray thee hide &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not from me: God do so to thee, and more also, if thou hide &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; thing from me of all the things that he said unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Samuel told him every whit, and hid nothing from him. And he said, It &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: let him do what seemeth him good.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And Samuel grew, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was with him, and did let none of his words fall to the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And all Israel from Dan even to Beer-sheba knew that Samuel &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; established &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; a prophet of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared again in Shiloh: for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; revealed himself to Samuel in Shiloh by the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>