<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="30" nextChapter="1samuel_19.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 19" prevChapter="1samuel_17.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 17" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, when he had made an end of speaking unto Saul, that the soul of Jonathan was knit with the soul of David, and Jonathan loved him as his own soul.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Saul took him that day, and would let him go no more home to his father's house.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Then Jonathan and David made a covenant, because he loved him as his own soul.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Jonathan stripped himself of the robe that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; upon him, and gave it to David, and his garments, even to his sword, and to his bow, and to his girdle.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And David went out whithersoever Saul sent him, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; behaved himself wisely: and Saul set him over the men of war, and he was accepted in the sight of all the people, and also in the sight of Saul's servants.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And it came to pass as they came, when David was returned from the slaughter of the Philistine, that the women came out of all cities of Israel, singing and dancing, to meet king Saul, with tabrets, with joy, and with instruments of musick.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the women answered &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one another&lt;/span&gt; as they played, and said, Saul hath slain his thousands, and David his ten thousands.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Saul was very wroth, and the saying displeased him; and he said, They have ascribed unto David ten thousands, and to me they have ascribed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; thousands: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;what&lt;/span&gt; can he have more but the kingdom?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Saul eyed David from that day and forward.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And it came to pass on the morrow, that the evil spirit from God came upon Saul, and he prophesied in the midst of the house: and David played with his hand, as at other times: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; a javelin in Saul's hand.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Saul cast the javelin; for he said, I will smite David even to the wall &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with it&lt;/span&gt;. And David avoided out of his presence twice.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And Saul was afraid of David, because the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was with him, and was departed from Saul.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Therefore Saul removed him from him, and made him his captain over a thousand; and he went out and came in before the people.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And David behaved himself wisely in all his ways; and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Wherefore when Saul saw that he behaved himself very wisely, he was afraid of him.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But all Israel and Judah loved David, because he went out and came in before them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And Saul said to David, Behold my elder daughter Merab, her will I give thee to wife: only be thou valiant for me, and fight the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s battles. For Saul said, Let not mine hand be upon him, but let the hand of the Philistines be upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And David said unto Saul, Who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; I? and what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my life, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; my father's family in Israel, that I should be son in law to the king?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But it came to pass at the time when Merab Saul's daughter should have been given to David, that she was given unto Adriel the Meholathite to wife.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Michal Saul's daughter loved David: and they told Saul, and the thing pleased him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Saul said, I will give him her, that she may be a snare to him, and that the hand of the Philistines may be against him. Wherefore Saul said to David, Thou shalt this day be my son in law in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the one of&lt;/span&gt; the twain.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And Saul commanded his servants, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Commune with David secretly, and say, Behold, the king hath delight in thee, and all his servants love thee: now therefore be the king's son in law.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Saul's servants spake those words in the ears of David. And David said, Seemeth it to you &lt;span class='extra'&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; light &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thing&lt;/span&gt; to be a king's son in law, seeing that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; a poor man, and lightly esteemed?</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the servants of Saul told him, saying, On this manner spake David.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Saul said, Thus shall ye say to David, The king desireth not any dowry, but an hundred foreskins of the Philistines, to be avenged of the king's enemies. But Saul thought to make David fall by the hand of the Philistines.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And when his servants told David these words, it pleased David well to be the king's son in law: and the days were not expired.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Wherefore David arose and went, he and his men, and slew of the Philistines two hundred men; and David brought their foreskins, and they gave them in full tale to the king, that he might be the king's son in law. And Saul gave him Michal his daughter to wife.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">And Saul saw and knew that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; with David, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; Michal Saul's daughter loved him.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Saul was yet the more afraid of David; and Saul became David's enemy continually.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Then the princes of the Philistines went forth: and it came to pass, after they went forth, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; David behaved himself more wisely than all the servants of Saul; so that his name was much set by.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>