<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="23" nextChapter="1samuel_17.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 17" prevChapter="1samuel_15.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 15" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Samuel, How long wilt thou mourn for Saul, seeing I have rejected him from reigning over Israel? fill thine horn with oil, and go, I will send thee to Jesse the Beth-lehemite: for I have provided me a king among his sons.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Samuel said, How can I go? if Saul hear &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, he will kill me. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said, Take an heifer with thee, and say, I am come to sacrifice to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And call Jesse to the sacrifice, and I will shew thee what thou shalt do: and thou shalt anoint unto me &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; whom I name unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Samuel did that which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake, and came to Beth-lehem. And the elders of the town trembled at his coming, and said, Comest thou peaceably?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he said, Peaceably: I am come to sacrifice unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: sanctify yourselves, and come with me to the sacrifice. And he sanctified Jesse and his sons, and called them to the sacrifice.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when they were come, that he looked on Eliab, and said, Surely the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s anointed &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; before him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Samuel, Look not on his countenance, or on the height of his stature; because I have refused him: for &lt;i&gt;the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; seeth&lt;/i&gt; not as man seeth; for man looketh on the outward appearance, but the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; looketh on the heart.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then Jesse called Abinadab, and made him pass before Samuel. And he said, Neither hath the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; chosen this.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then Jesse made Shammah to pass by. And he said, Neither hath the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; chosen this.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Again, Jesse made seven of his sons to pass before Samuel. And Samuel said unto Jesse, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath not chosen these.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Samuel said unto Jesse, Are here all &lt;i&gt;thy&lt;/i&gt; children? And he said, There remaineth yet the youngest, and, behold, he keepeth the sheep. And Samuel said unto Jesse, Send and fetch him: for we will not sit down till he come hither.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he sent, and brought him in. Now he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; ruddy, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; withal of a beautiful countenance, and goodly to look to. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said, Arise, anoint him: for this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then Samuel took the horn of oil, and anointed him in the midst of his brethren: and the Spirit of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came upon David from that day forward. So Samuel rose up, and went to Ramah.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">But the Spirit of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; departed from Saul, and an evil spirit from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; troubled him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Saul's servants said unto him, Behold now, an evil spirit from God troubleth thee.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Let our lord now command thy servants, &lt;i&gt;which are&lt;/i&gt; before thee, to seek out a man, &lt;i&gt;who is&lt;/i&gt; a cunning player on an harp: and it shall come to pass, when the evil spirit from God is upon thee, that he shall play with his hand, and thou shalt be well.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Saul said unto his servants, Provide me now a man that can play well, and bring &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; to me.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Then answered one of the servants, and said, Behold, I have seen a son of Jesse the Beth-lehemite, &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; cunning in playing, and a mighty valiant man, and a man of war, and prudent in matters, and a comely person, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">Wherefore Saul sent messengers unto Jesse, and said, Send me David thy son, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with the sheep.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Jesse took an ass &lt;i&gt;laden&lt;/i&gt; with bread, and a bottle of wine, and a kid, and sent &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; by David his son unto Saul.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And David came to Saul, and stood before him: and he loved him greatly; and he became his armourbearer.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Saul sent to Jesse, saying, Let David, I pray thee, stand before me; for he hath found favour in my sight.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And it came to pass, when the &lt;i&gt;evil&lt;/i&gt; spirit from God was upon Saul, that David took an harp, and played with his hand: so Saul was refreshed, and was well, and the evil spirit departed from him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>