<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="31" verseCount="13" nextChapter="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 1" prevChapter="1samuel_30.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 30" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now the Philistines fought against Israel: and the men of Israel fled from before the Philistines, and fell down slain in mount Gilboa.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the Philistines followed hard upon Saul and upon his sons; and the Philistines slew Jonathan, and Abinadab, and Malchi-shua, Saul's sons.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the battle went sore against Saul, and the archers hit him; and he was sore wounded of the archers.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Then said Saul unto his armourbearer, Draw thy sword, and thrust me through therewith; lest these uncircumcised come and thrust me through, and abuse me. But his armourbearer would not; for he was sore afraid. Therefore Saul took a sword, and fell upon it.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And when his armourbearer saw that Saul was dead, he fell likewise upon his sword, and died with him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">So Saul died, and his three sons, and his armourbearer, and all his men, that same day together.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And when the men of Israel that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; on the other side of the valley, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;they&lt;/span&gt; that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; on the other side Jordan, saw that the men of Israel fled, and that Saul and his sons were dead, they forsook the cities, and fled; and the Philistines came and dwelt in them.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And it came to pass on the morrow, when the Philistines came to strip the slain, that they found Saul and his three sons fallen in mount Gilboa.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And they cut off his head, and stripped off his armour, and sent into the land of the Philistines round about, to publish &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it in&lt;/span&gt; the house of their idols, and among the people.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they put his armour in the house of Ashtaroth: and they fastened his body to the wall of Beth-shan.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And when the inhabitants of Jabesh-gilead heard of that which the Philistines had done to Saul;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">All the valiant men arose, and went all night, and took the body of Saul and the bodies of his sons from the wall of Beth-shan, and came to Jabesh, and burnt them there.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And they took their bones, and buried &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; under a tree at Jabesh, and fasted seven days.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>