<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="28" nextChapter="1samuel_2.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 2" prevChapter="ruth_4.html" prevTitle="Ruth 4" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now there was a certain man of Ramathaim-zophim, of mount Ephraim, and his name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Elkanah, the son of Jeroham, the son of Elihu, the son of Tohu, the son of Zuph, an Ephrathite:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he had two wives; the name of the one &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Hannah, and the name of the other Peninnah: and Peninnah had children, but Hannah had no children.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And this man went up out of his city yearly to worship and to sacrifice unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts in Shiloh. And the two sons of Eli, Hophni and Phinehas, the priests of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; there.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And when the time was that Elkanah offered, he gave to Peninnah his wife, and to all her sons and her daughters, portions:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But unto Hannah he gave a worthy portion; for he loved Hannah: but the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had shut up her womb.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And her adversary also provoked her sore, for to make her fret, because the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had shut up her womb.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; he did so year by year, when she went up to the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, so she provoked her; therefore she wept, and did not eat.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then said Elkanah her husband to her, Hannah, why weepest thou? and why eatest thou not? and why is thy heart grieved? &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; not I better to thee than ten sons?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">So Hannah rose up after they had eaten in Shiloh, and after they had drunk. Now Eli the priest sat upon a seat by a post of the temple of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And she &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in bitterness of soul, and prayed unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and wept sore.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And she vowed a vow, and said, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, if thou wilt indeed look on the affliction of thine handmaid, and remember me, and not forget thine handmaid, but wilt give unto thine handmaid a man child, then I will give him unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; all the days of his life, and there shall no razor come upon his head.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And it came to pass, as she continued praying before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that Eli marked her mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Now Hannah, she spake in her heart; only her lips moved, but her voice was not heard: therefore Eli thought she had been drunken.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Eli said unto her, How long wilt thou be drunken? put away thy wine from thee.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Hannah answered and said, No, my lord, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; a woman of a sorrowful spirit: I have drunk neither wine nor strong drink, but have poured out my soul before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Count not thine handmaid for a daughter of Belial: for out of the abundance of my complaint and grief have I spoken hitherto.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then Eli answered and said, Go in peace: and the God of Israel grant &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt; thy petition that thou hast asked of him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And she said, Let thine handmaid find grace in thy sight. So the woman went her way, and did eat, and her countenance was no more &lt;i&gt;sad&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And they rose up in the morning early, and worshipped before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and returned, and came to their house to Ramah: and Elkanah knew Hannah his wife; and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; remembered her.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Wherefore it came to pass, when the time was come about after Hannah had conceived, that she bare a son, and called his name Samuel, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;, Because I have asked him of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the man Elkanah, and all his house, went up to offer unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; the yearly sacrifice, and his vow.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But Hannah went not up; for she said unto her husband, &lt;i&gt;I will not go up&lt;/i&gt; until the child be weaned, and &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; I will bring him, that he may appear before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and there abide for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Elkanah her husband said unto her, Do what seemeth thee good; tarry until thou have weaned him; only the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; establish his word. So the woman abode, and gave her son suck until she weaned him.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And when she had weaned him, she took him up with her, with three bullocks, and one ephah of flour, and a bottle of wine, and brought him unto the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in Shiloh: and the child &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; young.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they slew a bullock, and brought the child to Eli.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And she said, Oh my lord, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; thy soul liveth, my lord, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the woman that stood by thee here, praying unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For this child I prayed; and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath given me my petition which I asked of him:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Therefore also I have lent him to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; as long as he liveth he shall be lent to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. And he worshipped the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; there.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>