<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="36" nextChapter="1samuel_3.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 3" prevChapter="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 1" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Hannah prayed, and said, My heart rejoiceth in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, mine horn is exalted in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: my mouth is enlarged over mine enemies; because I rejoice in thy salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;There is&lt;/span&gt; none holy as the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none beside thee: neither &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; any rock like our God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Talk no more so exceeding proudly; let &lt;span class='extra'&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; arrogancy come out of your mouth: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a God of knowledge, and by him actions are weighed.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The bows of the mighty men &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; broken, and they that stumbled are girded with strength.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;They that were&lt;/span&gt; full have hired out themselves for bread; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they that were&lt;/span&gt; hungry ceased: so that the barren hath born seven; and she that hath many children is waxed feeble.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; killeth, and maketh alive: he bringeth down to the grave, and bringeth up.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; maketh poor, and maketh rich: he bringeth low, and lifteth up.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He raiseth up the poor out of the dust, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; lifteth up the beggar from the dunghill, to set &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; among princes, and to make them inherit the throne of glory: for the pillars of the earth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s, and he hath set the world upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He will keep the feet of his saints, and the wicked shall be silent in darkness; for by strength shall no man prevail.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The adversaries of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be broken to pieces; out of heaven shall he thunder upon them: the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall judge the ends of the earth; and he shall give strength unto his king, and exalt the horn of his anointed.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Elkanah went to Ramah to his house. And the child did minister unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; before Eli the priest.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Now the sons of Eli &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; sons of Belial; they knew not the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the priests' custom with the people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was, that&lt;/span&gt;, when any man offered sacrifice, the priest's servant came, while the flesh was in seething, with a fleshhook of three teeth in his hand;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he struck &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; into the pan, or kettle, or caldron, or pot; all that the fleshhook brought up the priest took for himself. So they did in Shiloh unto all the Israelites that came thither.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Also before they burnt the fat, the priest's servant came, and said to the man that sacrificed, Give flesh to roast for the priest; for he will not have sodden flesh of thee, but raw.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; any man said unto him, Let them not fail to burn the fat presently, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; take &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as much&lt;/span&gt; as thy soul desireth; then he would answer him, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Nay&lt;/span&gt;; but thou shalt give &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it me&lt;/span&gt; now: and if not, I will take &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; by force.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Wherefore the sin of the young men was very great before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for men abhorred the offering of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">But Samuel ministered before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; a child, girded with a linen ephod.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Moreover his mother made him a little coat, and brought &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to him from year to year, when she came up with her husband to offer the yearly sacrifice.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And Eli blessed Elkanah and his wife, and said, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; give thee seed of this woman for the loan which is lent to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. And they went unto their own home.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; visited Hannah, so that she conceived, and bare three sons and two daughters. And the child Samuel grew before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">Now Eli was very old, and heard all that his sons did unto all Israel; and how they lay with the women that assembled &lt;span class='extra'&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; the door of the tabernacle of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he said unto them, Why do ye such things? for I hear of your evil dealings by all this people.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Nay, my sons; for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; no good report that I hear: ye make the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s people to transgress.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">If one man sin against another, the judge shall judge him: but if a man sin against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, who shall intreat for him? Notwithstanding they hearkened not unto the voice of their father, because the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; would slay them.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And the child Samuel grew on, and was in favour both with the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and also with men.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And there came a man of God unto Eli, and said unto him, Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Did I plainly appear unto the house of thy father, when they were in Egypt in Pharaoh's house?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And did I choose him out of all the tribes of Israel &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; my priest, to offer upon mine altar, to burn incense, to wear an ephod before me? and did I give unto the house of thy father all the offerings made by fire of the children of Israel?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Wherefore kick ye at my sacrifice and at mine offering, which I have commanded &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in my&lt;/span&gt; habitation; and honourest thy sons above me, to make yourselves fat with the chiefest of all the offerings of Israel my people?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Wherefore the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel saith, I said indeed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thy house, and the house of thy father, should walk before me for ever: but now the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; saith, Be it far from me; for them that honour me I will honour, and they that despise me shall be lightly esteemed.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Behold, the days come, that I will cut off thine arm, and the arm of thy father's house, that there shall not be an old man in thine house.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And thou shalt see an enemy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in my&lt;/span&gt; habitation, in all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the wealth&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; shall give Israel: and there shall not be an old man in thine house for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And the man of thine, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;whom&lt;/span&gt; I shall not cut off from mine altar, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; to consume thine eyes, and to grieve thine heart: and all the increase of thine house shall die in the flower of their age.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a sign unto thee, that shall come upon thy two sons, on Hophni and Phinehas; in one day they shall die both of them.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And I will raise me up a faithful priest, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shall do according to &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in mine heart and in my mind: and I will build him a sure house; and he shall walk before mine anointed for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And it shall come to pass, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; every one that is left in thine house shall come &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; crouch to him for a piece of silver and a morsel of bread, and shall say, Put me, I pray thee, into one of the priests' offices, that I may eat a piece of bread.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>