<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="35" nextChapter="1samuel_16.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 16" prevChapter="1samuel_14.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 14" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Samuel also said unto Saul, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent me to anoint thee &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; king over his people, over Israel: now therefore hearken thou unto the voice of the words of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, I remember &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; which Amalek did to Israel, how he laid &lt;i&gt;wait&lt;/i&gt; for him in the way, when he came up from Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Now go and smite Amalek, and utterly destroy all that they have, and spare them not; but slay both man and woman, infant and suckling, ox and sheep, camel and ass.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Saul gathered the people together, and numbered them in Telaim, two hundred thousand footmen, and ten thousand men of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Saul came to a city of Amalek, and laid wait in the valley.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And Saul said unto the Kenites, Go, depart, get you down from among the Amalekites, lest I destroy you with them: for ye shewed kindness to all the children of Israel, when they came up out of Egypt. So the Kenites departed from among the Amalekites.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Saul smote the Amalekites from Havilah &lt;i&gt;until&lt;/i&gt; thou comest to Shur, that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; over against Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he took Agag the king of the Amalekites alive, and utterly destroyed all the people with the edge of the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But Saul and the people spared Agag, and the best of the sheep, and of the oxen, and of the fatlings, and the lambs, and all &lt;i&gt;that was&lt;/i&gt; good, and would not utterly destroy them: but every thing &lt;i&gt;that was&lt;/i&gt; vile and refuse, that they destroyed utterly.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Then came the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto Samuel, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">It repenteth me that I have set up Saul &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; king: for he is turned back from following me, and hath not performed my commandments. And it grieved Samuel; and he cried unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; all night.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And when Samuel rose early to meet Saul in the morning, it was told Samuel, saying, Saul came to Carmel, and, behold, he set him up a place, and is gone about, and passed on, and gone down to Gilgal.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Samuel came to Saul: and Saul said unto him, Blessed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; thou of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: I have performed the commandment of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Samuel said, What &lt;i&gt;meaneth&lt;/i&gt; then this bleating of the sheep in mine ears, and the lowing of the oxen which I hear?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Saul said, They have brought them from the Amalekites: for the people spared the best of the sheep and of the oxen, to sacrifice unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God; and the rest we have utterly destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Then Samuel said unto Saul, Stay, and I will tell thee what the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath said to me this night. And he said unto him, Say on.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Samuel said, When thou &lt;i&gt;wast&lt;/i&gt; little in thine own sight, &lt;i&gt;wast&lt;/i&gt; thou not &lt;i&gt;made&lt;/i&gt; the head of the tribes of Israel, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; anointed thee king over Israel?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent thee on a journey, and said, Go and utterly destroy the sinners the Amalekites, and fight against them until they be consumed.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Wherefore then didst thou not obey the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, but didst fly upon the spoil, and didst evil in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Saul said unto Samuel, Yea, I have obeyed the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and have gone the way which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent me, and have brought Agag the king of Amalek, and have utterly destroyed the Amalekites.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But the people took of the spoil, sheep and oxen, the chief of the things which should have been utterly destroyed, to sacrifice unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God in Gilgal.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Samuel said, Hath the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;as great&lt;/i&gt; delight in burnt offerings and sacrifices, as in obeying the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? Behold, to obey &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; better than sacrifice, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; to hearken than the fat of rams.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For rebellion &lt;i&gt;is as&lt;/i&gt; the sin of witchcraft, and stubbornness &lt;i&gt;is as&lt;/i&gt; iniquity and idolatry. Because thou hast rejected the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, he hath also rejected thee from &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; king.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And Saul said unto Samuel, I have sinned: for I have transgressed the commandment of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and thy words: because I feared the people, and obeyed their voice.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Now therefore, I pray thee, pardon my sin, and turn again with me, that I may worship the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Samuel said unto Saul, I will not return with thee: for thou hast rejected the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath rejected thee from being king over Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And as Samuel turned about to go away, he laid hold upon the skirt of his mantle, and it rent.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Samuel said unto him, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath rent the kingdom of Israel from thee this day, and hath given it to a neighbour of thine, &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; better than thou.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And also the Strength of Israel will not lie nor repent: for he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not a man, that he should repent.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Then he said, I have sinned: &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; honour me now, I pray thee, before the elders of my people, and before Israel, and turn again with me, that I may worship the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">So Samuel turned again after Saul; and Saul worshipped the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">Then said Samuel, Bring ye hither to me Agag the king of the Amalekites. And Agag came unto him delicately. And Agag said, Surely the bitterness of death is past.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And Samuel said, As thy sword hath made women childless, so shall thy mother be childless among women. And Samuel hewed Agag in pieces before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in Gilgal.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">Then Samuel went to Ramah; and Saul went up to his house to Gibeah of Saul.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And Samuel came no more to see Saul until the day of his death: nevertheless Samuel mourned for Saul: and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; repented that he had made Saul king over Israel.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>