<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="26" verseCount="25" nextChapter="1samuel_27.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 27" prevChapter="1samuel_25.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 25" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the Ziphites came unto Saul to Gibeah, saying, Doth not David hide himself in the hill of Hachilah, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which is&lt;/span&gt; before Jeshimon?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then Saul arose, and went down to the wilderness of Ziph, having three thousand chosen men of Israel with him, to seek David in the wilderness of Ziph.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Saul pitched in the hill of Hachilah, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; before Jeshimon, by the way. But David abode in the wilderness, and he saw that Saul came after him into the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">David therefore sent out spies, and understood that Saul was come in very deed.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And David arose, and came to the place where Saul had pitched: and David beheld the place where Saul lay, and Abner the son of Ner, the captain of his host: and Saul lay in the trench, and the people pitched round about him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Then answered David and said to Ahimelech the Hittite, and to Abishai the son of Zeruiah, brother to Joab, saying, Who will go down with me to Saul to the camp? And Abishai said, I will go down with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">So David and Abishai came to the people by night: and, behold, Saul lay sleeping within the trench, and his spear stuck in the ground at his bolster: but Abner and the people lay round about him.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then said Abishai to David, God hath delivered thine enemy into thine hand this day: now therefore let me smite him, I pray thee, with the spear even to the earth at once, and I will not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;smite&lt;/span&gt; him the second time.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And David said to Abishai, Destroy him not: for who can stretch forth his hand against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s anointed, and be guiltless?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">David said furthermore, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall smite him; or his day shall come to die; or he shall descend into battle, and perish.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; forbid that I should stretch forth mine hand against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s anointed: but, I pray thee, take thou now the spear that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; at his bolster, and the cruse of water, and let us go.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">So David took the spear and the cruse of water from Saul's bolster; and they gat them away, and no man saw &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, nor knew &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, neither awaked: for they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; all asleep; because a deep sleep from the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was fallen upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Then David went over to the other side, and stood on the top of an hill afar off; a great space &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; between them:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And David cried to the people, and to Abner the son of Ner, saying, Answerest thou not, Abner? Then Abner answered and said, Who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; criest to the king?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And David said to Abner, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Art&lt;/span&gt; not thou a &lt;span class='extra'&gt;valiant&lt;/span&gt; man? and who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; like to thee in Israel? wherefore then hast thou not kept thy lord the king? for there came one of the people in to destroy the king thy lord.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">This thing &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not good that thou hast done. &lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth, ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; worthy to die, because ye have not kept your master, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s anointed. And now see where the king's spear &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;, and the cruse of water that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; at his bolster.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Saul knew David's voice, and said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; this thy voice, my son David? And David said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; my voice, my lord, O king.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And he said, Wherefore doth my lord thus pursue after his servant? for what have I done? or what evil &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in mine hand?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Now therefore, I pray thee, let my lord the king hear the words of his servant. If the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have stirred thee up against me, let him accept an offering: but if &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they be&lt;/span&gt; the children of men, cursed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; they before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for they have driven me out this day from abiding in the inheritance of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, saying, Go, serve other gods.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Now therefore, let not my blood fall to the earth before the face of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for the king of Israel is come out to seek a flea, as when one doth hunt a partridge in the mountains.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Then said Saul, I have sinned: return, my son David: for I will no more do thee harm, because my soul was precious in thine eyes this day: behold, I have played the fool, and have erred exceedingly.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And David answered and said, Behold the king's spear! and let one of the young men come over and fetch it.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; render to every man his righteousness and his faithfulness: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; delivered thee into &lt;span class='extra'&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; hand to day, but I would not stretch forth mine hand against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s anointed.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And, behold, as thy life was much set by this day in mine eyes, so let my life be much set by in the eyes of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and let him deliver me out of all tribulation.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then Saul said to David, Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; thou, my son David: thou shalt both do great &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;, and also shalt still prevail. So David went on his way, and Saul returned to his place.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>