<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="30" verseCount="31" nextChapter="1samuel_31.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 31" prevChapter="1samuel_29.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 29" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, when David and his men were come to Ziklag on the third day, that the Amalekites had invaded the south, and Ziklag, and smitten Ziklag, and burned it with fire;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And had taken the women captives, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; therein: they slew not any, either great or small, but carried &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; away, and went on their way.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">So David and his men came to the city, and, behold, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it was&lt;/span&gt; burned with fire; and their wives, and their sons, and their daughters, were taken captives.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Then David and the people that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him lifted up their voice and wept, until they had no more power to weep.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And David's two wives were taken captives, Ahinoam the Jezreelitess, and Abigail the wife of Nabal the Carmelite.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And David was greatly distressed; for the people spake of stoning him, because the soul of all the people was grieved, every man for his sons and for his daughters: but David encouraged himself in the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And David said to Abiathar the priest, Ahimelech's son, I pray thee, bring me hither the ephod. And Abiathar brought thither the ephod to David.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And David enquired at the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, saying, Shall I pursue after this troop? shall I overtake them? And he answered him, Pursue: for thou shalt surely overtake &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, and without fail recover &lt;span class="extra"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">So David went, he and the six hundred men that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him, and came to the brook Besor, where those that were left behind stayed.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But David pursued, he and four hundred men: for two hundred abode behind, which were so faint that they could not go over the brook Besor.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And they found an Egyptian in the field, and brought him to David, and gave him bread, and he did eat; and they made him drink water;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And they gave him a piece of a cake of figs, and two clusters of raisins: and when he had eaten, his spirit came again to him: for he had eaten no bread, nor drunk &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; water, three days and three nights.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And David said unto him, To whom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;belongest&lt;/span&gt; thou? and whence &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; thou? And he said, I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; a young man of Egypt, servant to an Amalekite; and my master left me, because three days agone I fell sick.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">We made an invasion &lt;span class="extra"&gt;upon&lt;/span&gt; the south of the Cherethites, and upon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the coast&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;belongeth&lt;/span&gt; to Judah, and upon the south of Caleb; and we burned Ziklag with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And David said to him, Canst thou bring me down to this company? And he said, Swear unto me by God, that thou wilt neither kill me, nor deliver me into the hands of my master, and I will bring thee down to this company.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And when he had brought him down, behold, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;they were&lt;/span&gt; spread abroad upon all the earth, eating and drinking, and dancing, because of all the great spoil that they had taken out of the land of the Philistines, and out of the land of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And David smote them from the twilight even unto the evening of the next day: and there escaped not a man of them, save four hundred young men, which rode upon camels, and fled.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And David recovered all that the Amalekites had carried away: and David rescued his two wives.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And there was nothing lacking to them, neither small nor great, neither sons nor daughters, neither spoil, nor any &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thing&lt;/span&gt; that they had taken to them: David recovered all.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And David took all the flocks and the herds, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; they drave before those &lt;span class="extra"&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; cattle, and said, This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; David's spoil.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">And David came to the two hundred men, which were so faint that they could not follow David, whom they had made also to abide at the brook Besor: and they went forth to meet David, and to meet the people that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him: and when David came near to the people, he saluted them.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then answered all the wicked men and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; of Belial, of those that went with David, and said, Because they went not with us, we will not give them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ought&lt;/span&gt; of the spoil that we have recovered, save to every man his wife and his children, that they may lead &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; away, and depart.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Then said David, Ye shall not do so, my brethren, with that which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath given us, who hath preserved us, and delivered the company that came against us into our hand.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For who will hearken unto you in this matter? but as his part &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; that goeth down to the battle, so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall&lt;/span&gt; his part &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; that tarrieth by the stuff: they shall part alike.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And it was &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; from that day forward, that he made it a statute and an ordinance for Israel unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And when David came to Ziklag, he sent of the spoil unto the elders of Judah, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to his friends, saying, Behold a present for you of the spoil of the enemies of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">To &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Beth-el, and to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in south Ramoth, and to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Jattir,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Aroer, and to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Siphmoth, and to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Eshtemoa,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Rachal, and to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the cities of the Jerahmeelites, and to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the cities of the Kenites,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Hormah, and to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Chorashan, and to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Athach,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Hebron, and to all the places where David himself and his men were wont to haunt.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>