<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="25" nextChapter="1samuel_13.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 13" prevChapter="1samuel_11.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 11" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Samuel said unto all Israel, Behold, I have hearkened unto your voice in all that ye said unto me, and have made a king over you.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And now, behold, the king walketh before you: and I am old and grayheaded; and, behold, my sons &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; with you: and I have walked before you from my childhood unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Behold, here I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt;: witness against me before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and before his anointed: whose ox have I taken? or whose ass have I taken? or whom have I defrauded? whom have I oppressed? or of whose hand have I received &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; bribe to blind mine eyes therewith? and I will restore it you.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they said, Thou hast not defrauded us, nor oppressed us, neither hast thou taken ought of any man's hand.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he said unto them, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; witness against you, and his anointed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; witness this day, that ye have not found ought in my hand. And they answered, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;He is&lt;/span&gt; witness.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And Samuel said unto the people, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that advanced Moses and Aaron, and that brought your fathers up out of the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Now therefore stand still, that I may reason with you before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of all the righteous acts of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which he did to you and to your fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">When Jacob was come into Egypt, and your fathers cried unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, then the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent Moses and Aaron, which brought forth your fathers out of Egypt, and made them dwell in this place.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And when they forgat the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God, he sold them into the hand of Sisera, captain of the host of Hazor, and into the hand of the Philistines, and into the hand of the king of Moab, and they fought against them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they cried unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and said, We have sinned, because we have forsaken the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and have served Baalim and Ashtaroth: but now deliver us out of the hand of our enemies, and we will serve thee.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent Jerubbaal, and Bedan, and Jephthah, and Samuel, and delivered you out of the hand of your enemies on every side, and ye dwelled safe.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And when ye saw that Nahash the king of the children of Ammon came against you, ye said unto me, Nay; but a king shall reign over us: when the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; your king.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Now therefore behold the king whom ye have chosen, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; whom ye have desired! and, behold, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath set a king over you.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">If ye will fear the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and serve him, and obey his voice, and not rebel against the commandment of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, then shall both ye and also the king that reigneth over you continue following the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But if ye will not obey the voice of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, but rebel against the commandment of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, then shall the hand of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be against you, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it was&lt;/span&gt; against your fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Now therefore stand and see this great thing, which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will do before your eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is it&lt;/span&gt; not wheat harvest to day? I will call unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and he shall send thunder and rain; that ye may perceive and see that your wickedness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; great, which ye have done in the sight of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in asking you a king.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">So Samuel called unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent thunder and rain that day: and all the people greatly feared the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; and Samuel.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And all the people said unto Samuel, Pray for thy servants unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, that we die not: for we have added unto all our sins &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; evil, to ask us a king.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And Samuel said unto the people, Fear not: ye have done all this wickedness: yet turn not aside from following the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, but serve the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with all your heart;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And turn ye not aside: for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;then should ye go&lt;/span&gt; after vain &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;, which cannot profit nor deliver; for they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; vain.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will not forsake his people for his great name's sake: because it hath pleased the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to make you his people.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Moreover as for me, God forbid that I should sin against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in ceasing to pray for you: but I will teach you the good and the right way:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Only fear the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and serve him in truth with all your heart: for consider how great &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; he hath done for you.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">But if ye shall still do wickedly, ye shall be consumed, both ye and your king.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>