<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="9" name="1 Samuel" bookPage="1samuel.html" title="1 Samuel" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2samuel_1.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel" prevBook="ruth_1.html" prevTitle="Ruth">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="27" nextChapter="1samuel_11.html" nextTitle="1 Samuel 11" prevChapter="1samuel_9.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 9" chapterPage="1samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then Samuel took a vial of oil, and poured &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; upon his head, and kissed him, and said, &lt;i&gt;Is it&lt;/i&gt; not because the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath anointed thee &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; captain over his inheritance?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">When thou art departed from me to day, then thou shalt find two men by Rachel's sepulchre in the border of Benjamin at Zelzah; and they will say unto thee, The asses which thou wentest to seek are found: and, lo, thy father hath left the care of the asses, and sorroweth for you, saying, What shall I do for my son?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Then shalt thou go on forward from thence, and thou shalt come to the plain of Tabor, and there shall meet thee three men going up to God to Beth-el, one carrying three kids, and another carrying three loaves of bread, and another carrying a bottle of wine:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they will salute thee, and give thee two &lt;i&gt;loaves&lt;/i&gt; of bread; which thou shalt receive of their hands.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">After that thou shalt come to the hill of God, where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the garrison of the Philistines: and it shall come to pass, when thou art come thither to the city, that thou shalt meet a company of prophets coming down from the high place with a psaltery, and a tabret, and a pipe, and a harp, before them; and they shall prophesy:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the Spirit of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will come upon thee, and thou shalt prophesy with them, and shalt be turned into another man.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And let it be, when these signs are come unto thee, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thou do as occasion serve thee; for God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And thou shalt go down before me to Gilgal; and, behold, I will come down unto thee, to offer burnt offerings, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; to sacrifice sacrifices of peace offerings: seven days shalt thou tarry, till I come to thee, and shew thee what thou shalt do.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And it was &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt;, that when he had turned his back to go from Samuel, God gave him another heart: and all those signs came to pass that day.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And when they came thither to the hill, behold, a company of prophets met him; and the Spirit of God came upon him, and he prophesied among them.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And it came to pass, when all that knew him beforetime saw that, behold, he prophesied among the prophets, then the people said one to another, What &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; this &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; is come unto the son of Kish? &lt;i&gt;Is&lt;/i&gt; Saul also among the prophets?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And one of the same place answered and said, But who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; their father? Therefore it became a proverb, &lt;i&gt;Is&lt;/i&gt; Saul also among the prophets?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And when he had made an end of prophesying, he came to the high place.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And Saul's uncle said unto him and to his servant, Whither went ye? And he said, To seek the asses: and when we saw that &lt;i&gt;they were&lt;/i&gt; no where, we came to Samuel.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Saul's uncle said, Tell me, I pray thee, what Samuel said unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Saul said unto his uncle, He told us plainly that the asses were found. But of the matter of the kingdom, whereof Samuel spake, he told him not.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And Samuel called the people together unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to Mizpeh;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And said unto the children of Israel, Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, I brought up Israel out of Egypt, and delivered you out of the hand of the Egyptians, and out of the hand of all kingdoms, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; of them that oppressed you:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And ye have this day rejected your God, who himself saved you out of all your adversities and your tribulations; and ye have said unto him, &lt;i&gt;Nay&lt;/i&gt;, but set a king over us. Now therefore present yourselves before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; by your tribes, and by your thousands.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And when Samuel had caused all the tribes of Israel to come near, the tribe of Benjamin was taken.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">When he had caused the tribe of Benjamin to come near by their families, the family of Matri was taken, and Saul the son of Kish was taken: and when they sought him, he could not be found.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Therefore they enquired of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; further, if the man should yet come thither. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; answered, Behold, he hath hid himself among the stuff.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And they ran and fetched him thence: and when he stood among the people, he was higher than any of the people from his shoulders and upward.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Samuel said to all the people, See ye him whom the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath chosen, that &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none like him among all the people? And all the people shouted, and said, God save the king.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then Samuel told the people the manner of the kingdom, and wrote &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; in a book, and laid &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; up before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. And Samuel sent all the people away, every man to his house.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And Saul also went home to Gibeah; and there went with him a band of men, whose hearts God had touched.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">But the children of Belial said, How shall this man save us? And they despised him, and brought him no presents. But he held his peace.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>