<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="10" name="2 Samuel" bookPage="2samuel.html" title="2 Samuel" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1kings_1.html" nextTitle="1 Kings" prevBook="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="37" nextChapter="2samuel_16.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 16" prevChapter="2samuel_14.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel 14" chapterPage="2samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass after this, that Absalom prepared him chariots and horses, and fifty men to run before him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Absalom rose up early, and stood beside the way of the gate: and it was &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt;, that when any man that had a controversy came to the king for judgment, then Absalom called unto him, and said, Of what city &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; thou? And he said, Thy servant &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; of one of the tribes of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Absalom said unto him, See, thy matters &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; good and right; but &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no man &lt;i&gt;deputed&lt;/i&gt; of the king to hear thee.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Absalom said moreover, Oh that I were made judge in the land, that every man which hath any suit or cause might come unto me, and I would do him justice!</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And it was &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt;, that when any man came nigh &lt;i&gt;to him&lt;/i&gt; to do him obeisance, he put forth his hand, and took him, and kissed him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And on this manner did Absalom to all Israel that came to the king for judgment: so Absalom stole the hearts of the men of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And it came to pass after forty years, that Absalom said unto the king, I pray thee, let me go and pay my vow, which I have vowed unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in Hebron.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For thy servant vowed a vow while I abode at Geshur in Syria, saying, If the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall bring me again indeed to Jerusalem, then I will serve the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the king said unto him, Go in peace. So he arose, and went to Hebron.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">But Absalom sent spies throughout all the tribes of Israel, saying, As soon as ye hear the sound of the trumpet, then ye shall say, Absalom reigneth in Hebron.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And with Absalom went two hundred men out of Jerusalem, &lt;i&gt;that were&lt;/i&gt; called; and they went in their simplicity, and they knew not any thing.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Absalom sent for Ahithophel the Gilonite, David's counsellor, from his city, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; from Giloh, while he offered sacrifices. And the conspiracy was strong; for the people increased continually with Absalom.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And there came a messenger to David, saying, The hearts of the men of Israel are after Absalom.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And David said unto all his servants that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with him at Jerusalem, Arise, and let us flee; for we shall not &lt;i&gt;else&lt;/i&gt; escape from Absalom: make speed to depart, lest he overtake us suddenly, and bring evil upon us, and smite the city with the edge of the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the king's servants said unto the king, Behold, thy servants &lt;i&gt;are ready to do&lt;/i&gt; whatsoever my lord the king shall appoint.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the king went forth, and all his household after him. And the king left ten women, &lt;i&gt;which were&lt;/i&gt; concubines, to keep the house.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the king went forth, and all the people after him, and tarried in a place that was far off.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And all his servants passed on beside him; and all the Cherethites, and all the Pelethites, and all the Gittites, six hundred men which came after him from Gath, passed on before the king.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">Then said the king to Ittai the Gittite, Wherefore goest thou also with us? return to thy place, and abide with the king: for thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; a stranger, and also an exile.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Whereas thou camest &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; yesterday, should I this day make thee go up and down with us? seeing I go whither I may, return thou, and take back thy brethren: mercy and truth &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Ittai answered the king, and said, &lt;i&gt;As&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth, and &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; my lord the king liveth, surely in what place my lord the king shall be, whether in death or life, even there also will thy servant be.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And David said to Ittai, Go and pass over. And Ittai the Gittite passed over, and all his men, and all the little ones that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And all the country wept with a loud voice, and all the people passed over: the king also himself passed over the brook Kidron, and all the people passed over, toward the way of the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And lo Zadok also, and all the Levites &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with him, bearing the ark of the covenant of God: and they set down the ark of God; and Abiathar went up, until all the people had done passing out of the city.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the king said unto Zadok, Carry back the ark of God into the city: if I shall find favour in the eyes of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, he will bring me again, and shew me &lt;i&gt;both&lt;/i&gt; it, and his habitation:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">But if he thus say, I have no delight in thee; behold, &lt;i&gt;here am&lt;/i&gt; I, let him do to me as seemeth good unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The king said also unto Zadok the priest, &lt;i&gt;Art not&lt;/i&gt; thou a seer? return into the city in peace, and your two sons with you, Ahimaaz thy son, and Jonathan the son of Abiathar.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">See, I will tarry in the plain of the wilderness, until there come word from you to certify me.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Zadok therefore and Abiathar carried the ark of God again to Jerusalem: and they tarried there.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">And David went up by the ascent of &lt;i&gt;mount&lt;/i&gt; Olivet, and wept as he went up, and had his head covered, and he went barefoot: and all the people that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; with him covered every man his head, and they went up, weeping as they went up.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; told David, saying, Ahithophel &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; among the conspirators with Absalom. And David said, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I pray thee, turn the counsel of Ahithophel into foolishness.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">And it came to pass, that &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; David was come to the top &lt;i&gt;of the mount&lt;/i&gt;, where he worshipped God, behold, Hushai the Archite came to meet him with his coat rent, and earth upon his head:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Unto whom David said, If thou passest on with me, then thou shalt be a burden unto me:</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">But if thou return to the city, and say unto Absalom, I will be thy servant, O king; &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; I &lt;i&gt;have been&lt;/i&gt; thy father's servant hitherto, so &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; I now also &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; thy servant: then mayest thou for me defeat the counsel of Ahithophel.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And &lt;i&gt;hast thou&lt;/i&gt; not there with thee Zadok and Abiathar the priests? therefore it shall be, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; what thing soever thou shalt hear out of the king's house, thou shalt tell &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to Zadok and Abiathar the priests.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Behold, &lt;i&gt;they have&lt;/i&gt; there with them their two sons, Ahimaaz Zadok's &lt;i&gt;son&lt;/i&gt;, and Jonathan Abiathar's &lt;i&gt;son&lt;/i&gt;; and by them ye shall send unto me every thing that ye can hear.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">So Hushai David's friend came into the city, and Absalom came into Jerusalem.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>