<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="10" name="2 Samuel" bookPage="2samuel.html" title="2 Samuel" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1kings_1.html" nextTitle="1 Kings" prevBook="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="31" nextChapter="2samuel_13.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 13" prevChapter="2samuel_11.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel 11" chapterPage="2samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent Nathan unto David. And he came unto him, and said unto him, There were two men in one city; the one rich, and the other poor.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The rich &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; had exceeding many flocks and herds:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But the poor &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; had nothing, save one little ewe lamb, which he had bought and nourished up: and it grew up together with him, and with his children; it did eat of his own meat, and drank of his own cup, and lay in his bosom, and was unto him as a daughter.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And there came a traveller unto the rich man, and he spared to take of his own flock and of his own herd, to dress for the wayfaring man that was come unto him; but took the poor man's lamb, and dressed it for the man that was come to him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And David's anger was greatly kindled against the man; and he said to Nathan, &lt;i&gt;As&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth, the man that hath done this &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; shall surely die:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he shall restore the lamb fourfold, because he did this thing, and because he had no pity.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And Nathan said to David, Thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; the man. Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, I anointed thee king over Israel, and I delivered thee out of the hand of Saul;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I gave thee thy master's house, and thy master's wives into thy bosom, and gave thee the house of Israel and of Judah; and if &lt;i&gt;that had been&lt;/i&gt; too little, I would moreover have given unto thee such and such things.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Wherefore hast thou despised the commandment of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to do evil in his sight? thou hast killed Uriah the Hittite with the sword, and hast taken his wife &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; thy wife, and hast slain him with the sword of the children of Ammon.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Now therefore the sword shall never depart from thine house; because thou hast despised me, and hast taken the wife of Uriah the Hittite to be thy wife.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Behold, I will raise up evil against thee out of thine own house, and I will take thy wives before thine eyes, and give &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; unto thy neighbour, and he shall lie with thy wives in the sight of this sun.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For thou didst &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; secretly: but I will do this thing before all Israel, and before the sun.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And David said unto Nathan, I have sinned against the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. And Nathan said unto David, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; also hath put away thy sin; thou shalt not die.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Howbeit, because by this deed thou hast given great occasion to the enemies of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to blaspheme, the child also &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; born unto thee shall surely die.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And Nathan departed unto his house. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; struck the child that Uriah's wife bare unto David, and it was very sick.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">David therefore besought God for the child; and David fasted, and went in, and lay all night upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the elders of his house arose, &lt;i&gt;and went&lt;/i&gt; to him, to raise him up from the earth: but he would not, neither did he eat bread with them.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And it came to pass on the seventh day, that the child died. And the servants of David feared to tell him that the child was dead: for they said, Behold, while the child was yet alive, we spake unto him, and he would not hearken unto our voice: how will he then vex himself, if we tell him that the child is dead?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But when David saw that his servants whispered, David perceived that the child was dead: therefore David said unto his servants, Is the child dead? And they said, He is dead.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Then David arose from the earth, and washed, and anointed &lt;i&gt;himself&lt;/i&gt;, and changed his apparel, and came into the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and worshipped: then he came to his own house; and when he required, they set bread before him, and he did eat.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then said his servants unto him, What thing &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; this that thou hast done? thou didst fast and weep for the child, &lt;i&gt;while it was&lt;/i&gt; alive; but when the child was dead, thou didst rise and eat bread.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And he said, While the child was yet alive, I fasted and wept: for I said, Who can tell &lt;i&gt;whether&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; will be gracious to me, that the child may live?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But now he is dead, wherefore should I fast? can I bring him back again? I shall go to him, but he shall not return to me.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And David comforted Bath-sheba his wife, and went in unto her, and lay with her: and she bare a son, and he called his name Solomon: and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; loved him.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And he sent by the hand of Nathan the prophet; and he called his name Jedidiah, because of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And Joab fought against Rabbah of the children of Ammon, and took the royal city.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Joab sent messengers to David, and said, I have fought against Rabbah, and have taken the city of waters.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Now therefore gather the rest of the people together, and encamp against the city, and take it: lest I take the city, and it be called after my name.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And David gathered all the people together, and went to Rabbah, and fought against it, and took it.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And he took their king's crown from off his head, the weight whereof &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a talent of gold with the precious stones: and it was &lt;i&gt;set&lt;/i&gt; on David's head. And he brought forth the spoil of the city in great abundance.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And he brought forth the people that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; therein, and put &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; under saws, and under harrows of iron, and under axes of iron, and made them pass through the brickkiln: and thus did he unto all the cities of the children of Ammon. So David and all the people returned unto Jerusalem.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>