<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="10" name="2 Samuel" bookPage="2samuel.html" title="2 Samuel" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1kings_1.html" nextTitle="1 Kings" prevBook="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="29" nextChapter="2samuel_8.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 8" prevChapter="2samuel_6.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel 6" chapterPage="2samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, when the king sat in his house, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had given him rest round about from all his enemies;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That the king said unto Nathan the prophet, See now, I dwell in an house of cedar, but the ark of God dwelleth within curtains.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Nathan said to the king, Go, do all that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in thine heart; for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And it came to pass that night, that the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto Nathan, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Go and tell my servant David, Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Shalt thou build me an house for me to dwell in?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Whereas I have not dwelt in &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; house since the time that I brought up the children of Israel out of Egypt, even to this day, but have walked in a tent and in a tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">In all &lt;i&gt;the places&lt;/i&gt; wherein I have walked with all the children of Israel spake I a word with any of the tribes of Israel, whom I commanded to feed my people Israel, saying, Why build ye not me an house of cedar?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Now therefore so shalt thou say unto my servant David, Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, I took thee from the sheepcote, from following the sheep, to be ruler over my people, over Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And I was with thee whithersoever thou wentest, and have cut off all thine enemies out of thy sight, and have made thee a great name, like unto the name of the great &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Moreover I will appoint a place for my people Israel, and will plant them, that they may dwell in a place of their own, and move no more; neither shall the children of wickedness afflict them any more, as beforetime,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And as since the time that I commanded judges &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; over my people Israel, and have caused thee to rest from all thine enemies. Also the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; telleth thee that he will make thee an house.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And when thy days be fulfilled, and thou shalt sleep with thy fathers, I will set up thy seed after thee, which shall proceed out of thy bowels, and I will establish his kingdom.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He shall build an house for my name, and I will stablish the throne of his kingdom for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I will be his father, and he shall be my son. If he commit iniquity, I will chasten him with the rod of men, and with the stripes of the children of men:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But my mercy shall not depart away from him, as I took &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; from Saul, whom I put away before thee.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And thine house and thy kingdom shall be established for ever before thee: thy throne shall be established for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">According to all these words, and according to all this vision, so did Nathan speak unto David.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Then went king David in, and sat before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and he said, Who &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I, O Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;? and what &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my house, that thou hast brought me hitherto?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And this was yet a small thing in thy sight, O Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; but thou hast spoken also of thy servant's house for a great while to come. And &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; this the manner of man, O Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And what can David say more unto thee? for thou, Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, knowest thy servant.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For thy word's sake, and according to thine own heart, hast thou done all these great things, to make thy servant know &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Wherefore thou art great, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God: for &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none like thee, neither &lt;i&gt;is there any&lt;/i&gt; God beside thee, according to all that we have heard with our ears.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And what one nation in the earth &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; like thy people, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; like Israel, whom God went to redeem for a people to himself, and to make him a name, and to do for you great things and terrible, for thy land, before thy people, which thou redeemedst to thee from Egypt, &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; the nations and their gods?</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For thou hast confirmed to thyself thy people Israel &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; a people unto thee for ever: and thou, &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, art become their God.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And now, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God, the word that thou hast spoken concerning thy servant, and concerning his house, establish &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; for ever, and do as thou hast said.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And let thy name be magnified for ever, saying, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the God over Israel: and let the house of thy servant David be established before thee.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For thou, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, God of Israel, hast revealed to thy servant, saying, I will build thee an house: therefore hath thy servant found in his heart to pray this prayer unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And now, O Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; that God, and thy words be true, and thou hast promised this goodness unto thy servant:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Therefore now let it please thee to bless the house of thy servant, that it may continue for ever before thee: for thou, O Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, hast spoken &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;: and with thy blessing let the house of thy servant be blessed for ever.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>