<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="10" name="2 Samuel" bookPage="2samuel.html" title="2 Samuel" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1kings_1.html" nextTitle="1 Kings" prevBook="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="51" nextChapter="2samuel_23.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 23" prevChapter="2samuel_21.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel 21" chapterPage="2samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And David spake unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; the words of this song in the day &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had delivered him out of the hand of all his enemies, and out of the hand of Saul:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he said, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my rock, and my fortress, and my deliverer;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The God of my rock; in him will I trust: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; my shield, and the horn of my salvation, my high tower, and my refuge, my saviour; thou savest me from violence.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I will call on the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;who is&lt;/span&gt; worthy to be praised: so shall I be saved from mine enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">When the waves of death compassed me, the floods of ungodly men made me afraid;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The sorrows of hell compassed me about; the snares of death prevented me;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">In my distress I called upon the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and cried to my God: and he did hear my voice out of his temple, and my cry &lt;span class="extra"&gt;did enter&lt;/span&gt; into his ears.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then the earth shook and trembled; the foundations of heaven moved and shook, because he was wroth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">There went up a smoke out of his nostrils, and fire out of his mouth devoured: coals were kindled by it.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He bowed the heavens also, and came down; and darkness &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; under his feet.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he rode upon a cherub, and did fly: and he was seen upon the wings of the wind.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he made darkness pavilions round about him, dark waters, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; thick clouds of the skies.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Through the brightness before him were coals of fire kindled.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thundered from heaven, and the most High uttered his voice.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he sent out arrows, and scattered them; lightning, and discomfited them.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the channels of the sea appeared, the foundations of the world were discovered, at the rebuking of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, at the blast of the breath of his nostrils.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He sent from above, he took me; he drew me out of many waters;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He delivered me from my strong enemy, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; from them that hated me: for they were too strong for me.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">They prevented me in the day of my calamity: but the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was my stay.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He brought me forth also into a large place: he delivered me, because he delighted in me.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; rewarded me according to my righteousness: according to the cleanness of my hands hath he recompensed me.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For I have kept the ways of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and have not wickedly departed from my God.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For all his judgments &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; before me: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; his statutes, I did not depart from them.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">I was also upright before him, and have kept myself from mine iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Therefore the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath recompensed me according to my righteousness; according to my cleanness in his eye sight.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">With the merciful thou wilt shew thyself merciful, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; with the upright man thou wilt shew thyself upright.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">With the pure thou wilt shew thyself pure; and with the froward thou wilt shew thyself unsavoury.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the afflicted people thou wilt save: but thine eyes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; upon the haughty, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thou mayest bring &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; down.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; my lamp, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will lighten my darkness.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">For by thee I have run through a troop: by my God have I leaped over a wall.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;As for&lt;/span&gt; God, his way &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; perfect; the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; tried: he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a buckler to all them that trust in him.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">For who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; God, save the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? and who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a rock, save our God?</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my strength &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; power: and he maketh my way perfect.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">He maketh my feet like hinds' &lt;span class="extra"&gt;feet&lt;/span&gt;: and setteth me upon my high places.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">He teacheth my hands to war; so that a bow of steel is broken by mine arms.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Thou hast also given me the shield of thy salvation: and thy gentleness hath made me great.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Thou hast enlarged my steps under me; so that my feet did not slip.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">I have pursued mine enemies, and destroyed them; and turned not again until I had consumed them.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And I have consumed them, and wounded them, that they could not arise: yea, they are fallen under my feet.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">For thou hast girded me with strength to battle: them that rose up against me hast thou subdued under me.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Thou hast also given me the necks of mine enemies, that I might destroy them that hate me.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">They looked, but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; none to save; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, but he answered them not.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Then did I beat them as small as the dust of the earth, I did stamp them as the mire of the street, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; did spread them abroad.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">Thou also hast delivered me from the strivings of my people, thou hast kept me &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; head of the heathen: a people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; I knew not shall serve me.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">Strangers shall submit themselves unto me: as soon as they hear, they shall be obedient unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">Strangers shall fade away, and they shall be afraid out of their close places.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth; and blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; my rock; and exalted be the God of the rock of my salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">It &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; God that avengeth me, and that bringeth down the people under me,</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And that bringeth me forth from mine enemies: thou also hast lifted me up on high above them that rose up against me: thou hast delivered me from the violent man.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">Therefore I will give thanks unto thee, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, among the heathen, and I will sing praises unto thy name.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;He is&lt;/span&gt; the tower of salvation for his king: and sheweth mercy to his anointed, unto David, and to his seed for evermore.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>