<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="10" name="2 Samuel" bookPage="2samuel.html" title="2 Samuel" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1kings_1.html" nextTitle="1 Kings" prevBook="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="27" nextChapter="2samuel_2.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 2" prevChapter="1samuel_31.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel 31" chapterPage="2samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now it came to pass after the death of Saul, when David was returned from the slaughter of the Amalekites, and David had abode two days in Ziklag;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">It came even to pass on the third day, that, behold, a man came out of the camp from Saul with his clothes rent, and earth upon his head: and &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; it was, when he came to David, that he fell to the earth, and did obeisance.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And David said unto him, From whence comest thou? And he said unto him, Out of the camp of Israel am I escaped.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And David said unto him, How went the matter? I pray thee, tell me. And he answered, That the people are fled from the battle, and many of the people also are fallen and dead; and Saul and Jonathan his son are dead also.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And David said unto the young man that told him, How knowest thou that Saul and Jonathan his son be dead?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the young man that told him said, As I happened by chance upon mount Gilboa, behold, Saul leaned upon his spear; and, lo, the chariots and horsemen followed hard after him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when he looked behind him, he saw me, and called unto me. And I answered, Here &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he said unto me, Who &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; thou? And I answered him, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; an Amalekite.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He said unto me again, Stand, I pray thee, upon me, and slay me: for anguish is come upon me, because my life &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; yet whole in me.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">So I stood upon him, and slew him, because I was sure that he could not live after that he was fallen: and I took the crown that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; upon his head, and the bracelet that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; on his arm, and have brought them hither unto my lord.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then David took hold on his clothes, and rent them; and likewise all the men that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with him:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And they mourned, and wept, and fasted until even, for Saul, and for Jonathan his son, and for the people of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and for the house of Israel; because they were fallen by the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And David said unto the young man that told him, Whence &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; thou? And he answered, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the son of a stranger, an Amalekite.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And David said unto him, How wast thou not afraid to stretch forth thine hand to destroy the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s anointed?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And David called one of the young men, and said, Go near, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; fall upon him. And he smote him that he died.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And David said unto him, Thy blood &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; upon thy head; for thy mouth hath testified against thee, saying, I have slain the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s anointed.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And David lamented with this lamentation over Saul and over Jonathan his son:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">(Also he bade them teach the children of Judah &lt;i&gt;the use of&lt;/i&gt; the bow: behold, &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; written in the book of Jasher.)</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The beauty of Israel is slain upon thy high places: how are the mighty fallen!</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Tell &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not in Gath, publish &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not in the streets of Askelon; lest the daughters of the Philistines rejoice, lest the daughters of the uncircumcised triumph.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Ye mountains of Gilboa, &lt;i&gt;let there be&lt;/i&gt; no dew, neither &lt;i&gt;let there be&lt;/i&gt; rain, upon you, nor fields of offerings: for there the shield of the mighty is vilely cast away, the shield of Saul, &lt;i&gt;as though he had&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;been&lt;/i&gt; anointed with oil.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">From the blood of the slain, from the fat of the mighty, the bow of Jonathan turned not back, and the sword of Saul returned not empty.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Saul and Jonathan &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; lovely and pleasant in their lives, and in their death they were not divided: they were swifter than eagles, they were stronger than lions.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Ye daughters of Israel, weep over Saul, who clothed you in scarlet, with &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; delights, who put on ornaments of gold upon your apparel.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">How are the mighty fallen in the midst of the battle! O Jonathan, &lt;i&gt;thou wast&lt;/i&gt; slain in thine high places.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">I am distressed for thee, my brother Jonathan: very pleasant hast thou been unto me: thy love to me was wonderful, passing the love of women.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">How are the mighty fallen, and the weapons of war perished!</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>