<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="10" name="2 Samuel" bookPage="2samuel.html" title="2 Samuel" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1kings_1.html" nextTitle="1 Kings" prevBook="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel">
    <chapter number="23" verseCount="39" nextChapter="2samuel_24.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 24" prevChapter="2samuel_22.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel 22" chapterPage="2samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the last words of David. David the son of Jesse said, and the man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;who was&lt;/span&gt; raised up on high, the anointed of the God of Jacob, and the sweet psalmist of Israel, said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The Spirit of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake by me, and his word &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in my tongue.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The God of Israel said, the Rock of Israel spake to me, He that ruleth over men &lt;span class="extra"&gt;must be&lt;/span&gt; just, ruling in the fear of God.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he shall be&lt;/span&gt; as the light of the morning, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; the sun riseth, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; a morning without clouds; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the tender grass &lt;span class="extra"&gt;springing&lt;/span&gt; out of the earth by clear shining after rain.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Although my house &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; not so with God; yet he hath made with me an everlasting covenant, ordered in all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;, and sure: for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;this is&lt;/span&gt; all my salvation, and all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; desire, although he make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; not to grow.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">But &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the sons&lt;/span&gt; of Belial &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; all of them as thorns thrust away, because they cannot be taken with hands:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But the man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shall touch them must be fenced with iron and the staff of a spear; and they shall be utterly burned with fire in the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;same&lt;/span&gt; place.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the names of the mighty men whom David had: The Tachmonite that sat in the seat, chief among the captains; the same &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Adino the Eznite: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he lift up his spear&lt;/span&gt; against eight hundred, whom he slew at one time.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And after him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Eleazar the son of Dodo the Ahohite, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; of the three mighty men with David, when they defied the Philistines &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; were there gathered together to battle, and the men of Israel were gone away:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He arose, and smote the Philistines until his hand was weary, and his hand clave unto the sword: and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; wrought a great victory that day; and the people returned after him only to spoil.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And after him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Shammah the son of Agee the Hararite. And the Philistines were gathered together into a troop, where was a piece of ground full of lentiles: and the people fled from the Philistines.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But he stood in the midst of the ground, and defended it, and slew the Philistines: and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; wrought a great victory.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And three of the thirty chief went down, and came to David in the harvest time unto the cave of Adullam: and the troop of the Philistines pitched in the valley of Rephaim.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And David &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; then in an hold, and the garrison of the Philistines &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; then &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; Beth-lehem.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And David longed, and said, Oh that one would give me drink of the water of the well of Beth-lehem, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the gate!</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the three mighty men brake through the host of the Philistines, and drew water out of the well of Beth-lehem, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; by the gate, and took &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and brought &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to David: nevertheless he would not drink thereof, but poured it out unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he said, Be it far from me, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that I should do this: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is not this&lt;/span&gt; the blood of the men that went in jeopardy of their lives? therefore he would not drink it. These things did these three mighty men.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Abishai, the brother of Joab, the son of Zeruiah, was chief among three. And he lifted up his spear against three hundred, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; slew &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, and had the name among three.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Was he not most honourable of three? therefore he was their captain: howbeit he attained not unto the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; three.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the son of a valiant man, of Kabzeel, who had done many acts, he slew two lionlike men of Moab: he went down also and slew a lion in the midst of a pit in time of snow:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he slew an Egyptian, a goodly man: and the Egyptian had a spear in his hand; but he went down to him with a staff, and plucked the spear out of the Egyptian's hand, and slew him with his own spear.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; did Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, and had the name among three mighty men.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">He was more honourable than the thirty, but he attained not to the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; three. And David set him over his guard.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Asahel the brother of Joab &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; one of the thirty; Elhanan the son of Dodo of Beth-lehem,</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Shammah the Harodite, Elika the Harodite,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Helez the Paltite, Ira the son of Ikkesh the Tekoite,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Abi-ezer the Anethothite, Mebunnai the Hushathite,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Zalmon the Ahohite, Maharai the Netophathite,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Heleb the son of Baanah, a Netophathite, Ittai the son of Ribai out of Gibeah of the children of Benjamin,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Benaiah the Pirathonite, Hiddai of the brooks of Gaash,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Abi-albon the Arbathite, Azmaveth the Barhumite,</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Eliahba the Shaalbonite, of the sons of Jashen, Jonathan,</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Shammah the Hararite, Ahiam the son of Sharar the Hararite,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Eliphelet the son of Ahasbai, the son of the Maachathite, Eliam the son of Ahithophel the Gilonite,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Hezrai the Carmelite, Paarai the Arbite,</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Igal the son of Nathan of Zobah, Bani the Gadite,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Zelek the Ammonite, Naharai the Beerothite, armourbearer to Joab the son of Zeruiah,</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">Ira an Ithrite, Gareb an Ithrite,</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Uriah the Hittite: thirty and seven in all.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>