<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="10" name="2 Samuel" bookPage="2samuel.html" title="2 Samuel" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1kings_1.html" nextTitle="1 Kings" prevBook="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel">
    <chapter number="17" verseCount="29" nextChapter="2samuel_18.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 18" prevChapter="2samuel_16.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel 16" chapterPage="2samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover Ahithophel said unto Absalom, Let me now choose out twelve thousand men, and I will arise and pursue after David this night:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And I will come upon him while he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; weary and weak handed, and will make him afraid: and all the people that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; with him shall flee; and I will smite the king only:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I will bring back all the people unto thee: the man whom thou seekest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; as if all returned: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; all the people shall be in peace.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the saying pleased Absalom well, and all the elders of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then said Absalom, Call now Hushai the Archite also, and let us hear likewise what he saith.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And when Hushai was come to Absalom, Absalom spake unto him, saying, Ahithophel hath spoken after this manner: shall we do &lt;span class='extra'&gt;after&lt;/span&gt; his saying? if not; speak thou.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Hushai said unto Absalom, The counsel that Ahithophel hath given &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not good at this time.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For, said Hushai, thou knowest thy father and his men, that they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; mighty men, and they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; chafed in their minds, as a bear robbed of her whelps in the field: and thy father &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a man of war, and will not lodge with the people.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Behold, he is hid now in some pit, or in some &lt;span class='extra'&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; place: and it will come to pass, when some of them be overthrown at the first, that whosoever heareth it will say, There is a slaughter among the people that follow Absalom.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; valiant, whose heart &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; as the heart of a lion, shall utterly melt: for all Israel knoweth that thy father &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a mighty man, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; with him &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; valiant men.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Therefore I counsel that all Israel be generally gathered unto thee, from Dan even to Beer-sheba, as the sand that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the sea for multitude; and that thou go to battle in thine own person.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">So shall we come upon him in some place where he shall be found, and we will light upon him as the dew falleth on the ground: and of him and of all the men that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; with him there shall not be left so much as one.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Moreover, if he be gotten into a city, then shall all Israel bring ropes to that city, and we will draw it into the river, until there be not one small stone found there.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Absalom and all the men of Israel said, The counsel of Hushai the Archite &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; better than the counsel of Ahithophel. For the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had appointed to defeat the good counsel of Ahithophel, to the intent that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; might bring evil upon Absalom.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Then said Hushai unto Zadok and to Abiathar the priests, Thus and thus did Ahithophel counsel Absalom and the elders of Israel; and thus and thus have I counselled.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Now therefore send quickly, and tell David, saying, Lodge not this night in the plains of the wilderness, but speedily pass over; lest the king be swallowed up, and all the people that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Now Jonathan and Ahimaaz stayed by En-rogel; for they might not be seen to come into the city: and a wench went and told them; and they went and told king David.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Nevertheless a lad saw them, and told Absalom: but they went both of them away quickly, and came to a man's house in Bahurim, which had a well in his court; whither they went down.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the woman took and spread a covering over the well's mouth, and spread ground corn thereon; and the thing was not known.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And when Absalom's servants came to the woman to the house, they said, Where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Ahimaaz and Jonathan? And the woman said unto them, They be gone over the brook of water. And when they had sought and could not find &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, they returned to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And it came to pass, after they were departed, that they came up out of the well, and went and told king David, and said unto David, Arise, and pass quickly over the water: for thus hath Ahithophel counselled against you.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then David arose, and all the people that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him, and they passed over Jordan: by the morning light there lacked not one of them that was not gone over Jordan.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And when Ahithophel saw that his counsel was not followed, he saddled &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; ass, and arose, and gat him home to his house, to his city, and put his household in order, and hanged himself, and died, and was buried in the sepulchre of his father.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Then David came to Mahanaim. And Absalom passed over Jordan, he and all the men of Israel with him.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And Absalom made Amasa captain of the host instead of Joab: which Amasa &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; a man's son, whose name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Ithra an Israelite, that went in to Abigail the daughter of Nahash, sister to Zeruiah Joab's mother.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">So Israel and Absalom pitched in the land of Gilead.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when David was come to Mahanaim, that Shobi the son of Nahash of Rabbah of the children of Ammon, and Machir the son of Ammiel of Lo-debar, and Barzillai the Gileadite of Rogelim,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Brought beds, and basons, and earthen vessels, and wheat, and barley, and flour, and parched &lt;span class='extra'&gt;corn&lt;/span&gt;, and beans, and lentiles, and parched &lt;span class='extra'&gt;pulse&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And honey, and butter, and sheep, and cheese of kine, for David, and for the people that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with him, to eat: for they said, The people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; hungry, and weary, and thirsty, in the wilderness.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>