<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="10" name="2 Samuel" bookPage="2samuel.html" title="2 Samuel" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1kings_1.html" nextTitle="1 Kings" prevBook="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="18" nextChapter="2samuel_9.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 9" prevChapter="2samuel_7.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel 7" chapterPage="2samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And after this it came to pass, that David smote the Philistines, and subdued them: and David took Metheg-ammah out of the hand of the Philistines.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he smote Moab, and measured them with a line, casting them down to the ground; even with two lines measured he to put to death, and with one full line to keep alive. And &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; the Moabites became David's servants, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; brought gifts.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">David smote also Hadadezer, the son of Rehob, king of Zobah, as he went to recover his border at the river Euphrates.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And David took from him a thousand &lt;i&gt;chariots&lt;/i&gt;, and seven hundred horsemen, and twenty thousand footmen: and David houghed all the chariot &lt;i&gt;horses&lt;/i&gt;, but reserved of them &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an hundred chariots.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And when the Syrians of Damascus came to succour Hadadezer king of Zobah, David slew of the Syrians two and twenty thousand men.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Then David put garrisons in Syria of Damascus: and the Syrians became servants to David, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; brought gifts. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; preserved David whithersoever he went.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And David took the shields of gold that were on the servants of Hadadezer, and brought them to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And from Betah, and from Berothai, cities of Hadadezer, king David took exceeding much brass.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">When Toi king of Hamath heard that David had smitten all the host of Hadadezer,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then Toi sent Joram his son unto king David, to salute him, and to bless him, because he had fought against Hadadezer, and smitten him: for Hadadezer had wars with Toi. And &lt;i&gt;Joram&lt;/i&gt; brought with him vessels of silver, and vessels of gold, and vessels of brass:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Which also king David did dedicate unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, with the silver and gold that he had dedicated of all nations which he subdued;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Of Syria, and of Moab, and of the children of Ammon, and of the Philistines, and of Amalek, and of the spoil of Hadadezer, son of Rehob, king of Zobah.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And David gat &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; a name when he returned from smiting of the Syrians in the valley of salt, &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; eighteen thousand &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And he put garrisons in Edom; throughout all Edom put he garrisons, and all they of Edom became David's servants. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; preserved David whithersoever he went.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And David reigned over all Israel; and David executed judgment and justice unto all his people.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Joab the son of Zeruiah &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; over the host; and Jehoshaphat the son of Ahilud &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; recorder;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Zadok the son of Ahitub, and Ahimelech the son of Abiathar, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; the priests; and Seraiah &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the scribe;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Benaiah the son of Jehoiada &lt;i&gt;was over&lt;/i&gt; both the Cherethites and the Pelethites; and David's sons were chief rulers.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>