<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="10" name="2 Samuel" bookPage="2samuel.html" title="2 Samuel" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1kings_1.html" nextTitle="1 Kings" prevBook="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="23" nextChapter="2samuel_17.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 17" prevChapter="2samuel_15.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel 15" chapterPage="2samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And when David was a little past the top &lt;i&gt;of the hill&lt;/i&gt;, behold, Ziba the servant of Mephibosheth met him, with a couple of asses saddled, and upon them two hundred &lt;i&gt;loaves&lt;/i&gt; of bread, and an hundred bunches of raisins, and an hundred of summer fruits, and a bottle of wine.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the king said unto Ziba, What meanest thou by these? And Ziba said, The asses &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; for the king's household to ride on; and the bread and summer fruit for the young men to eat; and the wine, that such as be faint in the wilderness may drink.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the king said, And where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy master's son? And Ziba said unto the king, Behold, he abideth at Jerusalem: for he said, To day shall the house of Israel restore me the kingdom of my father.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Then said the king to Ziba, Behold, thine &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; all that &lt;i&gt;pertained&lt;/i&gt; unto Mephibosheth. And Ziba said, I humbly beseech thee &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I may find grace in thy sight, my lord, O king.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And when king David came to Bahurim, behold, thence came out a man of the family of the house of Saul, whose name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Shimei, the son of Gera: he came forth, and cursed still as he came.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he cast stones at David, and at all the servants of king David: and all the people and all the mighty men &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; on his right hand and on his left.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And thus said Shimei when he cursed, Come out, come out, thou bloody man, and thou man of Belial:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath returned upon thee all the blood of the house of Saul, in whose stead thou hast reigned; and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath delivered the kingdom into the hand of Absalom thy son: and, behold, thou &lt;i&gt;art taken&lt;/i&gt; in thy mischief, because thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; a bloody man.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Then said Abishai the son of Zeruiah unto the king, Why should this dead dog curse my lord the king? let me go over, I pray thee, and take off his head.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the king said, What have I to do with you, ye sons of Zeruiah? so let him curse, because the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath said unto him, Curse David. Who shall then say, Wherefore hast thou done so?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And David said to Abishai, and to all his servants, Behold, my son, which came forth of my bowels, seeketh my life: how much more now &lt;i&gt;may this&lt;/i&gt; Benjamite &lt;i&gt;do it&lt;/i&gt;? let him alone, and let him curse; for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath bidden him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">It may be that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will look on mine affliction, and that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will requite me good for his cursing this day.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And as David and his men went by the way, Shimei went along on the hill's side over against him, and cursed as he went, and threw stones at him, and cast dust.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the king, and all the people that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with him, came weary, and refreshed themselves there.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And Absalom, and all the people the men of Israel, came to Jerusalem, and Ahithophel with him.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And it came to pass, when Hushai the Archite, David's friend, was come unto Absalom, that Hushai said unto Absalom, God save the king, God save the king.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Absalom said to Hushai, &lt;i&gt;Is&lt;/i&gt; this thy kindness to thy friend? why wentest thou not with thy friend?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Hushai said unto Absalom, Nay; but whom the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and this people, and all the men of Israel, choose, his will I be, and with him will I abide.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And again, whom should I serve? &lt;i&gt;should I&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;serve&lt;/i&gt; in the presence of his son? as I have served in thy father's presence, so will I be in thy presence.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">Then said Absalom to Ahithophel, Give counsel among you what we shall do.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Ahithophel said unto Absalom, Go in unto thy father's concubines, which he hath left to keep the house; and all Israel shall hear that thou art abhorred of thy father: then shall the hands of all that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; with thee be strong.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">So they spread Absalom a tent upon the top of the house; and Absalom went in unto his father's concubines in the sight of all Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the counsel of Ahithophel, which he counselled in those days, &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; as if a man had enquired at the oracle of God: so &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; all the counsel of Ahithophel both with David and with Absalom.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>