<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="10" name="2 Samuel" bookPage="2samuel.html" title="2 Samuel" chapterCount="24" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1kings_1.html" nextTitle="1 Kings" prevBook="1samuel_1.html" prevTitle="1 Samuel">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="27" nextChapter="2samuel_12.html" nextTitle="2 Samuel 12" prevChapter="2samuel_10.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel 10" chapterPage="2samuel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, after the year was expired, at the time when kings go forth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to battle&lt;/span&gt;, that David sent Joab, and his servants with him, and all Israel; and they destroyed the children of Ammon, and besieged Rabbah. But David tarried still at Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">And it came to pass in an eveningtide, that David arose from off his bed, and walked upon the roof of the king's house: and from the roof he saw a woman washing herself; and the woman &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; very beautiful to look upon.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And David sent and enquired after the woman. And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; not this Bath-sheba, the daughter of Eliam, the wife of Uriah the Hittite?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And David sent messengers, and took her; and she came in unto him, and he lay with her; for she was purified from her uncleanness: and she returned unto her house.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the woman conceived, and sent and told David, and said, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; with child.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And David sent to Joab, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Send me Uriah the Hittite. And Joab sent Uriah to David.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when Uriah was come unto him, David demanded &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of him&lt;/span&gt; how Joab did, and how the people did, and how the war prospered.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And David said to Uriah, Go down to thy house, and wash thy feet. And Uriah departed out of the king's house, and there followed him a mess &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of meat&lt;/span&gt; from the king.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But Uriah slept at the door of the king's house with all the servants of his lord, and went not down to his house.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And when they had told David, saying, Uriah went not down unto his house, David said unto Uriah, Camest thou not from &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; journey? why &lt;span class='extra'&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; didst thou not go down unto thine house?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Uriah said unto David, The ark, and Israel, and Judah, abide in tents; and my lord Joab, and the servants of my lord, are encamped in the open fields; shall I then go into mine house, to eat and to drink, and to lie with my wife? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; thou livest, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; thy soul liveth, I will not do this thing.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And David said to Uriah, Tarry here to day also, and to morrow I will let thee depart. So Uriah abode in Jerusalem that day, and the morrow.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And when David had called him, he did eat and drink before him; and he made him drunk: and at even he went out to lie on his bed with the servants of his lord, but went not down to his house.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And it came to pass in the morning, that David wrote a letter to Joab, and sent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; by the hand of Uriah.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he wrote in the letter, saying, Set ye Uriah in the forefront of the hottest battle, and retire ye from him, that he may be smitten, and die.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And it came to pass, when Joab observed the city, that he assigned Uriah unto a place where he knew that valiant men &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the men of the city went out, and fought with Joab: and there fell &lt;span class='extra'&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of the people of the servants of David; and Uriah the Hittite died also.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Then Joab sent and told David all the things concerning the war;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And charged the messenger, saying, When thou hast made an end of telling the matters of the war unto the king,</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And if so be that the king's wrath arise, and he say unto thee, Wherefore approached ye so nigh unto the city when ye did fight? knew ye not that they would shoot from the wall?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Who smote Abimelech the son of Jerubbesheth? did not a woman cast a piece of a millstone upon him from the wall, that he died in Thebez? why went ye nigh the wall? then say thou, Thy servant Uriah the Hittite is dead also.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">So the messenger went, and came and shewed David all that Joab had sent him for.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the messenger said unto David, Surely the men prevailed against us, and came out unto us into the field, and we were upon them even unto the entering of the gate.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the shooters shot from off the wall upon thy servants; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of the king's servants be dead, and thy servant Uriah the Hittite is dead also.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then David said unto the messenger, Thus shalt thou say unto Joab, Let not this thing displease thee, for the sword devoureth one as well as another: make thy battle more strong against the city, and overthrow it: and encourage thou him.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And when the wife of Uriah heard that Uriah her husband was dead, she mourned for her husband.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And when the mourning was past, David sent and fetched her to his house, and she became his wife, and bare him a son. But the thing that David had done displeased the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>