<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="11" name="1 Kings" bookPage="1kings.html" title="1 Kings" chapterCount="22" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2kings_1.html" nextTitle="2 Kings" prevBook="2samuel_1.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="38" nextChapter="1kings_7.html" nextTitle="1 Kings 7" prevChapter="1kings_5.html" prevTitle="1 Kings 5" chapterPage="1kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass in the four hundred and eightieth year after the children of Israel were come out of the land of Egypt, in the fourth year of Solomon's reign over Israel, in the month Zif, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the second month, that he began to build the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the house which king Solomon built for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the length thereof &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; threescore cubits, and the breadth thereof twenty &lt;span class="extra"&gt;cubits&lt;/span&gt;, and the height thereof thirty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the porch before the temple of the house, twenty cubits &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the length thereof, according to the breadth of the house; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; ten cubits &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the breadth thereof before the house.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And for the house he made windows of narrow lights.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And against the wall of the house he built chambers round about, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;against&lt;/span&gt; the walls of the house round about, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; of the temple and of the oracle: and he made chambers round about:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The nethermost chamber &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; five cubits broad, and the middle &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; six cubits broad, and the third &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; seven cubits broad: for without &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in the wall&lt;/span&gt; of the house he made narrowed rests round about, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the beams&lt;/span&gt; should not be fastened in the walls of the house.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the house, when it was in building, was built of stone made ready before it was brought thither: so that there was neither hammer nor axe &lt;span class="extra"&gt;nor&lt;/span&gt; any tool of iron heard in the house, while it was in building.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The door for the middle chamber &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the right side of the house: and they went up with winding stairs into the middle &lt;span class="extra"&gt;chamber&lt;/span&gt;, and out of the middle into the third.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">So he built the house, and finished it; and covered the house with beams and boards of cedar.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; he built chambers against all the house, five cubits high: and they rested on the house with timber of cedar.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came to Solomon, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Concerning&lt;/span&gt; this house which thou art in building, if thou wilt walk in my statutes, and execute my judgments, and keep all my commandments to walk in them; then will I perform my word with thee, which I spake unto David thy father:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And I will dwell among the children of Israel, and will not forsake my people Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">So Solomon built the house, and finished it.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he built the walls of the house within with boards of cedar, both the floor of the house, and the walls of the cieling: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he covered &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; on the inside with wood, and covered the floor of the house with planks of fir.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he built twenty cubits on the sides of the house, both the floor and the walls with boards of cedar: he even built &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; for it within, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; for the oracle, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; for the most holy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the house, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;, the temple before it, was forty cubits &lt;span class="extra"&gt;long&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the cedar of the house within &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; carved with knops and open flowers: all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; cedar; there was no stone seen.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the oracle he prepared in the house within, to set there the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the oracle in the forepart &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; twenty cubits in length, and twenty cubits in breadth, and twenty cubits in the height thereof: and he overlaid it with pure gold; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; covered the altar &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which was of&lt;/span&gt; cedar.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">So Solomon overlaid the house within with pure gold: and he made a partition by the chains of gold before the oracle; and he overlaid it with gold.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the whole house he overlaid with gold, until he had finished all the house: also the whole altar that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; by the oracle he overlaid with gold.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And within the oracle he made two cherubims &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; olive tree, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; ten cubits high.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And five cubits &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the one wing of the cherub, and five cubits the other wing of the cherub: from the uttermost part of the one wing unto the uttermost part of the other &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; ten cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the other cherub &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; ten cubits: both the cherubims &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; of one measure and one size.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The height of the one cherub &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; ten cubits, and so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was it&lt;/span&gt; of the other cherub.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And he set the cherubims within the inner house: and they stretched forth the wings of the cherubims, so that the wing of the one touched the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; wall, and the wing of the other cherub touched the other wall; and their wings touched one another in the midst of the house.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he overlaid the cherubims with gold.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And he carved all the walls of the house round about with carved figures of cherubims and palm trees and open flowers, within and without.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the floor of the house he overlaid with gold, within and without.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And for the entering of the oracle he made doors &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; olive tree: the lintel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; side posts &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; a fifth part &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of the wall&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">The two doors also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were of&lt;/span&gt; olive tree; and he carved upon them carvings of cherubims and palm trees and open flowers, and overlaid &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; with gold, and spread gold upon the cherubims, and upon the palm trees.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">So also made he for the door of the temple posts &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; olive tree, a fourth part &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of the wall&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And the two doors &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were of&lt;/span&gt; fir tree: the two leaves of the one door &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; folding, and the two leaves of the other door &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; folding.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And he carved &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thereon&lt;/span&gt; cherubims and palm trees and open flowers: and covered &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; with gold fitted upon the carved work.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">And he built the inner court with three rows of hewed stone, and a row of cedar beams.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37" newPara="true">In the fourth year was the foundation of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; laid, in the month Zif:</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And in the eleventh year, in the month Bul, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the eighth month, was the house finished throughout all the parts thereof, and according to all the fashion of it. So was he seven years in building it.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>