<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="11" name="1 Kings" bookPage="1kings.html" title="1 Kings" chapterCount="22" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2kings_1.html" nextTitle="2 Kings" prevBook="2samuel_1.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="46" nextChapter="1kings_19.html" nextTitle="1 Kings 19" prevChapter="1kings_17.html" prevTitle="1 Kings 17" chapterPage="1kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; many days, that the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came to Elijah in the third year, saying, Go, shew thyself unto Ahab; and I will send rain upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Elijah went to shew himself unto Ahab. And &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; a sore famine in Samaria.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Ahab called Obadiah, which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the governor of &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; house. (Now Obadiah feared the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; greatly:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For it was &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt;, when Jezebel cut off the prophets of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that Obadiah took an hundred prophets, and hid them by fifty in a cave, and fed them with bread and water.)</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Ahab said unto Obadiah, Go into the land, unto all fountains of water, and unto all brooks: peradventure we may find grass to save the horses and mules alive, that we lose not all the beasts.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">So they divided the land between them to pass throughout it: Ahab went one way by himself, and Obadiah went another way by himself.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And as Obadiah was in the way, behold, Elijah met him: and he knew him, and fell on his face, and said, &lt;i&gt;Art&lt;/i&gt; thou that my lord Elijah?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he answered him, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt;: go, tell thy lord, Behold, Elijah &lt;i&gt;is here&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he said, What have I sinned, that thou wouldest deliver thy servant into the hand of Ahab, to slay me?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;i&gt;As&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God liveth, there is no nation or kingdom, whither my lord hath not sent to seek thee: and when they said, &lt;i&gt;He is&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt;; he took an oath of the kingdom and nation, that they found thee not.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And now thou sayest, Go, tell thy lord, Behold, Elijah &lt;i&gt;is here&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And it shall come to pass, &lt;i&gt;as soon as&lt;/i&gt; I am gone from thee, that the Spirit of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall carry thee whither I know not; and &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; when I come and tell Ahab, and he cannot find thee, he shall slay me: but I thy servant fear the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; from my youth.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Was it not told my lord what I did when Jezebel slew the prophets of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, how I hid an hundred men of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s prophets by fifty in a cave, and fed them with bread and water?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And now thou sayest, Go, tell thy lord, Behold, Elijah &lt;i&gt;is here&lt;/i&gt;: and he shall slay me.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Elijah said, &lt;i&gt;As&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts liveth, before whom I stand, I will surely shew myself unto him to day.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">So Obadiah went to meet Ahab, and told him: and Ahab went to meet Elijah.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when Ahab saw Elijah, that Ahab said unto him, &lt;i&gt;Art&lt;/i&gt; thou he that troubleth Israel?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And he answered, I have not troubled Israel; but thou, and thy father's house, in that ye have forsaken the commandments of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and thou hast followed Baalim.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Now therefore send, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; gather to me all Israel unto mount Carmel, and the prophets of Baal four hundred and fifty, and the prophets of the groves four hundred, which eat at Jezebel's table.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">So Ahab sent unto all the children of Israel, and gathered the prophets together unto mount Carmel.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Elijah came unto all the people, and said, How long halt ye between two opinions? if the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; God, follow him: but if Baal, &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; follow him. And the people answered him not a word.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then said Elijah unto the people, I, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; I only, remain a prophet of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; but Baal's prophets &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; four hundred and fifty men.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Let them therefore give us two bullocks; and let them choose one bullock for themselves, and cut it in pieces, and lay &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; on wood, and put no fire &lt;i&gt;under&lt;/i&gt;: and I will dress the other bullock, and lay &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; on wood, and put no fire &lt;i&gt;under&lt;/i&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And call ye on the name of your gods, and I will call on the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and the God that answereth by fire, let him be God. And all the people answered and said, It is well spoken.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Elijah said unto the prophets of Baal, Choose you one bullock for yourselves, and dress &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; first; for ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; many; and call on the name of your gods, but put no fire &lt;i&gt;under&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And they took the bullock which was given them, and they dressed &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and called on the name of Baal from morning even until noon, saying, O Baal, hear us. But &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; no voice, nor any that answered. And they leaped upon the altar which was made.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And it came to pass at noon, that Elijah mocked them, and said, Cry aloud: for he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a god; either he is talking, or he is pursuing, or he is in a journey, &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; peradventure he sleepeth, and must be awaked.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they cried aloud, and cut themselves after their manner with knives and lancets, till the blood gushed out upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And it came to pass, when midday was past, and they prophesied until the &lt;i&gt;time&lt;/i&gt; of the offering of the &lt;i&gt;evening&lt;/i&gt; sacrifice, that &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; neither voice, nor any to answer, nor any that regarded.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Elijah said unto all the people, Come near unto me. And all the people came near unto him. And he repaired the altar of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;that was&lt;/i&gt; broken down.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Elijah took twelve stones, according to the number of the tribes of the sons of Jacob, unto whom the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came, saying, Israel shall be thy name:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And with the stones he built an altar in the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and he made a trench about the altar, as great as would contain two measures of seed.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And he put the wood in order, and cut the bullock in pieces, and laid &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; on the wood, and said, Fill four barrels with water, and pour &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; on the burnt sacrifice, and on the wood.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And he said, Do &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; the second time. And they did &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; the second time. And he said, Do &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; the third time. And they did &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; the third time.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And the water ran round about the altar; and he filled the trench also with water.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And it came to pass at &lt;i&gt;the time of&lt;/i&gt; the offering of the &lt;i&gt;evening&lt;/i&gt; sacrifice, that Elijah the prophet came near, and said, &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Abraham, Isaac, and of Israel, let it be known this day that thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; God in Israel, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; thy servant, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I have done all these things at thy word.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Hear me, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hear me, that this people may know that thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thou hast turned their heart back again.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">Then the fire of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; fell, and consumed the burnt sacrifice, and the wood, and the stones, and the dust, and licked up the water that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in the trench.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And when all the people saw &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, they fell on their faces: and they said, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the God; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the God.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And Elijah said unto them, Take the prophets of Baal; let not one of them escape. And they took them: and Elijah brought them down to the brook Kishon, and slew them there.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41" newPara="true">And Elijah said unto Ahab, Get thee up, eat and drink; for &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; a sound of abundance of rain.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">So Ahab went up to eat and to drink. And Elijah went up to the top of Carmel; and he cast himself down upon the earth, and put his face between his knees,</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And said to his servant, Go up now, look toward the sea. And he went up, and looked, and said, &lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; nothing. And he said, Go again seven times.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And it came to pass at the seventh time, that he said, Behold, there ariseth a little cloud out of the sea, like a man's hand. And he said, Go up, say unto Ahab, Prepare &lt;i&gt;thy chariot&lt;/i&gt;, and get thee down, that the rain stop thee not.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And it came to pass in the mean while, that the heaven was black with clouds and wind, and there was a great rain. And Ahab rode, and went to Jezreel.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And the hand of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was on Elijah; and he girded up his loins, and ran before Ahab to the entrance of Jezreel.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>