<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="11" name="1 Kings" bookPage="1kings.html" title="1 Kings" chapterCount="22" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2kings_1.html" nextTitle="2 Kings" prevBook="2samuel_1.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="43" nextChapter="1kings_12.html" nextTitle="1 Kings 12" prevChapter="1kings_10.html" prevTitle="1 Kings 10" chapterPage="1kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">But king Solomon loved many strange women, together with the daughter of Pharaoh, women of the Moabites, Ammonites, Edomites, Zidonians, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Hittites;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Of the nations &lt;span class='extra'&gt;concerning&lt;/span&gt; which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto the children of Israel, Ye shall not go in to them, neither shall they come in unto you: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; surely they will turn away your heart after their gods: Solomon clave unto these in love.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he had seven hundred wives, princesses, and three hundred concubines: and his wives turned away his heart.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For it came to pass, when Solomon was old, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; his wives turned away his heart after other gods: and his heart was not perfect with the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the heart of David his father.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For Solomon went after Ashtoreth the goddess of the Zidonians, and after Milcom the abomination of the Ammonites.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Solomon did evil in the sight of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and went not fully after the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;did&lt;/span&gt; David his father.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then did Solomon build an high place for Chemosh, the abomination of Moab, in the hill that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; before Jerusalem, and for Molech, the abomination of the children of Ammon.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And likewise did he for all his strange wives, which burnt incense and sacrificed unto their gods.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was angry with Solomon, because his heart was turned from the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, which had appeared unto him twice,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And had commanded him concerning this thing, that he should not go after other gods: but he kept not that which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Wherefore the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Solomon, Forasmuch as this is done of thee, and thou hast not kept my covenant and my statutes, which I have commanded thee, I will surely rend the kingdom from thee, and will give it to thy servant.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Notwithstanding in thy days I will not do it for David thy father's sake: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; I will rend it out of the hand of thy son.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Howbeit I will not rend away all the kingdom; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; will give one tribe to thy son for David my servant's sake, and for Jerusalem's sake which I have chosen.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; stirred up an adversary unto Solomon, Hadad the Edomite: he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; of the king's seed in Edom.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For it came to pass, when David was in Edom, and Joab the captain of the host was gone up to bury the slain, after he had smitten every male in Edom;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">(For six months did Joab remain there with all Israel, until he had cut off every male in Edom:)</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">That Hadad fled, he and certain Edomites of his father's servants with him, to go into Egypt; Hadad &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; yet a little child.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And they arose out of Midian, and came to Paran: and they took men with them out of Paran, and they came to Egypt, unto Pharaoh king of Egypt; which gave him an house, and appointed him victuals, and gave him land.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Hadad found great favour in the sight of Pharaoh, so that he gave him to wife the sister of his own wife, the sister of Tahpenes the queen.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the sister of Tahpenes bare him Genubath his son, whom Tahpenes weaned in Pharaoh's house: and Genubath was in Pharaoh's household among the sons of Pharaoh.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And when Hadad heard in Egypt that David slept with his fathers, and that Joab the captain of the host was dead, Hadad said to Pharaoh, Let me depart, that I may go to mine own country.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then Pharaoh said unto him, But what hast thou lacked with me, that, behold, thou seekest to go to thine own country? And he answered, Nothing: howbeit let me go in any wise.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And God stirred him up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;another&lt;/span&gt; adversary, Rezon the son of Eliadah, which fled from his lord Hadadezer king of Zobah:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And he gathered men unto him, and became captain over a band, when David slew them &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of Zobah&lt;/span&gt;: and they went to Damascus, and dwelt therein, and reigned in Damascus.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And he was an adversary to Israel all the days of Solomon, beside the mischief that Hadad &lt;span class='extra'&gt;did&lt;/span&gt;: and he abhorred Israel, and reigned over Syria.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And Jeroboam the son of Nebat, an Ephrathite of Zereda, Solomon's servant, whose mother's name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Zeruah, a widow woman, even he lifted up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; hand against the king.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the cause that he lifted up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; hand against the king: Solomon built Millo, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; repaired the breaches of the city of David his father.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the man Jeroboam &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; a mighty man of valour: and Solomon seeing the young man that he was industrious, he made him ruler over all the charge of the house of Joseph.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And it came to pass at that time when Jeroboam went out of Jerusalem, that the prophet Ahijah the Shilonite found him in the way; and he had clad himself with a new garment; and they two &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; alone in the field:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Ahijah caught the new garment that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; on him, and rent it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; twelve pieces:</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And he said to Jeroboam, Take thee ten pieces: for thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the God of Israel, Behold, I will rend the kingdom out of the hand of Solomon, and will give ten tribes to thee:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">(But he shall have one tribe for my servant David's sake, and for Jerusalem's sake, the city which I have chosen out of all the tribes of Israel:)</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Because that they have forsaken me, and have worshipped Ashtoreth the goddess of the Zidonians, Chemosh the god of the Moabites, and Milcom the god of the children of Ammon, and have not walked in my ways, to do &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which is&lt;/span&gt; right in mine eyes, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to keep&lt;/span&gt; my statutes and my judgments, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;did&lt;/span&gt; David his father.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Howbeit I will not take the whole kingdom out of his hand: but I will make him prince all the days of his life for David my servant's sake, whom I chose, because he kept my commandments and my statutes:</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">But I will take the kingdom out of his son's hand, and will give it unto thee, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; ten tribes.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And unto his son will I give one tribe, that David my servant may have a light alway before me in Jerusalem, the city which I have chosen me to put my name there.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And I will take thee, and thou shalt reign according to all that thy soul desireth, and shalt be king over Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And it shall be, if thou wilt hearken unto all that I command thee, and wilt walk in my ways, and do &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; right in my sight, to keep my statutes and my commandments, as David my servant did; that I will be with thee, and build thee a sure house, as I built for David, and will give Israel unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And I will for this afflict the seed of David, but not for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Solomon sought therefore to kill Jeroboam. And Jeroboam arose, and fled into Egypt, unto Shishak king of Egypt, and was in Egypt until the death of Solomon.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41" newPara="true">And the rest of the acts of Solomon, and all that he did, and his wisdom, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they not written in the book of the acts of Solomon?</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And the time that Solomon reigned in Jerusalem over all Israel &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; forty years.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And Solomon slept with his fathers, and was buried in the city of David his father: and Rehoboam his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>