<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="11" name="1 Kings" bookPage="1kings.html" title="1 Kings" chapterCount="22" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2kings_1.html" nextTitle="2 Kings" prevBook="2samuel_1.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="28" nextChapter="1kings_10.html" nextTitle="1 Kings 10" prevChapter="1kings_8.html" prevTitle="1 Kings 8" chapterPage="1kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, when Solomon had finished the building of the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the king's house, and all Solomon's desire which he was pleased to do,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared to Solomon the second time, as he had appeared unto him at Gibeon.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, I have heard thy prayer and thy supplication, that thou hast made before me: I have hallowed this house, which thou hast built, to put my name there for ever; and mine eyes and mine heart shall be there perpetually.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And if thou wilt walk before me, as David thy father walked, in integrity of heart, and in uprightness, to do according to all that I have commanded thee, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; wilt keep my statutes and my judgments:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then I will establish the throne of thy kingdom upon Israel for ever, as I promised to David thy father, saying, There shall not fail thee a man upon the throne of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;But&lt;/span&gt; if ye shall at all turn from following me, ye or your children, and will not keep my commandments &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; my statutes which I have set before you, but go and serve other gods, and worship them:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then will I cut off Israel out of the land which I have given them; and this house, which I have hallowed for my name, will I cast out of my sight; and Israel shall be a proverb and a byword among all people:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And at this house, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; is high, every one that passeth by it shall be astonished, and shall hiss; and they shall say, Why hath the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; done thus unto this land, and to this house?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And they shall answer, Because they forsook the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God, who brought forth their fathers out of the land of Egypt, and have taken hold upon other gods, and have worshipped them, and served them: therefore hath the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought upon them all this evil.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And it came to pass at the end of twenty years, when Solomon had built the two houses, the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the king's house,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">(&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Now&lt;/span&gt; Hiram the king of Tyre had furnished Solomon with cedar trees and fir trees, and with gold, according to all his desire,) that then king Solomon gave Hiram twenty cities in the land of Galilee.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Hiram came out from Tyre to see the cities which Solomon had given him; and they pleased him not.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he said, What cities &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; these which thou hast given me, my brother? And he called them the land of Cabul unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Hiram sent to the king sixscore talents of gold.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the reason of the levy which king Solomon raised; for to build the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and his own house, and Millo, and the wall of Jerusalem, and Hazor, and Megiddo, and Gezer.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;For&lt;/span&gt; Pharaoh king of Egypt had gone up, and taken Gezer, and burnt it with fire, and slain the Canaanites that dwelt in the city, and given it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a present unto his daughter, Solomon's wife.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Solomon built Gezer, and Beth-horon the nether,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Baalath, and Tadmor in the wilderness, in the land,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And all the cities of store that Solomon had, and cities for his chariots, and cities for his horsemen, and that which Solomon desired to build in Jerusalem, and in Lebanon, and in all the land of his dominion.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; all the people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that were&lt;/span&gt; left of the Amorites, Hittites, Perizzites, Hivites, and Jebusites, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; not of the children of Israel,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Their children that were left after them in the land, whom the children of Israel also were not able utterly to destroy, upon those did Solomon levy a tribute of bondservice unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But of the children of Israel did Solomon make no bondmen: but they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; men of war, and his servants, and his princes, and his captains, and rulers of his chariots, and his horsemen.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the chief of the officers that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; over Solomon's work, five hundred and fifty, which bare rule over the people that wrought in the work.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">But Pharaoh's daughter came up out of the city of David unto her house which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Solomon&lt;/span&gt; had built for her: then did he build Millo.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And three times in a year did Solomon offer burnt offerings and peace offerings upon the altar which he built unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and he burnt incense upon the altar that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. So he finished the house.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And king Solomon made a navy of ships in Ezion-geber, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; beside Eloth, on the shore of the Red sea, in the land of Edom.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Hiram sent in the navy his servants, shipmen that had knowledge of the sea, with the servants of Solomon.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they came to Ophir, and fetched from thence gold, four hundred and twenty talents, and brought &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to king Solomon.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>