<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="11" name="1 Kings" bookPage="1kings.html" title="1 Kings" chapterCount="22" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2kings_1.html" nextTitle="2 Kings" prevBook="2samuel_1.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="31" nextChapter="1kings_15.html" nextTitle="1 Kings 15" prevChapter="1kings_13.html" prevTitle="1 Kings 13" chapterPage="1kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">At that time Abijah the son of Jeroboam fell sick.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Jeroboam said to his wife, Arise, I pray thee, and disguise thyself, that thou be not known to be the wife of Jeroboam; and get thee to Shiloh: behold, there &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Ahijah the prophet, which told me that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;I should be&lt;/span&gt; king over this people.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And take with thee ten loaves, and cracknels, and a cruse of honey, and go to him: he shall tell thee what shall become of the child.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Jeroboam's wife did so, and arose, and went to Shiloh, and came to the house of Ahijah. But Ahijah could not see; for his eyes were set by reason of his age.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Ahijah, Behold, the wife of Jeroboam cometh to ask a thing of thee for her son; for he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; sick: thus and thus shalt thou say unto her: for it shall be, when she cometh in, that she shall feign herself &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; another &lt;span class="extra"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And it was &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;, when Ahijah heard the sound of her feet, as she came in at the door, that he said, Come in, thou wife of Jeroboam; why feignest thou thyself &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; another? for I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; sent to thee &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; heavy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;tidings&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Go, tell Jeroboam, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, Forasmuch as I exalted thee from among the people, and made thee prince over my people Israel,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And rent the kingdom away from the house of David, and gave it thee: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yet&lt;/span&gt; thou hast not been as my servant David, who kept my commandments, and who followed me with all his heart, to do &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; only &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which was&lt;/span&gt; right in mine eyes;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But hast done evil above all that were before thee: for thou hast gone and made thee other gods, and molten images, to provoke me to anger, and hast cast me behind thy back:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Therefore, behold, I will bring evil upon the house of Jeroboam, and will cut off from Jeroboam him that pisseth against the wall, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; him that is shut up and left in Israel, and will take away the remnant of the house of Jeroboam, as a man taketh away dung, till it be all gone.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Him that dieth of Jeroboam in the city shall the dogs eat; and him that dieth in the field shall the fowls of the air eat: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Arise thou therefore, get thee to thine own house: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; when thy feet enter into the city, the child shall die.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And all Israel shall mourn for him, and bury him: for he only of Jeroboam shall come to the grave, because in him there is found &lt;span class="extra"&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; good thing toward the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel in the house of Jeroboam.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Moreover the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall raise him up a king over Israel, who shall cut off the house of Jeroboam that day: but what? even now.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall smite Israel, as a reed is shaken in the water, and he shall root up Israel out of this good land, which he gave to their fathers, and shall scatter them beyond the river, because they have made their groves, provoking the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to anger.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he shall give Israel up because of the sins of Jeroboam, who did sin, and who made Israel to sin.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And Jeroboam's wife arose, and departed, and came to Tirzah: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; when she came to the threshold of the door, the child died;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And they buried him; and all Israel mourned for him, according to the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which he spake by the hand of his servant Ahijah the prophet.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the rest of the acts of Jeroboam, how he warred, and how he reigned, behold, they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the days which Jeroboam reigned &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; two and twenty years: and he slept with his fathers, and Nadab his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">And Rehoboam the son of Solomon reigned in Judah. Rehoboam &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; forty and one years old when he began to reign, and he reigned seventeen years in Jerusalem, the city which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did choose out of all the tribes of Israel, to put his name there. And his mother's name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Naamah an Ammonitess.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Judah did evil in the sight of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and they provoked him to jealousy with their sins which they had committed, above all that their fathers had done.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For they also built them high places, and images, and groves, on every high hill, and under every green tree.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And there were also sodomites in the land: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; they did according to all the abominations of the nations which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; cast out before the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And it came to pass in the fifth year of king Rehoboam, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; Shishak king of Egypt came up against Jerusalem:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And he took away the treasures of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the treasures of the king's house; he even took away all: and he took away all the shields of gold which Solomon had made.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And king Rehoboam made in their stead brasen shields, and committed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; unto the hands of the chief of the guard, which kept the door of the king's house.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And it was &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;, when the king went into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that the guard bare them, and brought them back into the guard chamber.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">Now the rest of the acts of Rehoboam, and all that he did, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And there was war between Rehoboam and Jeroboam all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; days.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Rehoboam slept with his fathers, and was buried with his fathers in the city of David. And his mother's name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Naamah an Ammonitess. And Abijam his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>