<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="11" name="1 Kings" bookPage="1kings.html" title="1 Kings" chapterCount="22" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2kings_1.html" nextTitle="2 Kings" prevBook="2samuel_1.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel">
    <chapter number="17" verseCount="24" nextChapter="1kings_18.html" nextTitle="1 Kings 18" prevChapter="1kings_16.html" prevTitle="1 Kings 16" chapterPage="1kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Elijah the Tishbite, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;who was&lt;/span&gt; of the inhabitants of Gilead, said unto Ahab, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel liveth, before whom I stand, there shall not be dew nor rain these years, but according to my word.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto him, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Get thee hence, and turn thee eastward, and hide thyself by the brook Cherith, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; before Jordan.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And it shall be, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thou shalt drink of the brook; and I have commanded the ravens to feed thee there.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">So he went and did according unto the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for he went and dwelt by the brook Cherith, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; before Jordan.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the ravens brought him bread and flesh in the morning, and bread and flesh in the evening; and he drank of the brook.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And it came to pass after a while, that the brook dried up, because there had been no rain in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto him, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Arise, get thee to Zarephath, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;belongeth&lt;/span&gt; to Zidon, and dwell there: behold, I have commanded a widow woman there to sustain thee.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">So he arose and went to Zarephath. And when he came to the gate of the city, behold, the widow woman &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; there gathering of sticks: and he called to her, and said, Fetch me, I pray thee, a little water in a vessel, that I may drink.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And as she was going to fetch &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, he called to her, and said, Bring me, I pray thee, a morsel of bread in thine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And she said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God liveth, I have not a cake, but an handful of meal in a barrel, and a little oil in a cruse: and, behold, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; gathering two sticks, that I may go in and dress it for me and my son, that we may eat it, and die.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Elijah said unto her, Fear not; go &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; do as thou hast said: but make me thereof a little cake first, and bring &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; unto me, and after make for thee and for thy son.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, The barrel of meal shall not waste, neither shall the cruse of oil fail, until the day &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sendeth rain upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And she went and did according to the saying of Elijah: and she, and he, and her house, did eat &lt;span class='extra'&gt;many&lt;/span&gt; days.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; the barrel of meal wasted not, neither did the cruse of oil fail, according to the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which he spake by Elijah.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And it came to pass after these things, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the son of the woman, the mistress of the house, fell sick; and his sickness was so sore, that there was no breath left in him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And she said unto Elijah, What have I to do with thee, O thou man of God? art thou come unto me to call my sin to remembrance, and to slay my son?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he said unto her, Give me thy son. And he took him out of her bosom, and carried him up into a loft, where he abode, and laid him upon his own bed.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And he cried unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and said, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, hast thou also brought evil upon the widow with whom I sojourn, by slaying her son?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he stretched himself upon the child three times, and cried unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and said, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, I pray thee, let this child's soul come into him again.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; heard the voice of Elijah; and the soul of the child came into him again, and he revived.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Elijah took the child, and brought him down out of the chamber into the house, and delivered him unto his mother: and Elijah said, See, thy son liveth.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And the woman said to Elijah, Now by this I know that thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; a man of God, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; that the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in thy mouth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; truth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>