<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="11" name="1 Kings" bookPage="1kings.html" title="1 Kings" chapterCount="22" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2kings_1.html" nextTitle="2 Kings" prevBook="2samuel_1.html" prevTitle="2 Samuel">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="18" nextChapter="1kings_6.html" nextTitle="1 Kings 6" prevChapter="1kings_4.html" prevTitle="1 Kings 4" chapterPage="1kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Hiram king of Tyre sent his servants unto Solomon; for he had heard that they had anointed him king in the room of his father: for Hiram was ever a lover of David.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Solomon sent to Hiram, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou knowest how that David my father could not build an house unto the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God for the wars which were about him on every side, until the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; put them under the soles of his feet.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But now the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God hath given me rest on every side, &lt;i&gt;so that there is&lt;/i&gt; neither adversary nor evil occurrent.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And, behold, I purpose to build an house unto the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto David my father, saying, Thy son, whom I will set upon thy throne in thy room, he shall build an house unto my name.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Now therefore command thou that they hew me cedar trees out of Lebanon; and my servants shall be with thy servants: and unto thee will I give hire for thy servants according to all that thou shalt appoint: for thou knowest that &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; not among us any that can skill to hew timber like unto the Sidonians.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when Hiram heard the words of Solomon, that he rejoiced greatly, and said, Blessed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; this day, which hath given unto David a wise son over this great people.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Hiram sent to Solomon, saying, I have considered the things which thou sentest to me for: &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; I will do all thy desire concerning timber of cedar, and concerning timber of fir.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">My servants shall bring &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; down from Lebanon unto the sea: and I will convey them by sea in floats unto the place that thou shalt appoint me, and will cause them to be discharged there, and thou shalt receive &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;: and thou shalt accomplish my desire, in giving food for my household.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">So Hiram gave Solomon cedar trees and fir trees &lt;i&gt;according to&lt;/i&gt; all his desire.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Solomon gave Hiram twenty thousand measures of wheat &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; food to his household, and twenty measures of pure oil: thus gave Solomon to Hiram year by year.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; gave Solomon wisdom, as he promised him: and there was peace between Hiram and Solomon; and they two made a league together.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And king Solomon raised a levy out of all Israel; and the levy was thirty thousand men.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he sent them to Lebanon, ten thousand a month by courses: a month they were in Lebanon, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; two months at home: and Adoniram &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; over the levy.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Solomon had threescore and ten thousand that bare burdens, and fourscore thousand hewers in the mountains;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Beside the chief of Solomon's officers which &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; over the work, three thousand and three hundred, which ruled over the people that wrought in the work.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the king commanded, and they brought great stones, costly stones, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; hewed stones, to lay the foundation of the house.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Solomon's builders and Hiram's builders did hew &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;, and the stonesquarers: so they prepared timber and stones to build the house.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>