<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="12" name="2 Kings" bookPage="2kings.html" title="2 Kings" chapterCount="25" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles" prevBook="1kings_1.html" prevTitle="1 Kings">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="21" nextChapter="2kings_21.html" nextTitle="2 Kings 21" prevChapter="2kings_19.html" prevTitle="2 Kings 19" chapterPage="2kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In those days was Hezekiah sick unto death. And the prophet Isaiah the son of Amoz came to him, and said unto him, Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Set thine house in order; for thou shalt die, and not live.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then he turned his face to the wall, and prayed unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I beseech thee, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, remember now how I have walked before thee in truth and with a perfect heart, and have done &lt;i&gt;that which is&lt;/i&gt; good in thy sight. And Hezekiah wept sore.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And it came to pass, afore Isaiah was gone out into the middle court, that the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came to him, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Turn again, and tell Hezekiah the captain of my people, Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the God of David thy father, I have heard thy prayer, I have seen thy tears: behold, I will heal thee: on the third day thou shalt go up unto the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I will add unto thy days fifteen years; and I will deliver thee and this city out of the hand of the king of Assyria; and I will defend this city for mine own sake, and for my servant David's sake.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Isaiah said, Take a lump of figs. And they took and laid &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; on the boil, and he recovered.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And Hezekiah said unto Isaiah, What &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the sign that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will heal me, and that I shall go up into the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; the third day?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Isaiah said, This sign shalt thou have of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will do the thing that he hath spoken: shall the shadow go forward ten degrees, or go back ten degrees?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Hezekiah answered, It is a light thing for the shadow to go down ten degrees: nay, but let the shadow return backward ten degrees.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Isaiah the prophet cried unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and he brought the shadow ten degrees backward, by which it had gone down in the dial of Ahaz.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">At that time Berodach-baladan, the son of Baladan, king of Babylon, sent letters and a present unto Hezekiah: for he had heard that Hezekiah had been sick.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Hezekiah hearkened unto them, and shewed them all the house of his precious things, the silver, and the gold, and the spices, and the precious ointment, and &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; the house of his armour, and all that was found in his treasures: there was nothing in his house, nor in all his dominion, that Hezekiah shewed them not.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Then came Isaiah the prophet unto king Hezekiah, and said unto him, What said these men? and from whence came they unto thee? And Hezekiah said, They are come from a far country, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; from Babylon.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he said, What have they seen in thine house? And Hezekiah answered, All &lt;i&gt;the things&lt;/i&gt; that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in mine house have they seen: there is nothing among my treasures that I have not shewed them.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Isaiah said unto Hezekiah, Hear the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Behold, the days come, that all that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in thine house, and that which thy fathers have laid up in store unto this day, shall be carried into Babylon: nothing shall be left, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And of thy sons that shall issue from thee, which thou shalt beget, shall they take away; and they shall be eunuchs in the palace of the king of Babylon.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Then said Hezekiah unto Isaiah, Good &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which thou hast spoken. And he said, &lt;i&gt;Is it&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt;, if peace and truth be in my days?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And the rest of the acts of Hezekiah, and all his might, and how he made a pool, and a conduit, and brought water into the city, &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Hezekiah slept with his fathers: and Manasseh his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>