<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="12" name="2 Kings" bookPage="2kings.html" title="2 Kings" chapterCount="25" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles" prevBook="1kings_1.html" prevTitle="1 Kings">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="21" nextChapter="2kings_12.html" nextTitle="2 Kings 12" prevChapter="2kings_10.html" prevTitle="2 Kings 10" chapterPage="2kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And when Athaliah the mother of Ahaziah saw that her son was dead, she arose and destroyed all the seed royal.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">But Jehosheba, the daughter of king Joram, sister of Ahaziah, took Joash the son of Ahaziah, and stole him from among the king's sons &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which were&lt;/span&gt; slain; and they hid him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; him and his nurse, in the bedchamber from Athaliah, so that he was not slain.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he was with her hid in the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; six years. And Athaliah did reign over the land.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And the seventh year Jehoiada sent and fetched the rulers over hundreds, with the captains and the guard, and brought them to him into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and made a covenant with them, and took an oath of them in the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and shewed them the king's son.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he commanded them, saying, This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the thing that ye shall do; A third part of you that enter in on the sabbath shall even be keepers of the watch of the king's house;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And a third part &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; at the gate of Sur; and a third part at the gate behind the guard: so shall ye keep the watch of the house, that it be not broken down.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And two parts of all you that go forth on the sabbath, even they shall keep the watch of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; about the king.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And ye shall compass the king round about, every man with his weapons in his hand: and he that cometh within the ranges, let him be slain: and be ye with the king as he goeth out and as he cometh in.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the captains over the hundreds did according to all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; that Jehoiada the priest commanded: and they took every man his men that were to come in on the sabbath, with them that should go out on the sabbath, and came to Jehoiada the priest.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And to the captains over hundreds did the priest give king David's spears and shields, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the temple of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the guard stood, every man with his weapons in his hand, round about the king, from the right corner of the temple to the left corner of the temple, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;along&lt;/span&gt; by the altar and the temple.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he brought forth the king's son, and put the crown upon him, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;gave him&lt;/span&gt; the testimony; and they made him king, and anointed him; and they clapped their hands, and said, God save the king.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And when Athaliah heard the noise of the guard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; of the people, she came to the people into the temple of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And when she looked, behold, the king stood by a pillar, as the manner &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt;, and the princes and the trumpeters by the king, and all the people of the land rejoiced, and blew with trumpets: and Athaliah rent her clothes, and cried, Treason, Treason.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But Jehoiada the priest commanded the captains of the hundreds, the officers of the host, and said unto them, Have her forth without the ranges: and him that followeth her kill with the sword. For the priest had said, Let her not be slain in the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And they laid hands on her; and she went by the way by the which the horses came into the king's house: and there was she slain.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And Jehoiada made a covenant between the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; and the king and the people, that they should be the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s people; between the king also and the people.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And all the people of the land went into the house of Baal, and brake it down; his altars and his images brake they in pieces thoroughly, and slew Mattan the priest of Baal before the altars. And the priest appointed officers over the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he took the rulers over hundreds, and the captains, and the guard, and all the people of the land; and they brought down the king from the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and came by the way of the gate of the guard to the king's house. And he sat on the throne of the kings.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And all the people of the land rejoiced, and the city was in quiet: and they slew Athaliah with the sword &lt;span class="extra"&gt;beside&lt;/span&gt; the king's house.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Seven years old &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Jehoash when he began to reign.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>