<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="12" name="2 Kings" bookPage="2kings.html" title="2 Kings" chapterCount="25" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles" prevBook="1kings_1.html" prevTitle="1 Kings">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="29" nextChapter="2kings_15.html" nextTitle="2 Kings 15" prevChapter="2kings_13.html" prevTitle="2 Kings 13" chapterPage="2kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In the second year of Joash son of Jehoahaz king of Israel reigned Amaziah the son of Joash king of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">He was twenty and five years old when he began to reign, and reigned twenty and nine years in Jerusalem. And his mother's name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Jehoaddan of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he did &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which was&lt;/span&gt; right in the sight of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, yet not like David his father: he did according to all things as Joash his father did.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Howbeit the high places were not taken away: as yet the people did sacrifice and burnt incense on the high places.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And it came to pass, as soon as the kingdom was confirmed in his hand, that he slew his servants which had slain the king his father.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But the children of the murderers he slew not: according unto that which is written in the book of the law of Moses, wherein the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded, saying, The fathers shall not be put to death for the children, nor the children be put to death for the fathers; but every man shall be put to death for his own sin.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He slew of Edom in the valley of salt ten thousand, and took Selah by war, and called the name of it Joktheel unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Then Amaziah sent messengers to Jehoash, the son of Jehoahaz son of Jehu, king of Israel, saying, Come, let us look one another in the face.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Jehoash the king of Israel sent to Amaziah king of Judah, saying, The thistle that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in Lebanon sent to the cedar that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in Lebanon, saying, Give thy daughter to my son to wife: and there passed by a wild beast that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in Lebanon, and trode down the thistle.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thou hast indeed smitten Edom, and thine heart hath lifted thee up: glory &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of this&lt;/span&gt;, and tarry at home: for why shouldest thou meddle to &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; hurt, that thou shouldest fall, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; thou, and Judah with thee?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But Amaziah would not hear. Therefore Jehoash king of Israel went up; and he and Amaziah king of Judah looked one another in the face at Beth-shemesh, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;belongeth&lt;/span&gt; to Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Judah was put to the worse before Israel; and they fled every man to their tents.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Jehoash king of Israel took Amaziah king of Judah, the son of Jehoash the son of Ahaziah, at Beth-shemesh, and came to Jerusalem, and brake down the wall of Jerusalem from the gate of Ephraim unto the corner gate, four hundred cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he took all the gold and silver, and all the vessels that were found in the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and in the treasures of the king's house, and hostages, and returned to Samaria.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Now the rest of the acts of Jehoash which he did, and his might, and how he fought with Amaziah king of Judah, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Jehoash slept with his fathers, and was buried in Samaria with the kings of Israel; and Jeroboam his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And Amaziah the son of Joash king of Judah lived after the death of Jehoash son of Jehoahaz king of Israel fifteen years.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the rest of the acts of Amaziah, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Now they made a conspiracy against him in Jerusalem: and he fled to Lachish; but they sent after him to Lachish, and slew him there.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And they brought him on horses: and he was buried at Jerusalem with his fathers in the city of David.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">And all the people of Judah took Azariah, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; sixteen years old, and made him king instead of his father Amaziah.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">He built Elath, and restored it to Judah, after that the king slept with his fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">In the fifteenth year of Amaziah the son of Joash king of Judah Jeroboam the son of Joash king of Israel began to reign in Samaria, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and reigned&lt;/span&gt; forty and one years.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And he did &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which was&lt;/span&gt; evil in the sight of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: he departed not from all the sins of Jeroboam the son of Nebat, who made Israel to sin.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">He restored the coast of Israel from the entering of Hamath unto the sea of the plain, according to the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, which he spake by the hand of his servant Jonah, the son of Amittai, the prophet, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; of Gath-hepher.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; saw the affliction of Israel, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that it was&lt;/span&gt; very bitter: for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; not any shut up, nor any left, nor any helper for Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said not that he would blot out the name of Israel from under heaven: but he saved them by the hand of Jeroboam the son of Joash.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">Now the rest of the acts of Jeroboam, and all that he did, and his might, how he warred, and how he recovered Damascus, and Hamath, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which belonged&lt;/span&gt; to Judah, for Israel, are they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Jeroboam slept with his fathers, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; with the kings of Israel; and Zachariah his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>