<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="12" name="2 Kings" bookPage="2kings.html" title="2 Kings" chapterCount="25" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles" prevBook="1kings_1.html" prevTitle="1 Kings">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="37" nextChapter="2kings_19.html" nextTitle="2 Kings 19" prevChapter="2kings_17.html" prevTitle="2 Kings 17" chapterPage="2kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now it came to pass in the third year of Hoshea son of Elah king of Israel, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; Hezekiah the son of Ahaz king of Judah began to reign.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Twenty and five years old was he when he began to reign; and he reigned twenty and nine years in Jerusalem. His mother's name also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Abi, the daughter of Zachariah.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he did &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that which was&lt;/span&gt; right in the sight of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, according to all that David his father did.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">He removed the high places, and brake the images, and cut down the groves, and brake in pieces the brasen serpent that Moses had made: for unto those days the children of Israel did burn incense to it: and he called it Nehushtan.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">He trusted in the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel; so that after him was none like him among all the kings of Judah, nor &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; that were before him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For he clave to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; departed not from following him, but kept his commandments, which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was with him; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he prospered whithersoever he went forth: and he rebelled against the king of Assyria, and served him not.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He smote the Philistines, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto Gaza, and the borders thereof, from the tower of the watchmen to the fenced city.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And it came to pass in the fourth year of king Hezekiah, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the seventh year of Hoshea son of Elah king of Israel, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; Shalmaneser king of Assyria came up against Samaria, and besieged it.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And at the end of three years they took it: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; in the sixth year of Hezekiah, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the ninth year of Hoshea king of Israel, Samaria was taken.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the king of Assyria did carry away Israel unto Assyria, and put them in Halah and in Habor &lt;span class="extra"&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; the river of Gozan, and in the cities of the Medes:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Because they obeyed not the voice of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God, but transgressed his covenant, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; all that Moses the servant of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded, and would not hear &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, nor do &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Now in the fourteenth year of king Hezekiah did Sennacherib king of Assyria come up against all the fenced cities of Judah, and took them.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Hezekiah king of Judah sent to the king of Assyria to Lachish, saying, I have offended; return from me: that which thou puttest on me will I bear. And the king of Assyria appointed unto Hezekiah king of Judah three hundred talents of silver and thirty talents of gold.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Hezekiah gave &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; all the silver that was found in the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and in the treasures of the king's house.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">At that time did Hezekiah cut off &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the gold from&lt;/span&gt; the doors of the temple of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the pillars which Hezekiah king of Judah had overlaid, and gave it to the king of Assyria.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And the king of Assyria sent Tartan and Rab-saris and Rab-shakeh from Lachish to king Hezekiah with a great host against Jerusalem. And they went up and came to Jerusalem. And when they were come up, they came and stood by the conduit of the upper pool, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the highway of the fuller's field.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And when they had called to the king, there came out to them Eliakim the son of Hilkiah, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; over the household, and Shebna the scribe, and Joah the son of Asaph the recorder.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Rab-shakeh said unto them, Speak ye now to Hezekiah, Thus saith the great king, the king of Assyria, What confidence &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this wherein thou trustest?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Thou sayest, (but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;they are but&lt;/span&gt; vain words,) &lt;span class="extra"&gt;I have&lt;/span&gt; counsel and strength for the war. Now on whom dost thou trust, that thou rebellest against me?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Now, behold, thou trustest upon the staff of this bruised reed, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; upon Egypt, on which if a man lean, it will go into his hand, and pierce it: so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Pharaoh king of Egypt unto all that trust on him.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But if ye say unto me, We trust in the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not that he, whose high places and whose altars Hezekiah hath taken away, and hath said to Judah and Jerusalem, Ye shall worship before this altar in Jerusalem?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Now therefore, I pray thee, give pledges to my lord the king of Assyria, and I will deliver thee two thousand horses, if thou be able on thy part to set riders upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">How then wilt thou turn away the face of one captain of the least of my master's servants, and put thy trust on Egypt for chariots and for horsemen?</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Am I now come up without the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; against this place to destroy it? The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said to me, Go up against this land, and destroy it.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Then said Eliakim the son of Hilkiah, and Shebna, and Joah, unto Rab-shakeh, Speak, I pray thee, to thy servants in the Syrian language; for we understand &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;: and talk not with us in the Jews' language in the ears of the people that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; on the wall.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">But Rab-shakeh said unto them, Hath my master sent me to thy master, and to thee, to speak these words? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hath he&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class="extra"&gt;sent me&lt;/span&gt; to the men which sit on the wall, that they may eat their own dung, and drink their own piss with you?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Then Rab-shakeh stood and cried with a loud voice in the Jews' language, and spake, saying, Hear the word of the great king, the king of Assyria:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Thus saith the king, Let not Hezekiah deceive you: for he shall not be able to deliver you out of his hand:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Neither let Hezekiah make you trust in the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, saying, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will surely deliver us, and this city shall not be delivered into the hand of the king of Assyria.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Hearken not to Hezekiah: for thus saith the king of Assyria, Make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;an agreement&lt;/span&gt; with me by a present, and come out to me, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; eat ye every man of his own vine, and every one of his fig tree, and drink ye every one the waters of his cistern:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Until I come and take you away to a land like your own land, a land of corn and wine, a land of bread and vineyards, a land of oil olive and of honey, that ye may live, and not die: and hearken not unto Hezekiah, when he persuadeth you, saying, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will deliver us.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Hath any of the gods of the nations delivered at all his land out of the hand of the king of Assyria?</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the gods of Hamath, and of Arpad? where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the gods of Sepharvaim, Hena, and Ivah? have they delivered Samaria out of mine hand?</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they among all the gods of the countries, that have delivered their country out of mine hand, that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; should deliver Jerusalem out of mine hand?</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">But the people held their peace, and answered him not a word: for the king's commandment was, saying, Answer him not.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Then came Eliakim the son of Hilkiah, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; over the household, and Shebna the scribe, and Joah the son of Asaph the recorder, to Hezekiah with &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; clothes rent, and told him the words of Rab-shakeh.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>