<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="12" name="2 Kings" bookPage="2kings.html" title="2 Kings" chapterCount="25" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles" prevBook="1kings_1.html" prevTitle="1 Kings">
    <chapter number="21" verseCount="26" nextChapter="2kings_22.html" nextTitle="2 Kings 22" prevChapter="2kings_20.html" prevTitle="2 Kings 20" chapterPage="2kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Manasseh &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; twelve years old when he began to reign, and reigned fifty and five years in Jerusalem. And his mother's name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Hephzi-bah.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he did &lt;i&gt;that which was&lt;/i&gt; evil in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, after the abominations of the heathen, whom the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; cast out before the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For he built up again the high places which Hezekiah his father had destroyed; and he reared up altars for Baal, and made a grove, as did Ahab king of Israel; and worshipped all the host of heaven, and served them.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he built altars in the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, of which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said, In Jerusalem will I put my name.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he built altars for all the host of heaven in the two courts of the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he made his son pass through the fire, and observed times, and used enchantments, and dealt with familiar spirits and wizards: he wrought much wickedness in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to provoke &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; to anger.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he set a graven image of the grove that he had made in the house, of which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said to David, and to Solomon his son, In this house, and in Jerusalem, which I have chosen out of all tribes of Israel, will I put my name for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Neither will I make the feet of Israel move any more out of the land which I gave their fathers; only if they will observe to do according to all that I have commanded them, and according to all the law that my servant Moses commanded them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But they hearkened not: and Manasseh seduced them to do more evil than did the nations whom the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; destroyed before the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake by his servants the prophets, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Because Manasseh king of Judah hath done these abominations, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; hath done wickedly above all that the Amorites did, which &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; before him, and hath made Judah also to sin with his idols:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, Behold, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; bringing &lt;i&gt;such&lt;/i&gt; evil upon Jerusalem and Judah, that whosoever heareth of it, both his ears shall tingle.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And I will stretch over Jerusalem the line of Samaria, and the plummet of the house of Ahab: and I will wipe Jerusalem as &lt;i&gt;a man&lt;/i&gt; wipeth a dish, wiping &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and turning &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; upside down.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And I will forsake the remnant of mine inheritance, and deliver them into the hand of their enemies; and they shall become a prey and a spoil to all their enemies;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Because they have done &lt;i&gt;that which was&lt;/i&gt; evil in my sight, and have provoked me to anger, since the day their fathers came forth out of Egypt, even unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Moreover Manasseh shed innocent blood very much, till he had filled Jerusalem from one end to another; beside his sin wherewith he made Judah to sin, in doing &lt;i&gt;that which was&lt;/i&gt; evil in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Now the rest of the acts of Manasseh, and all that he did, and his sin that he sinned, &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Manasseh slept with his fathers, and was buried in the garden of his own house, in the garden of Uzza: and Amon his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">Amon &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; twenty and two years old when he began to reign, and he reigned two years in Jerusalem. And his mother's name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Meshullemeth, the daughter of Haruz of Jotbah.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And he did &lt;i&gt;that which was&lt;/i&gt; evil in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as his father Manasseh did.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he walked in all the way that his father walked in, and served the idols that his father served, and worshipped them:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And he forsook the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of his fathers, and walked not in the way of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And the servants of Amon conspired against him, and slew the king in his own house.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the people of the land slew all them that had conspired against king Amon; and the people of the land made Josiah his son king in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Now the rest of the acts of Amon which he did, &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And he was buried in his sepulchre in the garden of Uzza: and Josiah his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>