<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="12" name="2 Kings" bookPage="2kings.html" title="2 Kings" chapterCount="25" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles" prevBook="1kings_1.html" prevTitle="1 Kings">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="21" nextChapter="2kings_13.html" nextTitle="2 Kings 13" prevChapter="2kings_11.html" prevTitle="2 Kings 11" chapterPage="2kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In the seventh year of Jehu Jehoash began to reign; and forty years reigned he in Jerusalem. And his mother's name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Zibiah of Beer-sheba.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Jehoash did &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that which was&lt;/span&gt; right in the sight of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; all his days wherein Jehoiada the priest instructed him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But the high places were not taken away: the people still sacrificed and burnt incense in the high places.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And Jehoash said to the priests, All the money of the dedicated things that is brought into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the money of every one that passeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the account&lt;/span&gt;, the money that every man is set at, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; all the money that cometh into any man's heart to bring into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Let the priests take &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to them, every man of his acquaintance: and let them repair the breaches of the house, wheresoever any breach shall be found.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But it was &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so, that&lt;/span&gt; in the three and twentieth year of king Jehoash the priests had not repaired the breaches of the house.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then king Jehoash called for Jehoiada the priest, and the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; priests, and said unto them, Why repair ye not the breaches of the house? now therefore receive no &lt;span class="extra"&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; money of your acquaintance, but deliver it for the breaches of the house.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the priests consented to receive no &lt;span class="extra"&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; money of the people, neither to repair the breaches of the house.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But Jehoiada the priest took a chest, and bored a hole in the lid of it, and set it beside the altar, on the right side as one cometh into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and the priests that kept the door put therein all the money &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that was&lt;/span&gt; brought into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And it was &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;, when they saw that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; much money in the chest, that the king's scribe and the high priest came up, and they put up in bags, and told the money that was found in the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And they gave the money, being told, into the hands of them that did the work, that had the oversight of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and they laid it out to the carpenters and builders, that wrought upon the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And to masons, and hewers of stone, and to buy timber and hewed stone to repair the breaches of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and for all that was laid out for the house to repair &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Howbeit there were not made for the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; bowls of silver, snuffers, basons, trumpets, any vessels of gold, or vessels of silver, of the money &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that was&lt;/span&gt; brought into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But they gave that to the workmen, and repaired therewith the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Moreover they reckoned not with the men, into whose hand they delivered the money to be bestowed on workmen: for they dealt faithfully.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The trespass money and sin money was not brought into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: it was the priests'.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Then Hazael king of Syria went up, and fought against Gath, and took it: and Hazael set his face to go up to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Jehoash king of Judah took all the hallowed things that Jehoshaphat, and Jehoram, and Ahaziah, his fathers, kings of Judah, had dedicated, and his own hallowed things, and all the gold &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that was&lt;/span&gt; found in the treasures of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and in the king's house, and sent &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to Hazael king of Syria: and he went away from Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And the rest of the acts of Joash, and all that he did, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And his servants arose, and made a conspiracy, and slew Joash in the house of Millo, which goeth down to Silla.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For Jozachar the son of Shimeath, and Jehozabad the son of Shomer, his servants, smote him, and he died; and they buried him with his fathers in the city of David: and Amaziah his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>