<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="12" name="2 Kings" bookPage="2kings.html" title="2 Kings" chapterCount="25" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles" prevBook="1kings_1.html" prevTitle="1 Kings">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="20" nextChapter="2kings_23.html" nextTitle="2 Kings 23" prevChapter="2kings_21.html" prevTitle="2 Kings 21" chapterPage="2kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Josiah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; eight years old when he began to reign, and he reigned thirty and one years in Jerusalem. And his mother's name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Jedidah, the daughter of Adaiah of Boscath.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he did &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that which was&lt;/span&gt; right in the sight of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and walked in all the way of David his father, and turned not aside to the right hand or to the left.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And it came to pass in the eighteenth year of king Josiah, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the king sent Shaphan the son of Azaliah, the son of Meshullam, the scribe, to the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Go up to Hilkiah the high priest, that he may sum the silver which is brought into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which the keepers of the door have gathered of the people:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And let them deliver it into the hand of the doers of the work, that have the oversight of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and let them give it to the doers of the work which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to repair the breaches of the house,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Unto carpenters, and builders, and masons, and to buy timber and hewn stone to repair the house.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Howbeit there was no reckoning made with them of the money that was delivered into their hand, because they dealt faithfully.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And Hilkiah the high priest said unto Shaphan the scribe, I have found the book of the law in the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. And Hilkiah gave the book to Shaphan, and he read it.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Shaphan the scribe came to the king, and brought the king word again, and said, Thy servants have gathered the money that was found in the house, and have delivered it into the hand of them that do the work, that have the oversight of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Shaphan the scribe shewed the king, saying, Hilkiah the priest hath delivered me a book. And Shaphan read it before the king.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And it came to pass, when the king had heard the words of the book of the law, that he rent his clothes.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the king commanded Hilkiah the priest, and Ahikam the son of Shaphan, and Achbor the son of Michaiah, and Shaphan the scribe, and Asahiah a servant of the king's, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Go ye, enquire of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for me, and for the people, and for all Judah, concerning the words of this book that is found: for great &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the wrath of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that is kindled against us, because our fathers have not hearkened unto the words of this book, to do according unto all that which is written concerning us.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">So Hilkiah the priest, and Ahikam, and Achbor, and Shaphan, and Asahiah, went unto Huldah the prophetess, the wife of Shallum the son of Tikvah, the son of Harhas, keeper of the wardrobe; (now she dwelt in Jerusalem in the college;) and they communed with her.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And she said unto them, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, Tell the man that sent you to me,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Behold, I will bring evil upon this place, and upon the inhabitants thereof, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all the words of the book which the king of Judah hath read:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Because they have forsaken me, and have burned incense unto other gods, that they might provoke me to anger with all the works of their hands; therefore my wrath shall be kindled against this place, and shall not be quenched.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But to the king of Judah which sent you to enquire of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thus shall ye say to him, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;As touching&lt;/span&gt; the words which thou hast heard;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Because thine heart was tender, and thou hast humbled thyself before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, when thou heardest what I spake against this place, and against the inhabitants thereof, that they should become a desolation and a curse, and hast rent thy clothes, and wept before me; I also have heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt;, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Behold therefore, I will gather thee unto thy fathers, and thou shalt be gathered into thy grave in peace; and thine eyes shall not see all the evil which I will bring upon this place. And they brought the king word again.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>