<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="12" name="2 Kings" bookPage="2kings.html" title="2 Kings" chapterCount="25" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles" prevBook="1kings_1.html" prevTitle="1 Kings">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="27" nextChapter="2kings_6.html" nextTitle="2 Kings 6" prevChapter="2kings_4.html" prevTitle="2 Kings 4" chapterPage="2kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now Naaman, captain of the host of the king of Syria, was a great man with his master, and honourable, because by him the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had given deliverance unto Syria: he was also a mighty man in valour, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but he was&lt;/span&gt; a leper.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the Syrians had gone out by companies, and had brought away captive out of the land of Israel a little maid; and she waited on Naaman's wife.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And she said unto her mistress, Would God my lord &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; with the prophet that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in Samaria! for he would recover him of his leprosy.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; went in, and told his lord, saying, Thus and thus said the maid that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; of the land of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the king of Syria said, Go to, go, and I will send a letter unto the king of Israel. And he departed, and took with him ten talents of silver, and six thousand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;pieces&lt;/span&gt; of gold, and ten changes of raiment.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he brought the letter to the king of Israel, saying, Now when this letter is come unto thee, behold, I have &lt;span class='extra'&gt;therewith&lt;/span&gt; sent Naaman my servant to thee, that thou mayest recover him of his leprosy.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And it came to pass, when the king of Israel had read the letter, that he rent his clothes, and said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Am&lt;/span&gt; I God, to kill and to make alive, that this man doth send unto me to recover a man of his leprosy? wherefore consider, I pray you, and see how he seeketh a quarrel against me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And it was &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;, when Elisha the man of God had heard that the king of Israel had rent his clothes, that he sent to the king, saying, Wherefore hast thou rent thy clothes? let him come now to me, and he shall know that there is a prophet in Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">So Naaman came with his horses and with his chariot, and stood at the door of the house of Elisha.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Elisha sent a messenger unto him, saying, Go and wash in Jordan seven times, and thy flesh shall come again to thee, and thou shalt be clean.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But Naaman was wroth, and went away, and said, Behold, I thought, He will surely come out to me, and stand, and call on the name of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God, and strike his hand over the place, and recover the leper.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Are&lt;/span&gt; not Abana and Pharpar, rivers of Damascus, better than all the waters of Israel? may I not wash in them, and be clean? So he turned and went away in a rage.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And his servants came near, and spake unto him, and said, My father, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; the prophet had bid thee &lt;span class='extra'&gt;do some&lt;/span&gt; great thing, wouldest thou not have done &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;? how much rather then, when he saith to thee, Wash, and be clean?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then went he down, and dipped himself seven times in Jordan, according to the saying of the man of God: and his flesh came again like unto the flesh of a little child, and he was clean.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And he returned to the man of God, he and all his company, and came, and stood before him: and he said, Behold, now I know that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no God in all the earth, but in Israel: now therefore, I pray thee, take a blessing of thy servant.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But he said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth, before whom I stand, I will receive none. And he urged him to take &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;; but he refused.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Naaman said, Shall there not then, I pray thee, be given to thy servant two mules' burden of earth? for thy servant will henceforth offer neither burnt offering nor sacrifice unto other gods, but unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">In this thing the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; pardon thy servant, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; when my master goeth into the house of Rimmon to worship there, and he leaneth on my hand, and I bow myself in the house of Rimmon: when I bow down myself in the house of Rimmon, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; pardon thy servant in this thing.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he said unto him, Go in peace. So he departed from him a little way.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">But Gehazi, the servant of Elisha the man of God, said, Behold, my master hath spared Naaman this Syrian, in not receiving at his hands that which he brought: but, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth, I will run after him, and take somewhat of him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">So Gehazi followed after Naaman. And when Naaman saw &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; running after him, he lighted down from the chariot to meet him, and said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; all well?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And he said, All &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; well. My master hath sent me, saying, Behold, even now there be come to me from mount Ephraim two young men of the sons of the prophets: give them, I pray thee, a talent of silver, and two changes of garments.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Naaman said, Be content, take two talents. And he urged him, and bound two talents of silver in two bags, with two changes of garments, and laid &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; upon two of his servants; and they bare &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; before him.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And when he came to the tower, he took &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; from their hand, and bestowed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; in the house: and he let the men go, and they departed.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">But he went in, and stood before his master. And Elisha said unto him, Whence &lt;span class='extra'&gt;comest thou&lt;/span&gt;, Gehazi? And he said, Thy servant went no whither.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And he said unto him, Went not mine heart &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with thee&lt;/span&gt;, when the man turned again from his chariot to meet thee? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is it&lt;/span&gt; a time to receive money, and to receive garments, and oliveyards, and vineyards, and sheep, and oxen, and menservants, and maidservants?</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The leprosy therefore of Naaman shall cleave unto thee, and unto thy seed for ever. And he went out from his presence a leper &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as white&lt;/span&gt; as snow.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>