<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="12" name="2 Kings" bookPage="2kings.html" title="2 Kings" chapterCount="25" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="1chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles" prevBook="1kings_1.html" prevTitle="1 Kings">
    <chapter number="24" verseCount="20" nextChapter="2kings_25.html" nextTitle="2 Kings 25" prevChapter="2kings_23.html" prevTitle="2 Kings 23" chapterPage="2kings_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In his days Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon came up, and Jehoiakim became his servant three years: then he turned and rebelled against him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent against him bands of the Chaldees, and bands of the Syrians, and bands of the Moabites, and bands of the children of Ammon, and sent them against Judah to destroy it, according to the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which he spake by his servants the prophets.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Surely at the commandment of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; upon Judah, to remove &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; out of his sight, for the sins of Manasseh, according to all that he did;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And also for the innocent blood that he shed: for he filled Jerusalem with innocent blood; which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; would not pardon.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Now the rest of the acts of Jehoiakim, and all that he did, &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; they not written in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Judah?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">So Jehoiakim slept with his fathers: and Jehoiachin his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the king of Egypt came not again any more out of his land: for the king of Babylon had taken from the river of Egypt unto the river Euphrates all that pertained to the king of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Jehoiachin &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; eighteen years old when he began to reign, and he reigned in Jerusalem three months. And his mother's name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Nehushta, the daughter of Elnathan of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he did &lt;i&gt;that which was&lt;/i&gt; evil in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, according to all that his father had done.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">At that time the servants of Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon came up against Jerusalem, and the city was besieged.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Nebuchadnezzar king of Babylon came against the city, and his servants did besiege it.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Jehoiachin the king of Judah went out to the king of Babylon, he, and his mother, and his servants, and his princes, and his officers: and the king of Babylon took him in the eighth year of his reign.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he carried out thence all the treasures of the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the treasures of the king's house, and cut in pieces all the vessels of gold which Solomon king of Israel had made in the temple of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had said.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he carried away all Jerusalem, and all the princes, and all the mighty men of valour, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; ten thousand captives, and all the craftsmen and smiths: none remained, save the poorest sort of the people of the land.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he carried away Jehoiachin to Babylon, and the king's mother, and the king's wives, and his officers, and the mighty of the land, &lt;i&gt;those&lt;/i&gt; carried he into captivity from Jerusalem to Babylon.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And all the men of might, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; seven thousand, and craftsmen and smiths a thousand, all &lt;i&gt;that were&lt;/i&gt; strong &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; apt for war, even them the king of Babylon brought captive to Babylon.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And the king of Babylon made Mattaniah his father's brother king in his stead, and changed his name to Zedekiah.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Zedekiah &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; twenty and one years old when he began to reign, and he reigned eleven years in Jerusalem. And his mother's name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Hamutal, the daughter of Jeremiah of Libnah.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he did &lt;i&gt;that which was&lt;/i&gt; evil in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, according to all that Jehoiakim had done.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For through the anger of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; it came to pass in Jerusalem and Judah, until he had cast them out from his presence, that Zedekiah rebelled against the king of Babylon.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>