<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="23" verseCount="32" nextChapter="1chronicles_24.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 24" prevChapter="1chronicles_22.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 22" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">So when David was old and full of days, he made Solomon his son king over Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">And he gathered together all the princes of Israel, with the priests and the Levites.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Now the Levites were numbered from the age of thirty years and upward: and their number by their polls, man by man, was thirty and eight thousand.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Of which, twenty and four thousand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; to set forward the work of the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and six thousand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; officers and judges:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Moreover four thousand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; porters; and four thousand praised the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with the instruments which I made, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;said David&lt;/span&gt;, to praise &lt;span class='extra'&gt;therewith&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And David divided them into courses among the sons of Levi, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;namely&lt;/span&gt;, Gershon, Kohath, and Merari.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Of the Gershonites &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Laadan, and Shimei.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The sons of Laadan; the chief &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Jehiel, and Zetham, and Joel, three.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The sons of Shimei; Shelomith, and Haziel, and Haran, three. These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the chief of the fathers of Laadan.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the sons of Shimei &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Jahath, Zina, and Jeush, and Beriah. These four &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Shimei.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Jahath was the chief, and Zizah the second: but Jeush and Beriah had not many sons; therefore they were in one reckoning, according to &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; father's house.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">The sons of Kohath; Amram, Izhar, Hebron, and Uzziel, four.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The sons of Amram; Aaron and Moses: and Aaron was separated, that he should sanctify the most holy things, he and his sons for ever, to burn incense before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to minister unto him, and to bless in his name for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Now &lt;span class='extra'&gt;concerning&lt;/span&gt; Moses the man of God, his sons were named of the tribe of Levi.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The sons of Moses &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Gershom, and Eliezer.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Of the sons of Gershom, Shebuel &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the chief.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the sons of Eliezer &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Rehabiah the chief. And Eliezer had none other sons; but the sons of Rehabiah were very many.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Of the sons of Izhar; Shelomith the chief.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Of the sons of Hebron; Jeriah the first, Amariah the second, Jahaziel the third, and Jekameam the fourth.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Of the sons of Uzziel; Michah the first, and Jesiah the second.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">The sons of Merari; Mahli, and Mushi. The sons of Mahli; Eleazar, and Kish.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Eleazar died, and had no sons, but daughters: and their brethren the sons of Kish took them.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The sons of Mushi; Mahli, and Eder, and Jeremoth, three.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Levi after the house of their fathers; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the chief of the fathers, as they were counted by number of names by their polls, that did the work for the service of the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, from the age of twenty years and upward.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For David said, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel hath given rest unto his people, that they may dwell in Jerusalem for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And also unto the Levites; they shall no &lt;span class='extra'&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; carry the tabernacle, nor any vessels of it for the service thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For by the last words of David the Levites &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; numbered from twenty years old and above:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Because their office &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; to wait on the sons of Aaron for the service of the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in the courts, and in the chambers, and in the purifying of all holy things, and the work of the service of the house of God;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Both for the shewbread, and for the fine flour for meat offering, and for the unleavened cakes, and for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which is baked in&lt;/span&gt; the pan, and for that which is fried, and for all manner of measure and size;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And to stand every morning to thank and praise the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and likewise at even;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And to offer all burnt sacrifices unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the sabbaths, in the new moons, and on the set feasts, by number, according to the order commanded unto them, continually before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And that they should keep the charge of the tabernacle of the congregation, and the charge of the holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;, and the charge of the sons of Aaron their brethren, in the service of the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>