<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="17" nextChapter="1chronicles_15.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 15" prevChapter="1chronicles_13.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 13" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now Hiram king of Tyre sent messengers to David, and timber of cedars, with masons and carpenters, to build him an house.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And David perceived that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had confirmed him king over Israel, for his kingdom was lifted up on high, because of his people Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And David took more wives at Jerusalem: and David begat more sons and daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Now these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the names of &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; children which he had in Jerusalem; Shammua, and Shobab, Nathan, and Solomon,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Ibhar, and Elishua, and Elpalet,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Nogah, and Nepheg, and Japhia,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Elishama, and Beeliada, and Eliphalet.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And when the Philistines heard that David was anointed king over all Israel, all the Philistines went up to seek David. And David heard &lt;i&gt;of it&lt;/i&gt;, and went out against them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the Philistines came and spread themselves in the valley of Rephaim.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And David enquired of God, saying, Shall I go up against the Philistines? and wilt thou deliver them into mine hand? And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, Go up; for I will deliver them into thine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">So they came up to Baal-perazim; and David smote them there. Then David said, God hath broken in upon mine enemies by mine hand like the breaking forth of waters: therefore they called the name of that place Baal-perazim.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And when they had left their gods there, David gave a commandment, and they were burned with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the Philistines yet again spread themselves abroad in the valley.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Therefore David enquired again of God; and God said unto him, Go not up after them; turn away from them, and come upon them over against the mulberry trees.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And it shall be, when thou shalt hear a sound of going in the tops of the mulberry trees, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; then thou shalt go out to battle: for God is gone forth before thee to smite the host of the Philistines.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">David therefore did as God commanded him: and they smote the host of the Philistines from Gibeon even to Gazer.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the fame of David went out into all lands; and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought the fear of him upon all nations.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>