<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="44" nextChapter="1chronicles_10.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 10" prevChapter="1chronicles_8.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 8" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">So all Israel were reckoned by genealogies; and, behold, they &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; written in the book of the kings of Israel and Judah, &lt;i&gt;who&lt;/i&gt; were carried away to Babylon for their transgression.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">Now the first inhabitants that &lt;i&gt;dwelt&lt;/i&gt; in their possessions in their cities &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt;, the Israelites, the priests, Levites, and the Nethinims.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And in Jerusalem dwelt of the children of Judah, and of the children of Benjamin, and of the children of Ephraim, and Manasseh;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Uthai the son of Ammihud, the son of Omri, the son of Imri, the son of Bani, of the children of Pharez the son of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And of the Shilonites; Asaiah the firstborn, and his sons.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And of the sons of Zerah; Jeuel, and their brethren, six hundred and ninety.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And of the sons of Benjamin; Sallu the son of Meshullam, the son of Hodaviah, the son of Hasenuah,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Ibneiah the son of Jeroham, and Elah the son of Uzzi, the son of Michri, and Meshullam the son of Shephathiah, the son of Reuel, the son of Ibnijah;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And their brethren, according to their generations, nine hundred and fifty and six. All these men &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; chief of the fathers in the house of their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And of the priests; Jedaiah, and Jehoiarib, and Jachin,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Azariah the son of Hilkiah, the son of Meshullam, the son of Zadok, the son of Meraioth, the son of Ahitub, the ruler of the house of God;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Adaiah the son of Jeroham, the son of Pashur, the son of Malchijah, and Maasiai the son of Adiel, the son of Jahzerah, the son of Meshullam, the son of Meshillemith, the son of Immer;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And their brethren, heads of the house of their fathers, a thousand and seven hundred and threescore; very able men for the work of the service of the house of God.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And of the Levites; Shemaiah the son of Hasshub, the son of Azrikam, the son of Hashabiah, of the sons of Merari;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Bakbakkar, Heresh, and Galal, and Mattaniah the son of Micah, the son of Zichri, the son of Asaph;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Obadiah the son of Shemaiah, the son of Galal, the son of Jeduthun, and Berechiah the son of Asa, the son of Elkanah, that dwelt in the villages of the Netophathites.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the porters &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt;, Shallum, and Akkub, and Talmon, and Ahiman, and their brethren: Shallum &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the chief;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Who hitherto &lt;i&gt;waited&lt;/i&gt; in the king's gate eastward: they &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; porters in the companies of the children of Levi.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Shallum the son of Kore, the son of Ebiasaph, the son of Korah, and his brethren, of the house of his father, the Korahites, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; over the work of the service, keepers of the gates of the tabernacle: and their fathers, &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; over the host of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; keepers of the entry.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Phinehas the son of Eleazar was the ruler over them in time past, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;i&gt;And&lt;/i&gt; Zechariah the son of Meshelemiah &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; porter of the door of the tabernacle of the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">All these &lt;i&gt;which were&lt;/i&gt; chosen to be porters in the gates &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; two hundred and twelve. These were reckoned by their genealogy in their villages, whom David and Samuel the seer did ordain in their set office.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">So they and their children &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; the oversight of the gates of the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;namely&lt;/i&gt;, the house of the tabernacle, by wards.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">In four quarters were the porters, toward the east, west, north, and south.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And their brethren, &lt;i&gt;which were&lt;/i&gt; in their villages, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; to come after seven days from time to time with them.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For these Levites, the four chief porters, were in &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; set office, and were over the chambers and treasuries of the house of God.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And they lodged round about the house of God, because the charge &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; upon them, and the opening thereof every morning &lt;i&gt;pertained&lt;/i&gt; to them.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And &lt;i&gt;certain&lt;/i&gt; of them had the charge of the ministering vessels, that they should bring them in and out by tale.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;i&gt;Some&lt;/i&gt; of them also &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; appointed to oversee the vessels, and all the instruments of the sanctuary, and the fine flour, and the wine, and the oil, and the frankincense, and the spices.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; of the sons of the priests made the ointment of the spices.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Mattithiah, &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; of the Levites, who &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the firstborn of Shallum the Korahite, had the set office over the things that were made in the pans.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; of their brethren, of the sons of the Kohathites, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; over the shewbread, to prepare &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; every sabbath.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the singers, chief of the fathers of the Levites, &lt;i&gt;who remaining&lt;/i&gt; in the chambers &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; free: for they were employed in &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; work day and night.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">These chief fathers of the Levites &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; chief throughout their generations; these dwelt at Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35" newPara="true">And in Gibeon dwelt the father of Gibeon, Jehiel, whose wife's name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Maachah:</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And his firstborn son Abdon, then Zur, and Kish, and Baal, and Ner, and Nadab,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And Gedor, and Ahio, and Zechariah, and Mikloth.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And Mikloth begat Shimeam. And they also dwelt with their brethren at Jerusalem, over against their brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And Ner begat Kish; and Kish begat Saul; and Saul begat Jonathan, and Malchi-shua, and Abinadab, and Esh-baal.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And the son of Jonathan &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Merib-baal: and Merib-baal begat Micah.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And the sons of Micah &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt;, Pithon, and Melech, and Tahrea, &lt;i&gt;and Ahaz&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And Ahaz begat Jarah; and Jarah begat Alemeth, and Azmaveth, and Zimri; and Zimri begat Moza;</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And Moza begat Binea; and Rephaiah his son, Eleasah his son, Azel his son.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And Azel had six sons, whose names &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; these, Azrikam, Bocheru, and Ishmael, and Sheariah, and Obadiah, and Hanan: these &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; the sons of Azel.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>