<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="29" nextChapter="1chronicles_16.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 16" prevChapter="1chronicles_14.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 14" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And &lt;i&gt;David&lt;/i&gt; made him houses in the city of David, and prepared a place for the ark of God, and pitched for it a tent.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then David said, None ought to carry the ark of God but the Levites: for them hath the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; chosen to carry the ark of God, and to minister unto him for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And David gathered all Israel together to Jerusalem, to bring up the ark of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto his place, which he had prepared for it.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And David assembled the children of Aaron, and the Levites:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Of the sons of Kohath; Uriel the chief, and his brethren an hundred and twenty:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Of the sons of Merari; Asaiah the chief, and his brethren two hundred and twenty:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Of the sons of Gershom; Joel the chief, and his brethren an hundred and thirty:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Of the sons of Elizaphan; Shemaiah the chief, and his brethren two hundred:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Of the sons of Hebron; Eliel the chief, and his brethren fourscore:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Of the sons of Uzziel; Amminadab the chief, and his brethren an hundred and twelve.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And David called for Zadok and Abiathar the priests, and for the Levites, for Uriel, Asaiah, and Joel, Shemaiah, and Eliel, and Amminadab,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And said unto them, Ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the chief of the fathers of the Levites: sanctify yourselves, &lt;i&gt;both&lt;/i&gt; ye and your brethren, that ye may bring up the ark of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel unto &lt;i&gt;the place that&lt;/i&gt; I have prepared for it.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For because ye &lt;i&gt;did it&lt;/i&gt; not at the first, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God made a breach upon us, for that we sought him not after the due order.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">So the priests and the Levites sanctified themselves to bring up the ark of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the children of the Levites bare the ark of God upon their shoulders with the staves thereon, as Moses commanded according to the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And David spake to the chief of the Levites to appoint their brethren &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; the singers with instruments of musick, psalteries and harps and cymbals, sounding, by lifting up the voice with joy.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">So the Levites appointed Heman the son of Joel; and of his brethren, Asaph the son of Berechiah; and of the sons of Merari their brethren, Ethan the son of Kushaiah;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And with them their brethren of the second &lt;i&gt;degree&lt;/i&gt;, Zechariah, Ben, and Jaaziel, and Shemiramoth, and Jehiel, and Unni, Eliab, and Benaiah, and Maaseiah, and Mattithiah, and Elipheleh, and Mikneiah, and Obed-edom, and Jeiel, the porters.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">So the singers, Heman, Asaph, and Ethan, &lt;i&gt;were appointed&lt;/i&gt; to sound with cymbals of brass;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Zechariah, and Aziel, and Shemiramoth, and Jehiel, and Unni, and Eliab, and Maaseiah, and Benaiah, with psalteries on Alamoth;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Mattithiah, and Elipheleh, and Mikneiah, and Obed-edom, and Jeiel, and Azaziah, with harps on the Sheminith to excel.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Chenaniah, chief of the Levites, &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; for song: he instructed about the song, because he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; skilful.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Berechiah and Elkanah &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; doorkeepers for the ark.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Shebaniah, and Jehoshaphat, and Nethaneel, and Amasai, and Zechariah, and Benaiah, and Eliezer, the priests, did blow with the trumpets before the ark of God: and Obed-edom and Jehiah &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; doorkeepers for the ark.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">So David, and the elders of Israel, and the captains over thousands, went to bring up the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; out of the house of Obed-edom with joy.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And it came to pass, when God helped the Levites that bare the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that they offered seven bullocks and seven rams.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And David &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; clothed with a robe of fine linen, and all the Levites that bare the ark, and the singers, and Chenaniah the master of the song with the singers: David also &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; upon him an ephod of linen.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Thus all Israel brought up the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with shouting, and with sound of the cornet, and with trumpets, and with cymbals, making a noise with psalteries and harps.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">And it came to pass, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came to the city of David, that Michal the daughter of Saul looking out at a window saw king David dancing and playing: and she despised him in her heart.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>