<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="17" nextChapter="1chronicles_19.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 19" prevChapter="1chronicles_17.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 17" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now after this it came to pass, that David smote the Philistines, and subdued them, and took Gath and her towns out of the hand of the Philistines.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he smote Moab; and the Moabites became David's servants, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; brought gifts.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And David smote Hadarezer king of Zobah unto Hamath, as he went to stablish his dominion by the river Euphrates.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And David took from him a thousand chariots, and seven thousand horsemen, and twenty thousand footmen: David also houghed all the chariot &lt;i&gt;horses&lt;/i&gt;, but reserved of them an hundred chariots.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And when the Syrians of Damascus came to help Hadarezer king of Zobah, David slew of the Syrians two and twenty thousand men.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Then David put &lt;i&gt;garrisons&lt;/i&gt; in Syriadamascus; and the Syrians became David's servants, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; brought gifts. Thus the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; preserved David whithersoever he went.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And David took the shields of gold that were on the servants of Hadarezer, and brought them to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Likewise from Tibhath, and from Chun, cities of Hadarezer, brought David very much brass, wherewith Solomon made the brasen sea, and the pillars, and the vessels of brass.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Now when Tou king of Hamath heard how David had smitten all the host of Hadarezer king of Zobah;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He sent Hadoram his son to king David, to enquire of his welfare, and to congratulate him, because he had fought against Hadarezer, and smitten him; (for Hadarezer had war with Tou;) and &lt;i&gt;with him&lt;/i&gt; all manner of vessels of gold and silver and brass.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Them also king David dedicated unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, with the silver and the gold that he brought from all &lt;i&gt;these&lt;/i&gt; nations; from Edom, and from Moab, and from the children of Ammon, and from the Philistines, and from Amalek.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Moreover Abishai the son of Zeruiah slew of the Edomites in the valley of salt eighteen thousand.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And he put garrisons in Edom; and all the Edomites became David's servants. Thus the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; preserved David whithersoever he went.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">So David reigned over all Israel, and executed judgment and justice among all his people.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Joab the son of Zeruiah &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; over the host; and Jehoshaphat the son of Ahilud, recorder.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Zadok the son of Ahitub, and Abimelech the son of Abiathar, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; the priests; and Shavsha was scribe;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Benaiah the son of Jehoiada &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; over the Cherethites and the Pelethites; and the sons of David &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; chief about the king.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>