<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="29" verseCount="30" nextChapter="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 1" prevChapter="1chronicles_28.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 28" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Furthermore David the king said unto all the congregation, Solomon my son, whom alone God hath chosen, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is yet&lt;/span&gt; young and tender, and the work &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; great: for the palace &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not for man, but for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Now I have prepared with all my might for the house of my God the gold for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things to be made&lt;/span&gt; of gold, and the silver for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; of silver, and the brass for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; of brass, the iron for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; of iron, and wood for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; of wood; onyx stones, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;stones&lt;/span&gt; to be set, glistering stones, and of divers colours, and all manner of precious stones, and marble stones in abundance.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Moreover, because I have set my affection to the house of my God, I have of mine own proper good, of gold and silver, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; I have given to the house of my God, over and above all that I have prepared for the holy house,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Even&lt;/span&gt; three thousand talents of gold, of the gold of Ophir, and seven thousand talents of refined silver, to overlay the walls of the houses &lt;span class="extra"&gt;withal&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The gold for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; of gold, and the silver for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; of silver, and for all manner of work &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be made&lt;/span&gt; by the hands of artificers. And who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; is willing to consecrate his service this day unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Then the chief of the fathers and princes of the tribes of Israel, and the captains of thousands and of hundreds, with the rulers of the king's work, offered willingly,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And gave for the service of the house of God of gold five thousand talents and ten thousand drams, and of silver ten thousand talents, and of brass eighteen thousand talents, and one hundred thousand talents of iron.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And they with whom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;precious&lt;/span&gt; stones were found gave &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; to the treasure of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, by the hand of Jehiel the Gershonite.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then the people rejoiced, for that they offered willingly, because with perfect heart they offered willingly to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and David the king also rejoiced with great joy.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Wherefore David blessed the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; before all the congregation: and David said, Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; thou, &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel our father, for ever and ever.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thine, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the greatness, and the power, and the glory, and the victory, and the majesty: for all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; in the heaven and in the earth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is thine&lt;/span&gt;; thine &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the kingdom, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and thou art exalted as head above all.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Both riches and honour &lt;span class="extra"&gt;come&lt;/span&gt; of thee, and thou reignest over all; and in thine hand &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; power and might; and in thine hand &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; to make great, and to give strength unto all.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Now therefore, our God, we thank thee, and praise thy glorious name.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; I, and what &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my people, that we should be able to offer so willingly after this sort? for all things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;come&lt;/span&gt; of thee, and of thine own have we given thee.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For we &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; strangers before thee, and sojourners, as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; all our fathers: our days on the earth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; as a shadow, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none abiding.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, all this store that we have prepared to build thee an house for thine holy name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;cometh&lt;/span&gt; of thine hand, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; all thine own.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">I know also, my God, that thou triest the heart, and hast pleasure in uprightness. As for me, in the uprightness of mine heart I have willingly offered all these things: and now have I seen with joy thy people, which are present here, to offer willingly unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Abraham, Isaac, and of Israel, our fathers, keep this for ever in the imagination of the thoughts of the heart of thy people, and prepare their heart unto thee:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And give unto Solomon my son a perfect heart, to keep thy commandments, thy testimonies, and thy statutes, and to do all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;these things&lt;/span&gt;, and to build the palace, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the which I have made provision.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And David said to all the congregation, Now bless the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God. And all the congregation blessed the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of their fathers, and bowed down their heads, and worshipped the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the king.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they sacrificed sacrifices unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and offered burnt offerings unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, on the morrow after that day, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; a thousand bullocks, a thousand rams, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; a thousand lambs, with their drink offerings, and sacrifices in abundance for all Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And did eat and drink before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; on that day with great gladness. And they made Solomon the son of David king the second time, and anointed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; the chief governor, and Zadok &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; priest.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Then Solomon sat on the throne of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; as king instead of David his father, and prospered; and all Israel obeyed him.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And all the princes, and the mighty men, and all the sons likewise of king David, submitted themselves unto Solomon the king.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; magnified Solomon exceedingly in the sight of all Israel, and bestowed upon him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;such&lt;/span&gt; royal majesty as had not been on any king before him in Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">Thus David the son of Jesse reigned over all Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And the time that he reigned over Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; forty years; seven years reigned he in Hebron, and thirty and three &lt;span class="extra"&gt;years&lt;/span&gt; reigned he in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he died in a good old age, full of days, riches, and honour: and Solomon his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Now the acts of David the king, first and last, behold, they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; written in the book of Samuel the seer, and in the book of Nathan the prophet, and in the book of Gad the seer,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">With all his reign and his might, and the times that went over him, and over Israel, and over all the kingdoms of the countries.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>