<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="81" nextChapter="1chronicles_7.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 7" prevChapter="1chronicles_5.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 5" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The sons of Levi; Gershon, Kohath, and Merari.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the sons of Kohath; Amram, Izhar, and Hebron, and Uzziel.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the children of Amram; Aaron, and Moses, and Miriam. The sons also of Aaron; Nadab, and Abihu, Eleazar, and Ithamar.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Eleazar begat Phinehas, Phinehas begat Abishua,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Abishua begat Bukki, and Bukki begat Uzzi,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Uzzi begat Zerahiah, and Zerahiah begat Meraioth,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Meraioth begat Amariah, and Amariah begat Ahitub,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Ahitub begat Zadok, and Zadok begat Ahimaaz,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Ahimaaz begat Azariah, and Azariah begat Johanan,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Johanan begat Azariah, (he &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; that executed the priest's office in the temple that Solomon built in Jerusalem:)</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Azariah begat Amariah, and Amariah begat Ahitub,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Ahitub begat Zadok, and Zadok begat Shallum,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Shallum begat Hilkiah, and Hilkiah begat Azariah,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Azariah begat Seraiah, and Seraiah begat Jehozadak,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Jehozadak went &lt;i&gt;into captivity&lt;/i&gt;, when the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; carried away Judah and Jerusalem by the hand of Nebuchadnezzar.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">The sons of Levi; Gershom, Kohath, and Merari.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And these &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; the names of the sons of Gershom; Libni, and Shimei.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the sons of Kohath &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt;, Amram, and Izhar, and Hebron, and Uzziel.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The sons of Merari; Mahli, and Mushi. And these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the families of the Levites according to their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Of Gershom; Libni his son, Jahath his son, Zimmah his son,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Joah his son, Iddo his son, Zerah his son, Jeaterai his son.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The sons of Kohath; Amminadab his son, Korah his son, Assir his son,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Elkanah his son, and Ebiasaph his son, and Assir his son,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Tahath his son, Uriel his son, Uzziah his son, and Shaul his son.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the sons of Elkanah; Amasai, and Ahimoth.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;i&gt;As for&lt;/i&gt; Elkanah: the sons of Elkanah; Zophai his son, and Nahath his son,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Eliab his son, Jeroham his son, Elkanah his son.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the sons of Samuel; the firstborn Vashni, and Abiah.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The sons of Merari; Mahli, Libni his son, Shimei his son, Uzza his son,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Shimea his son, Haggiah his son, Asaiah his son.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And these &lt;i&gt;are they&lt;/i&gt; whom David set over the service of song in the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, after that the ark had rest.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And they ministered before the dwelling place of the tabernacle of the congregation with singing, until Solomon had built the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in Jerusalem: and &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; they waited on their office according to their order.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; they that waited with their children. Of the sons of the Kohathites: Heman a singer, the son of Joel, the son of Shemuel,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">The son of Elkanah, the son of Jeroham, the son of Eliel, the son of Toah,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">The son of Zuph, the son of Elkanah, the son of Mahath, the son of Amasai,</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">The son of Elkanah, the son of Joel, the son of Azariah, the son of Zephaniah,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">The son of Tahath, the son of Assir, the son of Ebiasaph, the son of Korah,</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">The son of Izhar, the son of Kohath, the son of Levi, the son of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And his brother Asaph, who stood on his right hand, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; Asaph the son of Berachiah, the son of Shimea,</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">The son of Michael, the son of Baaseiah, the son of Malchiah,</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">The son of Ethni, the son of Zerah, the son of Adaiah,</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">The son of Ethan, the son of Zimmah, the son of Shimei,</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">The son of Jahath, the son of Gershom, the son of Levi.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And their brethren the sons of Merari &lt;i&gt;stood&lt;/i&gt; on the left hand: Ethan the son of Kishi, the son of Abdi, the son of Malluch,</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">The son of Hashabiah, the son of Amaziah, the son of Hilkiah,</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">The son of Amzi, the son of Bani, the son of Shamer,</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">The son of Mahli, the son of Mushi, the son of Merari, the son of Levi.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">Their brethren also the Levites &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; appointed unto all manner of service of the tabernacle of the house of God.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49" newPara="true">But Aaron and his sons offered upon the altar of the burnt offering, and on the altar of incense, &lt;i&gt;and were appointed&lt;/i&gt; for all the work of the &lt;i&gt;place&lt;/i&gt; most holy, and to make an atonement for Israel, according to all that Moses the servant of God had commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">And these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the sons of Aaron; Eleazar his son, Phinehas his son, Abishua his son,</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">Bukki his son, Uzzi his son, Zerahiah his son,</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">Meraioth his son, Amariah his son, Ahitub his son,</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">Zadok his son, Ahimaaz his son.</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54" newPara="true">Now these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; their dwelling places throughout their castles in their coasts, of the sons of Aaron, of the families of the Kohathites: for theirs was the lot.</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">And they gave them Hebron in the land of Judah, and the suburbs thereof round about it.</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">But the fields of the city, and the villages thereof, they gave to Caleb the son of Jephunneh.</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">And to the sons of Aaron they gave the cities of Judah, &lt;i&gt;namely&lt;/i&gt;, Hebron, &lt;i&gt;the city&lt;/i&gt; of refuge, and Libnah with her suburbs, and Jattir, and Eshtemoa, with their suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">And Hilen with her suburbs, Debir with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">And Ashan with her suburbs, and Beth-shemesh with her suburbs:</verse>
      <verse number="60" id="v60">And out of the tribe of Benjamin; Geba with her suburbs, and Alemeth with her suburbs, and Anathoth with her suburbs. All their cities throughout their families &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thirteen cities.</verse>
      <verse number="61" id="v61">And unto the sons of Kohath, &lt;i&gt;which were&lt;/i&gt; left of the family of that tribe, &lt;i&gt;were cities given&lt;/i&gt; out of the half tribe, &lt;i&gt;namely, out of&lt;/i&gt; the half &lt;i&gt;tribe&lt;/i&gt; of Manasseh, by lot, ten cities.</verse>
      <verse number="62" id="v62">And to the sons of Gershom throughout their families out of the tribe of Issachar, and out of the tribe of Asher, and out of the tribe of Naphtali, and out of the tribe of Manasseh in Bashan, thirteen cities.</verse>
      <verse number="63" id="v63">Unto the sons of Merari &lt;i&gt;were given&lt;/i&gt; by lot, throughout their families, out of the tribe of Reuben, and out of the tribe of Gad, and out of the tribe of Zebulun, twelve cities.</verse>
      <verse number="64" id="v64">And the children of Israel gave to the Levites &lt;i&gt;these&lt;/i&gt; cities with their suburbs.</verse>
      <verse number="65" id="v65">And they gave by lot out of the tribe of the children of Judah, and out of the tribe of the children of Simeon, and out of the tribe of the children of Benjamin, these cities, which are called by &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; names.</verse>
      <verse number="66" id="v66">And &lt;i&gt;the residue&lt;/i&gt; of the families of the sons of Kohath had cities of their coasts out of the tribe of Ephraim.</verse>
      <verse number="67" id="v67">And they gave unto them, &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; the cities of refuge, Shechem in mount Ephraim with her suburbs; &lt;i&gt;they gave&lt;/i&gt; also Gezer with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="68" id="v68">And Jokmeam with her suburbs, and Beth-horon with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="69" id="v69">And Aijalon with her suburbs, and Gath-rimmon with her suburbs:</verse>
      <verse number="70" id="v70">And out of the half tribe of Manasseh; Aner with her suburbs, and Bileam with her suburbs, for the family of the remnant of the sons of Kohath.</verse>
      <verse number="71" id="v71">Unto the sons of Gershom &lt;i&gt;were given&lt;/i&gt; out of the family of the half tribe of Manasseh, Golan in Bashan with her suburbs, and Ashtaroth with her suburbs:</verse>
      <verse number="72" id="v72">And out of the tribe of Issachar; Kedesh with her suburbs, Daberath with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="73" id="v73">And Ramoth with her suburbs, and Anem with her suburbs:</verse>
      <verse number="74" id="v74">And out of the tribe of Asher; Mashal with her suburbs, and Abdon with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="75" id="v75">And Hukok with her suburbs, and Rehob with her suburbs:</verse>
      <verse number="76" id="v76">And out of the tribe of Naphtali; Kedesh in Galilee with her suburbs, and Hammon with her suburbs, and Kirjathaim with her suburbs.</verse>
      <verse number="77" id="v77">Unto the rest of the children of Merari &lt;i&gt;were given&lt;/i&gt; out of the tribe of Zebulun, Rimmon with her suburbs, Tabor with her suburbs:</verse>
      <verse number="78" id="v78">And on the other side Jordan by Jericho, on the east side of Jordan, &lt;i&gt;were given them&lt;/i&gt; out of the tribe of Reuben, Bezer in the wilderness with her suburbs, and Jahzah with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="79" id="v79">Kedemoth also with her suburbs, and Mephaath with her suburbs:</verse>
      <verse number="80" id="v80">And out of the tribe of Gad; Ramoth in Gilead with her suburbs, and Mahanaim with her suburbs,</verse>
      <verse number="81" id="v81">And Heshbon with her suburbs, and Jazer with her suburbs.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>