<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="19" nextChapter="1chronicles_23.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 23" prevChapter="1chronicles_21.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 21" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then David said, This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God, and this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the altar of the burnt offering for Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And David commanded to gather together the strangers that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; in the land of Israel; and he set masons to hew wrought stones to build the house of God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And David prepared iron in abundance for the nails for the doors of the gates, and for the joinings; and brass in abundance without weight;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Also cedar trees in abundance: for the Zidonians and they of Tyre brought much cedar wood to David.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And David said, Solomon my son &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; young and tender, and the house &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; to be builded for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;must be&lt;/i&gt; exceeding magnifical, of fame and of glory throughout all countries: I will &lt;i&gt;therefore&lt;/i&gt; now make preparation for it. So David prepared abundantly before his death.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Then he called for Solomon his son, and charged him to build an house for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And David said to Solomon, My son, as for me, it was in my mind to build an house unto the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came to me, saying, Thou hast shed blood abundantly, and hast made great wars: thou shalt not build an house unto my name, because thou hast shed much blood upon the earth in my sight.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Behold, a son shall be born to thee, who shall be a man of rest; and I will give him rest from all his enemies round about: for his name shall be Solomon, and I will give peace and quietness unto Israel in his days.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He shall build an house for my name; and he shall be my son, and I &lt;i&gt;will be&lt;/i&gt; his father; and I will establish the throne of his kingdom over Israel for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Now, my son, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be with thee; and prosper thou, and build the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, as he hath said of thee.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Only the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; give thee wisdom and understanding, and give thee charge concerning Israel, that thou mayest keep the law of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then shalt thou prosper, if thou takest heed to fulfil the statutes and judgments which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; charged Moses with concerning Israel: be strong, and of good courage; dread not, nor be dismayed.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Now, behold, in my trouble I have prepared for the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; an hundred thousand talents of gold, and a thousand thousand talents of silver; and of brass and iron without weight; for it is in abundance: timber also and stone have I prepared; and thou mayest add thereto.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Moreover &lt;i&gt;there are&lt;/i&gt; workmen with thee in abundance, hewers and workers of stone and timber, and all manner of cunning men for every manner of work.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Of the gold, the silver, and the brass, and the iron, &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no number. Arise &lt;i&gt;therefore&lt;/i&gt;, and be doing, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">David also commanded all the princes of Israel to help Solomon his son, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;i&gt;Is&lt;/i&gt; not the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God with you? and hath he &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; given you rest on every side? for he hath given the inhabitants of the land into mine hand; and the land is subdued before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and before his people.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Now set your heart and your soul to seek the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God; arise therefore, and build ye the sanctuary of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God, to bring the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the holy vessels of God, into the house that is to be built to the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>