<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="25" verseCount="31" nextChapter="1chronicles_26.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 26" prevChapter="1chronicles_24.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 24" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover David and the captains of the host separated to the service of the sons of Asaph, and of Heman, and of Jeduthun, who should prophesy with harps, with psalteries, and with cymbals: and the number of the workmen according to their service was:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Of the sons of Asaph; Zaccur, and Joseph, and Nethaniah, and Asarelah, the sons of Asaph under the hands of Asaph, which prophesied according to the order of the king.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Of Jeduthun: the sons of Jeduthun; Gedaliah, and Zeri, and Jeshaiah, Hashabiah, and Mattithiah, six, under the hands of their father Jeduthun, who prophesied with a harp, to give thanks and to praise the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Of Heman: the sons of Heman; Bukkiah, Mattaniah, Uzziel, Shebuel, and Jerimoth, Hananiah, Hanani, Eliathah, Giddalti, and Romamti-ezer, Joshbekashah, Mallothi, Hothir, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Mahazioth:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">All these &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; the sons of Heman the king's seer in the words of God, to lift up the horn. And God gave to Heman fourteen sons and three daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">All these &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; under the hands of their father for song &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, with cymbals, psalteries, and harps, for the service of the house of God, according to the king's order to Asaph, Jeduthun, and Heman.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">So the number of them, with their brethren that were instructed in the songs of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; all that were cunning, was two hundred fourscore and eight.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And they cast lots, ward against &lt;i&gt;ward&lt;/i&gt;, as well the small as the great, the teacher as the scholar.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Now the first lot came forth for Asaph to Joseph: the second to Gedaliah, who with his brethren and sons &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The third to Zaccur, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The fourth to Izri, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The fifth to Nethaniah, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The sixth to Bukkiah, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The seventh to Jesharelah, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The eighth to Jeshaiah, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The ninth to Mattaniah, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The tenth to Shimei, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The eleventh to Azareel, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The twelfth to Hashabiah, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The thirteenth to Shubael, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The fourteenth to Mattithiah, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The fifteenth to Jeremoth, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The sixteenth to Hananiah, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The seventeenth to Joshbekashah, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The eighteenth to Hanani, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The nineteenth to Mallothi, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The twentieth to Eliathah, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The one and twentieth to Hothir, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The two and twentieth to Giddalti, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The three and twentieth to Mahazioth, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The four and twentieth to Romamti-ezer, &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, his sons, and his brethren, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twelve.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>