<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="54" nextChapter="1chronicles_2.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 2" prevChapter="2kings_25.html" prevTitle="2 Kings 25" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Adam, Sheth, Enosh,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Kenan, Mahalaleel, Jered,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Henoch, Methuselah, Lamech,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Noah, Shem, Ham, and Japheth.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">The sons of Japheth; Gomer, and Magog, and Madai, and Javan, and Tubal, and Meshech, and Tiras.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the sons of Gomer; Ashchenaz, and Riphath, and Togarmah.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the sons of Javan; Elishah, and Tarshish, Kittim, and Dodanim.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">The sons of Ham; Cush, and Mizraim, Put, and Canaan.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the sons of Cush; Seba, and Havilah, and Sabta, and Raamah, and Sabtecha. And the sons of Raamah; Sheba, and Dedan.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Cush begat Nimrod: he began to be mighty upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Mizraim begat Ludim, and Anamim, and Lehabim, and Naphtuhim,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Pathrusim, and Casluhim, (of whom came the Philistines,) and Caphthorim.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Canaan begat Zidon his firstborn, and Heth,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The Jebusite also, and the Amorite, and the Girgashite,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the Hivite, and the Arkite, and the Sinite,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the Arvadite, and the Zemarite, and the Hamathite.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">The sons of Shem; Elam, and Asshur, and Arphaxad, and Lud, and Aram, and Uz, and Hul, and Gether, and Meshech.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Arphaxad begat Shelah, and Shelah begat Eber.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And unto Eber were born two sons: the name of the one &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Peleg; because in his days the earth was divided: and his brother's name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Joktan.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Joktan begat Almodad, and Sheleph, and Hazarmaveth, and Jerah,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Hadoram also, and Uzal, and Diklah,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Ebal, and Abimael, and Sheba,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Ophir, and Havilah, and Jobab. All these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Joktan.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">Shem, Arphaxad, Shelah,</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Eber, Peleg, Reu,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Serug, Nahor, Terah,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Abram; the same &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Abraham.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The sons of Abraham; Isaac, and Ishmael.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; their generations: The firstborn of Ishmael, Nebaioth; then Kedar, and Adbeel, and Mibsam,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Mishma, and Dumah, Massa, Hadad, and Tema,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Jetur, Naphish, and Kedemah. These are the sons of Ishmael.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">Now the sons of Keturah, Abraham's concubine: she bare Zimran, and Jokshan, and Medan, and Midian, and Ishbak, and Shuah. And the sons of Jokshan; Sheba, and Dedan.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And the sons of Midian; Ephah, and Epher, and Henoch, and Abida, and Eldaah. All these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Keturah.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And Abraham begat Isaac. The sons of Isaac; Esau and Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35" newPara="true">The sons of Esau; Eliphaz, Reuel, and Jeush, and Jaalam, and Korah.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">The sons of Eliphaz; Teman, and Omar, Zephi, and Gatam, Kenaz, and Timna, and Amalek.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">The sons of Reuel; Nahath, Zerah, Shammah, and Mizzah.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And the sons of Seir; Lotan, and Shobal, and Zibeon, and Anah, and Dishon, and Ezer, and Dishan.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And the sons of Lotan; Hori, and Homam: and Timna &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Lotan's sister.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">The sons of Shobal; Alian, and Manahath, and Ebal, Shephi, and Onam. And the sons of Zibeon; Aiah, and Anah.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">The sons of Anah; Dishon. And the sons of Dishon; Amram, and Eshban, and Ithran, and Cheran.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">The sons of Ezer; Bilhan, and Zavan, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Jakan. The sons of Dishan; Uz, and Aran.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43" newPara="true">Now these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the kings that reigned in the land of Edom before &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; king reigned over the children of Israel; Bela the son of Beor: and the name of his city &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Dinhabah.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And when Bela was dead, Jobab the son of Zerah of Bozrah reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And when Jobab was dead, Husham of the land of the Temanites reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And when Husham was dead, Hadad the son of Bedad, which smote Midian in the field of Moab, reigned in his stead: and the name of his city &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Avith.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">And when Hadad was dead, Samlah of Masrekah reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">And when Samlah was dead, Shaul of Rehoboth by the river reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And when Shaul was dead, Baal-hanan the son of Achbor reigned in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">And when Baal-hanan was dead, Hadad reigned in his stead: and the name of his city &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Pai; and his wife's name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Mehetabel, the daughter of Matred, the daughter of Mezahab.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51" newPara="true">Hadad died also. And the dukes of Edom were; duke Timnah, duke Aliah, duke Jetheth,</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">Duke Aholibamah, duke Elah, duke Pinon,</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">Duke Kenaz, duke Teman, duke Mibzar,</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">Duke Magdiel, duke Iram. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the dukes of Edom.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>