<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="26" verseCount="32" nextChapter="1chronicles_27.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 27" prevChapter="1chronicles_25.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 25" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Concerning the divisions of the porters: Of the Korhites &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Meshelemiah the son of Kore, of the sons of Asaph.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the sons of Meshelemiah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Zechariah the firstborn, Jediael the second, Zebadiah the third, Jathniel the fourth,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Elam the fifth, Jehohanan the sixth, Elioenai the seventh.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Moreover the sons of Obed-edom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Shemaiah the firstborn, Jehozabad the second, Joah the third, and Sacar the fourth, and Nethaneel the fifth,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Ammiel the sixth, Issachar the seventh, Peulthai the eighth: for God blessed him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Also unto Shemaiah his son were sons born, that ruled throughout the house of their father: for they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; mighty men of valour.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The sons of Shemaiah; Othni, and Rephael, and Obed, Elzabad, whose brethren &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; strong men, Elihu, and Semachiah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">All these of the sons of Obed-edom: they and their sons and their brethren, able men for strength for the service, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; threescore and two of Obed-edom.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Meshelemiah had sons and brethren, strong men, eighteen.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Also Hosah, of the children of Merari, had sons; Simri the chief, (for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;though&lt;/span&gt; he was not the firstborn, yet his father made him the chief;)</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Hilkiah the second, Tebaliah the third, Zechariah the fourth: all the sons and brethren of Hosah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; thirteen.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Among these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the divisions of the porters, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; among the chief men, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;having&lt;/span&gt; wards one against another, to minister in the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And they cast lots, as well the small as the great, according to the house of their fathers, for every gate.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the lot eastward fell to Shelemiah. Then for Zechariah his son, a wise counsellor, they cast lots; and his lot came out northward.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">To Obed-edom southward; and to his sons the house of Asuppim.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">To Shuppim and Hosah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the lot came forth&lt;/span&gt; westward, with the gate Shallecheth, by the causeway of the going up, ward against ward.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Eastward &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; six Levites, northward four a day, southward four a day, and toward Asuppim two &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; two.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">At Parbar westward, four at the causeway, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; two at Parbar.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the divisions of the porters among the sons of Kore, and among the sons of Merari.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And of the Levites, Ahijah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; over the treasures of the house of God, and over the treasures of the dedicated things.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;As concerning&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Laadan; the sons of the Gershonite Laadan, chief fathers, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of Laadan the Gershonite, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; Jehieli.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The sons of Jehieli; Zetham, and Joel his brother, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which were&lt;/span&gt; over the treasures of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Of the Amramites, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the Izharites, the Hebronites, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the Uzzielites:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Shebuel the son of Gershom, the son of Moses, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; ruler of the treasures.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And his brethren by Eliezer; Rehabiah his son, and Jeshaiah his son, and Joram his son, and Zichri his son, and Shelomith his son.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Which Shelomith and his brethren &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; over all the treasures of the dedicated things, which David the king, and the chief fathers, the captains over thousands and hundreds, and the captains of the host, had dedicated.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Out of the spoils won in battles did they dedicate to maintain the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And all that Samuel the seer, and Saul the son of Kish, and Abner the son of Ner, and Joab the son of Zeruiah, had dedicated; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; whosoever had dedicated &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any thing, it was&lt;/span&gt; under the hand of Shelomith, and of his brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">Of the Izharites, Chenaniah and his sons &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; for the outward business over Israel, for officers and judges.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; of the Hebronites, Hashabiah and his brethren, men of valour, a thousand and seven hundred, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; officers among them of Israel on this side Jordan westward in all the business of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and in the service of the king.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Among the Hebronites &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Jerijah the chief, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; among the Hebronites, according to the generations of his fathers. In the fortieth year of the reign of David they were sought for, and there were found among them mighty men of valour at Jazer of Gilead.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And his brethren, men of valour, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; two thousand and seven hundred chief fathers, whom king David made rulers over the Reubenites, the Gadites, and the half tribe of Manasseh, for every matter pertaining to God, and affairs of the king.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>