<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="14" nextChapter="1chronicles_14.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 14" prevChapter="1chronicles_12.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 12" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And David consulted with the captains of thousands and hundreds, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; with every leader.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And David said unto all the congregation of Israel, If &lt;i&gt;it seem&lt;/i&gt; good unto you, and &lt;i&gt;that it be&lt;/i&gt; of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, let us send abroad unto our brethren every where, &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; left in all the land of Israel, and with them &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; to the priests and Levites &lt;i&gt;which are&lt;/i&gt; in their cities &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; suburbs, that they may gather themselves unto us:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And let us bring again the ark of our God to us: for we enquired not at it in the days of Saul.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And all the congregation said that they would do so: for the thing was right in the eyes of all the people.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">So David gathered all Israel together, from Shihor of Egypt even unto the entering of Hemath, to bring the ark of God from Kirjath-jearim.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And David went up, and all Israel, to Baalah, &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt;, to Kirjath-jearim, which &lt;i&gt;belonged&lt;/i&gt; to Judah, to bring up thence the ark of God the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that dwelleth &lt;i&gt;between&lt;/i&gt; the cherubims, whose name is called &lt;i&gt;on it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they carried the ark of God in a new cart out of the house of Abinadab: and Uzza and Ahio drave the cart.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And David and all Israel played before God with all &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; might, and with singing, and with harps, and with psalteries, and with timbrels, and with cymbals, and with trumpets.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And when they came unto the threshingfloor of Chidon, Uzza put forth his hand to hold the ark; for the oxen stumbled.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the anger of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was kindled against Uzza, and he smote him, because he put his hand to the ark: and there he died before God.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And David was displeased, because the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had made a breach upon Uzza: wherefore that place is called Perez-uzza to this day.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And David was afraid of God that day, saying, How shall I bring the ark of God &lt;i&gt;home&lt;/i&gt; to me?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">So David brought not the ark &lt;i&gt;home&lt;/i&gt; to himself to the city of David, but carried it aside into the house of Obed-edom the Gittite.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the ark of God remained with the family of Obed-edom in his house three months. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; blessed the house of Obed-edom, and all that he had.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>