<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="40" nextChapter="1chronicles_9.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 9" prevChapter="1chronicles_7.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 7" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now Benjamin begat Bela his firstborn, Ashbel the second, and Aharah the third,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Nohah the fourth, and Rapha the fifth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the sons of Bela were, Addar, and Gera, and Abihud,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Abishua, and Naaman, and Ahoah,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Gera, and Shephuphan, and Huram.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Ehud: these are the heads of the fathers of the inhabitants of Geba, and they removed them to Manahath:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Naaman, and Ahiah, and Gera, he removed them, and begat Uzza, and Ahihud.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Shaharaim begat &lt;span class='extra'&gt;children&lt;/span&gt; in the country of Moab, after he had sent them away; Hushim and Baara &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; his wives.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he begat of Hodesh his wife, Jobab, and Zibia, and Mesha, and Malcham,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Jeuz, and Shachia, and Mirma. These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; his sons, heads of the fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And of Hushim he begat Abitub, and Elpaal.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The sons of Elpaal; Eber, and Misham, and Shamed, who built Ono, and Lod, with the towns thereof:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Beriah also, and Shema, who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; heads of the fathers of the inhabitants of Aijalon, who drove away the inhabitants of Gath:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Ahio, Shashak, and Jeremoth,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Zebadiah, and Arad, and Ader,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Michael, and Ispah, and Joha, the sons of Beriah;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Zebadiah, and Meshullam, and Hezeki, and Heber,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Ishmerai also, and Jezliah, and Jobab, the sons of Elpaal;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Jakim, and Zichri, and Zabdi,</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Elienai, and Zilthai, and Eliel,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Adaiah, and Beraiah, and Shimrath, the sons of Shimhi;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Ishpan, and Heber, and Eliel,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Abdon, and Zichri, and Hanan,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Hananiah, and Elam, and Antothijah,</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Iphedeiah, and Penuel, the sons of Shashak;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And Shamsherai, and Shehariah, and Athaliah,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Jaresiah, and Eliah, and Zichri, the sons of Jeroham.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; heads of the fathers, by their generations, chief &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;. These dwelt in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And at Gibeon dwelt the father of Gibeon; whose wife's name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Maachah:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And his firstborn son Abdon, and Zur, and Kish, and Baal, and Nadab,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Gedor, and Ahio, and Zacher.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And Mikloth begat Shimeah. And these also dwelt with their brethren in Jerusalem, over against them.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">And Ner begat Kish, and Kish begat Saul, and Saul begat Jonathan, and Malchi-shua, and Abinadab, and Esh-baal.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And the son of Jonathan &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Merib-baal; and Merib-baal begat Micah.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And the sons of Micah &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Pithon, and Melech, and Tarea, and Ahaz.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And Ahaz begat Jehoadah; and Jehoadah begat Alemeth, and Azmaveth, and Zimri; and Zimri begat Moza,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And Moza begat Binea: Rapha &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; his son, Eleasah his son, Azel his son:</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And Azel had six sons, whose names &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; these, Azrikam, Bocheru, and Ishmael, and Sheariah, and Obadiah, and Hanan. All these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Azel.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And the sons of Eshek his brother &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Ulam his firstborn, Jehush the second, and Eliphelet the third.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And the sons of Ulam were mighty men of valour, archers, and had many sons, and sons' sons, an hundred and fifty. All these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; of the sons of Benjamin.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>