<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="24" nextChapter="1chronicles_4.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 4" prevChapter="1chronicles_2.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 2" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now these were the sons of David, which were born unto him in Hebron; the firstborn Amnon, of Ahinoam the Jezreelitess; the second Daniel, of Abigail the Carmelitess:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The third, Absalom the son of Maachah the daughter of Talmai king of Geshur: the fourth, Adonijah the son of Haggith:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The fifth, Shephatiah of Abital: the sixth, Ithream by Eglah his wife.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;These&lt;/span&gt; six were born unto him in Hebron; and there he reigned seven years and six months: and in Jerusalem he reigned thirty and three years.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And these were born unto him in Jerusalem; Shimea, and Shobab, and Nathan, and Solomon, four, of Bath-shua the daughter of Ammiel:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Ibhar also, and Elishama, and Eliphelet,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Nogah, and Nepheg, and Japhia,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Elishama, and Eliada, and Eliphelet, nine.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;These were&lt;/span&gt; all the sons of David, beside the sons of the concubines, and Tamar their sister.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And Solomon's son &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Rehoboam, Abia his son, Asa his son, Jehoshaphat his son,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Joram his son, Ahaziah his son, Joash his son,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Amaziah his son, Azariah his son, Jotham his son,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Ahaz his son, Hezekiah his son, Manasseh his son,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Amon his son, Josiah his son.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the sons of Josiah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, the firstborn Johanan, the second Jehoiakim, the third Zedekiah, the fourth Shallum.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the sons of Jehoiakim: Jeconiah his son, Zedekiah his son.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And the sons of Jeconiah; Assir, Salathiel his son,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Malchiram also, and Pedaiah, and Shenazar, Jecamiah, Hoshama, and Nedabiah.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the sons of Pedaiah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Zerubbabel, and Shimei: and the sons of Zerubbabel; Meshullam, and Hananiah, and Shelomith their sister:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Hashubah, and Ohel, and Berechiah, and Hasadiah, Jushab-hesed, five.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the sons of Hananiah; Pelatiah, and Jesaiah: the sons of Rephaiah, the sons of Arnan, the sons of Obadiah, the sons of Shechaniah.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the sons of Shechaniah; Shemaiah: and the sons of Shemaiah; Hattush, and Igeal, and Bariah, and Neariah, and Shaphat, six.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the sons of Neariah; Elioenai, and Hezekiah, and Azrikam, three.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the sons of Elioenai &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Hodaiah, and Eliashib, and Pelaiah, and Akkub, and Johanan, and Dalaiah, and Anani, seven.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>