<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="47" nextChapter="1chronicles_12.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 12" prevChapter="1chronicles_10.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 10" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then all Israel gathered themselves to David unto Hebron, saying, Behold, we &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; thy bone and thy flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And moreover in time past, even when Saul was king, thou &lt;i&gt;wast&lt;/i&gt; he that leddest out and broughtest in Israel: and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God said unto thee, Thou shalt feed my people Israel, and thou shalt be ruler over my people Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Therefore came all the elders of Israel to the king to Hebron; and David made a covenant with them in Hebron before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and they anointed David king over Israel, according to the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; by Samuel.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And David and all Israel went to Jerusalem, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Jebus; where the Jebusites &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt;, the inhabitants of the land.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the inhabitants of Jebus said to David, Thou shalt not come hither. Nevertheless David took the castle of Zion, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the city of David.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And David said, Whosoever smiteth the Jebusites first shall be chief and captain. So Joab the son of Zeruiah went first up, and was chief.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And David dwelt in the castle; therefore they called it the city of David.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he built the city round about, even from Millo round about: and Joab repaired the rest of the city.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">So David waxed greater and greater: for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">These also &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the chief of the mighty men whom David had, who strengthened themselves with him in his kingdom, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; with all Israel, to make him king, according to the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; concerning Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the number of the mighty men whom David had; Jashobeam, an Hachmonite, the chief of the captains: he lifted up his spear against three hundred slain &lt;i&gt;by him&lt;/i&gt; at one time.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And after him &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Eleazar the son of Dodo, the Ahohite, who &lt;i&gt;was one&lt;/i&gt; of the three mighties.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He was with David at Pas-dammim, and there the Philistines were gathered together to battle, where was a parcel of ground full of barley; and the people fled from before the Philistines.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they set themselves in the midst of &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; parcel, and delivered it, and slew the Philistines; and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; saved &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; by a great deliverance.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Now three of the thirty captains went down to the rock to David, into the cave of Adullam; and the host of the Philistines encamped in the valley of Rephaim.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And David &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; then in the hold, and the Philistines' garrison &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; then at Beth-lehem.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And David longed, and said, Oh that one would give me drink of the water of the well of Beth-lehem, that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; at the gate!</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the three brake through the host of the Philistines, and drew water out of the well of Beth-lehem, that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; by the gate, and took &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and brought &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to David: but David would not drink &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; it, but poured it out to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And said, My God forbid it me, that I should do this thing: shall I drink the blood of these men that have put their lives in jeopardy? for with &lt;i&gt;the jeopardy of&lt;/i&gt; their lives they brought it. Therefore he would not drink it. These things did these three mightiest.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And Abishai the brother of Joab, he was chief of the three: for lifting up his spear against three hundred, he slew &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;, and had a name among the three.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Of the three, he was more honourable than the two; for he was their captain: howbeit he attained not to the &lt;i&gt;first&lt;/i&gt; three.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, the son of a valiant man of Kabzeel, who had done many acts; he slew two lionlike men of Moab: also he went down and slew a lion in a pit in a snowy day.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he slew an Egyptian, a man of &lt;i&gt;great&lt;/i&gt; stature, five cubits high; and in the Egyptian's hand &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a spear like a weaver's beam; and he went down to him with a staff, and plucked the spear out of the Egyptian's hand, and slew him with his own spear.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">These &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; did Benaiah the son of Jehoiada, and had the name among the three mighties.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Behold, he was honourable among the thirty, but attained not to the &lt;i&gt;first&lt;/i&gt; three: and David set him over his guard.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">Also the valiant men of the armies &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt;, Asahel the brother of Joab, Elhanan the son of Dodo of Beth-lehem,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Shammoth the Harorite, Helez the Pelonite,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Ira the son of Ikkesh the Tekoite, Abi-ezer the Antothite,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Sibbecai the Hushathite, Ilai the Ahohite,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Maharai the Netophathite, Heled the son of Baanah the Netophathite,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Ithai the son of Ribai of Gibeah, &lt;i&gt;that pertained&lt;/i&gt; to the children of Benjamin, Benaiah the Pirathonite,</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Hurai of the brooks of Gaash, Abiel the Arbathite,</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Azmaveth the Baharumite, Eliahba the Shaalbonite,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">The sons of Hashem the Gizonite, Jonathan the son of Shage the Hararite,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Ahiam the son of Sacar the Hararite, Eliphal the son of Ur,</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Hepher the Mecherathite, Ahijah the Pelonite,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Hezro the Carmelite, Naarai the son of Ezbai,</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">Joel the brother of Nathan, Mibhar the son of Haggeri,</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Zelek the Ammonite, Naharai the Berothite, the armourbearer of Joab the son of Zeruiah,</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Ira the Ithrite, Gareb the Ithrite,</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Uriah the Hittite, Zabad the son of Ahlai,</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Adina the son of Shiza the Reubenite, a captain of the Reubenites, and thirty with him,</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Hanan the son of Maachah, and Joshaphat the Mithnite,</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">Uzzia the Ashterathite, Shama and Jehiel the sons of Hothan the Aroerite,</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">Jediael the son of Shimri, and Joha his brother, the Tizite,</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">Eliel the Mahavite, and Jeribai, and Joshaviah, the sons of Elnaam, and Ithmah the Moabite,</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">Eliel, and Obed, and Jasiel the Mesobaite.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>