<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="43" nextChapter="1chronicles_5.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 5" prevChapter="1chronicles_3.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 3" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The sons of Judah; Pharez, Hezron, and Carmi, and Hur, and Shobal.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Reaiah the son of Shobal begat Jahath; and Jahath begat Ahumai, and Lahad. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the families of the Zorathites.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were of&lt;/span&gt; the father of Etam; Jezreel, and Ishma, and Idbash: and the name of their sister &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Hazelelponi:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Penuel the father of Gedor, and Ezer the father of Hushah. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Hur, the firstborn of Ephratah, the father of Beth-lehem.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And Ashur the father of Tekoa had two wives, Helah and Naarah.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Naarah bare him Ahuzam, and Hepher, and Temeni, and Haahashtari. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Naarah.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the sons of Helah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Zereth, and Jezoar, and Ethnan.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Coz begat Anub, and Zobebah, and the families of Aharhel the son of Harum.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And Jabez was more honourable than his brethren: and his mother called his name Jabez, saying, Because I bare him with sorrow.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Jabez called on the God of Israel, saying, Oh that thou wouldest bless me indeed, and enlarge my coast, and that thine hand might be with me, and that thou wouldest keep &lt;span class="extra"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; from evil, that it may not grieve me! And God granted him that which he requested.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And Chelub the brother of Shuah begat Mehir, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the father of Eshton.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Eshton begat Beth-rapha, and Paseah, and Tehinnah the father of Ir-nahash. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the men of Rechah.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the sons of Kenaz; Othniel, and Seraiah: and the sons of Othniel; Hathath.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Meonothai begat Ophrah: and Seraiah begat Joab, the father of the valley of Charashim; for they were craftsmen.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the sons of Caleb the son of Jephunneh; Iru, Elah, and Naam: and the sons of Elah, even Kenaz.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the sons of Jehaleleel; Ziph, and Ziphah, Tiria, and Asareel.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the sons of Ezra &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Jether, and Mered, and Epher, and Jalon: and she bare Miriam, and Shammai, and Ishbah the father of Eshtemoa.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And his wife Jehudijah bare Jered the father of Gedor, and Heber the father of Socho, and Jekuthiel the father of Zanoah. And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Bithiah the daughter of Pharaoh, which Mered took.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the sons of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; wife Hodiah the sister of Naham, the father of Keilah the Garmite, and Eshtemoa the Maachathite.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the sons of Shimon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Amnon, and Rinnah, Ben-hanan, and Tilon. And the sons of Ishi &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Zoheth, and Ben-zoheth.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">The sons of Shelah the son of Judah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Er the father of Lecah, and Laadah the father of Mareshah, and the families of the house of them that wrought fine linen, of the house of Ashbea,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Jokim, and the men of Chozeba, and Joash, and Saraph, who had the dominion in Moab, and Jashubi-lehem. And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;these are&lt;/span&gt; ancient things.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the potters, and those that dwelt among plants and hedges: there they dwelt with the king for his work.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">The sons of Simeon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Nemuel, and Jamin, Jarib, Zerah, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Shaul:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Shallum his son, Mibsam his son, Mishma his son.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And the sons of Mishma; Hamuel his son, Zacchur his son, Shimei his son.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Shimei had sixteen sons and six daughters; but his brethren had not many children, neither did all their family multiply, like to the children of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they dwelt at Beer-sheba, and Moladah, and Hazar-shual,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And at Bilhah, and at Ezem, and at Tolad,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And at Bethuel, and at Hormah, and at Ziklag,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And at Beth-marcaboth, and Hazar-susim, and at Beth-birei, and at Shaaraim. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; their cities unto the reign of David.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And their villages &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;, Etam, and Ain, Rimmon, and Tochen, and Ashan, five cities:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And all their villages that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; round about the same cities, unto Baal. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; their habitations, and their genealogy.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And Meshobab, and Jamlech, and Joshah the son of Amaziah,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And Joel, and Jehu the son of Josibiah, the son of Seraiah, the son of Asiel,</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And Elioenai, and Jaakobah, and Jeshohaiah, and Asaiah, and Adiel, and Jesimiel, and Benaiah,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And Ziza the son of Shiphi, the son of Allon, the son of Jedaiah, the son of Shimri, the son of Shemaiah;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">These mentioned by &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; names &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; princes in their families: and the house of their fathers increased greatly.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39" newPara="true">And they went to the entrance of Gedor, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto the east side of the valley, to seek pasture for their flocks.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And they found fat pasture and good, and the land &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; wide, and quiet, and peaceable; for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;they&lt;/span&gt; of Ham had dwelt there of old.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And these written by name came in the days of Hezekiah king of Judah, and smote their tents, and the habitations that were found there, and destroyed them utterly unto this day, and dwelt in their rooms: because &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; pasture there for their flocks.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of them, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of the sons of Simeon, five hundred men, went to mount Seir, having for their captains Pelatiah, and Neariah, and Rephaiah, and Uzziel, the sons of Ishi.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And they smote the rest of the Amalekites that were escaped, and dwelt there unto this day.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>