<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="24" verseCount="31" nextChapter="1chronicles_25.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 25" prevChapter="1chronicles_23.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 23" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now &lt;span class="extra"&gt;these are&lt;/span&gt; the divisions of the sons of Aaron. The sons of Aaron; Nadab, and Abihu, Eleazar, and Ithamar.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">But Nadab and Abihu died before their father, and had no children: therefore Eleazar and Ithamar executed the priest's office.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And David distributed them, both Zadok of the sons of Eleazar, and Ahimelech of the sons of Ithamar, according to their offices in their service.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And there were more chief men found of the sons of Eleazar than of the sons of Ithamar; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thus&lt;/span&gt; were they divided. Among the sons of Eleazar &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there were&lt;/span&gt; sixteen chief men of the house of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; fathers, and eight among the sons of Ithamar according to the house of their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thus were they divided by lot, one sort with another; for the governors of the sanctuary, and governors &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of the house&lt;/span&gt; of God, were of the sons of Eleazar, and of the sons of Ithamar.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Shemaiah the son of Nethaneel the scribe, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; of the Levites, wrote them before the king, and the princes, and Zadok the priest, and Ahimelech the son of Abiathar, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;before&lt;/span&gt; the chief of the fathers of the priests and Levites: one principal household being taken for Eleazar, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; taken for Ithamar.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Now the first lot came forth to Jehoiarib, the second to Jedaiah,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The third to Harim, the fourth to Seorim,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The fifth to Malchijah, the sixth to Mijamin,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The seventh to Hakkoz, the eighth to Abijah,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The ninth to Jeshua, the tenth to Shecaniah,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The eleventh to Eliashib, the twelfth to Jakim,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The thirteenth to Huppah, the fourteenth to Jeshebeab,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The fifteenth to Bilgah, the sixteenth to Immer,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The seventeenth to Hezir, the eighteenth to Aphses,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The nineteenth to Pethahiah, the twentieth to Jehezekel,</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The one and twentieth to Jachin, the two and twentieth to Gamul,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The three and twentieth to Delaiah, the four and twentieth to Maaziah.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the orderings of them in their service to come into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, according to their manner, under Aaron their father, as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel had commanded him.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And the rest of the sons of Levi &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were these&lt;/span&gt;: Of the sons of Amram; Shubael: of the sons of Shubael; Jehdeiah.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Concerning Rehabiah: of the sons of Rehabiah, the first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Isshiah.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Of the Izharites; Shelomoth: of the sons of Shelomoth; Jahath.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the sons &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of Hebron&lt;/span&gt;; Jeriah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the first&lt;/span&gt;, Amariah the second, Jahaziel the third, Jekameam the fourth.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Of&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Uzziel; Michah: of the sons of Michah; Shamir.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The brother of Michah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Isshiah: of the sons of Isshiah; Zechariah.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The sons of Merari &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; Mahli and Mushi: the sons of Jaaziah; Beno.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">The sons of Merari by Jaaziah; Beno, and Shoham, and Zaccur, and Ibri.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Of Mahli &lt;span class="extra"&gt;came&lt;/span&gt; Eleazar, who had no sons.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Concerning Kish: the son of Kish &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Jerahmeel.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The sons also of Mushi; Mahli, and Eder, and Jerimoth. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the sons of the Levites after the house of their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">These likewise cast lots over against their brethren the sons of Aaron in the presence of David the king, and Zadok, and Ahimelech, and the chief of the fathers of the priests and Levites, even the principal fathers over against their younger brethren.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>