<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="13" name="1 Chronicles" bookPage="1chronicles.html" title="1 Chronicles" chapterCount="29" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="2chronicles_1.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles" prevBook="2kings_1.html" prevTitle="2 Kings">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="43" nextChapter="1chronicles_17.html" nextTitle="1 Chronicles 17" prevChapter="1chronicles_15.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles 15" chapterPage="1chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">So they brought the ark of God, and set it in the midst of the tent that David had pitched for it: and they offered burnt sacrifices and peace offerings before God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And when David had made an end of offering the burnt offerings and the peace offerings, he blessed the people in the name of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he dealt to every one of Israel, both man and woman, to every one a loaf of bread, and a good piece of flesh, and a flagon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of wine&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And he appointed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;certain&lt;/span&gt; of the Levites to minister before the ark of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and to record, and to thank and praise the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Asaph the chief, and next to him Zechariah, Jeiel, and Shemiramoth, and Jehiel, and Mattithiah, and Eliab, and Benaiah, and Obed-edom: and Jeiel with psalteries and with harps; but Asaph made a sound with cymbals;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Benaiah also and Jahaziel the priests with trumpets continually before the ark of the covenant of God.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Then on that day David delivered first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;this psalm&lt;/span&gt; to thank the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; into the hand of Asaph and his brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Give thanks unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, call upon his name, make known his deeds among the people.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Sing unto him, sing psalms unto him, talk ye of all his wondrous works.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Glory ye in his holy name: let the heart of them rejoice that seek the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Seek the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; and his strength, seek his face continually.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Remember his marvellous works that he hath done, his wonders, and the judgments of his mouth;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">O ye seed of Israel his servant, ye children of Jacob, his chosen ones.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">He &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God; his judgments &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in all the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Be ye mindful always of his covenant; the word &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; he commanded to a thousand generations;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Even of the covenant&lt;/span&gt; which he made with Abraham, and of his oath unto Isaac;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And hath confirmed the same to Jacob for a law, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; an everlasting covenant,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Saying, Unto thee will I give the land of Canaan, the lot of your inheritance;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">When ye were but few, even a few, and strangers in it.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; they went from nation to nation, and from &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; kingdom to another people;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">He suffered no man to do them wrong: yea, he reproved kings for their sakes,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Saying&lt;/span&gt;, Touch not mine anointed, and do my prophets no harm.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Sing unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, all the earth; shew forth from day to day his salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Declare his glory among the heathen; his marvellous works among all nations.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For great &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and greatly to be praised: he also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; to be feared above all gods.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For all the gods of the people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; idols: but the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made the heavens.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Glory and honour &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in his presence; strength and gladness &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in his place.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Give unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, ye kindreds of the people, give unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; glory and strength.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Give unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; the glory &lt;span class="extra"&gt;due&lt;/span&gt; unto his name: bring an offering, and come before him: worship the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the beauty of holiness.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Fear before him, all the earth: the world also shall be stable, that it be not moved.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Let the heavens be glad, and let the earth rejoice: and let &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; say among the nations, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; reigneth.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Let the sea roar, and the fulness thereof: let the fields rejoice, and all that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; therein.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Then shall the trees of the wood sing out at the presence of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, because he cometh to judge the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">O give thanks unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; good; for his mercy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;endureth&lt;/span&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And say ye, Save us, O God of our salvation, and gather us together, and deliver us from the heathen, that we may give thanks to thy holy name, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; glory in thy praise.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel for ever and ever. And all the people said, Amen, and praised the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37" newPara="true">So he left there before the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; Asaph and his brethren, to minister before the ark continually, as every day's work required:</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And Obed-edom with their brethren, threescore and eight; Obed-edom also the son of Jeduthun and Hosah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; porters:</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And Zadok the priest, and his brethren the priests, before the tabernacle of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the high place that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; at Gibeon,</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">To offer burnt offerings unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; upon the altar of the burnt offering continually morning and evening, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to do&lt;/span&gt; according to all that is written in the law of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which he commanded Israel;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And with them Heman and Jeduthun, and the rest that were chosen, who were expressed by name, to give thanks to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, because his mercy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;endureth&lt;/span&gt; for ever;</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And with them Heman and Jeduthun with trumpets and cymbals for those that should make a sound, and with musical instruments of God. And the sons of Jeduthun &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; porters.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And all the people departed every man to his house: and David returned to bless his house.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>