<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="25" verseCount="28" nextChapter="2chronicles_26.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 26" prevChapter="2chronicles_24.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 24" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Amaziah &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; twenty and five years old &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; he began to reign, and he reigned twenty and nine years in Jerusalem. And his mother's name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Jehoaddan of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he did &lt;i&gt;that which was&lt;/i&gt; right in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, but not with a perfect heart.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Now it came to pass, when the kingdom was established to him, that he slew his servants that had killed the king his father.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But he slew not their children, but &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; as &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; written in the law in the book of Moses, where the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded, saying, The fathers shall not die for the children, neither shall the children die for the fathers, but every man shall die for his own sin.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Moreover Amaziah gathered Judah together, and made them captains over thousands, and captains over hundreds, according to the houses of &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; fathers, throughout all Judah and Benjamin: and he numbered them from twenty years old and above, and found them three hundred thousand choice &lt;i&gt;men, able&lt;/i&gt; to go forth to war, that could handle spear and shield.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He hired also an hundred thousand mighty men of valour out of Israel for an hundred talents of silver.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But there came a man of God to him, saying, O king, let not the army of Israel go with thee; for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not with Israel, &lt;i&gt;to wit, with&lt;/i&gt; all the children of Ephraim.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But if thou wilt go, do &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, be strong for the battle: God shall make thee fall before the enemy: for God hath power to help, and to cast down.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Amaziah said to the man of God, But what shall we do for the hundred talents which I have given to the army of Israel? And the man of God answered, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; is able to give thee much more than this.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then Amaziah separated them, &lt;i&gt;to wit&lt;/i&gt;, the army that was come to him out of Ephraim, to go home again: wherefore their anger was greatly kindled against Judah, and they returned home in great anger.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And Amaziah strengthened himself, and led forth his people, and went to the valley of salt, and smote of the children of Seir ten thousand.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; ten thousand &lt;i&gt;left&lt;/i&gt; alive did the children of Judah carry away captive, and brought them unto the top of the rock, and cast them down from the top of the rock, that they all were broken in pieces.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">But the soldiers of the army which Amaziah sent back, that they should not go with him to battle, fell upon the cities of Judah, from Samaria even unto Beth-horon, and smote three thousand of them, and took much spoil.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Now it came to pass, after that Amaziah was come from the slaughter of the Edomites, that he brought the gods of the children of Seir, and set them up &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; his gods, and bowed down himself before them, and burned incense unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Wherefore the anger of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was kindled against Amaziah, and he sent unto him a prophet, which said unto him, Why hast thou sought after the gods of the people, which could not deliver their own people out of thine hand?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And it came to pass, as he talked with him, that &lt;i&gt;the king&lt;/i&gt; said unto him, Art thou made of the king's counsel? forbear; why shouldest thou be smitten? Then the prophet forbare, and said, I know that God hath determined to destroy thee, because thou hast done this, and hast not hearkened unto my counsel.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Then Amaziah king of Judah took advice, and sent to Joash, the son of Jehoahaz, the son of Jehu, king of Israel, saying, Come, let us see one another in the face.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Joash king of Israel sent to Amaziah king of Judah, saying, The thistle that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in Lebanon sent to the cedar that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in Lebanon, saying, Give thy daughter to my son to wife: and there passed by a wild beast that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in Lebanon, and trode down the thistle.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thou sayest, Lo, thou hast smitten the Edomites; and thine heart lifteth thee up to boast: abide now at home; why shouldest thou meddle to &lt;i&gt;thine&lt;/i&gt; hurt, that thou shouldest fall, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; thou, and Judah with thee?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But Amaziah would not hear; for it &lt;i&gt;came&lt;/i&gt; of God, that he might deliver them into the hand &lt;i&gt;of their enemies&lt;/i&gt;, because they sought after the gods of Edom.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">So Joash the king of Israel went up; and they saw one another in the face, &lt;i&gt;both&lt;/i&gt; he and Amaziah king of Judah, at Beth-shemesh, which &lt;i&gt;belongeth&lt;/i&gt; to Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Judah was put to the worse before Israel, and they fled every man to his tent.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Joash the king of Israel took Amaziah king of Judah, the son of Joash, the son of Jehoahaz, at Beth-shemesh, and brought him to Jerusalem, and brake down the wall of Jerusalem from the gate of Ephraim to the corner gate, four hundred cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And &lt;i&gt;he took&lt;/i&gt; all the gold and the silver, and all the vessels that were found in the house of God with Obed-edom, and the treasures of the king's house, the hostages also, and returned to Samaria.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And Amaziah the son of Joash king of Judah lived after the death of Joash son of Jehoahaz king of Israel fifteen years.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Now the rest of the acts of Amaziah, first and last, behold, &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; they not written in the book of the kings of Judah and Israel?</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">Now after the time that Amaziah did turn away from following the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; they made a conspiracy against him in Jerusalem; and he fled to Lachish: but they sent to Lachish after him, and slew him there.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they brought him upon horses, and buried him with his fathers in the city of Judah.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>