<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="14" nextChapter="2chronicles_6.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 6" prevChapter="2chronicles_4.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 4" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Thus all the work that Solomon made for the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was finished: and Solomon brought in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;all&lt;/span&gt; the things that David his father had dedicated; and the silver, and the gold, and all the instruments, put he among the treasures of the house of God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">Then Solomon assembled the elders of Israel, and all the heads of the tribes, the chief of the fathers of the children of Israel, unto Jerusalem, to bring up the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; out of the city of David, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Zion.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Wherefore all the men of Israel assembled themselves unto the king in the feast which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the seventh month.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And all the elders of Israel came; and the Levites took up the ark.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they brought up the ark, and the tabernacle of the congregation, and all the holy vessels that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the tabernacle, these did the priests &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the Levites bring up.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Also king Solomon, and all the congregation of Israel that were assembled unto him before the ark, sacrificed sheep and oxen, which could not be told nor numbered for multitude.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the priests brought in the ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto his place, to the oracle of the house, into the most holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place, even&lt;/span&gt; under the wings of the cherubims:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For the cherubims spread forth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; wings over the place of the ark, and the cherubims covered the ark and the staves thereof above.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And they drew out the staves &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of the ark&lt;/span&gt;, that the ends of the staves were seen from the ark before the oracle; but they were not seen without. And there it is unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;There was&lt;/span&gt; nothing in the ark save the two tables which Moses put &lt;span class='extra'&gt;therein&lt;/span&gt; at Horeb, when the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; made &lt;span class='extra'&gt;a covenant&lt;/span&gt; with the children of Israel, when they came out of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when the priests were come out of the holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;: (for all the priests &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that were&lt;/span&gt; present were sanctified, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; did not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; wait by course:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Also the Levites &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which were&lt;/span&gt; the singers, all of them of Asaph, of Heman, of Jeduthun, with their sons and their brethren, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; arrayed in white linen, having cymbals and psalteries and harps, stood at the east end of the altar, and with them an hundred and twenty priests sounding with trumpets:)</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">It came even to pass, as the trumpeters and singers &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; as one, to make one sound to be heard in praising and thanking the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and when they lifted up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; voice with the trumpets and cymbals and instruments of musick, and praised the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, For &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; good; for his mercy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;endureth&lt;/span&gt; for ever: that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; the house was filled with a cloud, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">So that the priests could not stand to minister by reason of the cloud: for the glory of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had filled the house of God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>