<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="30" verseCount="27" nextChapter="2chronicles_31.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 31" prevChapter="2chronicles_29.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 29" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Hezekiah sent to all Israel and Judah, and wrote letters also to Ephraim and Manasseh, that they should come to the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; at Jerusalem, to keep the passover unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For the king had taken counsel, and his princes, and all the congregation in Jerusalem, to keep the passover in the second month.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For they could not keep it at that time, because the priests had not sanctified themselves sufficiently, neither had the people gathered themselves together to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the thing pleased the king and all the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">So they established a decree to make proclamation throughout all Israel, from Beer-sheba even to Dan, that they should come to keep the passover unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel at Jerusalem: for they had not done &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; of a long &lt;span class='extra'&gt;time in such sort&lt;/span&gt; as it was written.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">So the posts went with the letters from the king and his princes throughout all Israel and Judah, and according to the commandment of the king, saying, Ye children of Israel, turn again unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel, and he will return to the remnant of you, that are escaped out of the hand of the kings of Assyria.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And be not ye like your fathers, and like your brethren, which trespassed against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of their fathers, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;who&lt;/span&gt; therefore gave them up to desolation, as ye see.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Now be ye not stiffnecked, as your fathers &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were, but&lt;/span&gt; yield yourselves unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and enter into his sanctuary, which he hath sanctified for ever: and serve the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, that the fierceness of his wrath may turn away from you.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For if ye turn again unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, your brethren and your children &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall find&lt;/span&gt; compassion before them that lead them captive, so that they shall come again into this land: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; gracious and merciful, and will not turn away &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; face from you, if ye return unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">So the posts passed from city to city through the country of Ephraim and Manasseh even unto Zebulun: but they laughed them to scorn, and mocked them.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Nevertheless divers of Asher and Manasseh and of Zebulun humbled themselves, and came to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Also in Judah the hand of God was to give them one heart to do the commandment of the king and of the princes, by the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And there assembled at Jerusalem much people to keep the feast of unleavened bread in the second month, a very great congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they arose and took away the altars that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Jerusalem, and all the altars for incense took they away, and cast &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; into the brook Kidron.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Then they killed the passover on the fourteenth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the second month: and the priests and the Levites were ashamed, and sanctified themselves, and brought in the burnt offerings into the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And they stood in their place after their manner, according to the law of Moses the man of God: the priests sprinkled the blood, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which they received&lt;/span&gt; of the hand of the Levites.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there were&lt;/span&gt; many in the congregation that were not sanctified: therefore the Levites had the charge of the killing of the passovers for every one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that was&lt;/span&gt; not clean, to sanctify &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For a multitude of the people, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; many of Ephraim, and Manasseh, Issachar, and Zebulun, had not cleansed themselves, yet did they eat the passover otherwise than it was written. But Hezekiah prayed for them, saying, The good &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; pardon every one</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;That&lt;/span&gt; prepareth his heart to seek God, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of his fathers, though &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he be&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;cleansed&lt;/span&gt; according to the purification of the sanctuary.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hearkened to Hezekiah, and healed the people.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the children of Israel that were present at Jerusalem kept the feast of unleavened bread seven days with great gladness: and the Levites and the priests praised the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; day by day, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;singing&lt;/span&gt; with loud instruments unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Hezekiah spake comfortably unto all the Levites that taught the good knowledge of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and they did eat throughout the feast seven days, offering peace offerings, and making confession to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the whole assembly took counsel to keep other seven days: and they kept &lt;span class='extra'&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; seven days with gladness.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For Hezekiah king of Judah did give to the congregation a thousand bullocks and seven thousand sheep; and the princes gave to the congregation a thousand bullocks and ten thousand sheep: and a great number of priests sanctified themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And all the congregation of Judah, with the priests and the Levites, and all the congregation that came out of Israel, and the strangers that came out of the land of Israel, and that dwelt in Judah, rejoiced.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">So there was great joy in Jerusalem: for since the time of Solomon the son of David king of Israel &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; not the like in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">Then the priests the Levites arose and blessed the people: and their voice was heard, and their prayer came &lt;span class='extra'&gt;up&lt;/span&gt; to his holy dwelling place, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto heaven.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>