<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="17" verseCount="19" nextChapter="2chronicles_18.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 18" prevChapter="2chronicles_16.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 16" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Jehoshaphat his son reigned in his stead, and strengthened himself against Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he placed forces in all the fenced cities of Judah, and set garrisons in the land of Judah, and in the cities of Ephraim, which Asa his father had taken.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was with Jehoshaphat, because he walked in the first ways of his father David, and sought not unto Baalim;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But sought to the &lt;i&gt;&lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt; God of his father, and walked in his commandments, and not after the doings of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Therefore the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; stablished the kingdom in his hand; and all Judah brought to Jehoshaphat presents; and he had riches and honour in abundance.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And his heart was lifted up in the ways of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: moreover he took away the high places and groves out of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Also in the third year of his reign he sent to his princes, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to Ben-hail, and to Obadiah, and to Zechariah, and to Nethaneel, and to Michaiah, to teach in the cities of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And with them &lt;i&gt;he sent&lt;/i&gt; Levites, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; Shemaiah, and Nethaniah, and Zebadiah, and Asahel, and Shemiramoth, and Jehonathan, and Adonijah, and Tobijah, and Tob-adonijah, Levites; and with them Elishama and Jehoram, priests.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And they taught in Judah, and &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; the book of the law of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with them, and went about throughout all the cities of Judah, and taught the people.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And the fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; fell upon all the kingdoms of the lands that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; round about Judah, so that they made no war against Jehoshaphat.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Also &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; of the Philistines brought Jehoshaphat presents, and tribute silver; and the Arabians brought him flocks, seven thousand and seven hundred rams, and seven thousand and seven hundred he goats.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And Jehoshaphat waxed great exceedingly; and he built in Judah castles, and cities of store.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he had much business in the cities of Judah: and the men of war, mighty men of valour, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the numbers of them according to the house of their fathers: Of Judah, the captains of thousands; Adnah the chief, and with him mighty men of valour three hundred thousand.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And next to him &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Jehohanan the captain, and with him two hundred and fourscore thousand.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And next him &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Amasiah the son of Zichri, who willingly offered himself unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and with him two hundred thousand mighty men of valour.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And of Benjamin; Eliada a mighty man of valour, and with him armed men with bow and shield two hundred thousand.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And next him &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Jehozabad, and with him an hundred and fourscore thousand ready prepared for the war.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">These waited on the king, beside &lt;i&gt;those&lt;/i&gt; whom the king put in the fenced cities throughout all Judah.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>