<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="22" nextChapter="2chronicles_5.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 5" prevChapter="2chronicles_3.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 3" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover he made an altar of brass, twenty cubits the length thereof, and twenty cubits the breadth thereof, and ten cubits the height thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">Also he made a molten sea of ten cubits from brim to brim, round in compass, and five cubits the height thereof; and a line of thirty cubits did compass it round about.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And under it &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the similitude of oxen, which did compass it round about: ten in a cubit, compassing the sea round about. Two rows of oxen &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; cast, when it was cast.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">It stood upon twelve oxen, three looking toward the north, and three looking toward the west, and three looking toward the south, and three looking toward the east: and the sea &lt;i&gt;was set&lt;/i&gt; above upon them, and all their hinder parts &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; inward.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the thickness of it &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; an handbreadth, and the brim of it like the work of the brim of a cup, with flowers of lilies; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; it received and held three thousand baths.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">He made also ten lavers, and put five on the right hand, and five on the left, to wash in them: such things as they offered for the burnt offering they washed in them; but the sea &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; for the priests to wash in.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he made ten candlesticks of gold according to their form, and set &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in the temple, five on the right hand, and five on the left.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He made also ten tables, and placed &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in the temple, five on the right side, and five on the left. And he made an hundred basons of gold.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Furthermore he made the court of the priests, and the great court, and doors for the court, and overlaid the doors of them with brass.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he set the sea on the right side of the east end, over against the south.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Huram made the pots, and the shovels, and the basons. And Huram finished the work that he was to make for king Solomon for the house of God;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;i&gt;To wit&lt;/i&gt;, the two pillars, and the pommels, and the chapiters &lt;i&gt;which were&lt;/i&gt; on the top of the two pillars, and the two wreaths to cover the two pommels of the chapiters which &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; on the top of the pillars;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And four hundred pomegranates on the two wreaths; two rows of pomegranates on each wreath, to cover the two pommels of the chapiters which &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; upon the pillars.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">He made also bases, and lavers made he upon the bases;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">One sea, and twelve oxen under it.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The pots also, and the shovels, and the fleshhooks, and all their instruments, did Huram his father make to king Solomon for the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of bright brass.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">In the plain of Jordan did the king cast them, in the clay ground between Succoth and Zeredathah.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thus Solomon made all these vessels in great abundance: for the weight of the brass could not be found out.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And Solomon made all the vessels that &lt;i&gt;were for&lt;/i&gt; the house of God, the golden altar also, and the tables whereon the shewbread &lt;i&gt;was set&lt;/i&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Moreover the candlesticks with their lamps, that they should burn after the manner before the oracle, of pure gold;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the flowers, and the lamps, and the tongs, &lt;i&gt;made he of&lt;/i&gt; gold, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; that perfect gold;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the snuffers, and the basons, and the spoons, and the censers, &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; pure gold: and the entry of the house, the inner doors thereof for the most holy &lt;i&gt;place&lt;/i&gt;, and the doors of the house of the temple, &lt;i&gt;were of&lt;/i&gt; gold.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>