<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="17" nextChapter="2chronicles_4.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 4" prevChapter="2chronicles_2.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 2" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then Solomon began to build the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; at Jerusalem in mount Moriah, where &lt;i&gt;the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt; appeared unto David his father, in the place that David had prepared in the threshingfloor of Ornan the Jebusite.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he began to build in the second &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the second month, in the fourth year of his reign.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Now these &lt;i&gt;are the things wherein&lt;/i&gt; Solomon was instructed for the building of the house of God. The length by cubits after the first measure &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; threescore cubits, and the breadth twenty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the porch that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in the front &lt;i&gt;of the house&lt;/i&gt;, the length &lt;i&gt;of it was&lt;/i&gt; according to the breadth of the house, twenty cubits, and the height &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; an hundred and twenty: and he overlaid it within with pure gold.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the greater house he cieled with fir tree, which he overlaid with fine gold, and set thereon palm trees and chains.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he garnished the house with precious stones for beauty: and the gold &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; gold of Parvaim.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He overlaid also the house, the beams, the posts, and the walls thereof, and the doors thereof, with gold; and graved cherubims on the walls.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he made the most holy house, the length whereof &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; according to the breadth of the house, twenty cubits, and the breadth thereof twenty cubits: and he overlaid it with fine gold, &lt;i&gt;amounting&lt;/i&gt; to six hundred talents.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the weight of the nails &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; fifty shekels of gold. And he overlaid the upper chambers with gold.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And in the most holy house he made two cherubims of image work, and overlaid them with gold.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And the wings of the cherubims &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; twenty cubits long: one wing &lt;i&gt;of the one cherub was&lt;/i&gt; five cubits, reaching to the wall of the house: and the other wing &lt;i&gt;was likewise&lt;/i&gt; five cubits, reaching to the wing of the other cherub.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; wing of the other cherub &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; five cubits, reaching to the wall of the house: and the other wing &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; five cubits &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt;, joining to the wing of the other cherub.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The wings of these cherubims spread themselves forth twenty cubits: and they stood on their feet, and their faces &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; inward.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And he made the vail &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; blue, and purple, and crimson, and fine linen, and wrought cherubims thereon.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Also he made before the house two pillars of thirty and five cubits high, and the chapiter that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; on the top of each of them &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; five cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he made chains, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; in the oracle, and put &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; on the heads of the pillars; and made an hundred pomegranates, and put &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; on the chains.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he reared up the pillars before the temple, one on the right hand, and the other on the left; and called the name of that on the right hand Jachin, and the name of that on the left Boaz.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>