<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="27" verseCount="9" nextChapter="2chronicles_28.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 28" prevChapter="2chronicles_26.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 26" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Jotham &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; twenty and five years old when he began to reign, and he reigned sixteen years in Jerusalem. His mother's name also &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Jerushah, the daughter of Zadok.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he did &lt;i&gt;that which was&lt;/i&gt; right in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, according to all that his father Uzziah did: howbeit he entered not into the temple of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. And the people did yet corruptly.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">He built the high gate of the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and on the wall of Ophel he built much.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Moreover he built cities in the mountains of Judah, and in the forests he built castles and towers.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">He fought also with the king of the Ammonites, and prevailed against them. And the children of Ammon gave him the same year an hundred talents of silver, and ten thousand measures of wheat, and ten thousand of barley. So much did the children of Ammon pay unto him, both the second year, and the third.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">So Jotham became mighty, because he prepared his ways before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Now the rest of the acts of Jotham, and all his wars, and his ways, lo, they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; written in the book of the kings of Israel and Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He was five and twenty years old when he began to reign, and reigned sixteen years in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And Jotham slept with his fathers, and they buried him in the city of David: and Ahaz his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>