<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="22" nextChapter="2chronicles_14.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 14" prevChapter="2chronicles_12.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 12" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now in the eighteenth year of king Jeroboam began Abijah to reign over Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">He reigned three years in Jerusalem. His mother's name also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Michaiah the daughter of Uriel of Gibeah. And there was war between Abijah and Jeroboam.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Abijah set the battle in array with an army of valiant men of war, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; four hundred thousand chosen men: Jeroboam also set the battle in array against him with eight hundred thousand chosen men, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; mighty men of valour.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And Abijah stood up upon mount Zemaraim, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in mount Ephraim, and said, Hear me, thou Jeroboam, and all Israel;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Ought ye not to know that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel gave the kingdom over Israel to David for ever, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to him and to his sons by a covenant of salt?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Yet Jeroboam the son of Nebat, the servant of Solomon the son of David, is risen up, and hath rebelled against his lord.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And there are gathered unto him vain men, the children of Belial, and have strengthened themselves against Rehoboam the son of Solomon, when Rehoboam was young and tenderhearted, and could not withstand them.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And now ye think to withstand the kingdom of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the hand of the sons of David; and ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; a great multitude, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there are&lt;/span&gt; with you golden calves, which Jeroboam made you for gods.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Have ye not cast out the priests of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the sons of Aaron, and the Levites, and have made you priests after the manner of the nations of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; lands? so that whosoever cometh to consecrate himself with a young bullock and seven rams, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the same&lt;/span&gt; may be a priest of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them that are&lt;/span&gt; no gods.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But as for us, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our God, and we have not forsaken him; and the priests, which minister unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Aaron, and the Levites &lt;span class='extra'&gt;wait&lt;/span&gt; upon &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; business:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And they burn unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; every morning and every evening burnt sacrifices and sweet incense: the shewbread also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;set they in order&lt;/span&gt; upon the pure table; and the candlestick of gold with the lamps thereof, to burn every evening: for we keep the charge of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God; but ye have forsaken him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And, behold, God himself &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with us for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; captain, and his priests with sounding trumpets to cry alarm against you. O children of Israel, fight ye not against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of your fathers; for ye shall not prosper.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">But Jeroboam caused an ambushment to come about behind them: so they were before Judah, and the ambushment &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; behind them.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And when Judah looked back, behold, the battle &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; before and behind: and they cried unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the priests sounded with the trumpets.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Then the men of Judah gave a shout: and as the men of Judah shouted, it came to pass, that God smote Jeroboam and all Israel before Abijah and Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the children of Israel fled before Judah: and God delivered them into their hand.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Abijah and his people slew them with a great slaughter: so there fell down slain of Israel five hundred thousand chosen men.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thus the children of Israel were brought under at that time, and the children of Judah prevailed, because they relied upon the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Abijah pursued after Jeroboam, and took cities from him, Beth-el with the towns thereof, and Jeshanah with the towns thereof, and Ephrain with the towns thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Neither did Jeroboam recover strength again in the days of Abijah: and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; struck him, and he died.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">But Abijah waxed mighty, and married fourteen wives, and begat twenty and two sons, and sixteen daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the rest of the acts of Abijah, and his ways, and his sayings, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; written in the story of the prophet Iddo.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>