<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="19" nextChapter="2chronicles_16.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 16" prevChapter="2chronicles_14.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 14" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the Spirit of God came upon Azariah the son of Oded:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he went out to meet Asa, and said unto him, Hear ye me, Asa, and all Judah and Benjamin; The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with you, while ye be with him; and if ye seek him, he will be found of you; but if ye forsake him, he will forsake you.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Now for a long season Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hath been&lt;/span&gt; without the true God, and without a teaching priest, and without law.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But when they in their trouble did turn unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, and sought him, he was found of them.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And in those times &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; no peace to him that went out, nor to him that came in, but great vexations &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; upon all the inhabitants of the countries.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And nation was destroyed of nation, and city of city: for God did vex them with all adversity.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Be ye strong therefore, and let not your hands be weak: for your work shall be rewarded.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And when Asa heard these words, and the prophecy of Oded the prophet, he took courage, and put away the abominable idols out of all the land of Judah and Benjamin, and out of the cities which he had taken from mount Ephraim, and renewed the altar of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; before the porch of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he gathered all Judah and Benjamin, and the strangers with them out of Ephraim and Manasseh, and out of Simeon: for they fell to him out of Israel in abundance, when they saw that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">So they gathered themselves together at Jerusalem in the third month, in the fifteenth year of the reign of Asa.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And they offered unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; the same time, of the spoil &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; they had brought, seven hundred oxen and seven thousand sheep.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And they entered into a covenant to seek the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of their fathers with all their heart and with all their soul;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">That whosoever would not seek the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel should be put to death, whether small or great, whether man or woman.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they sware unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with a loud voice, and with shouting, and with trumpets, and with cornets.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And all Judah rejoiced at the oath: for they had sworn with all their heart, and sought him with their whole desire; and he was found of them: and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; gave them rest round about.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;concerning&lt;/span&gt; Maachah the mother of Asa the king, he removed her from &lt;span class="extra"&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; queen, because she had made an idol in a grove: and Asa cut down her idol, and stamped &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and burnt &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; at the brook Kidron.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But the high places were not taken away out of Israel: nevertheless the heart of Asa was perfect all his days.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And he brought into the house of God the things that his father had dedicated, and that he himself had dedicated, silver, and gold, and vessels.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And there was no &lt;span class="extra"&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; war unto the five and thirtieth year of the reign of Asa.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>