<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="19" nextChapter="2chronicles_11.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 11" prevChapter="2chronicles_9.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 9" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Rehoboam went to Shechem: for to Shechem were all Israel come to make him king.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And it came to pass, when Jeroboam the son of Nebat, who &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in Egypt, whither he had fled from the presence of Solomon the king, heard &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, that Jeroboam returned out of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they sent and called him. So Jeroboam and all Israel came and spake to Rehoboam, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thy father made our yoke grievous: now therefore ease thou somewhat the grievous servitude of thy father, and his heavy yoke that he put upon us, and we will serve thee.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he said unto them, Come again unto me after three days. And the people departed.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And king Rehoboam took counsel with the old men that had stood before Solomon his father while he yet lived, saying, What counsel give ye &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; to return answer to this people?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they spake unto him, saying, If thou be kind to this people, and please them, and speak good words to them, they will be thy servants for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But he forsook the counsel which the old men gave him, and took counsel with the young men that were brought up with him, that stood before him.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he said unto them, What advice give ye that we may return answer to this people, which have spoken to me, saying, Ease somewhat the yoke that thy father did put upon us?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the young men that were brought up with him spake unto him, saying, Thus shalt thou answer the people that spake unto thee, saying, Thy father made our yoke heavy, but make thou &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; somewhat lighter for us; thus shalt thou say unto them, My little &lt;i&gt;finger&lt;/i&gt; shall be thicker than my father's loins.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For whereas my father put a heavy yoke upon you, I will put more to your yoke: my father chastised you with whips, but I &lt;i&gt;will chastise you&lt;/i&gt; with scorpions.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">So Jeroboam and all the people came to Rehoboam on the third day, as the king bade, saying, Come again to me on the third day.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the king answered them roughly; and king Rehoboam forsook the counsel of the old men,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And answered them after the advice of the young men, saying, My father made your yoke heavy, but I will add thereto: my father chastised you with whips, but I &lt;i&gt;will chastise you&lt;/i&gt; with scorpions.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So the king hearkened not unto the people: for the cause was of God, that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; might perform his word, which he spake by the hand of Ahijah the Shilonite to Jeroboam the son of Nebat.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And when all Israel &lt;i&gt;saw&lt;/i&gt; that the king would not hearken unto them, the people answered the king, saying, What portion have we in David? and &lt;i&gt;we have&lt;/i&gt; none inheritance in the son of Jesse: every man to your tents, O Israel: &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; now, David, see to thine own house. So all Israel went to their tents.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But &lt;i&gt;as for&lt;/i&gt; the children of Israel that dwelt in the cities of Judah, Rehoboam reigned over them.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Then king Rehoboam sent Hadoram that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; over the tribute; and the children of Israel stoned him with stones, that he died. But king Rehoboam made speed to get him up to &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; chariot, to flee to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Israel rebelled against the house of David unto this day.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>