<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="22" nextChapter="2chronicles_8.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 8" prevChapter="2chronicles_6.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 6" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now when Solomon had made an end of praying, the fire came down from heaven, and consumed the burnt offering and the sacrifices; and the glory of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; filled the house.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the priests could not enter into the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, because the glory of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had filled the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s house.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And when all the children of Israel saw how the fire came down, and the glory of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; upon the house, they bowed themselves with their faces to the ground upon the pavement, and worshipped, and praised the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;, For &lt;i&gt;he is&lt;/i&gt; good; for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Then the king and all the people offered sacrifices before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And king Solomon offered a sacrifice of twenty and two thousand oxen, and an hundred and twenty thousand sheep: so the king and all the people dedicated the house of God.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the priests waited on their offices: the Levites also with instruments of musick of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which David the king had made to praise the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, because his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever, when David praised by their ministry; and the priests sounded trumpets before them, and all Israel stood.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Moreover Solomon hallowed the middle of the court that &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; before the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for there he offered burnt offerings, and the fat of the peace offerings, because the brasen altar which Solomon had made was not able to receive the burnt offerings, and the meat offerings, and the fat.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Also at the same time Solomon kept the feast seven days, and all Israel with him, a very great congregation, from the entering in of Hamath unto the river of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And in the eighth day they made a solemn assembly: for they kept the dedication of the altar seven days, and the feast seven days.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And on the three and twentieth day of the seventh month he sent the people away into their tents, glad and merry in heart for the goodness that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had shewed unto David, and to Solomon, and to Israel his people.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thus Solomon finished the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the king's house: and all that came into Solomon's heart to make in the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and in his own house, he prosperously effected.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; appeared to Solomon by night, and said unto him, I have heard thy prayer, and have chosen this place to myself for an house of sacrifice.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">If I shut up heaven that there be no rain, or if I command the locusts to devour the land, or if I send pestilence among my people;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">If my people, which are called by my name, shall humble themselves, and pray, and seek my face, and turn from their wicked ways; then will I hear from heaven, and will forgive their sin, and will heal their land.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Now mine eyes shall be open, and mine ears attent unto the prayer &lt;i&gt;that is made&lt;/i&gt; in this place.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For now have I chosen and sanctified this house, that my name may be there for ever: and mine eyes and mine heart shall be there perpetually.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And as for thee, if thou wilt walk before me, as David thy father walked, and do according to all that I have commanded thee, and shalt observe my statutes and my judgments;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Then will I stablish the throne of thy kingdom, according as I have covenanted with David thy father, saying, There shall not fail thee a man &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; ruler in Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But if ye turn away, and forsake my statutes and my commandments, which I have set before you, and shall go and serve other gods, and worship them;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Then will I pluck them up by the roots out of my land which I have given them; and this house, which I have sanctified for my name, will I cast out of my sight, and will make it &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; a proverb and a byword among all nations.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And this house, which is high, shall be an astonishment to every one that passeth by it; so that he shall say, Why hath the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; done thus unto this land, and unto this house?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And it shall be answered, Because they forsook the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of their fathers, which brought them forth out of the land of Egypt, and laid hold on other gods, and worshipped them, and served them: therefore hath he brought all this evil upon them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>