<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="26" verseCount="23" nextChapter="2chronicles_27.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 27" prevChapter="2chronicles_25.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 25" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then all the people of Judah took Uzziah, who &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; sixteen years old, and made him king in the room of his father Amaziah.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">He built Eloth, and restored it to Judah, after that the king slept with his fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Sixteen years old &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Uzziah when he began to reign, and he reigned fifty and two years in Jerusalem. His mother's name also &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Jecoliah of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he did &lt;i&gt;that which was&lt;/i&gt; right in the sight of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, according to all that his father Amaziah did.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he sought God in the days of Zechariah, who had understanding in the visions of God: and as long as he sought the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, God made him to prosper.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he went forth and warred against the Philistines, and brake down the wall of Gath, and the wall of Jabneh, and the wall of Ashdod, and built cities about Ashdod, and among the Philistines.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And God helped him against the Philistines, and against the Arabians that dwelt in Gur-baal, and the Mehunims.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the Ammonites gave gifts to Uzziah: and his name spread abroad &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to the entering in of Egypt; for he strengthened &lt;i&gt;himself&lt;/i&gt; exceedingly.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Moreover Uzziah built towers in Jerusalem at the corner gate, and at the valley gate, and at the turning &lt;i&gt;of the wall&lt;/i&gt;, and fortified them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Also he built towers in the desert, and digged many wells: for he had much cattle, both in the low country, and in the plains: husbandmen &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt;, and vine dressers in the mountains, and in Carmel: for he loved husbandry.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Moreover Uzziah had an host of fighting men, that went out to war by bands, according to the number of their account by the hand of Jeiel the scribe and Maaseiah the ruler, under the hand of Hananiah, &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; of the king's captains.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The whole number of the chief of the fathers of the mighty men of valour &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; two thousand and six hundred.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And under their hand &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; an army, three hundred thousand and seven thousand and five hundred, that made war with mighty power, to help the king against the enemy.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Uzziah prepared for them throughout all the host shields, and spears, and helmets, and habergeons, and bows, and slings &lt;i&gt;to cast&lt;/i&gt; stones.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he made in Jerusalem engines, invented by cunning men, to be on the towers and upon the bulwarks, to shoot arrows and great stones withal. And his name spread far abroad; for he was marvellously helped, till he was strong.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">But when he was strong, his heart was lifted up to &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; destruction: for he transgressed against the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God, and went into the temple of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to burn incense upon the altar of incense.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Azariah the priest went in after him, and with him fourscore priests of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;that were&lt;/i&gt; valiant men:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And they withstood Uzziah the king, and said unto him, &lt;i&gt;It appertaineth&lt;/i&gt; not unto thee, Uzziah, to burn incense unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, but to the priests the sons of Aaron, that are consecrated to burn incense: go out of the sanctuary; for thou hast trespassed; neither &lt;i&gt;shall it be&lt;/i&gt; for thine honour from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Then Uzziah was wroth, and &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; a censer in his hand to burn incense: and while he was wroth with the priests, the leprosy even rose up in his forehead before the priests in the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, from beside the incense altar.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Azariah the chief priest, and all the priests, looked upon him, and, behold, he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; leprous in his forehead, and they thrust him out from thence; yea, himself hasted also to go out, because the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had smitten him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Uzziah the king was a leper unto the day of his death, and dwelt in a several house, &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; a leper; for he was cut off from the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and Jotham his son &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; over the king's house, judging the people of the land.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">Now the rest of the acts of Uzziah, first and last, did Isaiah the prophet, the son of Amoz, write.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">So Uzziah slept with his fathers, and they buried him with his fathers in the field of the burial which &lt;i&gt;belonged&lt;/i&gt; to the kings; for they said, He &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a leper: and Jotham his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>