<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="16" nextChapter="2chronicles_13.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 13" prevChapter="2chronicles_11.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 11" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, when Rehoboam had established the kingdom, and had strengthened himself, he forsook the law of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and all Israel with him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And it came to pass, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; in the fifth year of king Rehoboam Shishak king of Egypt came up against Jerusalem, because they had transgressed against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">With twelve hundred chariots, and threescore thousand horsemen: and the people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; without number that came with him out of Egypt; the Lubims, the Sukkiims, and the Ethiopians.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he took the fenced cities which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;pertained&lt;/span&gt; to Judah, and came to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Then came Shemaiah the prophet to Rehoboam, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the princes of Judah, that were gathered together to Jerusalem because of Shishak, and said unto them, Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Ye have forsaken me, and therefore have I also left you in the hand of Shishak.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Whereupon the princes of Israel and the king humbled themselves; and they said, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; righteous.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; saw that they humbled themselves, the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came to Shemaiah, saying, They have humbled themselves; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;therefore&lt;/span&gt; I will not destroy them, but I will grant them some deliverance; and my wrath shall not be poured out upon Jerusalem by the hand of Shishak.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Nevertheless they shall be his servants; that they may know my service, and the service of the kingdoms of the countries.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">So Shishak king of Egypt came up against Jerusalem, and took away the treasures of the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the treasures of the king's house; he took all: he carried away also the shields of gold which Solomon had made.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Instead of which king Rehoboam made shields of brass, and committed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; to the hands of the chief of the guard, that kept the entrance of the king's house.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And when the king entered into the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the guard came and fetched them, and brought them again into the guard chamber.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And when he humbled himself, the wrath of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; turned from him, that he would not destroy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; altogether: and also in Judah things went well.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">So king Rehoboam strengthened himself in Jerusalem, and reigned: for Rehoboam &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; one and forty years old when he began to reign, and he reigned seventeen years in Jerusalem, the city which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had chosen out of all the tribes of Israel, to put his name there. And his mother's name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Naamah an Ammonitess.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he did evil, because he prepared not his heart to seek the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Now the acts of Rehoboam, first and last, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they not written in the book of Shemaiah the prophet, and of Iddo the seer concerning genealogies? And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there were&lt;/span&gt; wars between Rehoboam and Jeroboam continually.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Rehoboam slept with his fathers, and was buried in the city of David: and Abijah his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>