<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="23" nextChapter="2chronicles_12.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 12" prevChapter="2chronicles_10.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 10" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And when Rehoboam was come to Jerusalem, he gathered of the house of Judah and Benjamin an hundred and fourscore thousand chosen &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;, which were warriors, to fight against Israel, that he might bring the kingdom again to Rehoboam.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">But the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came to Shemaiah the man of God, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Speak unto Rehoboam the son of Solomon, king of Judah, and to all Israel in Judah and Benjamin, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Ye shall not go up, nor fight against your brethren: return every man to his house: for this thing is done of me. And they obeyed the words of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and returned from going against Jeroboam.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And Rehoboam dwelt in Jerusalem, and built cities for defence in Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He built even Beth-lehem, and Etam, and Tekoa,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Beth-zur, and Shoco, and Adullam,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Gath, and Mareshah, and Ziph,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Adoraim, and Lachish, and Azekah,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Zorah, and Aijalon, and Hebron, which &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in Judah and in Benjamin fenced cities.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he fortified the strong holds, and put captains in them, and store of victual, and of oil and wine.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And in every several city &lt;i&gt;he put&lt;/i&gt; shields and spears, and made them exceeding strong, having Judah and Benjamin on his side.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And the priests and the Levites that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; in all Israel resorted to him out of all their coasts.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For the Levites left their suburbs and their possession, and came to Judah and Jerusalem: for Jeroboam and his sons had cast them off from executing the priest's office unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he ordained him priests for the high places, and for the devils, and for the calves which he had made.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And after them out of all the tribes of Israel such as set their hearts to seek the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel came to Jerusalem, to sacrifice unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">So they strengthened the kingdom of Judah, and made Rehoboam the son of Solomon strong, three years: for three years they walked in the way of David and Solomon.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And Rehoboam took him Mahalath the daughter of Jerimoth the son of David to wife, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Abihail the daughter of Eliab the son of Jesse;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Which bare him children; Jeush, and Shamariah, and Zaham.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And after her he took Maachah the daughter of Absalom; which bare him Abijah, and Attai, and Ziza, and Shelomith.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And Rehoboam loved Maachah the daughter of Absalom above all his wives and his concubines: (for he took eighteen wives, and threescore concubines; and begat twenty and eight sons, and threescore daughters.)</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And Rehoboam made Abijah the son of Maachah the chief, &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; ruler among his brethren: for &lt;i&gt;he thought&lt;/i&gt; to make him king.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he dealt wisely, and dispersed of all his children throughout all the countries of Judah and Benjamin, unto every fenced city: and he gave them victual in abundance. And he desired many wives.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>