<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="14" name="2 Chronicles" bookPage="2chronicles.html" title="2 Chronicles" chapterCount="36" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezra_1.html" nextTitle="Ezra" prevBook="1chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="1 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="19" verseCount="11" nextChapter="2chronicles_20.html" nextTitle="2 Chronicles 20" prevChapter="2chronicles_18.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles 18" chapterPage="2chronicles_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Jehoshaphat the king of Judah returned to his house in peace to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Jehu the son of Hanani the seer went out to meet him, and said to king Jehoshaphat, Shouldest thou help the ungodly, and love them that hate the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? therefore &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; wrath upon thee from before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Nevertheless there are good things found in thee, in that thou hast taken away the groves out of the land, and hast prepared thine heart to seek God.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Jehoshaphat dwelt at Jerusalem: and he went out again through the people from Beer-sheba to mount Ephraim, and brought them back unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And he set judges in the land throughout all the fenced cities of Judah, city by city,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And said to the judges, Take heed what ye do: for ye judge not for man, but for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with you in the judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Wherefore now let the fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be upon you; take heed and do &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;: for &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no iniquity with the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, nor respect of persons, nor taking of gifts.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Moreover in Jerusalem did Jehoshaphat set of the Levites, and &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; the priests, and of the chief of the fathers of Israel, for the judgment of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and for controversies, when they returned to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he charged them, saying, Thus shall ye do in the fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, faithfully, and with a perfect heart.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And what cause soever shall come to you of your brethren that dwell in their cities, between blood and blood, between law and commandment, statutes and judgments, ye shall even warn them that they trespass not against the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; wrath come upon you, and upon your brethren: this do, and ye shall not trespass.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And, behold, Amariah the chief priest &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; over you in all matters of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and Zebadiah the son of Ishmael, the ruler of the house of Judah, for all the king's matters: also the Levites &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; officers before you. Deal courageously, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be with the good.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>