<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="15" name="Ezra" bookPage="ezra.html" title="Ezra" chapterCount="10" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="nehemiah_1.html" nextTitle="Nehemiah" prevBook="2chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="28" nextChapter="ezra_8.html" nextTitle="Ezra 8" prevChapter="ezra_6.html" prevTitle="Ezra 6" chapterPage="ezra_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now after these things, in the reign of Artaxerxes king of Persia, Ezra the son of Seraiah, the son of Azariah, the son of Hilkiah,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The son of Shallum, the son of Zadok, the son of Ahitub,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The son of Amariah, the son of Azariah, the son of Meraioth,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The son of Zerahiah, the son of Uzzi, the son of Bukki,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The son of Abishua, the son of Phinehas, the son of Eleazar, the son of Aaron the chief priest:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">This Ezra went up from Babylon; and he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a ready scribe in the law of Moses, which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel had given: and the king granted him all his request, according to the hand of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And there went up &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; of the children of Israel, and of the priests, and the Levites, and the singers, and the porters, and the Nethinims, unto Jerusalem, in the seventh year of Artaxerxes the king.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he came to Jerusalem in the fifth month, which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in the seventh year of the king.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For upon the first &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the first month began he to go up from Babylon, and on the first &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the fifth month came he to Jerusalem, according to the good hand of his God upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For Ezra had prepared his heart to seek the law of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and to do &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and to teach in Israel statutes and judgments.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Now this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the copy of the letter that the king Artaxerxes gave unto Ezra the priest, the scribe, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; a scribe of the words of the commandments of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and of his statutes to Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Artaxerxes, king of kings, unto Ezra the priest, a scribe of the law of the God of heaven, perfect &lt;i&gt;peace&lt;/i&gt;, and at such a time.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">I make a decree, that all they of the people of Israel, and &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; his priests and Levites, in my realm, which are minded of their own freewill to go up to Jerusalem, go with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Forasmuch as thou art sent of the king, and of his seven counsellors, to enquire concerning Judah and Jerusalem, according to the law of thy God which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in thine hand;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And to carry the silver and gold, which the king and his counsellors have freely offered unto the God of Israel, whose habitation &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in Jerusalem,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And all the silver and gold that thou canst find in all the province of Babylon, with the freewill offering of the people, and of the priests, offering willingly for the house of their God which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in Jerusalem:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">That thou mayest buy speedily with this money bullocks, rams, lambs, with their meat offerings and their drink offerings, and offer them upon the altar of the house of your God which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And whatsoever shall seem good to thee, and to thy brethren, to do with the rest of the silver and the gold, that do after the will of your God.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The vessels also that are given thee for the service of the house of thy God, &lt;i&gt;those&lt;/i&gt; deliver thou before the God of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And whatsoever more shall be needful for the house of thy God, which thou shalt have occasion to bestow, bestow &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; out of the king's treasure house.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And I, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; I Artaxerxes the king, do make a decree to all the treasurers which &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; beyond the river, that whatsoever Ezra the priest, the scribe of the law of the God of heaven, shall require of you, it be done speedily,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Unto an hundred talents of silver, and to an hundred measures of wheat, and to an hundred baths of wine, and to an hundred baths of oil, and salt without prescribing &lt;i&gt;how much&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Whatsoever is commanded by the God of heaven, let it be diligently done for the house of the God of heaven: for why should there be wrath against the realm of the king and his sons?</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Also we certify you, that touching any of the priests and Levites, singers, porters, Nethinims, or ministers of this house of God, it shall not be lawful to impose toll, tribute, or custom, upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And thou, Ezra, after the wisdom of thy God, that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in thine hand, set magistrates and judges, which may judge all the people that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; beyond the river, all such as know the laws of thy God; and teach ye them that know &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; not.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And whosoever will not do the law of thy God, and the law of the king, let judgment be executed speedily upon him, whether &lt;i&gt;it be&lt;/i&gt; unto death, or to banishment, or to confiscation of goods, or to imprisonment.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">Blessed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of our fathers, which hath put &lt;i&gt;such a thing&lt;/i&gt; as this in the king's heart, to beautify the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in Jerusalem:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And hath extended mercy unto me before the king, and his counsellors, and before all the king's mighty princes. And I was strengthened as the hand of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; upon me, and I gathered together out of Israel chief men to go up with me.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>