<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="15" name="Ezra" bookPage="ezra.html" title="Ezra" chapterCount="10" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="nehemiah_1.html" nextTitle="Nehemiah" prevBook="2chronicles_1.html" prevTitle="2 Chronicles">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="70" nextChapter="ezra_3.html" nextTitle="Ezra 3" prevChapter="ezra_1.html" prevTitle="Ezra 1" chapterPage="ezra_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the children of the province that went up out of the captivity, of those which had been carried away, whom Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon had carried away unto Babylon, and came again unto Jerusalem and Judah, every one unto his city;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Which came with Zerubbabel: Jeshua, Nehemiah, Seraiah, Reelaiah, Mordecai, Bilshan, Mispar, Bigvai, Rehum, Baanah. The number of the men of the people of Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The children of Parosh, two thousand an hundred seventy and two.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The children of Shephatiah, three hundred seventy and two.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The children of Arah, seven hundred seventy and five.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The children of Pahath-moab, of the children of Jeshua &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Joab, two thousand eight hundred and twelve.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The children of Elam, a thousand two hundred fifty and four.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The children of Zattu, nine hundred forty and five.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The children of Zaccai, seven hundred and threescore.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The children of Bani, six hundred forty and two.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The children of Bebai, six hundred twenty and three.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The children of Azgad, a thousand two hundred twenty and two.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The children of Adonikam, six hundred sixty and six.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The children of Bigvai, two thousand fifty and six.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The children of Adin, four hundred fifty and four.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The children of Ater of Hezekiah, ninety and eight.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The children of Bezai, three hundred twenty and three.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The children of Jorah, an hundred and twelve.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The children of Hashum, two hundred twenty and three.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The children of Gibbar, ninety and five.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The children of Beth-lehem, an hundred twenty and three.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The men of Netophah, fifty and six.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The men of Anathoth, an hundred twenty and eight.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The children of Azmaveth, forty and two.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The children of Kirjath-arim, Chephirah, and Beeroth, seven hundred and forty and three.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The children of Ramah and Gaba, six hundred twenty and one.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The men of Michmas, an hundred twenty and two.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The men of Beth-el and Ai, two hundred twenty and three.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The children of Nebo, fifty and two.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The children of Magbish, an hundred fifty and six.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The children of the other Elam, a thousand two hundred fifty and four.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">The children of Harim, three hundred and twenty.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">The children of Lod, Hadid, and Ono, seven hundred twenty and five.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">The children of Jericho, three hundred forty and five.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">The children of Senaah, three thousand and six hundred and thirty.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">The priests: the children of Jedaiah, of the house of Jeshua, nine hundred seventy and three.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">The children of Immer, a thousand fifty and two.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">The children of Pashur, a thousand two hundred forty and seven.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">The children of Harim, a thousand and seventeen.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40" newPara="true">The Levites: the children of Jeshua and Kadmiel, of the children of Hodaviah, seventy and four.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41" newPara="true">The singers: the children of Asaph, an hundred twenty and eight.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42" newPara="true">The children of the porters: the children of Shallum, the children of Ater, the children of Talmon, the children of Akkub, the children of Hatita, the children of Shobai, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; all an hundred thirty and nine.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43" newPara="true">The Nethinims: the children of Ziha, the children of Hasupha, the children of Tabbaoth,</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">The children of Keros, the children of Siaha, the children of Padon,</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">The children of Lebanah, the children of Hagabah, the children of Akkub,</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">The children of Hagab, the children of Shalmai, the children of Hanan,</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">The children of Giddel, the children of Gahar, the children of Reaiah,</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">The children of Rezin, the children of Nekoda, the children of Gazzam,</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">The children of Uzza, the children of Paseah, the children of Besai,</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">The children of Asnah, the children of Mehunim, the children of Nephusim,</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">The children of Bakbuk, the children of Hakupha, the children of Harhur,</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">The children of Bazluth, the children of Mehida, the children of Harsha,</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">The children of Barkos, the children of Sisera, the children of Thamah,</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">The children of Neziah, the children of Hatipha.</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55" newPara="true">The children of Solomon's servants: the children of Sotai, the children of Sophereth, the children of Peruda,</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">The children of Jaalah, the children of Darkon, the children of Giddel,</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">The children of Shephatiah, the children of Hattil, the children of Pochereth of Zebaim, the children of Ami.</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">All the Nethinims, and the children of Solomon's servants, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; three hundred ninety and two.</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">And these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; they which went up from Tel-melah, Tel-harsa, Cherub, Addan, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Immer: but they could not shew their father's house, and their seed, whether they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; of Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="60" id="v60">The children of Delaiah, the children of Tobiah, the children of Nekoda, six hundred fifty and two.</verse>
      <verse number="61" id="v61" newPara="true">And of the children of the priests: the children of Habaiah, the children of Koz, the children of Barzillai; which took a wife of the daughters of Barzillai the Gileadite, and was called after their name:</verse>
      <verse number="62" id="v62">These sought their register &lt;span class='extra'&gt;among&lt;/span&gt; those that were reckoned by genealogy, but they were not found: therefore were they, as polluted, put from the priesthood.</verse>
      <verse number="63" id="v63">And the Tirshatha said unto them, that they should not eat of the most holy things, till there stood up a priest with Urim and with Thummim.</verse>
      <verse number="64" id="v64" newPara="true">The whole congregation together &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; forty and two thousand three hundred &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; threescore,</verse>
      <verse number="65" id="v65">Beside their servants and their maids, of whom &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there were&lt;/span&gt; seven thousand three hundred thirty and seven: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there were&lt;/span&gt; among them two hundred singing men and singing women.</verse>
      <verse number="66" id="v66">Their horses &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; seven hundred thirty and six; their mules, two hundred forty and five;</verse>
      <verse number="67" id="v67">Their camels, four hundred thirty and five; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; asses, six thousand seven hundred and twenty.</verse>
      <verse number="68" id="v68" newPara="true">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of the chief of the fathers, when they came to the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; at Jerusalem, offered freely for the house of God to set it up in his place:</verse>
      <verse number="69" id="v69">They gave after their ability unto the treasure of the work threescore and one thousand drams of gold, and five thousand pound of silver, and one hundred priests' garments.</verse>
      <verse number="70" id="v70">So the priests, and the Levites, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of the people, and the singers, and the porters, and the Nethinims, dwelt in their cities, and all Israel in their cities.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>