<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="16" name="Nehemiah" bookPage="nehemiah.html" title="Nehemiah" chapterCount="13" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="esther_1.html" nextTitle="Esther" prevBook="ezra_1.html" prevTitle="Ezra">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="47" nextChapter="nehemiah_13.html" nextTitle="Nehemiah 13" prevChapter="nehemiah_11.html" prevTitle="Nehemiah 11" chapterPage="nehemiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the priests and the Levites that went up with Zerubbabel the son of Shealtiel, and Jeshua: Seraiah, Jeremiah, Ezra,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Amariah, Malluch, Hattush,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Shechaniah, Rehum, Meremoth,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Iddo, Ginnetho, Abijah,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Miamin, Maadiah, Bilgah,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Shemaiah, and Joiarib, Jedaiah,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Sallu, Amok, Hilkiah, Jedaiah. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the chief of the priests and of their brethren in the days of Jeshua.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Moreover the Levites: Jeshua, Binnui, Kadmiel, Sherebiah, Judah, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Mattaniah, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which was&lt;/span&gt; over the thanksgiving, he and his brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Also Bakbukiah and Unni, their brethren, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; over against them in the watches.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And Jeshua begat Joiakim, Joiakim also begat Eliashib, and Eliashib begat Joiada,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Joiada begat Jonathan, and Jonathan begat Jaddua.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And in the days of Joiakim were priests, the chief of the fathers: of Seraiah, Meraiah; of Jeremiah, Hananiah;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Of Ezra, Meshullam; of Amariah, Jehohanan;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Of Melicu, Jonathan; of Shebaniah, Joseph;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Of Harim, Adna; of Meraioth, Helkai;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Of Iddo, Zechariah; of Ginnethon, Meshullam;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Of Abijah, Zichri; of Miniamin, of Moadiah, Piltai;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Of Bilgah, Shammua; of Shemaiah, Jehonathan;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And of Joiarib, Mattenai; of Jedaiah, Uzzi;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Of Sallai, Kallai; of Amok, Eber;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Of Hilkiah, Hashabiah; of Jedaiah, Nethaneel.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">The Levites in the days of Eliashib, Joiada, and Johanan, and Jaddua, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; recorded chief of the fathers: also the priests, to the reign of Darius the Persian.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The sons of Levi, the chief of the fathers, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; written in the book of the chronicles, even until the days of Johanan the son of Eliashib.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the chief of the Levites: Hashabiah, Sherebiah, and Jeshua the son of Kadmiel, with their brethren over against them, to praise &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to give thanks, according to the commandment of David the man of God, ward over against ward.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Mattaniah, and Bakbukiah, Obadiah, Meshullam, Talmon, Akkub, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; porters keeping the ward at the thresholds of the gates.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the days of Joiakim the son of Jeshua, the son of Jozadak, and in the days of Nehemiah the governor, and of Ezra the priest, the scribe.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And at the dedication of the wall of Jerusalem they sought the Levites out of all their places, to bring them to Jerusalem, to keep the dedication with gladness, both with thanksgivings, and with singing, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; cymbals, psalteries, and with harps.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the sons of the singers gathered themselves together, both out of the plain country round about Jerusalem, and from the villages of Netophathi;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Also from the house of Gilgal, and out of the fields of Geba and Azmaveth: for the singers had builded them villages round about Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the priests and the Levites purified themselves, and purified the people, and the gates, and the wall.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Then I brought up the princes of Judah upon the wall, and appointed two great &lt;span class="extra"&gt;companies of them that gave&lt;/span&gt; thanks, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;whereof one&lt;/span&gt; went on the right hand upon the wall toward the dung gate:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And after them went Hoshaiah, and half of the princes of Judah,</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And Azariah, Ezra, and Meshullam,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Judah, and Benjamin, and Shemaiah, and Jeremiah,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;certain&lt;/span&gt; of the priests' sons with trumpets; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;namely&lt;/span&gt;, Zechariah the son of Jonathan, the son of Shemaiah, the son of Mattaniah, the son of Michaiah, the son of Zaccur, the son of Asaph:</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And his brethren, Shemaiah, and Azarael, Milalai, Gilalai, Maai, Nethaneel, and Judah, Hanani, with the musical instruments of David the man of God, and Ezra the scribe before them.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And at the fountain gate, which was over against them, they went up by the stairs of the city of David, at the going up of the wall, above the house of David, even unto the water gate eastward.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And the other &lt;span class="extra"&gt;company of them that gave&lt;/span&gt; thanks went over against &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, and I after them, and the half of the people upon the wall, from beyond the tower of the furnaces even unto the broad wall;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And from above the gate of Ephraim, and above the old gate, and above the fish gate, and the tower of Hananeel, and the tower of Meah, even unto the sheep gate: and they stood still in the prison gate.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">So stood the two &lt;span class="extra"&gt;companies of them that gave&lt;/span&gt; thanks in the house of God, and I, and the half of the rulers with me:</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And the priests; Eliakim, Maaseiah, Miniamin, Michaiah, Elioenai, Zechariah, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Hananiah, with trumpets;</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And Maaseiah, and Shemaiah, and Eleazar, and Uzzi, and Jehohanan, and Malchijah, and Elam, and Ezer. And the singers sang loud, with Jezrahiah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; overseer.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Also that day they offered great sacrifices, and rejoiced: for God had made them rejoice with great joy: the wives also and the children rejoiced: so that the joy of Jerusalem was heard even afar off.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44" newPara="true">And at that time were some appointed over the chambers for the treasures, for the offerings, for the firstfruits, and for the tithes, to gather into them out of the fields of the cities the portions of the law for the priests and Levites: for Judah rejoiced for the priests and for the Levites that waited.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And both the singers and the porters kept the ward of their God, and the ward of the purification, according to the commandment of David, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; of Solomon his son.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">For in the days of David and Asaph of old &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there were&lt;/span&gt; chief of the singers, and songs of praise and thanksgiving unto God.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">And all Israel in the days of Zerubbabel, and in the days of Nehemiah, gave the portions of the singers and the porters, every day his portion: and they sanctified &lt;span class="extra"&gt;holy things&lt;/span&gt; unto the Levites; and the Levites sanctified &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; unto the children of Aaron.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>