<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="16" name="Nehemiah" bookPage="nehemiah.html" title="Nehemiah" chapterCount="13" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="esther_1.html" nextTitle="Esther" prevBook="ezra_1.html" prevTitle="Ezra">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="11" nextChapter="nehemiah_2.html" nextTitle="Nehemiah 2" prevChapter="ezra_10.html" prevTitle="Ezra 10" chapterPage="nehemiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The words of Nehemiah the son of Hachaliah. And it came to pass in the month Chisleu, in the twentieth year, as I was in Shushan the palace,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That Hanani, one of my brethren, came, he and &lt;i&gt;certain&lt;/i&gt; men of Judah; and I asked them concerning the Jews that had escaped, which were left of the captivity, and concerning Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they said unto me, The remnant that are left of the captivity there in the province &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in great affliction and reproach: the wall of Jerusalem also &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; broken down, and the gates thereof are burned with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when I heard these words, that I sat down and wept, and mourned &lt;i&gt;certain&lt;/i&gt; days, and fasted, and prayed before the God of heaven,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And said, I beseech thee, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of heaven, the great and terrible God, that keepeth covenant and mercy for them that love him and observe his commandments:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Let thine ear now be attentive, and thine eyes open, that thou mayest hear the prayer of thy servant, which I pray before thee now, day and night, for the children of Israel thy servants, and confess the sins of the children of Israel, which we have sinned against thee: both I and my father's house have sinned.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">We have dealt very corruptly against thee, and have not kept the commandments, nor the statutes, nor the judgments, which thou commandedst thy servant Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Remember, I beseech thee, the word that thou commandedst thy servant Moses, saying, &lt;i&gt;If&lt;/i&gt; ye transgress, I will scatter you abroad among the nations:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; ye turn unto me, and keep my commandments, and do them; though there were of you cast out unto the uttermost part of the heaven, &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; will I gather them from thence, and will bring them unto the place that I have chosen to set my name there.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Now these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; thy servants and thy people, whom thou hast redeemed by thy great power, and by thy strong hand.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">O Lord, I beseech thee, let now thine ear be attentive to the prayer of thy servant, and to the prayer of thy servants, who desire to fear thy name: and prosper, I pray thee, thy servant this day, and grant him mercy in the sight of this man. For I was the king's cupbearer.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>