<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="16" name="Nehemiah" bookPage="nehemiah.html" title="Nehemiah" chapterCount="13" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="esther_1.html" nextTitle="Esther" prevBook="ezra_1.html" prevTitle="Ezra">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="31" nextChapter="esther_1.html" nextTitle="Esther 1" prevChapter="nehemiah_12.html" prevTitle="Nehemiah 12" chapterPage="nehemiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">On that day they read in the book of Moses in the audience of the people; and therein was found written, that the Ammonite and the Moabite should not come into the congregation of God for ever;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Because they met not the children of Israel with bread and with water, but hired Balaam against them, that he should curse them: howbeit our God turned the curse into a blessing.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Now it came to pass, when they had heard the law, that they separated from Israel all the mixed multitude.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And before this, Eliashib the priest, having the oversight of the chamber of the house of our God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; allied unto Tobiah:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he had prepared for him a great chamber, where aforetime they laid the meat offerings, the frankincense, and the vessels, and the tithes of the corn, the new wine, and the oil, which was commanded &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be given&lt;/span&gt; to the Levites, and the singers, and the porters; and the offerings of the priests.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But in all this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;time&lt;/span&gt; was not I at Jerusalem: for in the two and thirtieth year of Artaxerxes king of Babylon came I unto the king, and after certain days obtained I leave of the king:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And I came to Jerusalem, and understood of the evil that Eliashib did for Tobiah, in preparing him a chamber in the courts of the house of God.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And it grieved me sore: therefore I cast forth all the household stuff of Tobiah out of the chamber.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then I commanded, and they cleansed the chambers: and thither brought I again the vessels of the house of God, with the meat offering and the frankincense.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And I perceived that the portions of the Levites had not been given &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;: for the Levites and the singers, that did the work, were fled every one to his field.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then contended I with the rulers, and said, Why is the house of God forsaken? And I gathered them together, and set them in their place.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Then brought all Judah the tithe of the corn and the new wine and the oil unto the treasuries.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And I made treasurers over the treasuries, Shelemiah the priest, and Zadok the scribe, and of the Levites, Pedaiah: and next to them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Hanan the son of Zaccur, the son of Mattaniah: for they were counted faithful, and their office &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; to distribute unto their brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Remember me, O my God, concerning this, and wipe not out my good deeds that I have done for the house of my God, and for the offices thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">In those days saw I in Judah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; treading wine presses on the sabbath, and bringing in sheaves, and lading asses; as also wine, grapes, and figs, and all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;manner of&lt;/span&gt; burdens, which they brought into Jerusalem on the sabbath day: and I testified &lt;span class="extra"&gt;against them&lt;/span&gt; in the day wherein they sold victuals.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">There dwelt men of Tyre also therein, which brought fish, and all manner of ware, and sold on the sabbath unto the children of Judah, and in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then I contended with the nobles of Judah, and said unto them, What evil thing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this that ye do, and profane the sabbath day?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Did not your fathers thus, and did not our God bring all this evil upon us, and upon this city? yet ye bring more wrath upon Israel by profaning the sabbath.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And it came to pass, that when the gates of Jerusalem began to be dark before the sabbath, I commanded that the gates should be shut, and charged that they should not be opened till after the sabbath: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of my servants set I at the gates, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; there should no burden be brought in on the sabbath day.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">So the merchants and sellers of all kind of ware lodged without Jerusalem once or twice.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then I testified against them, and said unto them, Why lodge ye about the wall? if ye do &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; again, I will lay hands on you. From that time forth came they no &lt;span class="extra"&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; on the sabbath.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And I commanded the Levites that they should cleanse themselves, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; they should come &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; keep the gates, to sanctify the sabbath day. Remember me, O my God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;concerning&lt;/span&gt; this also, and spare me according to the greatness of thy mercy.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">In those days also saw I Jews &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; had married wives of Ashdod, of Ammon, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; of Moab:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And their children spake half in the speech of Ashdod, and could not speak in the Jews' language, but according to the language of each people.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And I contended with them, and cursed them, and smote certain of them, and plucked off their hair, and made them swear by God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Ye shall not give your daughters unto their sons, nor take their daughters unto your sons, or for yourselves.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Did not Solomon king of Israel sin by these things? yet among many nations was there no king like him, who was beloved of his God, and God made him king over all Israel: nevertheless even him did outlandish women cause to sin.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Shall we then hearken unto you to do all this great evil, to transgress against our God in marrying strange wives?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; of the sons of Joiada, the son of Eliashib the high priest, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; son in law to Sanballat the Horonite: therefore I chased him from me.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Remember them, O my God, because they have defiled the priesthood, and the covenant of the priesthood, and of the Levites.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Thus cleansed I them from all strangers, and appointed the wards of the priests and the Levites, every one in his business;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And for the wood offering, at times appointed, and for the firstfruits. Remember me, O my God, for good.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>