<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="16" name="Nehemiah" bookPage="nehemiah.html" title="Nehemiah" chapterCount="13" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="esther_1.html" nextTitle="Esther" prevBook="ezra_1.html" prevTitle="Ezra">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="36" nextChapter="nehemiah_12.html" nextTitle="Nehemiah 12" prevChapter="nehemiah_10.html" prevTitle="Nehemiah 10" chapterPage="nehemiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the rulers of the people dwelt at Jerusalem: the rest of the people also cast lots, to bring one of ten to dwell in Jerusalem the holy city, and nine parts &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to dwell&lt;/span&gt; in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; cities.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the people blessed all the men, that willingly offered themselves to dwell at Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Now these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the chief of the province that dwelt in Jerusalem: but in the cities of Judah dwelt every one in his possession in their cities, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to wit&lt;/span&gt;, Israel, the priests, and the Levites, and the Nethinims, and the children of Solomon's servants.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And at Jerusalem dwelt &lt;span class="extra"&gt;certain&lt;/span&gt; of the children of Judah, and of the children of Benjamin. Of the children of Judah; Athaiah the son of Uzziah, the son of Zechariah, the son of Amariah, the son of Shephatiah, the son of Mahalaleel, of the children of Perez;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Maaseiah the son of Baruch, the son of Col-hozeh, the son of Hazaiah, the son of Adaiah, the son of Joiarib, the son of Zechariah, the son of Shiloni.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">All the sons of Perez that dwelt at Jerusalem &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; four hundred threescore and eight valiant men.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the sons of Benjamin; Sallu the son of Meshullam, the son of Joed, the son of Pedaiah, the son of Kolaiah, the son of Maaseiah, the son of Ithiel, the son of Jesaiah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And after him Gabbai, Sallai, nine hundred twenty and eight.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And Joel the son of Zichri &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; their overseer: and Judah the son of Senuah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; second over the city.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Of the priests: Jedaiah the son of Joiarib, Jachin.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Seraiah the son of Hilkiah, the son of Meshullam, the son of Zadok, the son of Meraioth, the son of Ahitub, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the ruler of the house of God.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And their brethren that did the work of the house &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; eight hundred twenty and two: and Adaiah the son of Jeroham, the son of Pelaliah, the son of Amzi, the son of Zechariah, the son of Pashur, the son of Malchiah,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And his brethren, chief of the fathers, two hundred forty and two: and Amashai the son of Azareel, the son of Ahasai, the son of Meshillemoth, the son of Immer,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And their brethren, mighty men of valour, an hundred twenty and eight: and their overseer &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Zabdiel, the son of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one of&lt;/span&gt; the great men.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Also of the Levites: Shemaiah the son of Hashub, the son of Azrikam, the son of Hashabiah, the son of Bunni;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Shabbethai and Jozabad, of the chief of the Levites, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;had&lt;/span&gt; the oversight of the outward business of the house of God.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Mattaniah the son of Micha, the son of Zabdi, the son of Asaph, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the principal to begin the thanksgiving in prayer: and Bakbukiah the second among his brethren, and Abda the son of Shammua, the son of Galal, the son of Jeduthun.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">All the Levites in the holy city &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; two hundred fourscore and four.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Moreover the porters, Akkub, Talmon, and their brethren that kept the gates, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; an hundred seventy and two.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And the residue of Israel, of the priests, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the Levites, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in all the cities of Judah, every one in his inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But the Nethinims dwelt in Ophel: and Ziha and Gispa &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; over the Nethinims.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The overseer also of the Levites at Jerusalem &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Uzzi the son of Bani, the son of Hashabiah, the son of Mattaniah, the son of Micha. Of the sons of Asaph, the singers &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; over the business of the house of God.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it was&lt;/span&gt; the king's commandment concerning them, that a certain portion should be for the singers, due for every day.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Pethahiah the son of Meshezabeel, of the children of Zerah the son of Judah, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; at the king's hand in all matters concerning the people.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And for the villages, with their fields, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of the children of Judah dwelt at Kirjath-arba, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the villages thereof, and at Dibon, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the villages thereof, and at Jekabzeel, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the villages thereof,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And at Jeshua, and at Moladah, and at Beth-phelet,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And at Hazar-shual, and at Beer-sheba, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the villages thereof,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And at Ziklag, and at Mekonah, and in the villages thereof,</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And at En-rimmon, and at Zareah, and at Jarmuth,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Zanoah, Adullam, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; their villages, at Lachish, and the fields thereof, at Azekah, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the villages thereof. And they dwelt from Beer-sheba unto the valley of Hinnom.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The children also of Benjamin from Geba &lt;span class="extra"&gt;dwelt&lt;/span&gt; at Michmash, and Aija, and Beth-el, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; their villages,</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; at Anathoth, Nob, Ananiah,</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Hazor, Ramah, Gittaim,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Hadid, Zeboim, Neballat,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Lod, and Ono, the valley of craftsmen.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And of the Levites &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; divisions &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; Judah, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; in Benjamin.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>