<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="26" nextChapter="job_4.html" nextTitle="Job 4" prevChapter="job_2.html" prevTitle="Job 2" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">After this opened Job his mouth, and cursed his day.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Job spake, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Let the day perish wherein I was born, and the night &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in which&lt;/span&gt; it was said, There is a man child conceived.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Let that day be darkness; let not God regard it from above, neither let the light shine upon it.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Let darkness and the shadow of death stain it; let a cloud dwell upon it; let the blackness of the day terrify it.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; that night, let darkness seize upon it; let it not be joined unto the days of the year, let it not come into the number of the months.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Lo, let that night be solitary, let no joyful voice come therein.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Let them curse it that curse the day, who are ready to raise up their mourning.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Let the stars of the twilight thereof be dark; let it look for light, but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;have&lt;/span&gt; none; neither let it see the dawning of the day:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Because it shut not up the doors of my &lt;span class='extra'&gt;mother's&lt;/span&gt; womb, nor hid sorrow from mine eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Why died I not from the womb? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;why&lt;/span&gt; did I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; give up the ghost when I came out of the belly?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Why did the knees prevent me? or why the breasts that I should suck?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For now should I have lain still and been quiet, I should have slept: then had I been at rest,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">With kings and counsellors of the earth, which built desolate places for themselves;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Or with princes that had gold, who filled their houses with silver:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Or as an hidden untimely birth I had not been; as infants &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; never saw light.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">There the wicked cease &lt;span class='extra'&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; troubling; and there the weary be at rest.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;There&lt;/span&gt; the prisoners rest together; they hear not the voice of the oppressor.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The small and great are there; and the servant &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; free from his master.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Wherefore is light given to him that is in misery, and life unto the bitter &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; soul;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Which long for death, but it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;cometh&lt;/span&gt; not; and dig for it more than for hid treasures;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Which rejoice exceedingly, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; are glad, when they can find the grave?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Why is light given&lt;/span&gt; to a man whose way is hid, and whom God hath hedged in?</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For my sighing cometh before I eat, and my roarings are poured out like the waters.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For the thing which I greatly feared is come upon me, and that which I was afraid of is come unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">I was not in safety, neither had I rest, neither was I quiet; yet trouble came.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>