<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="24" verseCount="25" nextChapter="job_25.html" nextTitle="Job 25" prevChapter="job_23.html" prevTitle="Job 23" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Why, seeing times are not hidden from the Almighty, do they that know him not see his days?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Some&lt;/span&gt; remove the landmarks; they violently take away flocks, and feed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thereof&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">They drive away the ass of the fatherless, they take the widow's ox for a pledge.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They turn the needy out of the way: the poor of the earth hide themselves together.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Behold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; wild asses in the desert, go they forth to their work; rising betimes for a prey: the wilderness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;yieldeth&lt;/span&gt; food for them &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; children.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">They reap &lt;span class='extra'&gt;every one&lt;/span&gt; his corn in the field: and they gather the vintage of the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">They cause the naked to lodge without clothing, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they have&lt;/span&gt; no covering in the cold.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">They are wet with the showers of the mountains, and embrace the rock for want of a shelter.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">They pluck the fatherless from the breast, and take a pledge of the poor.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">They cause &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; to go naked without clothing, and they take away the sheaf &lt;span class='extra'&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the hungry;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Which&lt;/span&gt; make oil within their walls, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; tread &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; winepresses, and suffer thirst.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Men groan from out of the city, and the soul of the wounded crieth out: yet God layeth not folly &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">They are of those that rebel against the light; they know not the ways thereof, nor abide in the paths thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The murderer rising with the light killeth the poor and needy, and in the night is as a thief.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The eye also of the adulterer waiteth for the twilight, saying, No eye shall see me: and disguiseth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; face.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">In the dark they dig through houses, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; they had marked for themselves in the daytime: they know not the light.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For the morning &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; to them even as the shadow of death: if &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; know &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them, they are in&lt;/span&gt; the terrors of the shadow of death.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; swift as the waters; their portion is cursed in the earth: he beholdeth not the way of the vineyards.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Drought and heat consume the snow waters: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so doth&lt;/span&gt; the grave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;those which&lt;/span&gt; have sinned.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The womb shall forget him; the worm shall feed sweetly on him; he shall be no more remembered; and wickedness shall be broken as a tree.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">He evil entreateth the barren &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; beareth not: and doeth not good to the widow.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">He draweth also the mighty with his power: he riseth up, and no &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; is sure of life.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Though&lt;/span&gt; it be given him &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; in safety, whereon he resteth; yet his eyes &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; upon their ways.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">They are exalted for a little while, but are gone and brought low; they are taken out of the way as all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;other&lt;/span&gt;, and cut off as the tops of the ears of corn.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And if &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; now, who will make me a liar, and make my speech nothing worth?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>