<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="30" nextChapter="job_7.html" nextTitle="Job 7" prevChapter="job_5.html" prevTitle="Job 5" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">But Job answered and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Oh that my grief were throughly weighed, and my calamity laid in the balances together!</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For now it would be heavier than the sand of the sea: therefore my words are swallowed up.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For the arrows of the Almighty &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; within me, the poison whereof drinketh up my spirit: the terrors of God do set themselves in array against me.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Doth the wild ass bray when he hath grass? or loweth the ox over his fodder?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Can that which is unsavoury be eaten without salt? or is there &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; taste in the white of an egg?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The things &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; my soul refused to touch &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; as my sorrowful meat.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Oh that I might have my request; and that God would grant &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; the thing that I long for!</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Even that it would please God to destroy me; that he would let loose his hand, and cut me off!</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then should I yet have comfort; yea, I would harden myself in sorrow: let him not spare; for I have not concealed the words of the Holy One.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my strength, that I should hope? and what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine end, that I should prolong my life?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; my strength the strength of stones? or &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my flesh of brass?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; not my help in me? and is wisdom driven quite from me?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">To him that is afflicted pity &lt;span class='extra'&gt;should be shewed&lt;/span&gt; from his friend; but he forsaketh the fear of the Almighty.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">My brethren have dealt deceitfully as a brook, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; as the stream of brooks they pass away;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Which are blackish by reason of the ice, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; wherein the snow is hid:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">What time they wax warm, they vanish: when it is hot, they are consumed out of their place.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The paths of their way are turned aside; they go to nothing, and perish.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The troops of Tema looked, the companies of Sheba waited for them.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">They were confounded because they had hoped; they came thither, and were ashamed.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For now ye are nothing; ye see &lt;span class='extra'&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; casting down, and are afraid.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Did I say, Bring unto me? or, Give a reward for me of your substance?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Or, Deliver me from the enemy's hand? or, Redeem me from the hand of the mighty?</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Teach me, and I will hold my tongue: and cause me to understand wherein I have erred.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">How forcible are right words! but what doth your arguing reprove?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Do ye imagine to reprove words, and the speeches of one that is desperate, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which are&lt;/span&gt; as wind?</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Yea, ye overwhelm the fatherless, and ye dig &lt;span class='extra'&gt;a pit&lt;/span&gt; for your friend.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Now therefore be content, look upon me; for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; evident unto you if I lie.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Return, I pray you, let it not be iniquity; yea, return again, my righteousness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in it.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Is there iniquity in my tongue? cannot my taste discern perverse things?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>