<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="25" nextChapter="job_13.html" nextTitle="Job 13" prevChapter="job_11.html" prevTitle="Job 11" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Job answered and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">No doubt but ye &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the people, and wisdom shall die with you.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But I have understanding as well as you; I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; not inferior to you: yea, who knoweth not such things as these?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I am &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; one mocked of his neighbour, who calleth upon God, and he answereth him: the just upright &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man is&lt;/span&gt; laughed to scorn.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">He that is ready to slip with &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; feet &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is as&lt;/span&gt; a lamp despised in the thought of him that is at ease.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The tabernacles of robbers prosper, and they that provoke God are secure; into whose hand God bringeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;abundantly&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But ask now the beasts, and they shall teach thee; and the fowls of the air, and they shall tell thee:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Or speak to the earth, and it shall teach thee: and the fishes of the sea shall declare unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Who knoweth not in all these that the hand of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath wrought this?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">In whose hand &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the soul of every living thing, and the breath of all mankind.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Doth not the ear try words? and the mouth taste his meat?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">With the ancient &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; wisdom; and in length of days understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">With him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; wisdom and strength, he hath counsel and understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Behold, he breaketh down, and it cannot be built again: he shutteth up a man, and there can be no opening.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Behold, he withholdeth the waters, and they dry up: also he sendeth them out, and they overturn the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">With him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; strength and wisdom: the deceived and the deceiver &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; his.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He leadeth counsellors away spoiled, and maketh the judges fools.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He looseth the bond of kings, and girdeth their loins with a girdle.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He leadeth princes away spoiled, and overthroweth the mighty.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He removeth away the speech of the trusty, and taketh away the understanding of the aged.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">He poureth contempt upon princes, and weakeneth the strength of the mighty.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">He discovereth deep things out of darkness, and bringeth out to light the shadow of death.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">He increaseth the nations, and destroyeth them: he enlargeth the nations, and straiteneth them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;again&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">He taketh away the heart of the chief of the people of the earth, and causeth them to wander in a wilderness &lt;span class="extra"&gt;where there is&lt;/span&gt; no way.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">They grope in the dark without light, and he maketh them to stagger like &lt;span class="extra"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; drunken &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>