<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="17" verseCount="16" nextChapter="job_18.html" nextTitle="Job 18" prevChapter="job_16.html" prevTitle="Job 16" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">My breath is corrupt, my days are extinct, the graves &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are ready&lt;/span&gt; for me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Are there&lt;/span&gt; not mockers with me? and doth not mine eye continue in their provocation?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Lay down now, put me in a surety with thee; who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; will strike hands with me?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For thou hast hid their heart from understanding: therefore shalt thou not exalt &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">He that speaketh flattery to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; friends, even the eyes of his children shall fail.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He hath made me also a byword of the people; and aforetime I was as a tabret.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Mine eye also is dim by reason of sorrow, and all my members &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; as a shadow.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Upright &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; shall be astonied at this, and the innocent shall stir up himself against the hypocrite.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The righteous also shall hold on his way, and he that hath clean hands shall be stronger and stronger.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But as for you all, do ye return, and come now: for I cannot find &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; wise &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; among you.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">My days are past, my purposes are broken off, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the thoughts of my heart.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They change the night into day: the light &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; short because of darkness.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">If I wait, the grave &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine house: I have made my bed in the darkness.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I have said to corruption, Thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; my father: to the worm, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Thou art&lt;/span&gt; my mother, and my sister.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; now my hope? as for my hope, who shall see it?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">They shall go down to the bars of the pit, when &lt;span class="extra"&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; rest together &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the dust.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>