<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="34" verseCount="37" nextChapter="job_35.html" nextTitle="Job 35" prevChapter="job_33.html" prevTitle="Job 33" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Furthermore Elihu answered and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Hear my words, O ye wise &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;; and give ear unto me, ye that have knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For the ear trieth words, as the mouth tasteth meat.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Let us choose to us judgment: let us know among ourselves what &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; good.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For Job hath said, I am righteous: and God hath taken away my judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Should I lie against my right? my wound &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; incurable without transgression.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">What man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; like Job, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;who&lt;/span&gt; drinketh up scorning like water?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Which goeth in company with the workers of iniquity, and walketh with wicked men.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For he hath said, It profiteth a man nothing that he should delight himself with God.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Therefore hearken unto me, ye men of understanding: far be it from God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that he should do&lt;/span&gt; wickedness; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the Almighty, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that he should commit&lt;/span&gt; iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For the work of a man shall he render unto him, and cause every man to find according to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; ways.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Yea, surely God will not do wickedly, neither will the Almighty pervert judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Who hath given him a charge over the earth? or who hath disposed the whole world?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">If he set his heart upon man, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; he gather unto himself his spirit and his breath;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">All flesh shall perish together, and man shall turn again unto dust.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">If now &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thou hast&lt;/span&gt; understanding, hear this: hearken to the voice of my words.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Shall even he that hateth right govern? and wilt thou condemn him that is most just?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Is it fit&lt;/span&gt; to say to a king, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Thou art&lt;/span&gt; wicked? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to princes, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Ye are&lt;/span&gt; ungodly?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;How much less to him&lt;/span&gt; that accepteth not the persons of princes, nor regardeth the rich more than the poor? for they all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the work of his hands.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">In a moment shall they die, and the people shall be troubled at midnight, and pass away: and the mighty shall be taken away without hand.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For his eyes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; upon the ways of man, and he seeth all his goings.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;There is&lt;/span&gt; no darkness, nor shadow of death, where the workers of iniquity may hide themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For he will not lay upon man more &lt;span class="extra"&gt;than right&lt;/span&gt;; that he should enter into judgment with God.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">He shall break in pieces mighty men without number, and set others in their stead.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Therefore he knoweth their works, and he overturneth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; in the night, so that they are destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">He striketh them as wicked men in the open sight of others;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Because they turned back from him, and would not consider any of his ways:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">So that they cause the cry of the poor to come unto him, and he heareth the cry of the afflicted.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">When he giveth quietness, who then can make trouble? and when he hideth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; face, who then can behold him? whether &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it be done&lt;/span&gt; against a nation, or against a man only:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">That the hypocrite reign not, lest the people be ensnared.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Surely it is meet to be said unto God, I have borne &lt;span class="extra"&gt;chastisement&lt;/span&gt;, I will not offend &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any more&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;That which&lt;/span&gt; I see not teach thou me: if I have done iniquity, I will do no more.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Should it be&lt;/span&gt; according to thy mind? he will recompense it, whether thou refuse, or whether thou choose; and not I: therefore speak what thou knowest.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Let men of understanding tell me, and let a wise man hearken unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Job hath spoken without knowledge, and his words &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; without wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">My desire &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is that&lt;/span&gt; Job may be tried unto the end because of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; answers for wicked men.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">For he addeth rebellion unto his sin, he clappeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his hands&lt;/span&gt; among us, and multiplieth his words against God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>