<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="29" nextChapter="job_21.html" nextTitle="Job 21" prevChapter="job_19.html" prevTitle="Job 19" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then answered Zophar the Naamathite, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Therefore do my thoughts cause me to answer, and for &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; I make haste.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I have heard the check of my reproach, and the spirit of my understanding causeth me to answer.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Knowest thou &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; this of old, since man was placed upon earth,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">That the triumphing of the wicked &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; short, and the joy of the hypocrite &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; for a moment?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Though his excellency mount up to the heavens, and his head reach unto the clouds;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;i&gt;Yet&lt;/i&gt; he shall perish for ever like his own dung: they which have seen him shall say, Where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He shall fly away as a dream, and shall not be found: yea, he shall be chased away as a vision of the night.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The eye also &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; saw him shall &lt;i&gt;see him&lt;/i&gt; no more; neither shall his place any more behold him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">His children shall seek to please the poor, and his hands shall restore their goods.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">His bones are full &lt;i&gt;of the sin&lt;/i&gt; of his youth, which shall lie down with him in the dust.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Though wickedness be sweet in his mouth, &lt;i&gt;though&lt;/i&gt; he hide it under his tongue;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;i&gt;Though&lt;/i&gt; he spare it, and forsake it not; but keep it still within his mouth:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;i&gt;Yet&lt;/i&gt; his meat in his bowels is turned, &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; the gall of asps within him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He hath swallowed down riches, and he shall vomit them up again: God shall cast them out of his belly.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He shall suck the poison of asps: the viper's tongue shall slay him.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He shall not see the rivers, the floods, the brooks of honey and butter.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">That which he laboured for shall he restore, and shall not swallow &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; down: according to &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; substance &lt;i&gt;shall&lt;/i&gt; the restitution &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt;, and he shall not rejoice &lt;i&gt;therein&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Because he hath oppressed &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; hath forsaken the poor; &lt;i&gt;because&lt;/i&gt; he hath violently taken away an house which he builded not;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Surely he shall not feel quietness in his belly, he shall not save of that which he desired.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">There shall none of his meat be left; therefore shall no man look for his goods.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">In the fulness of his sufficiency he shall be in straits: every hand of the wicked shall come upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;i&gt;When&lt;/i&gt; he is about to fill his belly, &lt;i&gt;God&lt;/i&gt; shall cast the fury of his wrath upon him, and shall rain &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; upon him while he is eating.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">He shall flee from the iron weapon, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the bow of steel shall strike him through.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">It is drawn, and cometh out of the body; yea, the glittering sword cometh out of his gall: terrors &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">All darkness &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; hid in his secret places: a fire not blown shall consume him; it shall go ill with him that is left in his tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The heaven shall reveal his iniquity; and the earth shall rise up against him.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The increase of his house shall depart, &lt;i&gt;and his goods&lt;/i&gt; shall flow away in the day of his wrath.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the portion of a wicked man from God, and the heritage appointed unto him by God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>