<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="19" verseCount="29" nextChapter="job_20.html" nextTitle="Job 20" prevChapter="job_18.html" prevTitle="Job 18" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then Job answered and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">How long will ye vex my soul, and break me in pieces with words?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">These ten times have ye reproached me: ye are not ashamed &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; ye make yourselves strange to me.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And be it indeed &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I have erred, mine error remaineth with myself.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">If indeed ye will magnify &lt;i&gt;yourselves&lt;/i&gt; against me, and plead against me my reproach:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Know now that God hath overthrown me, and hath compassed me with his net.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Behold, I cry out of wrong, but I am not heard: I cry aloud, but &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He hath fenced up my way that I cannot pass, and he hath set darkness in my paths.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He hath stripped me of my glory, and taken the crown &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; my head.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He hath destroyed me on every side, and I am gone: and mine hope hath he removed like a tree.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He hath also kindled his wrath against me, and he counteth me unto him as &lt;i&gt;one of&lt;/i&gt; his enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">His troops come together, and raise up their way against me, and encamp round about my tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He hath put my brethren far from me, and mine acquaintance are verily estranged from me.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">My kinsfolk have failed, and my familiar friends have forgotten me.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">They that dwell in mine house, and my maids, count me for a stranger: I am an alien in their sight.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I called my servant, and he gave &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; no answer; I intreated him with my mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">My breath is strange to my wife, though I intreated for the children's &lt;i&gt;sake&lt;/i&gt; of mine own body.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Yea, young children despised me; I arose, and they spake against me.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">All my inward friends abhorred me: and they whom I loved are turned against me.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">My bone cleaveth to my skin and to my flesh, and I am escaped with the skin of my teeth.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Have pity upon me, have pity upon me, O ye my friends; for the hand of God hath touched me.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Why do ye persecute me as God, and are not satisfied with my flesh?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Oh that my words were now written! oh that they were printed in a book!</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">That they were graven with an iron pen and lead in the rock for ever!</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For I know &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; my redeemer liveth, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; he shall stand at the latter &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; upon the earth:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And &lt;i&gt;though&lt;/i&gt; after my skin &lt;i&gt;worms&lt;/i&gt; destroy this &lt;i&gt;body&lt;/i&gt;, yet in my flesh shall I see God:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Whom I shall see for myself, and mine eyes shall behold, and not another; &lt;i&gt;though&lt;/i&gt; my reins be consumed within me.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">But ye should say, Why persecute we him, seeing the root of the matter is found in me?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Be ye afraid of the sword: for wrath &lt;i&gt;bringeth&lt;/i&gt; the punishments of the sword, that ye may know &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; a judgment.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>