<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="22" nextChapter="job_17.html" nextTitle="Job 17" prevChapter="job_15.html" prevTitle="Job 15" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then Job answered and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I have heard many such things: miserable comforters &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; ye all.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Shall vain words have an end? or what emboldeneth thee that thou answerest?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I also could speak as ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;: if your soul were in my soul's stead, I could heap up words against you, and shake mine head at you.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;But&lt;/span&gt; I would strengthen you with my mouth, and the moving of my lips should asswage &lt;span class='extra'&gt;your grief&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Though I speak, my grief is not asswaged: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;though&lt;/span&gt; I forbear, what am I eased?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But now he hath made me weary: thou hast made desolate all my company.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And thou hast filled me with wrinkles, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; is a witness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;against me&lt;/span&gt;: and my leanness rising up in me beareth witness to my face.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He teareth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; in his wrath, who hateth me: he gnasheth upon me with his teeth; mine enemy sharpeneth his eyes upon me.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">They have gaped upon me with their mouth; they have smitten me upon the cheek reproachfully; they have gathered themselves together against me.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">God hath delivered me to the ungodly, and turned me over into the hands of the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I was at ease, but he hath broken me asunder: he hath also taken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; by my neck, and shaken me to pieces, and set me up for his mark.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">His archers compass me round about, he cleaveth my reins asunder, and doth not spare; he poureth out my gall upon the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">He breaketh me with breach upon breach, he runneth upon me like a giant.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I have sewed sackcloth upon my skin, and defiled my horn in the dust.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">My face is foul with weeping, and on my eyelids &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the shadow of death;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Not for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; injustice in mine hands: also my prayer &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; pure.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">O earth, cover not thou my blood, and let my cry have no place.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Also now, behold, my witness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in heaven, and my record &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; on high.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">My friends scorn me: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; mine eye poureth out &lt;span class='extra'&gt;tears&lt;/span&gt; unto God.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">O that one might plead for a man with God, as a man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;pleadeth&lt;/span&gt; for his neighbour!</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">When a few years are come, then I shall go the way &lt;span class='extra'&gt;whence&lt;/span&gt; I shall not return.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>