<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="28" nextChapter="job_14.html" nextTitle="Job 14" prevChapter="job_12.html" prevTitle="Job 12" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Lo, mine eye hath seen all &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt;, mine ear hath heard and understood it.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">What ye know, &lt;i&gt;the same&lt;/i&gt; do I know also: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; not inferior unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Surely I would speak to the Almighty, and I desire to reason with God.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; forgers of lies, ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; all physicians of no value.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">O that ye would altogether hold your peace! and it should be your wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Hear now my reasoning, and hearken to the pleadings of my lips.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Will ye speak wickedly for God? and talk deceitfully for him?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Will ye accept his person? will ye contend for God?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Is it good that he should search you out? or as one man mocketh another, do ye &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; mock him?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He will surely reprove you, if ye do secretly accept persons.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Shall not his excellency make you afraid? and his dread fall upon you?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Your remembrances &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; like unto ashes, your bodies to bodies of clay.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Hold your peace, let me alone, that I may speak, and let come on me what &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Wherefore do I take my flesh in my teeth, and put my life in mine hand?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Though he slay me, yet will I trust in him: but I will maintain mine own ways before him.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He also &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; my salvation: for an hypocrite shall not come before him.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Hear diligently my speech, and my declaration with your ears.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Behold now, I have ordered &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; cause; I know that I shall be justified.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; will plead with me? for now, if I hold my tongue, I shall give up the ghost.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Only do not two &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; unto me: then will I not hide myself from thee.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Withdraw thine hand far from me: and let not thy dread make me afraid.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then call thou, and I will answer: or let me speak, and answer thou me.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">How many &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; mine iniquities and sins? make me to know my transgression and my sin.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Wherefore hidest thou thy face, and holdest me for thine enemy?</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Wilt thou break a leaf driven to and fro? and wilt thou pursue the dry stubble?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For thou writest bitter things against me, and makest me to possess the iniquities of my youth.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Thou puttest my feet also in the stocks, and lookest narrowly unto all my paths; thou settest a print upon the heels of my feet.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he, as a rotten thing, consumeth, as a garment that is moth eaten.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>