<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="21" verseCount="34" nextChapter="job_22.html" nextTitle="Job 22" prevChapter="job_20.html" prevTitle="Job 20" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">But Job answered and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Hear diligently my speech, and let this be your consolations.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Suffer me that I may speak; and after that I have spoken, mock on.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">As for me, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my complaint to man? and if &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it were so&lt;/span&gt;, why should not my spirit be troubled?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Mark me, and be astonished, and lay &lt;span class='extra'&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; hand upon &lt;span class='extra'&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Even when I remember I am afraid, and trembling taketh hold on my flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Wherefore do the wicked live, become old, yea, are mighty in power?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Their seed is established in their sight with them, and their offspring before their eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Their houses &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; safe from fear, neither &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the rod of God upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Their bull gendereth, and faileth not; their cow calveth, and casteth not her calf.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">They send forth their little ones like a flock, and their children dance.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They take the timbrel and harp, and rejoice at the sound of the organ.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">They spend their days in wealth, and in a moment go down to the grave.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Therefore they say unto God, Depart from us; for we desire not the knowledge of thy ways.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the Almighty, that we should serve him? and what profit should we have, if we pray unto him?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Lo, their good &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not in their hand: the counsel of the wicked is far from me.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">How oft is the candle of the wicked put out! and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;how oft&lt;/span&gt; cometh their destruction upon them! &lt;span class='extra'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; distributeth sorrows in his anger.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">They are as stubble before the wind, and as chaff that the storm carrieth away.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">God layeth up his iniquity for his children: he rewardeth him, and he shall know &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">His eyes shall see his destruction, and he shall drink of the wrath of the Almighty.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For what pleasure &lt;span class='extra'&gt;hath&lt;/span&gt; he in his house after him, when the number of his months is cut off in the midst?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Shall &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; teach God knowledge? seeing he judgeth those that are high.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">One dieth in his full strength, being wholly at ease and quiet.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">His breasts are full of milk, and his bones are moistened with marrow.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And another dieth in the bitterness of his soul, and never eateth with pleasure.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">They shall lie down alike in the dust, and the worms shall cover them.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Behold, I know your thoughts, and the devices &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; ye wrongfully imagine against me.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">For ye say, Where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the house of the prince? and where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the dwelling places of the wicked?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Have ye not asked them that go by the way? and do ye not know their tokens,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">That the wicked is reserved to the day of destruction? they shall be brought forth to the day of wrath.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Who shall declare his way to his face? and who shall repay him &lt;span class='extra'&gt;what&lt;/span&gt; he hath done?</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Yet shall he be brought to the grave, and shall remain in the tomb.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">The clods of the valley shall be sweet unto him, and every man shall draw after him, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there are&lt;/span&gt; innumerable before him.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">How then comfort ye me in vain, seeing in your answers there remaineth falsehood?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>