<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="30" verseCount="31" nextChapter="job_31.html" nextTitle="Job 31" prevChapter="job_29.html" prevTitle="Job 29" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">But now &lt;i&gt;they that are&lt;/i&gt; younger than I have me in derision, whose fathers I would have disdained to have set with the dogs of my flock.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Yea, whereto &lt;i&gt;might&lt;/i&gt; the strength of their hands &lt;i&gt;profit&lt;/i&gt; me, in whom old age was perished?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For want and famine &lt;i&gt;they were&lt;/i&gt; solitary; fleeing into the wilderness in former time desolate and waste.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Who cut up mallows by the bushes, and juniper roots &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; their meat.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They were driven forth from among &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;, (they cried after them as &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; a thief;)</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">To dwell in the clifts of the valleys, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; caves of the earth, and &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the rocks.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Among the bushes they brayed; under the nettles they were gathered together.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;i&gt;They were&lt;/i&gt; children of fools, yea, children of base men: they were viler than the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And now am I their song, yea, I am their byword.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">They abhor me, they flee far from me, and spare not to spit in my face.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Because he hath loosed my cord, and afflicted me, they have also let loose the bridle before me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Upon &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; right &lt;i&gt;hand&lt;/i&gt; rise the youth; they push away my feet, and they raise up against me the ways of their destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">They mar my path, they set forward my calamity, they have no helper.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">They came &lt;i&gt;upon me&lt;/i&gt; as a wide breaking in &lt;i&gt;of waters&lt;/i&gt;: in the desolation they rolled themselves &lt;i&gt;upon me&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Terrors are turned upon me: they pursue my soul as the wind: and my welfare passeth away as a cloud.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And now my soul is poured out upon me; the days of affliction have taken hold upon me.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">My bones are pierced in me in the night season: and my sinews take no rest.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">By the great force &lt;i&gt;of my disease&lt;/i&gt; is my garment changed: it bindeth me about as the collar of my coat.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He hath cast me into the mire, and I am become like dust and ashes.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">I cry unto thee, and thou dost not hear me: I stand up, and thou regardest me &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Thou art become cruel to me: with thy strong hand thou opposest thyself against me.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Thou liftest me up to the wind; thou causest me to ride &lt;i&gt;upon it&lt;/i&gt;, and dissolvest my substance.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For I know &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thou wilt bring me &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; death, and &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; the house appointed for all living.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Howbeit he will not stretch out &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; hand to the grave, though they cry in his destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Did not I weep for him that was in trouble? was &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; my soul grieved for the poor?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">When I looked for good, then evil came &lt;i&gt;unto me&lt;/i&gt;: and when I waited for light, there came darkness.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">My bowels boiled, and rested not: the days of affliction prevented me.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">I went mourning without the sun: I stood up, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; I cried in the congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">I am a brother to dragons, and a companion to owls.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">My skin is black upon me, and my bones are burned with heat.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">My harp also is &lt;i&gt;turned&lt;/i&gt; to mourning, and my organ into the voice of them that weep.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>