<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="26" verseCount="14" nextChapter="job_27.html" nextTitle="Job 27" prevChapter="job_25.html" prevTitle="Job 25" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">But Job answered and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">How hast thou helped &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him that is&lt;/span&gt; without power? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;how&lt;/span&gt; savest thou the arm &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that hath&lt;/span&gt; no strength?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">How hast thou counselled &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him that hath&lt;/span&gt; no wisdom? and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;how&lt;/span&gt; hast thou plentifully declared the thing as it is?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">To whom hast thou uttered words? and whose spirit came from thee?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Dead &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; are formed from under the waters, and the inhabitants thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Hell &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; naked before him, and destruction hath no covering.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He stretcheth out the north over the empty place, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; hangeth the earth upon nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He bindeth up the waters in his thick clouds; and the cloud is not rent under them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He holdeth back the face of his throne, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; spreadeth his cloud upon it.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He hath compassed the waters with bounds, until the day and night come to an end.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The pillars of heaven tremble and are astonished at his reproof.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">He divideth the sea with his power, and by his understanding he smiteth through the proud.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">By his spirit he hath garnished the heavens; his hand hath formed the crooked serpent.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Lo, these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; parts of his ways: but how little a portion is heard of him? but the thunder of his power who can understand?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>