<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="28" verseCount="28" nextChapter="job_29.html" nextTitle="Job 29" prevChapter="job_27.html" prevTitle="Job 27" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Surely there is a vein for the silver, and a place for gold &lt;i&gt;where&lt;/i&gt; they fine &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Iron is taken out of the earth, and brass &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; molten &lt;i&gt;out of&lt;/i&gt; the stone.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">He setteth an end to darkness, and searcheth out all perfection: the stones of darkness, and the shadow of death.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The flood breaketh out from the inhabitant; &lt;i&gt;even the waters&lt;/i&gt; forgotten of the foot: they are dried up, they are gone away from men.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;i&gt;As for&lt;/i&gt; the earth, out of it cometh bread: and under it is turned up as it were fire.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The stones of it &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the place of sapphires: and it hath dust of gold.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; a path which no fowl knoweth, and which the vulture's eye hath not seen:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The lion's whelps have not trodden it, nor the fierce lion passed by it.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He putteth forth his hand upon the rock; he overturneth the mountains by the roots.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He cutteth out rivers among the rocks; and his eye seeth every precious thing.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He bindeth the floods from overflowing; and &lt;i&gt;the thing that is&lt;/i&gt; hid bringeth he forth to light.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But where shall wisdom be found? and where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the place of understanding?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Man knoweth not the price thereof; neither is it found in the land of the living.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The depth saith, It &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not in me: and the sea saith, &lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; not with me.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">It cannot be gotten for gold, neither shall silver be weighed &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; the price thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">It cannot be valued with the gold of Ophir, with the precious onyx, or the sapphire.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The gold and the crystal cannot equal it: and the exchange of it &lt;i&gt;shall not be for&lt;/i&gt; jewels of fine gold.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">No mention shall be made of coral, or of pearls: for the price of wisdom &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; above rubies.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The topaz of Ethiopia shall not equal it, neither shall it be valued with pure gold.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Whence then cometh wisdom? and where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the place of understanding?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Seeing it is hid from the eyes of all living, and kept close from the fowls of the air.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Destruction and death say, We have heard the fame thereof with our ears.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">God understandeth the way thereof, and he knoweth the place thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For he looketh to the ends of the earth, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; seeth under the whole heaven;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">To make the weight for the winds; and he weigheth the waters by measure.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">When he made a decree for the rain, and a way for the lightning of the thunder:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Then did he see it, and declare it; he prepared it, yea, and searched it out.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And unto man he said, Behold, the fear of the Lord, that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; wisdom; and to depart from evil &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; understanding.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>