<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="27" verseCount="23" nextChapter="job_28.html" nextTitle="Job 28" prevChapter="job_26.html" prevTitle="Job 26" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover Job continued his parable, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; God liveth, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;who&lt;/span&gt; hath taken away my judgment; and the Almighty, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;who&lt;/span&gt; hath vexed my soul;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">All the while my breath &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in me, and the spirit of God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in my nostrils;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">My lips shall not speak wickedness, nor my tongue utter deceit.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">God forbid that I should justify you: till I die I will not remove mine integrity from me.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">My righteousness I hold fast, and will not let it go: my heart shall not reproach &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; so long as I live.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Let mine enemy be as the wicked, and he that riseth up against me as the unrighteous.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the hope of the hypocrite, though he hath gained, when God taketh away his soul?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Will God hear his cry when trouble cometh upon him?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Will he delight himself in the Almighty? will he always call upon God?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">I will teach you by the hand of God: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with the Almighty will I not conceal.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Behold, all ye yourselves have seen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;; why then are ye thus altogether vain?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the portion of a wicked man with God, and the heritage of oppressors, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; they shall receive of the Almighty.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">If his children be multiplied, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; for the sword: and his offspring shall not be satisfied with bread.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Those that remain of him shall be buried in death: and his widows shall not weep.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Though he heap up silver as the dust, and prepare raiment as the clay;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He may prepare &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, but the just shall put &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on, and the innocent shall divide the silver.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He buildeth his house as a moth, and as a booth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the keeper maketh.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The rich man shall lie down, but he shall not be gathered: he openeth his eyes, and he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Terrors take hold on him as waters, a tempest stealeth him away in the night.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The east wind carrieth him away, and he departeth: and as a storm hurleth him out of his place.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For &lt;span class='extra'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; shall cast upon him, and not spare: he would fain flee out of his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Men&lt;/span&gt; shall clap their hands at him, and shall hiss him out of his place.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>