<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="29" verseCount="25" nextChapter="job_30.html" nextTitle="Job 30" prevChapter="job_28.html" prevTitle="Job 28" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover Job continued his parable, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Oh that I were as &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; months past, as &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the days &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; God preserved me;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">When his candle shined upon my head, &lt;i&gt;and when&lt;/i&gt; by his light I walked &lt;i&gt;through&lt;/i&gt; darkness;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">As I was in the days of my youth, when the secret of God &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; upon my tabernacle;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">When the Almighty &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; yet with me, &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; my children &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; about me;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">When I washed my steps with butter, and the rock poured me out rivers of oil;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">When I went out to the gate through the city, &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; I prepared my seat in the street!</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The young men saw me, and hid themselves: and the aged arose, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; stood up.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The princes refrained talking, and laid &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; hand on their mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The nobles held their peace, and their tongue cleaved to the roof of their mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">When the ear heard &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt;, then it blessed me; and when the eye saw &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt;, it gave witness to me:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Because I delivered the poor that cried, and the fatherless, and &lt;i&gt;him that had&lt;/i&gt; none to help him.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The blessing of him that was ready to perish came upon me: and I caused the widow's heart to sing for joy.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I put on righteousness, and it clothed me: my judgment &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; as a robe and a diadem.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I was eyes to the blind, and feet &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; I to the lame.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a father to the poor: and the cause &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; I knew not I searched out.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And I brake the jaws of the wicked, and plucked the spoil out of his teeth.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Then I said, I shall die in my nest, and I shall multiply &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; days as the sand.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">My root &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; spread out by the waters, and the dew lay all night upon my branch.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">My glory &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; fresh in me, and my bow was renewed in my hand.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Unto me &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; gave ear, and waited, and kept silence at my counsel.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">After my words they spake not again; and my speech dropped upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And they waited for me as for the rain; and they opened their mouth wide &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; for the latter rain.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;i&gt;If&lt;/i&gt; I laughed on them, they believed &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not; and the light of my countenance they cast not down.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">I chose out their way, and sat chief, and dwelt as a king in the army, as one &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; comforteth the mourners.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>