<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="40" verseCount="24" nextChapter="job_41.html" nextTitle="Job 41" prevChapter="job_39.html" prevTitle="Job 39" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; answered Job, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Shall he that contendeth with the Almighty instruct &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;? he that reproveth God, let him answer it.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Then Job answered the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Behold, I am vile; what shall I answer thee? I will lay mine hand upon my mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Once have I spoken; but I will not answer: yea, twice; but I will proceed no further.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Then answered the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto Job out of the whirlwind, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Gird up thy loins now like a man: I will demand of thee, and declare thou unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Wilt thou also disannul my judgment? wilt thou condemn me, that thou mayest be righteous?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Hast thou an arm like God? or canst thou thunder with a voice like him?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Deck thyself now &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; majesty and excellency; and array thyself with glory and beauty.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Cast abroad the rage of thy wrath: and behold every one &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; proud, and abase him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Look on every one &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; proud, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; bring him low; and tread down the wicked in their place.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Hide them in the dust together; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; bind their faces in secret.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then will I also confess unto thee that thine own right hand can save thee.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Behold now behemoth, which I made with thee; he eateth grass as an ox.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Lo now, his strength &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in his loins, and his force &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the navel of his belly.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He moveth his tail like a cedar: the sinews of his stones are wrapped together.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">His bones &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are as&lt;/span&gt; strong pieces of brass; his bones &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; like bars of iron.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the chief of the ways of God: he that made him can make his sword to approach &lt;span class="extra"&gt;unto him&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Surely the mountains bring him forth food, where all the beasts of the field play.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">He lieth under the shady trees, in the covert of the reed, and fens.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The shady trees cover him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; their shadow; the willows of the brook compass him about.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Behold, he drinketh up a river, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; hasteth not: he trusteth that he can draw up Jordan into his mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">He taketh it with his eyes: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; nose pierceth through snares.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>