<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="32" verseCount="22" nextChapter="job_33.html" nextTitle="Job 33" prevChapter="job_31.html" prevTitle="Job 31" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">So these three men ceased to answer Job, because he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; righteous in his own eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then was kindled the wrath of Elihu the son of Barachel the Buzite, of the kindred of Ram: against Job was his wrath kindled, because he justified himself rather than God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Also against his three friends was his wrath kindled, because they had found no answer, and &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; had condemned Job.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Now Elihu had waited till Job had spoken, because they &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; elder than he.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">When Elihu saw that &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; no answer in the mouth of &lt;i&gt;these&lt;/i&gt; three men, then his wrath was kindled.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Elihu the son of Barachel the Buzite answered and said, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; young, and ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; very old; wherefore I was afraid, and durst not shew you mine opinion.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">I said, Days should speak, and multitude of years should teach wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; a spirit in man: and the inspiration of the Almighty giveth them understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Great men are not &lt;i&gt;always&lt;/i&gt; wise: neither do the aged understand judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Therefore I said, Hearken to me; I also will shew mine opinion.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Behold, I waited for your words; I gave ear to your reasons, whilst ye searched out what to say.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Yea, I attended unto you, and, behold, &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; none of you that convinced Job, &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; that answered his words:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Lest ye should say, We have found out wisdom: God thrusteth him down, not man.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Now he hath not directed &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; words against me: neither will I answer him with your speeches.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">They were amazed, they answered no more: they left off speaking.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">When I had waited, (for they spake not, but stood still, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; answered no more;)</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;i&gt;I said&lt;/i&gt;, I will answer also my part, I also will shew mine opinion.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For I am full of matter, the spirit within me constraineth me.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Behold, my belly &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as wine &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; hath no vent; it is ready to burst like new bottles.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">I will speak, that I may be refreshed: I will open my lips and answer.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Let me not, I pray you, accept any man's person, neither let me give flattering titles unto man.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For I know not to give flattering titles; &lt;i&gt;in so doing&lt;/i&gt; my maker would soon take me away.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>