<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="21" nextChapter="job_8.html" nextTitle="Job 8" prevChapter="job_6.html" prevTitle="Job 6" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is there&lt;/span&gt; not an appointed time to man upon earth? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are not&lt;/span&gt; his days also like the days of an hireling?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">As a servant earnestly desireth the shadow, and as an hireling looketh for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the reward of&lt;/span&gt; his work:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">So am I made to possess months of vanity, and wearisome nights are appointed to me.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">When I lie down, I say, When shall I arise, and the night be gone? and I am full of tossings to and fro unto the dawning of the day.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">My flesh is clothed with worms and clods of dust; my skin is broken, and become loathsome.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">My days are swifter than a weaver's shuttle, and are spent without hope.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">O remember that my life &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; wind: mine eye shall no more see good.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The eye of him that hath seen me shall see me no &lt;span class='extra'&gt;more&lt;/span&gt;: thine eyes &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; upon me, and I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; not.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; the cloud is consumed and vanisheth away: so he that goeth down to the grave shall come up no &lt;span class='extra'&gt;more&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He shall return no more to his house, neither shall his place know him any more.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Therefore I will not refrain my mouth; I will speak in the anguish of my spirit; I will complain in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Am&lt;/span&gt; I a sea, or a whale, that thou settest a watch over me?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">When I say, My bed shall comfort me, my couch shall ease my complaint;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then thou scarest me with dreams, and terrifiest me through visions:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So that my soul chooseth strangling, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; death rather than my life.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I loathe &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;; I would not live alway: let me alone; for my days &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; man, that thou shouldest magnify him? and that thou shouldest set thine heart upon him?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thou shouldest visit him every morning, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; try him every moment?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">How long wilt thou not depart from me, nor let me alone till I swallow down my spittle?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">I have sinned; what shall I do unto thee, O thou preserver of men? why hast thou set me as a mark against thee, so that I am a burden to myself?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And why dost thou not pardon my transgression, and take away mine iniquity? for now shall I sleep in the dust; and thou shalt seek me in the morning, but I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>