<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="35" nextChapter="job_16.html" nextTitle="Job 16" prevChapter="job_14.html" prevTitle="Job 14" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then answered Eliphaz the Temanite, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Should a wise man utter vain knowledge, and fill his belly with the east wind?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Should he reason with unprofitable talk? or with speeches wherewith he can do no good?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Yea, thou castest off fear, and restrainest prayer before God.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For thy mouth uttereth thine iniquity, and thou choosest the tongue of the crafty.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thine own mouth condemneth thee, and not I: yea, thine own lips testify against thee.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Art&lt;/span&gt; thou the first man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; was born? or wast thou made before the hills?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Hast thou heard the secret of God? and dost thou restrain wisdom to thyself?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">What knowest thou, that we know not? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;what&lt;/span&gt; understandest thou, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not in us?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">With us &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; both the grayheaded and very aged men, much elder than thy father.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Are&lt;/span&gt; the consolations of God small with thee? is there any secret thing with thee?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Why doth thine heart carry thee away? and what do thy eyes wink at,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">That thou turnest thy spirit against God, and lettest &lt;span class="extra"&gt;such&lt;/span&gt; words go out of thy mouth?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">What &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; man, that he should be clean? and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he which is&lt;/span&gt; born of a woman, that he should be righteous?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Behold, he putteth no trust in his saints; yea, the heavens are not clean in his sight.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">How much more abominable and filthy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; man, which drinketh iniquity like water?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">I will shew thee, hear me; and that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; I have seen I will declare;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Which wise men have told from their fathers, and have not hid &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Unto whom alone the earth was given, and no stranger passed among them.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The wicked man travaileth with pain all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; days, and the number of years is hidden to the oppressor.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">A dreadful sound &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in his ears: in prosperity the destroyer shall come upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">He believeth not that he shall return out of darkness, and he is waited for of the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">He wandereth abroad for bread, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt;? he knoweth that the day of darkness is ready at his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Trouble and anguish shall make him afraid; they shall prevail against him, as a king ready to the battle.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For he stretcheth out his hand against God, and strengtheneth himself against the Almighty.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">He runneth upon him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; neck, upon the thick bosses of his bucklers:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Because he covereth his face with his fatness, and maketh collops of fat on &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; flanks.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he dwelleth in desolate cities, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; in houses which no man inhabiteth, which are ready to become heaps.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">He shall not be rich, neither shall his substance continue, neither shall he prolong the perfection thereof upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">He shall not depart out of darkness; the flame shall dry up his branches, and by the breath of his mouth shall he go away.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Let not him that is deceived trust in vanity: for vanity shall be his recompence.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">It shall be accomplished before his time, and his branch shall not be green.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">He shall shake off his unripe grape as the vine, and shall cast off his flower as the olive.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">For the congregation of hypocrites &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; desolate, and fire shall consume the tabernacles of bribery.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">They conceive mischief, and bring forth vanity, and their belly prepareth deceit.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>