<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="36" verseCount="33" nextChapter="job_37.html" nextTitle="Job 37" prevChapter="job_35.html" prevTitle="Job 35" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Elihu also proceeded, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Suffer me a little, and I will shew thee that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;I have&lt;/span&gt; yet to speak on God's behalf.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I will fetch my knowledge from afar, and will ascribe righteousness to my Maker.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For truly my words &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; false: he that is perfect in knowledge &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Behold, God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mighty, and despiseth not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any: he is&lt;/span&gt; mighty in strength &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He preserveth not the life of the wicked: but giveth right to the poor.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He withdraweth not his eyes from the righteous: but with kings &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are they&lt;/span&gt; on the throne; yea, he doth establish them for ever, and they are exalted.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And if &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they be&lt;/span&gt; bound in fetters, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; be holden in cords of affliction;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then he sheweth them their work, and their transgressions that they have exceeded.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He openeth also their ear to discipline, and commandeth that they return from iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">If they obey and serve &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, they shall spend their days in prosperity, and their years in pleasures.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But if they obey not, they shall perish by the sword, and they shall die without knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But the hypocrites in heart heap up wrath: they cry not when he bindeth them.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">They die in youth, and their life &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; among the unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He delivereth the poor in his affliction, and openeth their ears in oppression.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Even so would he have removed thee out of the strait &lt;span class='extra'&gt;into&lt;/span&gt; a broad place, where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no straitness; and that which should be set on thy table &lt;span class='extra'&gt;should be&lt;/span&gt; full of fatness.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But thou hast fulfilled the judgment of the wicked: judgment and justice take hold &lt;span class='extra'&gt;on thee&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Because &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; wrath, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;beware&lt;/span&gt; lest he take thee away with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; stroke: then a great ransom cannot deliver thee.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Will he esteem thy riches? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;no&lt;/span&gt;, not gold, nor all the forces of strength.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Desire not the night, when people are cut off in their place.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Take heed, regard not iniquity: for this hast thou chosen rather than affliction.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Behold, God exalteth by his power: who teacheth like him?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Who hath enjoined him his way? or who can say, Thou hast wrought iniquity?</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Remember that thou magnify his work, which men behold.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Every man may see it; man may behold &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; afar off.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Behold, God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; great, and we know &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; not, neither can the number of his years be searched out.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For he maketh small the drops of water: they pour down rain according to the vapour thereof:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Which the clouds do drop &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; distil upon man abundantly.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Also can &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; understand the spreadings of the clouds, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; the noise of his tabernacle?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Behold, he spreadeth his light upon it, and covereth the bottom of the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">For by them judgeth he the people; he giveth meat in abundance.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">With clouds he covereth the light; and commandeth it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;not to shine&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the cloud&lt;/span&gt; that cometh betwixt.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">The noise thereof sheweth concerning it, the cattle also concerning the vapour.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>