<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="20" nextChapter="job_12.html" nextTitle="Job 12" prevChapter="job_10.html" prevTitle="Job 10" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then answered Zophar the Naamathite, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Should not the multitude of words be answered? and should a man full of talk be justified?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Should thy lies make men hold their peace? and when thou mockest, shall no man make thee ashamed?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For thou hast said, My doctrine &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; pure, and I am clean in thine eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But oh that God would speak, and open his lips against thee;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And that he would shew thee the secrets of wisdom, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they are&lt;/span&gt; double to that which is! Know therefore that God exacteth of thee &lt;span class='extra'&gt;less&lt;/span&gt; than thine iniquity &lt;span class='extra'&gt;deserveth&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Canst thou by searching find out God? canst thou find out the Almighty unto perfection?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; as high as heaven; what canst thou do? deeper than hell; what canst thou know?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The measure thereof &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; longer than the earth, and broader than the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">If he cut off, and shut up, or gather together, then who can hinder him?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For he knoweth vain men: he seeth wickedness also; will he not then consider &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For vain man would be wise, though man be born &lt;span class='extra'&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; a wild ass's colt.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">If thou prepare thine heart, and stretch out thine hands toward him;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">If iniquity &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in thine hand, put it far away, and let not wickedness dwell in thy tabernacles.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For then shalt thou lift up thy face without spot; yea, thou shalt be stedfast, and shalt not fear:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Because thou shalt forget &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; misery, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; remember &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; as waters &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; pass away:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thine&lt;/span&gt; age shall be clearer than the noonday; thou shalt shine forth, thou shalt be as the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And thou shalt be secure, because there is hope; yea, thou shalt dig &lt;span class='extra'&gt;about thee, and&lt;/span&gt; thou shalt take thy rest in safety.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Also thou shalt lie down, and none shall make &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt; afraid; yea, many shall make suit unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But the eyes of the wicked shall fail, and they shall not escape, and their hope &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be as&lt;/span&gt; the giving up of the ghost.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>