<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="22" nextChapter="job_11.html" nextTitle="Job 11" prevChapter="job_9.html" prevTitle="Job 9" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">My soul is weary of my life; I will leave my complaint upon myself; I will speak in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I will say unto God, Do not condemn me; shew me wherefore thou contendest with me.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;i&gt;Is it&lt;/i&gt; good unto thee that thou shouldest oppress, that thou shouldest despise the work of thine hands, and shine upon the counsel of the wicked?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Hast thou eyes of flesh? or seest thou as man seeth?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;i&gt;Are&lt;/i&gt; thy days as the days of man? &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; thy years as man's days,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">That thou enquirest after mine iniquity, and searchest after my sin?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thou knowest that I am not wicked; and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none that can deliver out of thine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Thine hands have made me and fashioned me together round about; yet thou dost destroy me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Remember, I beseech thee, that thou hast made me as the clay; and wilt thou bring me into dust again?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Hast thou not poured me out as milk, and curdled me like cheese?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thou hast clothed me with skin and flesh, and hast fenced me with bones and sinews.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Thou hast granted me life and favour, and thy visitation hath preserved my spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And these &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; hast thou hid in thine heart: I know that this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">If I sin, then thou markest me, and thou wilt not acquit me from mine iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">If I be wicked, woe unto me; and &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; I be righteous, &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; will I not lift up my head. &lt;i&gt;I am&lt;/i&gt; full of confusion; therefore see thou mine affliction;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For it increaseth. Thou huntest me as a fierce lion: and again thou shewest thyself marvellous upon me.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thou renewest thy witnesses against me, and increasest thine indignation upon me; changes and war &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; against me.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Wherefore then hast thou brought me forth out of the womb? Oh that I had given up the ghost, and no eye had seen me!</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">I should have been as though I had not been; I should have been carried from the womb to the grave.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;i&gt;Are&lt;/i&gt; not my days few? cease &lt;i&gt;then, and&lt;/i&gt; let me alone, that I may take comfort a little,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Before I go &lt;i&gt;whence&lt;/i&gt; I shall not return, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to the land of darkness and the shadow of death;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">A land of darkness, as darkness &lt;i&gt;itself; and&lt;/i&gt; of the shadow of death, without any order, and &lt;i&gt;where&lt;/i&gt; the light &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as darkness.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>