<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="35" verseCount="16" nextChapter="job_36.html" nextTitle="Job 36" prevChapter="job_34.html" prevTitle="Job 34" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Elihu spake moreover, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thinkest thou this to be right, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thou saidst, My righteousness &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; more than God's?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For thou saidst, What advantage will it be unto thee? &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt;, What profit shall I have, &lt;i&gt;if I be cleansed&lt;/i&gt; from my sin?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I will answer thee, and thy companions with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Look unto the heavens, and see; and behold the clouds &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; are higher than thou.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">If thou sinnest, what doest thou against him? or &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; thy transgressions be multiplied, what doest thou unto him?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">If thou be righteous, what givest thou him? or what receiveth he of thine hand?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Thy wickedness &lt;i&gt;may hurt&lt;/i&gt; a man as thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt;; and thy righteousness &lt;i&gt;may profit&lt;/i&gt; the son of man.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">By reason of the multitude of oppressions they make &lt;i&gt;the oppressed&lt;/i&gt; to cry: they cry out by reason of the arm of the mighty.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But none saith, Where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; God my maker, who giveth songs in the night;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Who teacheth us more than the beasts of the earth, and maketh us wiser than the fowls of heaven?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">There they cry, but none giveth answer, because of the pride of evil men.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Surely God will not hear vanity, neither will the Almighty regard it.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Although thou sayest thou shalt not see him, &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; judgment &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; before him; therefore trust thou in him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But now, because &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt;, he hath visited in his anger; yet he knoweth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not in great extremity:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Therefore doth Job open his mouth in vain; he multiplieth words without knowledge.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>