<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="22" nextChapter="job_9.html" nextTitle="Job 9" prevChapter="job_7.html" prevTitle="Job 7" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then answered Bildad the Shuhite, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">How long wilt thou speak these &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt;? and &lt;i&gt;how long shall&lt;/i&gt; the words of thy mouth &lt;i&gt;be like&lt;/i&gt; a strong wind?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Doth God pervert judgment? or doth the Almighty pervert justice?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">If thy children have sinned against him, and he have cast them away for their transgression;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">If thou wouldest seek unto God betimes, and make thy supplication to the Almighty;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">If thou &lt;i&gt;wert&lt;/i&gt; pure and upright; surely now he would awake for thee, and make the habitation of thy righteousness prosperous.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Though thy beginning was small, yet thy latter end should greatly increase.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For enquire, I pray thee, of the former age, and prepare thyself to the search of their fathers:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">(For we &lt;i&gt;are but of&lt;/i&gt; yesterday, and know nothing, because our days upon earth &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; a shadow:)</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Shall not they teach thee, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; tell thee, and utter words out of their heart?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Can the rush grow up without mire? can the flag grow without water?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Whilst it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; yet in his greenness, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; not cut down, it withereth before any &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; herb.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">So &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the paths of all that forget God; and the hypocrite's hope shall perish:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Whose hope shall be cut off, and whose trust &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; a spider's web.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He shall lean upon his house, but it shall not stand: he shall hold it fast, but it shall not endure.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; green before the sun, and his branch shooteth forth in his garden.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">His roots are wrapped about the heap, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; seeth the place of stones.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">If he destroy him from his place, then &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; shall deny him, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;, I have not seen thee.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Behold, this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the joy of his way, and out of the earth shall others grow.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Behold, God will not cast away a perfect &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;, neither will he help the evil doers:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Till he fill thy mouth with laughing, and thy lips with rejoicing.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">They that hate thee shall be clothed with shame; and the dwelling place of the wicked shall come to nought.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>