<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="38" verseCount="41" nextChapter="job_39.html" nextTitle="Job 39" prevChapter="job_37.html" prevTitle="Job 37" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; answered Job out of the whirlwind, and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this that darkeneth counsel by words without knowledge?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Gird up now thy loins like a man; for I will demand of thee, and answer thou me.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Where wast thou when I laid the foundations of the earth? declare, if thou hast understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Who hath laid the measures thereof, if thou knowest? or who hath stretched the line upon it?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Whereupon are the foundations thereof fastened? or who laid the corner stone thereof;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">When the morning stars sang together, and all the sons of God shouted for joy?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Or &lt;span class='extra'&gt;who&lt;/span&gt; shut up the sea with doors, when it brake forth, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as if&lt;/span&gt; it had issued out of the womb?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">When I made the cloud the garment thereof, and thick darkness a swaddlingband for it,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And brake up for it my decreed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;, and set bars and doors,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And said, Hitherto shalt thou come, but no further: and here shall thy proud waves be stayed?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Hast thou commanded the morning since thy days; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; caused the dayspring to know his place;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">That it might take hold of the ends of the earth, that the wicked might be shaken out of it?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">It is turned as clay &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the seal; and they stand as a garment.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And from the wicked their light is withholden, and the high arm shall be broken.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Hast thou entered into the springs of the sea? or hast thou walked in the search of the depth?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Have the gates of death been opened unto thee? or hast thou seen the doors of the shadow of death?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Hast thou perceived the breadth of the earth? declare if thou knowest it all.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the way &lt;span class='extra'&gt;where&lt;/span&gt; light dwelleth? and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; darkness, where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the place thereof,</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">That thou shouldest take it to the bound thereof, and that thou shouldest know the paths &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the house thereof?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Knowest thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, because thou wast then born? or &lt;span class='extra'&gt;because&lt;/span&gt; the number of thy days &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; great?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Hast thou entered into the treasures of the snow? or hast thou seen the treasures of the hail,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Which I have reserved against the time of trouble, against the day of battle and war?</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">By what way is the light parted, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; scattereth the east wind upon the earth?</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Who hath divided a watercourse for the overflowing of waters, or a way for the lightning of thunder;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">To cause it to rain on the earth, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;where&lt;/span&gt; no man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is; on&lt;/span&gt; the wilderness, wherein &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no man;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">To satisfy the desolate and waste &lt;span class='extra'&gt;ground&lt;/span&gt;; and to cause the bud of the tender herb to spring forth?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Hath the rain a father? or who hath begotten the drops of dew?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Out of whose womb came the ice? and the hoary frost of heaven, who hath gendered it?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The waters are hid as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; a stone, and the face of the deep is frozen.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Canst thou bind the sweet influences of Pleiades, or loose the bands of Orion?</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Canst thou bring forth Mazzaroth in his season? or canst thou guide Arcturus with his sons?</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Knowest thou the ordinances of heaven? canst thou set the dominion thereof in the earth?</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Canst thou lift up thy voice to the clouds, that abundance of waters may cover thee?</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Canst thou send lightnings, that they may go, and say unto thee, Here we &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Who hath put wisdom in the inward parts? or who hath given understanding to the heart?</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Who can number the clouds in wisdom? or who can stay the bottles of heaven,</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">When the dust groweth into hardness, and the clods cleave fast together?</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Wilt thou hunt the prey for the lion? or fill the appetite of the young lions,</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">When they couch in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; dens, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; abide in the covert to lie in wait?</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Who provideth for the raven his food? when his young ones cry unto God, they wander for lack of meat.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>