<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="31" verseCount="40" nextChapter="job_32.html" nextTitle="Job 32" prevChapter="job_30.html" prevTitle="Job 30" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I made a covenant with mine eyes; why then should I think upon a maid?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For what portion of God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; from above? and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;what&lt;/span&gt; inheritance of the Almighty from on high?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; not destruction to the wicked? and a strange &lt;span class="extra"&gt;punishment&lt;/span&gt; to the workers of iniquity?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Doth not he see my ways, and count all my steps?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">If I have walked with vanity, or if my foot hath hasted to deceit;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Let me be weighed in an even balance, that God may know mine integrity.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">If my step hath turned out of the way, and mine heart walked after mine eyes, and if any blot hath cleaved to mine hands;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; let me sow, and let another eat; yea, let my offspring be rooted out.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">If mine heart have been deceived by a woman, or &lt;span class="extra"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; I have laid wait at my neighbour's door;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; let my wife grind unto another, and let others bow down upon her.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an heinous crime; yea, it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an iniquity &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be punished by&lt;/span&gt; the judges.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a fire &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; consumeth to destruction, and would root out all mine increase.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">If I did despise the cause of my manservant or of my maidservant, when they contended with me;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">What then shall I do when God riseth up? and when he visiteth, what shall I answer him?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Did not he that made me in the womb make him? and did not one fashion us in the womb?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">If I have withheld the poor from &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; desire, or have caused the eyes of the widow to fail;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Or have eaten my morsel myself alone, and the fatherless hath not eaten thereof;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">(For from my youth he was brought up with me, as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; a father, and I have guided her from my mother's womb;)</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">If I have seen any perish for want of clothing, or any poor without covering;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">If his loins have not blessed me, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; he were &lt;span class="extra"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; warmed with the fleece of my sheep;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">If I have lifted up my hand against the fatherless, when I saw my help in the gate:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; let mine arm fall from my shoulder blade, and mine arm be broken from the bone.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For destruction &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; a terror to me, and by reason of his highness I could not endure.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">If I have made gold my hope, or have said to the fine gold, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Thou art&lt;/span&gt; my confidence;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">If I rejoiced because my wealth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; great, and because mine hand had gotten much;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">If I beheld the sun when it shined, or the moon walking &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; brightness;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And my heart hath been secretly enticed, or my mouth hath kissed my hand:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">This also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; an iniquity &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be punished by&lt;/span&gt; the judge: for I should have denied the God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; above.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">If I rejoiced at the destruction of him that hated me, or lifted up myself when evil found him:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Neither have I suffered my mouth to sin by wishing a curse to his soul.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">If the men of my tabernacle said not, Oh that we had of his flesh! we cannot be satisfied.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">The stranger did not lodge in the street: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; I opened my doors to the traveller.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">If I covered my transgressions as Adam, by hiding mine iniquity in my bosom:</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Did I fear a great multitude, or did the contempt of families terrify me, that I kept silence, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; went not out of the door?</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Oh that one would hear me! behold, my desire &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is, that&lt;/span&gt; the Almighty would answer me, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; mine adversary had written a book.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Surely I would take it upon my shoulder, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; bind it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; a crown to me.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">I would declare unto him the number of my steps; as a prince would I go near unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">If my land cry against me, or that the furrows likewise thereof complain;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">If I have eaten the fruits thereof without money, or have caused the owners thereof to lose their life:</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Let thistles grow instead of wheat, and cockle instead of barley. The words of Job are ended.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>