<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="27" nextChapter="job_6.html" nextTitle="Job 6" prevChapter="job_4.html" prevTitle="Job 4" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Call now, if there be any that will answer thee; and to which of the saints wilt thou turn?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For wrath killeth the foolish man, and envy slayeth the silly one.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I have seen the foolish taking root: but suddenly I cursed his habitation.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">His children are far from safety, and they are crushed in the gate, neither &lt;i&gt;is there&lt;/i&gt; any to deliver &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Whose harvest the hungry eateth up, and taketh it even out of the thorns, and the robber swalloweth up their substance.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Although affliction cometh not forth of the dust, neither doth trouble spring out of the ground;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Yet man is born unto trouble, as the sparks fly upward.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I would seek unto God, and unto God would I commit my cause:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Which doeth great things and unsearchable; marvellous things without number:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Who giveth rain upon the earth, and sendeth waters upon the fields:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">To set up on high those that be low; that those which mourn may be exalted to safety.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">He disappointeth the devices of the crafty, so that their hands cannot perform &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; enterprise.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He taketh the wise in their own craftiness: and the counsel of the froward is carried headlong.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">They meet with darkness in the daytime, and grope in the noonday as in the night.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But he saveth the poor from the sword, from their mouth, and from the hand of the mighty.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">So the poor hath hope, and iniquity stoppeth her mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Behold, happy &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the man whom God correcteth: therefore despise not thou the chastening of the Almighty:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For he maketh sore, and bindeth up: he woundeth, and his hands make whole.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He shall deliver thee in six troubles: yea, in seven there shall no evil touch thee.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">In famine he shall redeem thee from death: and in war from the power of the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Thou shalt be hid from the scourge of the tongue: neither shalt thou be afraid of destruction when it cometh.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">At destruction and famine thou shalt laugh: neither shalt thou be afraid of the beasts of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For thou shalt be in league with the stones of the field: and the beasts of the field shall be at peace with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And thou shalt know that thy tabernacle &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; in peace; and thou shalt visit thy habitation, and shalt not sin.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Thou shalt know also that thy seed &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; great, and thine offspring as the grass of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Thou shalt come to &lt;i&gt;thy&lt;/i&gt; grave in a full age, like as a shock of corn cometh in in his season.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Lo this, we have searched it, so it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt;; hear it, and know thou &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; for thy good.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>