<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="23" verseCount="17" nextChapter="job_24.html" nextTitle="Job 24" prevChapter="job_22.html" prevTitle="Job 22" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then Job answered and said,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Even to day &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my complaint bitter: my stroke is heavier than my groaning.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Oh that I knew where I might find him! &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; I might come &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to his seat!</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I would order &lt;span class='extra'&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; cause before him, and fill my mouth with arguments.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I would know the words &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; he would answer me, and understand what he would say unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Will he plead against me with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; great power? No; but he would put &lt;span class='extra'&gt;strength&lt;/span&gt; in me.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">There the righteous might dispute with him; so should I be delivered for ever from my judge.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Behold, I go forward, but he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there&lt;/span&gt;; and backward, but I cannot perceive him:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">On the left hand, where he doth work, but I cannot behold &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;: he hideth himself on the right hand, that I cannot see &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But he knoweth the way that I take: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; he hath tried me, I shall come forth as gold.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">My foot hath held his steps, his way have I kept, and not declined.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Neither have I gone back from the commandment of his lips; I have esteemed the words of his mouth more than my necessary &lt;span class='extra'&gt;food&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;mind&lt;/span&gt;, and who can turn him? and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;what&lt;/span&gt; his soul desireth, even &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; he doeth.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For he performeth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the thing that is&lt;/span&gt; appointed for me: and many such &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things are&lt;/span&gt; with him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Therefore am I troubled at his presence: when I consider, I am afraid of him.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For God maketh my heart soft, and the Almighty troubleth me:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Because I was not cut off before the darkness, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;neither&lt;/span&gt; hath he covered the darkness from my face.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>