<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="18" name="Job" bookPage="job.html" title="Job" chapterCount="42" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="psalms_1.html" nextTitle="Psalms" prevBook="esther_1.html" prevTitle="Esther">
    <chapter number="41" verseCount="34" nextChapter="job_42.html" nextTitle="Job 42" prevChapter="job_40.html" prevTitle="Job 40" chapterPage="job_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Canst thou draw out leviathan with an hook? or his tongue with a cord &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; thou lettest down?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Canst thou put an hook into his nose? or bore his jaw through with a thorn?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Will he make many supplications unto thee? will he speak soft &lt;span class='extra'&gt;words&lt;/span&gt; unto thee?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Will he make a covenant with thee? wilt thou take him for a servant for ever?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Wilt thou play with him as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; a bird? or wilt thou bind him for thy maidens?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Shall the companions make a banquet of him? shall they part him among the merchants?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Canst thou fill his skin with barbed irons? or his head with fish spears?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Lay thine hand upon him, remember the battle, do no more.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Behold, the hope of him is in vain: shall not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; be cast down even at the sight of him?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">None &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is so&lt;/span&gt; fierce that dare stir him up: who then is able to stand before me?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Who hath prevented me, that I should repay &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him? whatsoever is&lt;/span&gt; under the whole heaven is mine.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I will not conceal his parts, nor his power, nor his comely proportion.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Who can discover the face of his garment? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; who can come &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to him&lt;/span&gt; with his double bridle?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Who can open the doors of his face? his teeth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; terrible round about.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;His&lt;/span&gt; scales &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are his&lt;/span&gt; pride, shut up together &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as with&lt;/span&gt; a close seal.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">One is so near to another, that no air can come between them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">They are joined one to another, they stick together, that they cannot be sundered.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">By his neesings a light doth shine, and his eyes &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; like the eyelids of the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Out of his mouth go burning lamps, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; sparks of fire leap out.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Out of his nostrils goeth smoke, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;out&lt;/span&gt; of a seething pot or caldron.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">His breath kindleth coals, and a flame goeth out of his mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">In his neck remaineth strength, and sorrow is turned into joy before him.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The flakes of his flesh are joined together: they are firm in themselves; they cannot be moved.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">His heart is as firm as a stone; yea, as hard as a piece of the nether &lt;span class='extra'&gt;millstone&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">When he raiseth up himself, the mighty are afraid: by reason of breakings they purify themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The sword of him that layeth at him cannot hold: the spear, the dart, nor the habergeon.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">He esteemeth iron as straw, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; brass as rotten wood.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The arrow cannot make him flee: slingstones are turned with him into stubble.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Darts are counted as stubble: he laugheth at the shaking of a spear.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Sharp stones &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; under him: he spreadeth sharp pointed things upon the mire.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">He maketh the deep to boil like a pot: he maketh the sea like a pot of ointment.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">He maketh a path to shine after him; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; would think the deep &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; hoary.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Upon earth there is not his like, who is made without fear.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">He beholdeth all high &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;: he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a king over all the children of pride.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>