<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="52" verseCount="9" nextChapter="psalms_53.html" nextTitle="Psalms 53" prevChapter="psalms_51.html" prevTitle="Psalms 51" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, Maschil, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;A Psalm&lt;/span&gt; of David, when Doeg the Edomite came and told Saul, and said unto him, David is come to the house of Ahimelech.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Why boastest thou thyself in mischief, O mighty man? the goodness of God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;endureth&lt;/span&gt; continually.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thy tongue deviseth mischiefs; like a sharp razor, working deceitfully.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou lovest evil more than good; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; lying rather than to speak righteousness. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thou lovest all devouring words, O &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thou&lt;/span&gt; deceitful tongue.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">God shall likewise destroy thee for ever, he shall take thee away, and pluck thee out of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; dwelling place, and root thee out of the land of the living. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The righteous also shall see, and fear, and shall laugh at him:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Lo, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this is&lt;/span&gt; the man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; made not God his strength; but trusted in the abundance of his riches, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; strengthened himself in his wickedness.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; like a green olive tree in the house of God: I trust in the mercy of God for ever and ever.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I will praise thee for ever, because thou hast done &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;: and I will wait on thy name; for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; good before thy saints.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>