<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="141" verseCount="10" nextChapter="psalms_142.html" nextTitle="Psalms 142" prevChapter="psalms_140.html" prevTitle="Psalms 140" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Psalm of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I cry unto thee: make haste unto me; give ear unto my voice, when I cry unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Let my prayer be set forth before thee &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; incense; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the lifting up of my hands &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the evening sacrifice.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Set a watch, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, before my mouth; keep the door of my lips.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Incline not my heart to &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; evil thing, to practise wicked works with men that work iniquity: and let me not eat of their dainties.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Let the righteous smite me; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it shall be&lt;/span&gt; a kindness: and let him reprove me; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it shall be&lt;/span&gt; an excellent oil, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; shall not break my head: for yet my prayer also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; in their calamities.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">When their judges are overthrown in stony places, they shall hear my words; for they are sweet.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Our bones are scattered at the grave's mouth, as when one cutteth and cleaveth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;wood&lt;/span&gt; upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But mine eyes &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; unto thee, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; the Lord: in thee is my trust; leave not my soul destitute.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Keep me from the snares &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; they have laid for me, and the gins of the workers of iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Let the wicked fall into their own nets, whilst that I withal escape.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>