<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="48" verseCount="14" nextChapter="psalms_49.html" nextTitle="Psalms 49" prevChapter="psalms_47.html" prevTitle="Psalms 47" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Song &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Psalm for the sons of Korah.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Great &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and greatly to be praised in the city of our God, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the mountain of his holiness.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Beautiful for situation, the joy of the whole earth, &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; mount Zion, &lt;i&gt;on&lt;/i&gt; the sides of the north, the city of the great King.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">God is known in her palaces for a refuge.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For, lo, the kings were assembled, they passed by together.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They saw &lt;i&gt;it, and&lt;/i&gt; so they marvelled; they were troubled, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; hasted away.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Fear took hold upon them there, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; pain, as of a woman in travail.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thou breakest the ships of Tarshish with an east wind.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">As we have heard, so have we seen in the city of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, in the city of our God: God will establish it for ever. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">We have thought of thy lovingkindness, O God, in the midst of thy temple.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">According to thy name, O God, so &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy praise unto the ends of the earth: thy right hand is full of righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Let mount Zion rejoice, let the daughters of Judah be glad, because of thy judgments.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Walk about Zion, and go round about her: tell the towers thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Mark ye well her bulwarks, consider her palaces; that ye may tell &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to the generation following.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For this God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; our God for ever and ever: he will be our guide &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; unto death.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>