<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="12" nextChapter="psalms_6.html" nextTitle="Psalms 6" prevChapter="psalms_4.html" prevTitle="Psalms 4" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician upon Nehiloth, A Psalm of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Give ear to my words, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, consider my meditation.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Hearken unto the voice of my cry, my King, and my God: for unto thee will I pray.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">My voice shalt thou hear in the morning, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; in the morning will I direct &lt;i&gt;my prayer&lt;/i&gt; unto thee, and will look up.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; not a God that hath pleasure in wickedness: neither shall evil dwell with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The foolish shall not stand in thy sight: thou hatest all workers of iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thou shalt destroy them that speak leasing: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will abhor the bloody and deceitful man.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But as for me, I will come &lt;i&gt;into&lt;/i&gt; thy house in the multitude of thy mercy: &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; in thy fear will I worship toward thy holy temple.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Lead me, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in thy righteousness because of mine enemies; make thy way straight before my face.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no faithfulness in their mouth; their inward part &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; very wickedness; their throat &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an open sepulchre; they flatter with their tongue.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Destroy thou them, O God; let them fall by their own counsels; cast them out in the multitude of their transgressions; for they have rebelled against thee.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But let all those that put their trust in thee rejoice: let them ever shout for joy, because thou defendest them: let them also that love thy name be joyful in thee.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For thou, &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, wilt bless the righteous; with favour wilt thou compass him as &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; a shield.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>