<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="63" verseCount="11" nextChapter="psalms_64.html" nextTitle="Psalms 64" prevChapter="psalms_62.html" prevTitle="Psalms 62" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Psalm of David, when he was in the wilderness of Judah.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O God, thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; my God; early will I seek thee: my soul thirsteth for thee, my flesh longeth for thee in a dry and thirsty land, where no water is;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">To see thy power and thy glory, so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; I have seen thee in the sanctuary.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Because thy lovingkindness &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; better than life, my lips shall praise thee.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thus will I bless thee while I live: I will lift up my hands in thy name.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">My soul shall be satisfied as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; marrow and fatness; and my mouth shall praise &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt; with joyful lips:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">When I remember thee upon my bed, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; meditate on thee in the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;night&lt;/span&gt; watches.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Because thou hast been my help, therefore in the shadow of thy wings will I rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">My soul followeth hard after thee: thy right hand upholdeth me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But those &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; seek my soul, to destroy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, shall go into the lower parts of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">They shall fall by the sword: they shall be a portion for foxes.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But the king shall rejoice in God; every one that sweareth by him shall glory: but the mouth of them that speak lies shall be stopped.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>