<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="36" verseCount="12" nextChapter="psalms_37.html" nextTitle="Psalms 37" prevChapter="psalms_35.html" prevTitle="Psalms 35" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;A Psalm&lt;/span&gt; of David the servant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The transgression of the wicked saith within my heart, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that there is&lt;/span&gt; no fear of God before his eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For he flattereth himself in his own eyes, until his iniquity be found to be hateful.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The words of his mouth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; iniquity and deceit: he hath left off to be wise, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to do good.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He deviseth mischief upon his bed; he setteth himself in a way &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; not good; he abhorreth not evil.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thy mercy, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the heavens; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; thy faithfulness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;reacheth&lt;/span&gt; unto the clouds.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thy righteousness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; like the great mountains; thy judgments &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; a great deep: O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou preservest man and beast.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">How excellent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy lovingkindness, O God! therefore the children of men put their trust under the shadow of thy wings.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">They shall be abundantly satisfied with the fatness of thy house; and thou shalt make them drink of the river of thy pleasures.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For with thee &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the fountain of life: in thy light shall we see light.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">O continue thy lovingkindness unto them that know thee; and thy righteousness to the upright in heart.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Let not the foot of pride come against me, and let not the hand of the wicked remove me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">There are the workers of iniquity fallen: they are cast down, and shall not be able to rise.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>