<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="104" verseCount="35" nextChapter="psalms_105.html" nextTitle="Psalms 105" prevChapter="psalms_103.html" prevTitle="Psalms 103" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Bless the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, O my soul. O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, thou art very great; thou art clothed with honour and majesty.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Who coverest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thyself&lt;/span&gt; with light as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; a garment: who stretchest out the heavens like a curtain:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Who layeth the beams of his chambers in the waters: who maketh the clouds his chariot: who walketh upon the wings of the wind:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Who maketh his angels spirits; his ministers a flaming fire:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Who&lt;/span&gt; laid the foundations of the earth, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; it should not be removed for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thou coveredst it with the deep as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; a garment: the waters stood above the mountains.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">At thy rebuke they fled; at the voice of thy thunder they hasted away.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">They go up by the mountains; they go down by the valleys unto the place which thou hast founded for them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thou hast set a bound that they may not pass over; that they turn not again to cover the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He sendeth the springs into the valleys, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; run among the hills.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">They give drink to every beast of the field: the wild asses quench their thirst.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">By them shall the fowls of the heaven have their habitation, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; sing among the branches.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He watereth the hills from his chambers: the earth is satisfied with the fruit of thy works.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">He causeth the grass to grow for the cattle, and herb for the service of man: that he may bring forth food out of the earth;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And wine &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; maketh glad the heart of man, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; oil to make &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; face to shine, and bread &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; strengtheneth man's heart.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The trees of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; are full &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of sap&lt;/span&gt;; the cedars of Lebanon, which he hath planted;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Where the birds make their nests: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; the stork, the fir trees &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; her house.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The high hills &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; a refuge for the wild goats; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the rocks for the conies.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He appointed the moon for seasons: the sun knoweth his going down.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Thou makest darkness, and it is night: wherein all the beasts of the forest do creep &lt;span class='extra'&gt;forth&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The young lions roar after their prey, and seek their meat from God.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The sun ariseth, they gather themselves together, and lay them down in their dens.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Man goeth forth unto his work and to his labour until the evening.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, how manifold are thy works! in wisdom hast thou made them all: the earth is full of thy riches.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;So is&lt;/span&gt; this great and wide sea, wherein &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; things creeping innumerable, both small and great beasts.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">There go the ships: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; that leviathan, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;whom&lt;/span&gt; thou hast made to play therein.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">These wait all upon thee; that thou mayest give &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; their meat in due season.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;That&lt;/span&gt; thou givest them they gather: thou openest thine hand, they are filled with good.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Thou hidest thy face, they are troubled: thou takest away their breath, they die, and return to their dust.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Thou sendest forth thy spirit, they are created: and thou renewest the face of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The glory of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall endure for ever: the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall rejoice in his works.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">He looketh on the earth, and it trembleth: he toucheth the hills, and they smoke.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">I will sing unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; as long as I live: I will sing praise to my God while I have my being.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">My meditation of him shall be sweet: I will be glad in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Let the sinners be consumed out of the earth, and let the wicked be no more. Bless thou the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, O my soul. Praise ye the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>