<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="76" verseCount="12" nextChapter="psalms_77.html" nextTitle="Psalms 77" prevChapter="psalms_75.html" prevTitle="Psalms 75" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician on Neginoth, A Psalm &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; Song of Asaph.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In Judah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; God known: his name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; great in Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">In Salem also is his tabernacle, and his dwelling place in Zion.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">There brake he the arrows of the bow, the shield, and the sword, and the battle. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; more glorious &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; excellent than the mountains of prey.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The stouthearted are spoiled, they have slept their sleep: and none of the men of might have found their hands.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">At thy rebuke, O God of Jacob, both the chariot and horse are cast into a dead sleep.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thou, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; thou, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; to be feared: and who may stand in thy sight when once thou art angry?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Thou didst cause judgment to be heard from heaven; the earth feared, and was still,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">When God arose to judgment, to save all the meek of the earth. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Surely the wrath of man shall praise thee: the remainder of wrath shalt thou restrain.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Vow, and pay unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God: let all that be round about him bring presents unto him that ought to be feared.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">He shall cut off the spirit of princes: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; terrible to the kings of the earth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>