<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="79" verseCount="13" nextChapter="psalms_80.html" nextTitle="Psalms 80" prevChapter="psalms_78.html" prevTitle="Psalms 78" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Psalm of Asaph.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O God, the heathen are come into thine inheritance; thy holy temple have they defiled; they have laid Jerusalem on heaps.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The dead bodies of thy servants have they given &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; meat unto the fowls of the heaven, the flesh of thy saints unto the beasts of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Their blood have they shed like water round about Jerusalem; and &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; none to bury &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">We are become a reproach to our neighbours, a scorn and derision to them that are round about us.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">How long, &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? wilt thou be angry for ever? shall thy jealousy burn like fire?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Pour out thy wrath upon the heathen that have not known thee, and upon the kingdoms that have not called upon thy name.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For they have devoured Jacob, and laid waste his dwelling place.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">O remember not against us former iniquities: let thy tender mercies speedily prevent us: for we are brought very low.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Help us, O God of our salvation, for the glory of thy name: and deliver us, and purge away our sins, for thy name's sake.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Wherefore should the heathen say, Where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; their God? let him be known among the heathen in our sight &lt;i&gt;by&lt;/i&gt; the revenging of the blood of thy servants &lt;i&gt;which is&lt;/i&gt; shed.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Let the sighing of the prisoner come before thee; according to the greatness of thy power preserve thou those that are appointed to die;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And render unto our neighbours sevenfold into their bosom their reproach, wherewith they have reproached thee, O Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">So we thy people and sheep of thy pasture will give thee thanks for ever: we will shew forth thy praise to all generations.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>