<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="27" verseCount="14" nextChapter="psalms_28.html" nextTitle="Psalms 28" prevChapter="psalms_26.html" prevTitle="Psalms 26" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;A Psalm&lt;/span&gt; of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my light and my salvation; whom shall I fear? the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the strength of my life; of whom shall I be afraid?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">When the wicked, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; mine enemies and my foes, came upon me to eat up my flesh, they stumbled and fell.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Though an host should encamp against me, my heart shall not fear: though war should rise against me, in this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;will&lt;/span&gt; I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; confident.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">One &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thing&lt;/span&gt; have I desired of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that will I seek after; that I may dwell in the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; all the days of my life, to behold the beauty of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and to enquire in his temple.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For in the time of trouble he shall hide me in his pavilion: in the secret of his tabernacle shall he hide me; he shall set me up upon a rock.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And now shall mine head be lifted up above mine enemies round about me: therefore will I offer in his tabernacle sacrifices of joy; I will sing, yea, I will sing praises unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Hear, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; I cry with my voice: have mercy also upon me, and answer me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;When thou saidst&lt;/span&gt;, Seek ye my face; my heart said unto thee, Thy face, &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, will I seek.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Hide not thy face &lt;span class="extra"&gt;far&lt;/span&gt; from me; put not thy servant away in anger: thou hast been my help; leave me not, neither forsake me, O God of my salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">When my father and my mother forsake me, then the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will take me up.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Teach me thy way, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and lead me in a plain path, because of mine enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Deliver me not over unto the will of mine enemies: for false witnesses are risen up against me, and such as breathe out cruelty.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;I had fainted&lt;/span&gt;, unless I had believed to see the goodness of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the land of the living.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Wait on the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: be of good courage, and he shall strengthen thine heart: wait, I say, on the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>