<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="58" verseCount="11" nextChapter="psalms_59.html" nextTitle="Psalms 59" prevChapter="psalms_57.html" prevTitle="Psalms 57" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, Al-taschith, Michtam of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Do ye indeed speak righteousness, O congregation? do ye judge uprightly, O ye sons of men?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Yea, in heart ye work wickedness; ye weigh the violence of your hands in the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The wicked are estranged from the womb: they go astray as soon as they be born, speaking lies.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Their poison &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; like the poison of a serpent: &lt;i&gt;they are&lt;/i&gt; like the deaf adder &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; stoppeth her ear;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Which will not hearken to the voice of charmers, charming never so wisely.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Break their teeth, O God, in their mouth: break out the great teeth of the young lions, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Let them melt away as waters &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; run continually: &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; he bendeth &lt;i&gt;his bow to shoot&lt;/i&gt; his arrows, let them be as cut in pieces.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">As a snail &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; melteth, let &lt;i&gt;every one of them&lt;/i&gt; pass away: &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; the untimely birth of a woman, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; they may not see the sun.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Before your pots can feel the thorns, he shall take them away as with a whirlwind, both living, and in &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; wrath.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The righteous shall rejoice when he seeth the vengeance: he shall wash his feet in the blood of the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">So that a man shall say, Verily &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; a reward for the righteous: verily he is a God that judgeth in the earth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>