<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="89" verseCount="52" nextChapter="psalms_90.html" nextTitle="Psalms 90" prevChapter="psalms_88.html" prevTitle="Psalms 88" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">Maschil of Ethan the Ezrahite.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I will sing of the mercies of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for ever: with my mouth will I make known thy faithfulness to all generations.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For I have said, Mercy shall be built up for ever: thy faithfulness shalt thou establish in the very heavens.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I have made a covenant with my chosen, I have sworn unto David my servant,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thy seed will I establish for ever, and build up thy throne to all generations. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the heavens shall praise thy wonders, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: thy faithfulness also in the congregation of the saints.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For who in the heaven can be compared unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;who&lt;/span&gt; among the sons of the mighty can be likened unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">God is greatly to be feared in the assembly of the saints, and to be had in reverence of all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them that are&lt;/span&gt; about him.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of hosts, who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a strong &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; like unto thee? or to thy faithfulness round about thee?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thou rulest the raging of the sea: when the waves thereof arise, thou stillest them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thou hast broken Rahab in pieces, as one that is slain; thou hast scattered thine enemies with thy strong arm.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The heavens &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; thine, the earth also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thine: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; the world and the fulness thereof, thou hast founded them.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The north and the south thou hast created them: Tabor and Hermon shall rejoice in thy name.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thou hast a mighty arm: strong is thy hand, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; high is thy right hand.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Justice and judgment &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the habitation of thy throne: mercy and truth shall go before thy face.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the people that know the joyful sound: they shall walk, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in the light of thy countenance.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">In thy name shall they rejoice all the day: and in thy righteousness shall they be exalted.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; the glory of their strength: and in thy favour our horn shall be exalted.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our defence; and the Holy One of Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our king.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Then thou spakest in vision to thy holy one, and saidst, I have laid help upon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one that is&lt;/span&gt; mighty; I have exalted &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; chosen out of the people.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">I have found David my servant; with my holy oil have I anointed him:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">With whom my hand shall be established: mine arm also shall strengthen him.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The enemy shall not exact upon him; nor the son of wickedness afflict him.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And I will beat down his foes before his face, and plague them that hate him.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But my faithfulness and my mercy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; with him: and in my name shall his horn be exalted.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">I will set his hand also in the sea, and his right hand in the rivers.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">He shall cry unto me, Thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; my father, my God, and the rock of my salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Also I will make him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; firstborn, higher than the kings of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">My mercy will I keep for him for evermore, and my covenant shall stand fast with him.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">His seed also will I make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to endure&lt;/span&gt; for ever, and his throne as the days of heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">If his children forsake my law, and walk not in my judgments;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">If they break my statutes, and keep not my commandments;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Then will I visit their transgression with the rod, and their iniquity with stripes.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Nevertheless my lovingkindness will I not utterly take from him, nor suffer my faithfulness to fail.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">My covenant will I not break, nor alter the thing that is gone out of my lips.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Once have I sworn by my holiness that I will not lie unto David.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">His seed shall endure for ever, and his throne as the sun before me.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">It shall be established for ever as the moon, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; a faithful witness in heaven. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">But thou hast cast off and abhorred, thou hast been wroth with thine anointed.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Thou hast made void the covenant of thy servant: thou hast profaned his crown &lt;span class="extra"&gt;by casting it&lt;/span&gt; to the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Thou hast broken down all his hedges; thou hast brought his strong holds to ruin.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">All that pass by the way spoil him: he is a reproach to his neighbours.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Thou hast set up the right hand of his adversaries; thou hast made all his enemies to rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Thou hast also turned the edge of his sword, and hast not made him to stand in the battle.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">Thou hast made his glory to cease, and cast his throne down to the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">The days of his youth hast thou shortened: thou hast covered him with shame. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">How long, &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? wilt thou hide thyself for ever? shall thy wrath burn like fire?</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">Remember how short my time is: wherefore hast thou made all men in vain?</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">What man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is he that&lt;/span&gt; liveth, and shall not see death? shall he deliver his soul from the hand of the grave? Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">Lord, where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; thy former lovingkindnesses, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; thou swarest unto David in thy truth?</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">Remember, Lord, the reproach of thy servants; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;how&lt;/span&gt; I do bear in my bosom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the reproach of&lt;/span&gt; all the mighty people;</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">Wherewith thine enemies have reproached, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; wherewith they have reproached the footsteps of thine anointed.</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for evermore. Amen, and Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>