<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="94" verseCount="23" nextChapter="psalms_95.html" nextTitle="Psalms 95" prevChapter="psalms_93.html" prevTitle="Psalms 93" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God, to whom vengeance belongeth; O God, to whom vengeance belongeth, shew thyself.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Lift up thyself, thou judge of the earth: render a reward to the proud.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, how long shall the wicked, how long shall the wicked triumph?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;How long&lt;/span&gt; shall they utter &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; speak hard things? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; all the workers of iniquity boast themselves?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They break in pieces thy people, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and afflict thine heritage.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">They slay the widow and the stranger, and murder the fatherless.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Yet they say, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall not see, neither shall the God of Jacob regard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Understand, ye brutish among the people: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ye&lt;/span&gt; fools, when will ye be wise?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He that planted the ear, shall he not hear? he that formed the eye, shall he not see?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He that chastiseth the heathen, shall not he correct? he that teacheth man knowledge, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall not he know&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; knoweth the thoughts of man, that they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the man whom thou chastenest, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and teachest him out of thy law;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">That thou mayest give him rest from the days of adversity, until the pit be digged for the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will not cast off his people, neither will he forsake his inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But judgment shall return unto righteousness: and all the upright in heart shall follow it.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Who will rise up for me against the evildoers? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; who will stand up for me against the workers of iniquity?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Unless the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;had been&lt;/span&gt; my help, my soul had almost dwelt in silence.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">When I said, My foot slippeth; thy mercy, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, held me up.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">In the multitude of my thoughts within me thy comforts delight my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Shall the throne of iniquity have fellowship with thee, which frameth mischief by a law?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">They gather themselves together against the soul of the righteous, and condemn the innocent blood.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; is my defence; and my God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the rock of my refuge.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he shall bring upon them their own iniquity, and shall cut them off in their own wickedness; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yea&lt;/span&gt;, the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God shall cut them off.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>