<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="25" verseCount="22" nextChapter="psalms_26.html" nextTitle="Psalms 26" prevChapter="psalms_24.html" prevTitle="Psalms 24" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">&lt;i&gt;A Psalm&lt;/i&gt; of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Unto thee, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, do I lift up my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">O my God, I trust in thee: let me not be ashamed, let not mine enemies triumph over me.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Yea, let none that wait on thee be ashamed: let them be ashamed which transgress without cause.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Shew me thy ways, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; teach me thy paths.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Lead me in thy truth, and teach me: for thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; the God of my salvation; on thee do I wait all the day.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Remember, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thy tender mercies and thy lovingkindnesses; for they &lt;i&gt;have been&lt;/i&gt; ever of old.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Remember not the sins of my youth, nor my transgressions: according to thy mercy remember thou me for thy goodness' sake, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Good and upright &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: therefore will he teach sinners in the way.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The meek will he guide in judgment: and the meek will he teach his way.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">All the paths of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; mercy and truth unto such as keep his covenant and his testimonies.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For thy name's sake, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, pardon mine iniquity; for it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; great.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">What man &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he that feareth the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? him shall he teach in the way &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; he shall choose.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">His soul shall dwell at ease; and his seed shall inherit the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The secret of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with them that fear him; and he will shew them his covenant.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Mine eyes &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; ever toward the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for he shall pluck my feet out of the net.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Turn thee unto me, and have mercy upon me; for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; desolate and afflicted.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The troubles of my heart are enlarged: &lt;i&gt;O&lt;/i&gt; bring thou me out of my distresses.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Look upon mine affliction and my pain; and forgive all my sins.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Consider mine enemies; for they are many; and they hate me with cruel hatred.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">O keep my soul, and deliver me: let me not be ashamed; for I put my trust in thee.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Let integrity and uprightness preserve me; for I wait on thee.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Redeem Israel, O God, out of all his troubles.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>