<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="83" verseCount="18" nextChapter="psalms_84.html" nextTitle="Psalms 84" prevChapter="psalms_82.html" prevTitle="Psalms 82" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Song &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; Psalm of Asaph.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Keep not thou silence, O God: hold not thy peace, and be not still, O God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For, lo, thine enemies make a tumult: and they that hate thee have lifted up the head.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">They have taken crafty counsel against thy people, and consulted against thy hidden ones.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They have said, Come, and let us cut them off from &lt;span class="extra"&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; a nation; that the name of Israel may be no more in remembrance.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For they have consulted together with one consent: they are confederate against thee:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The tabernacles of Edom, and the Ishmaelites; of Moab, and the Hagarenes;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Gebal, and Ammon, and Amalek; the Philistines with the inhabitants of Tyre;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Assur also is joined with them: they have holpen the children of Lot. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Do unto them as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;unto&lt;/span&gt; the Midianites; as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; Sisera, as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; Jabin, at the brook of Kison:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Which&lt;/span&gt; perished at Endor: they became &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; dung for the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Make their nobles like Oreb, and like Zeeb: yea, all their princes as Zebah, and as Zalmunna:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Who said, Let us take to ourselves the houses of God in possession.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">O my God, make them like a wheel; as the stubble before the wind.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">As the fire burneth a wood, and as the flame setteth the mountains on fire;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So persecute them with thy tempest, and make them afraid with thy storm.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Fill their faces with shame; that they may seek thy name, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Let them be confounded and troubled for ever; yea, let them be put to shame, and perish:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">That &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; may know that thou, whose name alone &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; JEHOVAH, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; the most high over all the earth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>