<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="59" verseCount="17" nextChapter="psalms_60.html" nextTitle="Psalms 60" prevChapter="psalms_58.html" prevTitle="Psalms 58" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, Al-taschith, Michtam of David; when Saul sent, and they watched the house to kill him.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Deliver me from mine enemies, O my God: defend me from them that rise up against me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Deliver me from the workers of iniquity, and save me from bloody men.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For, lo, they lie in wait for my soul: the mighty are gathered against me; not &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; my transgression, nor &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; my sin, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They run and prepare themselves without &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; fault: awake to help me, and behold.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thou therefore, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of hosts, the God of Israel, awake to visit all the heathen: be not merciful to any wicked transgressors. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">They return at evening: they make a noise like a dog, and go round about the city.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Behold, they belch out with their mouth: swords &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in their lips: for who, &lt;i&gt;say they&lt;/i&gt;, doth hear?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But thou, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, shalt laugh at them; thou shalt have all the heathen in derision.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;i&gt;Because of&lt;/i&gt; his strength will I wait upon thee: for God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my defence.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The God of my mercy shall prevent me: God shall let me see &lt;i&gt;my desire&lt;/i&gt; upon mine enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Slay them not, lest my people forget: scatter them by thy power; and bring them down, O Lord our shield.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;i&gt;For&lt;/i&gt; the sin of their mouth &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the words of their lips let them even be taken in their pride: and for cursing and lying &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; they speak.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Consume &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in wrath, consume &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;, that they &lt;i&gt;may&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt;: and let them know that God ruleth in Jacob unto the ends of the earth. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And at evening let them return; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; let them make a noise like a dog, and go round about the city.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Let them wander up and down for meat, and grudge if they be not satisfied.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But I will sing of thy power; yea, I will sing aloud of thy mercy in the morning: for thou hast been my defence and refuge in the day of my trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Unto thee, O my strength, will I sing: for God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my defence, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the God of my mercy.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>