<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="28" verseCount="9" nextChapter="psalms_29.html" nextTitle="Psalms 29" prevChapter="psalms_27.html" prevTitle="Psalms 27" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">&lt;i&gt;A Psalm&lt;/i&gt; of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Unto thee will I cry, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my rock; be not silent to me: lest, &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; thou be silent to me, I become like them that go down into the pit.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Hear the voice of my supplications, when I cry unto thee, when I lift up my hands toward thy holy oracle.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Draw me not away with the wicked, and with the workers of iniquity, which speak peace to their neighbours, but mischief &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in their hearts.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Give them according to their deeds, and according to the wickedness of their endeavours: give them after the work of their hands; render to them their desert.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Because they regard not the works of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, nor the operation of his hands, he shall destroy them, and not build them up.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Blessed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, because he hath heard the voice of my supplications.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my strength and my shield; my heart trusted in him, and I am helped: therefore my heart greatly rejoiceth; and with my song will I praise him.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; their strength, and he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the saving strength of his anointed.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Save thy people, and bless thine inheritance: feed them also, and lift them up for ever.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>