<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="92" verseCount="15" nextChapter="psalms_93.html" nextTitle="Psalms 93" prevChapter="psalms_91.html" prevTitle="Psalms 91" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Psalm &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; Song for the sabbath day.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;It is a&lt;/span&gt; good &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thing&lt;/span&gt; to give thanks unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and to sing praises unto thy name, O most High:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">To shew forth thy lovingkindness in the morning, and thy faithfulness every night,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Upon an instrument of ten strings, and upon the psaltery; upon the harp with a solemn sound.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For thou, &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hast made me glad through thy work: I will triumph in the works of thy hands.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, how great are thy works! &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; thy thoughts are very deep.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">A brutish man knoweth not; neither doth a fool understand this.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">When the wicked spring as the grass, and when all the workers of iniquity do flourish; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; that they shall be destroyed for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But thou, &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art most&lt;/span&gt; high for evermore.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For, lo, thine enemies, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, for, lo, thine enemies shall perish; all the workers of iniquity shall be scattered.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But my horn shalt thou exalt like &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the horn of&lt;/span&gt; an unicorn: I shall be anointed with fresh oil.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Mine eye also shall see &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my desire&lt;/span&gt; on mine enemies, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; mine ears shall hear &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my desire&lt;/span&gt; of the wicked that rise up against me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The righteous shall flourish like the palm tree: he shall grow like a cedar in Lebanon.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Those that be planted in the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall flourish in the courts of our God.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">They shall still bring forth fruit in old age; they shall be fat and flourishing;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">To shew that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upright: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; my rock, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no unrighteousness in him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>