<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="51" verseCount="19" nextChapter="psalms_52.html" nextTitle="Psalms 52" prevChapter="psalms_50.html" prevTitle="Psalms 50" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Psalm of David, when Nathan the prophet came unto him, after he had gone in to Bath-sheba.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Have mercy upon me, O God, according to thy lovingkindness: according unto the multitude of thy tender mercies blot out my transgressions.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Wash me throughly from mine iniquity, and cleanse me from my sin.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For I acknowledge my transgressions: and my sin &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; ever before me.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Against thee, thee only, have I sinned, and done &lt;span class="extra"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; evil in thy sight: that thou mightest be justified when thou speakest, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; be clear when thou judgest.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Behold, I was shapen in iniquity; and in sin did my mother conceive me.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Behold, thou desirest truth in the inward parts: and in the hidden &lt;span class="extra"&gt;part&lt;/span&gt; thou shalt make me to know wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Purge me with hyssop, and I shall be clean: wash me, and I shall be whiter than snow.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Make me to hear joy and gladness; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the bones &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; thou hast broken may rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Hide thy face from my sins, and blot out all mine iniquities.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Create in me a clean heart, O God; and renew a right spirit within me.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Cast me not away from thy presence; and take not thy holy spirit from me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Restore unto me the joy of thy salvation; and uphold me &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with thy&lt;/span&gt; free spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Then&lt;/span&gt; will I teach transgressors thy ways; and sinners shall be converted unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Deliver me from bloodguiltiness, O God, thou God of my salvation: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; my tongue shall sing aloud of thy righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">O Lord, open thou my lips; and my mouth shall shew forth thy praise.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For thou desirest not sacrifice; else would I give &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;: thou delightest not in burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The sacrifices of God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; a broken spirit: a broken and a contrite heart, O God, thou wilt not despise.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Do good in thy good pleasure unto Zion: build thou the walls of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Then shalt thou be pleased with the sacrifices of righteousness, with burnt offering and whole burnt offering: then shall they offer bullocks upon thine altar.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>