<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="20" nextChapter="psalms_10.html" nextTitle="Psalms 10" prevChapter="psalms_8.html" prevTitle="Psalms 8" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician upon Muth-labben, A Psalm of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I will praise &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt;, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, with my whole heart; I will shew forth all thy marvellous works.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I will be glad and rejoice in thee: I will sing praise to thy name, O thou most High.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">When mine enemies are turned back, they shall fall and perish at thy presence.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For thou hast maintained my right and my cause; thou satest in the throne judging right.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thou hast rebuked the heathen, thou hast destroyed the wicked, thou hast put out their name for ever and ever.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">O thou enemy, destructions are come to a perpetual end: and thou hast destroyed cities; their memorial is perished with them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall endure for ever: he hath prepared his throne for judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he shall judge the world in righteousness, he shall minister judgment to the people in uprightness.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; also will be a refuge for the oppressed, a refuge in times of trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they that know thy name will put their trust in thee: for thou, &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hast not forsaken them that seek thee.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Sing praises to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which dwelleth in Zion: declare among the people his doings.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">When he maketh inquisition for blood, he remembereth them: he forgetteth not the cry of the humble.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Have mercy upon me, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; consider my trouble &lt;i&gt;which I suffer&lt;/i&gt; of them that hate me, thou that liftest me up from the gates of death:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">That I may shew forth all thy praise in the gates of the daughter of Zion: I will rejoice in thy salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The heathen are sunk down in the pit &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; they made: in the net which they hid is their own foot taken.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; is known &lt;i&gt;by&lt;/i&gt; the judgment &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; he executeth: the wicked is snared in the work of his own hands. Higgaion. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The wicked shall be turned into hell, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; all the nations that forget God.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For the needy shall not alway be forgotten: the expectation of the poor shall &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; perish for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Arise, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; let not man prevail: let the heathen be judged in thy sight.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Put them in fear, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the nations may know themselves &lt;i&gt;to be but&lt;/i&gt; men. Selah.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>