<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="40" verseCount="17" nextChapter="psalms_41.html" nextTitle="Psalms 41" prevChapter="psalms_39.html" prevTitle="Psalms 39" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Psalm of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I waited patiently for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and he inclined unto me, and heard my cry.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">He brought me up also out of an horrible pit, out of the miry clay, and set my feet upon a rock, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; established my goings.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he hath put a new song in my mouth, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; praise unto our God: many shall see &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and fear, and shall trust in the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; that man that maketh the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his trust, and respecteth not the proud, nor such as turn aside to lies.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Many, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; thy wonderful works &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; thou hast done, and thy thoughts &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which are&lt;/span&gt; to us-ward: they cannot be reckoned up in order unto thee: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; I would declare and speak &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of them&lt;/span&gt;, they are more than can be numbered.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Sacrifice and offering thou didst not desire; mine ears hast thou opened: burnt offering and sin offering hast thou not required.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then said I, Lo, I come: in the volume of the book &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; written of me,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I delight to do thy will, O my God: yea, thy law &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; within my heart.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I have preached righteousness in the great congregation: lo, I have not refrained my lips, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou knowest.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I have not hid thy righteousness within my heart; I have declared thy faithfulness and thy salvation: I have not concealed thy lovingkindness and thy truth from the great congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Withhold not thou thy tender mercies from me, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: let thy lovingkindness and thy truth continually preserve me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For innumerable evils have compassed me about: mine iniquities have taken hold upon me, so that I am not able to look up; they are more than the hairs of mine head: therefore my heart faileth me.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Be pleased, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to deliver me: O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, make haste to help me.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Let them be ashamed and confounded together that seek after my soul to destroy it; let them be driven backward and put to shame that wish me evil.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Let them be desolate for a reward of their shame that say unto me, Aha, aha.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Let all those that seek thee rejoice and be glad in thee: let such as love thy salvation say continually, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be magnified.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; poor and needy; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yet&lt;/span&gt; the Lord thinketh upon me: thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; my help and my deliverer; make no tarrying, O my God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>