<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="72" verseCount="20" nextChapter="psalms_73.html" nextTitle="Psalms 73" prevChapter="psalms_71.html" prevTitle="Psalms 71" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">&lt;i&gt;A Psalm&lt;/i&gt; for Solomon.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Give the king thy judgments, O God, and thy righteousness unto the king's son.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">He shall judge thy people with righteousness, and thy poor with judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The mountains shall bring peace to the people, and the little hills, by righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He shall judge the poor of the people, he shall save the children of the needy, and shall break in pieces the oppressor.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They shall fear thee as long as the sun and moon endure, throughout all generations.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He shall come down like rain upon the mown grass: as showers &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; water the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">In his days shall the righteous flourish; and abundance of peace so long as the moon endureth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He shall have dominion also from sea to sea, and from the river unto the ends of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">They that dwell in the wilderness shall bow before him; and his enemies shall lick the dust.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The kings of Tarshish and of the isles shall bring presents: the kings of Sheba and Seba shall offer gifts.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Yea, all kings shall fall down before him: all nations shall serve him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For he shall deliver the needy when he crieth; the poor also, and &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; that hath no helper.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He shall spare the poor and needy, and shall save the souls of the needy.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">He shall redeem their soul from deceit and violence: and precious shall their blood be in his sight.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he shall live, and to him shall be given of the gold of Sheba: prayer also shall be made for him continually; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; daily shall he be praised.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">There shall be an handful of corn in the earth upon the top of the mountains; the fruit thereof shall shake like Lebanon: and &lt;i&gt;they&lt;/i&gt; of the city shall flourish like grass of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">His name shall endure for ever: his name shall be continued as long as the sun: and &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; shall be blessed in him: all nations shall call him blessed.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Blessed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God, the God of Israel, who only doeth wondrous things.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And blessed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; his glorious name for ever: and let the whole earth be filled &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; his glory; Amen, and Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The prayers of David the son of Jesse are ended.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>