<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="46" verseCount="11" nextChapter="psalms_47.html" nextTitle="Psalms 47" prevChapter="psalms_45.html" prevTitle="Psalms 45" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician for the sons of Korah, A Song upon Alamoth.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; our refuge and strength, a very present help in trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Therefore will not we fear, though the earth be removed, and though the mountains be carried into the midst of the sea;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;i&gt;Though&lt;/i&gt; the waters thereof roar &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; be troubled, &lt;i&gt;though&lt;/i&gt; the mountains shake with the swelling thereof. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; a river, the streams whereof shall make glad the city of God, the holy &lt;i&gt;place&lt;/i&gt; of the tabernacles of the most High.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the midst of her; she shall not be moved: God shall help her, &lt;i&gt;and that&lt;/i&gt; right early.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The heathen raged, the kingdoms were moved: he uttered his voice, the earth melted.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with us; the God of Jacob &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; our refuge. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Come, behold the works of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, what desolations he hath made in the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He maketh wars to cease unto the end of the earth; he breaketh the bow, and cutteth the spear in sunder; he burneth the chariot in the fire.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Be still, and know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; God: I will be exalted among the heathen, I will be exalted in the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with us; the God of Jacob &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; our refuge. Selah.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>