<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="37" verseCount="40" nextChapter="psalms_38.html" nextTitle="Psalms 38" prevChapter="psalms_36.html" prevTitle="Psalms 36" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">&lt;i&gt;A Psalm&lt;/i&gt; of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Fret not thyself because of evildoers, neither be thou envious against the workers of iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For they shall soon be cut down like the grass, and wither as the green herb.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Trust in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and do good; &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; shalt thou dwell in the land, and verily thou shalt be fed.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Delight thyself also in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and he shall give thee the desires of thine heart.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Commit thy way unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; trust also in him; and he shall bring &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to pass.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he shall bring forth thy righteousness as the light, and thy judgment as the noonday.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Rest in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and wait patiently for him: fret not thyself because of him who prospereth in his way, because of the man who bringeth wicked devices to pass.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Cease from anger, and forsake wrath: fret not thyself in any wise to do evil.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For evildoers shall be cut off: but those that wait upon the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, they shall inherit the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For yet a little while, and the wicked &lt;i&gt;shall&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt;: yea, thou shalt diligently consider his place, and it &lt;i&gt;shall&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But the meek shall inherit the earth; and shall delight themselves in the abundance of peace.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The wicked plotteth against the just, and gnasheth upon him with his teeth.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The Lord shall laugh at him: for he seeth that his day is coming.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The wicked have drawn out the sword, and have bent their bow, to cast down the poor and needy, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; to slay such as be of upright conversation.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Their sword shall enter into their own heart, and their bows shall be broken.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">A little that a righteous man hath &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; better than the riches of many wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For the arms of the wicked shall be broken: but the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; upholdeth the righteous.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; knoweth the days of the upright: and their inheritance shall be for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">They shall not be ashamed in the evil time: and in the days of famine they shall be satisfied.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But the wicked shall perish, and the enemies of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; as the fat of lambs: they shall consume; into smoke shall they consume away.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The wicked borroweth, and payeth not again: but the righteous sheweth mercy, and giveth.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For &lt;i&gt;such as be&lt;/i&gt; blessed of him shall inherit the earth; and &lt;i&gt;they that be&lt;/i&gt; cursed of him shall be cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The steps of a &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; man are ordered by the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and he delighteth in his way.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Though he fall, he shall not be utterly cast down: for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; upholdeth &lt;i&gt;him with&lt;/i&gt; his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">I have been young, and &lt;i&gt;now&lt;/i&gt; am old; yet have I not seen the righteous forsaken, nor his seed begging bread.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;i&gt;He is&lt;/i&gt; ever merciful, and lendeth; and his seed &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; blessed.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Depart from evil, and do good; and dwell for evermore.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">For the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; loveth judgment, and forsaketh not his saints; they are preserved for ever: but the seed of the wicked shall be cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The righteous shall inherit the land, and dwell therein for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The mouth of the righteous speaketh wisdom, and his tongue talketh of judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The law of his God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in his heart; none of his steps shall slide.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">The wicked watcheth the righteous, and seeketh to slay him.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will not leave him in his hand, nor condemn him when he is judged.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Wait on the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and keep his way, and he shall exalt thee to inherit the land: when the wicked are cut off, thou shalt see &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">I have seen the wicked in great power, and spreading himself like a green bay tree.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Yet he passed away, and, lo, he &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; not: yea, I sought him, but he could not be found.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Mark the perfect &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;, and behold the upright: for the end of &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; man &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; peace.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">But the transgressors shall be destroyed together: the end of the wicked shall be cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">But the salvation of the righteous &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;i&gt;he is&lt;/i&gt; their strength in the time of trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall help them, and deliver them: he shall deliver them from the wicked, and save them, because they trust in him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>