<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="145" verseCount="21" nextChapter="psalms_146.html" nextTitle="Psalms 146" prevChapter="psalms_144.html" prevTitle="Psalms 144" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">David's &lt;i&gt;Psalm&lt;/i&gt; of praise.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I will extol thee, my God, O king; and I will bless thy name for ever and ever.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Every day will I bless thee; and I will praise thy name for ever and ever.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Great &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and greatly to be praised; and his greatness &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; unsearchable.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">One generation shall praise thy works to another, and shall declare thy mighty acts.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I will speak of the glorious honour of thy majesty, and of thy wondrous works.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; shall speak of the might of thy terrible acts: and I will declare thy greatness.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">They shall abundantly utter the memory of thy great goodness, and shall sing of thy righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; gracious, and full of compassion; slow to anger, and of great mercy.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; good to all: and his tender mercies &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; over all his works.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">All thy works shall praise thee, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and thy saints shall bless thee.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">They shall speak of the glory of thy kingdom, and talk of thy power;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">To make known to the sons of men his mighty acts, and the glorious majesty of his kingdom.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thy kingdom &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an everlasting kingdom, and thy dominion &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; throughout all generations.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; upholdeth all that fall, and raiseth up all &lt;i&gt;those that be&lt;/i&gt; bowed down.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The eyes of all wait upon thee; and thou givest them their meat in due season.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thou openest thine hand, and satisfiest the desire of every living thing.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; righteous in all his ways, and holy in all his works.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; nigh unto all them that call upon him, to all that call upon him in truth.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He will fulfil the desire of them that fear him: he also will hear their cry, and will save them.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; preserveth all them that love him: but all the wicked will he destroy.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">My mouth shall speak the praise of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and let all flesh bless his holy name for ever and ever.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>