<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="35" verseCount="28" nextChapter="psalms_36.html" nextTitle="Psalms 36" prevChapter="psalms_34.html" prevTitle="Psalms 34" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;A Psalm&lt;/span&gt; of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Plead &lt;span class='extra'&gt;my cause&lt;/span&gt;, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, with them that strive with me: fight against them that fight against me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Take hold of shield and buckler, and stand up for mine help.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Draw out also the spear, and stop &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the way&lt;/span&gt; against them that persecute me: say unto my soul, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; thy salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Let them be confounded and put to shame that seek after my soul: let them be turned back and brought to confusion that devise my hurt.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Let them be as chaff before the wind: and let the angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; chase &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Let their way be dark and slippery: and let the angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; persecute them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For without cause have they hid for me their net &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; a pit, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; without cause they have digged for my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Let destruction come upon him at unawares; and let his net that he hath hid catch himself: into that very destruction let him fall.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And my soul shall be joyful in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: it shall rejoice in his salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">All my bones shall say, &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; like unto thee, which deliverest the poor from him that is too strong for him, yea, the poor and the needy from him that spoileth him?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">False witnesses did rise up; they laid to my charge &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; that I knew not.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They rewarded me evil for good &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the spoiling of my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But as for me, when they were sick, my clothing &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; sackcloth: I humbled my soul with fasting; and my prayer returned into mine own bosom.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I behaved myself as though &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he had been&lt;/span&gt; my friend &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; brother: I bowed down heavily, as one that mourneth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for his&lt;/span&gt; mother.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But in mine adversity they rejoiced, and gathered themselves together: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;yea&lt;/span&gt;, the abjects gathered themselves together against me, and I knew &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; not; they did tear &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt;, and ceased not:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">With hypocritical mockers in feasts, they gnashed upon me with their teeth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Lord, how long wilt thou look on? rescue my soul from their destructions, my darling from the lions.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">I will give thee thanks in the great congregation: I will praise thee among much people.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Let not them that are mine enemies wrongfully rejoice over me: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;neither&lt;/span&gt; let them wink with the eye that hate me without a cause.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For they speak not peace: but they devise deceitful matters against &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them that are&lt;/span&gt; quiet in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Yea, they opened their mouth wide against me, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; said, Aha, aha, our eye hath seen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;This&lt;/span&gt; thou hast seen, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: keep not silence: O Lord, be not far from me.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Stir up thyself, and awake to my judgment, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto my cause, my God and my Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Judge me, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, according to thy righteousness; and let them not rejoice over me.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Let them not say in their hearts, Ah, so would we have it: let them not say, We have swallowed him up.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Let them be ashamed and brought to confusion together that rejoice at mine hurt: let them be clothed with shame and dishonour that magnify &lt;span class='extra'&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt; against me.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Let them shout for joy, and be glad, that favour my righteous cause: yea, let them say continually, Let the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be magnified, which hath pleasure in the prosperity of his servant.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And my tongue shall speak of thy righteousness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; of thy praise all the day long.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>