<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="45" verseCount="17" nextChapter="psalms_46.html" nextTitle="Psalms 46" prevChapter="psalms_44.html" prevTitle="Psalms 44" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician upon Shoshannim, for the sons of Korah, Maschil, A Song of loves.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">My heart is inditing a good matter: I speak of the things which I have made touching the king: my tongue &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the pen of a ready writer.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thou art fairer than the children of men: grace is poured into thy lips: therefore God hath blessed thee for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Gird thy sword upon &lt;i&gt;thy&lt;/i&gt; thigh, O &lt;i&gt;most&lt;/i&gt; mighty, with thy glory and thy majesty.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And in thy majesty ride prosperously because of truth and meekness &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; righteousness; and thy right hand shall teach thee terrible things.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thine arrows &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; sharp in the heart of the king's enemies; &lt;i&gt;whereby&lt;/i&gt; the people fall under thee.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thy throne, O God, &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; for ever and ever: the sceptre of thy kingdom &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a right sceptre.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thou lovest righteousness, and hatest wickedness: therefore God, thy God, hath anointed thee with the oil of gladness above thy fellows.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">All thy garments &lt;i&gt;smell&lt;/i&gt; of myrrh, and aloes, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; cassia, out of the ivory palaces, whereby they have made thee glad.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Kings' daughters &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; among thy honourable women: upon thy right hand did stand the queen in gold of Ophir.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Hearken, O daughter, and consider, and incline thine ear; forget also thine own people, and thy father's house;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">So shall the king greatly desire thy beauty: for he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy Lord; and worship thou him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the daughter of Tyre &lt;i&gt;shall be there&lt;/i&gt; with a gift; &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the rich among the people shall intreat thy favour.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The king's daughter &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; all glorious within: her clothing &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; of wrought gold.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">She shall be brought unto the king in raiment of needlework: the virgins her companions that follow her shall be brought unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">With gladness and rejoicing shall they be brought: they shall enter into the king's palace.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Instead of thy fathers shall be thy children, whom thou mayest make princes in all the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">I will make thy name to be remembered in all generations: therefore shall the people praise thee for ever and ever.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>