<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="139" verseCount="24" nextChapter="psalms_140.html" nextTitle="Psalms 140" prevChapter="psalms_138.html" prevTitle="Psalms 138" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Psalm of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou hast searched me, and known &lt;span class="extra"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thou knowest my downsitting and mine uprising, thou understandest my thought afar off.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou compassest my path and my lying down, and art acquainted &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; all my ways.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; not a word in my tongue, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt;, lo, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou knowest it altogether.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thou hast beset me behind and before, and laid thine hand upon me.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Such&lt;/span&gt; knowledge &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; too wonderful for me; it is high, I cannot &lt;span class="extra"&gt;attain&lt;/span&gt; unto it.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Whither shall I go from thy spirit? or whither shall I flee from thy presence?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">If I ascend up into heaven, thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; there: if I make my bed in hell, behold, thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art there&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;If&lt;/span&gt; I take the wings of the morning, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; dwell in the uttermost parts of the sea;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Even there shall thy hand lead me, and thy right hand shall hold me.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">If I say, Surely the darkness shall cover me; even the night shall be light about me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Yea, the darkness hideth not from thee; but the night shineth as the day: the darkness and the light &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; both alike &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to thee&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For thou hast possessed my reins: thou hast covered me in my mother's womb.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I will praise thee; for I am fearfully &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; wonderfully made: marvellous &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; thy works; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; my soul knoweth right well.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">My substance was not hid from thee, when I was made in secret, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; curiously wrought in the lowest parts of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thine eyes did see my substance, yet being unperfect; and in thy book all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my members&lt;/span&gt; were written, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; in continuance were fashioned, when &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as yet there was&lt;/span&gt; none of them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">How precious also are thy thoughts unto me, O God! how great is the sum of them!</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;If&lt;/span&gt; I should count them, they are more in number than the sand: when I awake, I am still with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Surely thou wilt slay the wicked, O God: depart from me therefore, ye bloody men.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For they speak against thee wickedly, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; thine enemies take &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thy name&lt;/span&gt; in vain.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Do not I hate them, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that hate thee? and am not I grieved with those that rise up against thee?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">I hate them with perfect hatred: I count them mine enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Search me, O God, and know my heart: try me, and know my thoughts:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And see if &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there be any&lt;/span&gt; wicked way in me, and lead me in the way everlasting.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>