<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="38" verseCount="22" nextChapter="psalms_39.html" nextTitle="Psalms 39" prevChapter="psalms_37.html" prevTitle="Psalms 37" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Psalm of David, to bring to remembrance.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, rebuke me not in thy wrath: neither chasten me in thy hot displeasure.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For thine arrows stick fast in me, and thy hand presseth me sore.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; no soundness in my flesh because of thine anger; neither &lt;i&gt;is there any&lt;/i&gt; rest in my bones because of my sin.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For mine iniquities are gone over mine head: as an heavy burden they are too heavy for me.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">My wounds stink &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; are corrupt because of my foolishness.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I am troubled; I am bowed down greatly; I go mourning all the day long.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For my loins are filled with a loathsome &lt;i&gt;disease&lt;/i&gt;: and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no soundness in my flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I am feeble and sore broken: I have roared by reason of the disquietness of my heart.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Lord, all my desire &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; before thee; and my groaning is not hid from thee.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">My heart panteth, my strength faileth me: as for the light of mine eyes, it also is gone from me.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">My lovers and my friends stand aloof from my sore; and my kinsmen stand afar off.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They also that seek after my life lay snares &lt;i&gt;for me&lt;/i&gt;: and they that seek my hurt speak mischievous things, and imagine deceits all the day long.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But I, as a deaf &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;, heard not; and &lt;i&gt;I was&lt;/i&gt; as a dumb man &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; openeth not his mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thus I was as a man that heareth not, and in whose mouth &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; no reproofs.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For in thee, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, do I hope: thou wilt hear, O Lord my God.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For I said, &lt;i&gt;Hear me&lt;/i&gt;, lest &lt;i&gt;otherwise&lt;/i&gt; they should rejoice over me: when my foot slippeth, they magnify &lt;i&gt;themselves&lt;/i&gt; against me.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; ready to halt, and my sorrow &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; continually before me.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For I will declare mine iniquity; I will be sorry for my sin.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But mine enemies &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; lively, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; they are strong: and they that hate me wrongfully are multiplied.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">They also that render evil for good are mine adversaries; because I follow &lt;i&gt;the thing that&lt;/i&gt; good &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Forsake me not, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: O my God, be not far from me.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Make haste to help me, O Lord my salvation.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>