<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="41" verseCount="13" nextChapter="psalms_42.html" nextTitle="Psalms 42" prevChapter="psalms_40.html" prevTitle="Psalms 40" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Psalm of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Blessed &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he that considereth the poor: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will deliver him in time of trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will preserve him, and keep him alive; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; he shall be blessed upon the earth: and thou wilt not deliver him unto the will of his enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will strengthen him upon the bed of languishing: thou wilt make all his bed in his sickness.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I said, &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, be merciful unto me: heal my soul; for I have sinned against thee.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Mine enemies speak evil of me, When shall he die, and his name perish?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And if he come to see &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt;, he speaketh vanity: his heart gathereth iniquity to itself; &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; he goeth abroad, he telleth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">All that hate me whisper together against me: against me do they devise my hurt.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">An evil disease, &lt;i&gt;say they&lt;/i&gt;, cleaveth fast unto him: and &lt;i&gt;now&lt;/i&gt; that he lieth he shall rise up no more.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Yea, mine own familiar friend, in whom I trusted, which did eat of my bread, hath lifted up &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; heel against me.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But thou, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, be merciful unto me, and raise me up, that I may requite them.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">By this I know that thou favourest me, because mine enemy doth not triumph over me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And as for me, thou upholdest me in mine integrity, and settest me before thy face for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Blessed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel from everlasting, and to everlasting. Amen, and Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>