<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="64" verseCount="10" nextChapter="psalms_65.html" nextTitle="Psalms 65" prevChapter="psalms_63.html" prevTitle="Psalms 63" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Psalm of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hear my voice, O God, in my prayer: preserve my life from fear of the enemy.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Hide me from the secret counsel of the wicked; from the insurrection of the workers of iniquity:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Who whet their tongue like a sword, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; bend &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their bows to shoot&lt;/span&gt; their arrows, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; bitter words:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">That they may shoot in secret at the perfect: suddenly do they shoot at him, and fear not.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They encourage themselves &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; an evil matter: they commune of laying snares privily; they say, Who shall see them?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">They search out iniquities; they accomplish a diligent search: both the inward &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thought&lt;/span&gt; of every one &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of them&lt;/span&gt;, and the heart, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; deep.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But God shall shoot at them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; an arrow; suddenly shall they be wounded.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">So they shall make their own tongue to fall upon themselves: all that see them shall flee away.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And all men shall fear, and shall declare the work of God; for they shall wisely consider of his doing.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The righteous shall be glad in the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and shall trust in him; and all the upright in heart shall glory.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>