<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="144" verseCount="15" nextChapter="psalms_145.html" nextTitle="Psalms 145" prevChapter="psalms_143.html" prevTitle="Psalms 143" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">&lt;i&gt;A Psalm&lt;/i&gt; of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Blessed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my strength, which teacheth my hands to war, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; my fingers to fight:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">My goodness, and my fortress; my high tower, and my deliverer; my shield, and &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt; in whom I trust; who subdueth my people under me.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, what &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; man, that thou takest knowledge of him! &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; the son of man, that thou makest account of him!</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Man is like to vanity: his days &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; as a shadow that passeth away.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Bow thy heavens, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and come down: touch the mountains, and they shall smoke.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Cast forth lightning, and scatter them: shoot out thine arrows, and destroy them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Send thine hand from above; rid me, and deliver me out of great waters, from the hand of strange children;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Whose mouth speaketh vanity, and their right hand &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a right hand of falsehood.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I will sing a new song unto thee, O God: upon a psaltery &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; an instrument of ten strings will I sing praises unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;i&gt;It is he&lt;/i&gt; that giveth salvation unto kings: who delivereth David his servant from the hurtful sword.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Rid me, and deliver me from the hand of strange children, whose mouth speaketh vanity, and their right hand &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a right hand of falsehood:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">That our sons &lt;i&gt;may be&lt;/i&gt; as plants grown up in their youth; &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; our daughters &lt;i&gt;may be&lt;/i&gt; as corner stones, polished &lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt; the similitude of a palace:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;i&gt;That&lt;/i&gt; our garners &lt;i&gt;may be&lt;/i&gt; full, affording all manner of store: &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; our sheep may bring forth thousands and ten thousands in our streets:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;i&gt;That&lt;/i&gt; our oxen &lt;i&gt;may be&lt;/i&gt; strong to labour; &lt;i&gt;that there be&lt;/i&gt; no breaking in, nor going out; that &lt;i&gt;there be&lt;/i&gt; no complaining in our streets.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Happy &lt;i&gt;is that&lt;/i&gt; people, that is in such a case: &lt;i&gt;yea&lt;/i&gt;, happy &lt;i&gt;is that&lt;/i&gt; people, whose God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>