<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="49" verseCount="20" nextChapter="psalms_50.html" nextTitle="Psalms 50" prevChapter="psalms_48.html" prevTitle="Psalms 48" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Psalm for the sons of Korah.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hear this, all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;ye&lt;/span&gt; people; give ear, all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;ye&lt;/span&gt; inhabitants of the world:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Both low and high, rich and poor, together.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">My mouth shall speak of wisdom; and the meditation of my heart &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; of understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I will incline mine ear to a parable: I will open my dark saying upon the harp.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Wherefore should I fear in the days of evil, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; the iniquity of my heels shall compass me about?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">They that trust in their wealth, and boast themselves in the multitude of their riches;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">None &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of them&lt;/span&gt; can by any means redeem his brother, nor give to God a ransom for him:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">(For the redemption of their soul &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; precious, and it ceaseth for ever:)</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">That he should still live for ever, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; not see corruption.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For he seeth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; wise men die, likewise the fool and the brutish person perish, and leave their wealth to others.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Their inward thought &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is, that&lt;/span&gt; their houses &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall continue&lt;/span&gt; for ever, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; their dwelling places to all generations; they call &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; lands after their own names.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Nevertheless man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; in honour abideth not: he is like the beasts &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; perish.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">This their way &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; their folly: yet their posterity approve their sayings. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Like sheep they are laid in the grave; death shall feed on them; and the upright shall have dominion over them in the morning; and their beauty shall consume in the grave from their dwelling.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But God will redeem my soul from the power of the grave: for he shall receive me. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Be not thou afraid when one is made rich, when the glory of his house is increased;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For when he dieth he shall carry nothing away: his glory shall not descend after him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Though while he lived he blessed his soul: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; will praise thee, when thou doest well to thyself.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He shall go to the generation of his fathers; they shall never see light.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; in honour, and understandeth not, is like the beasts &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; perish.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>