<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="65" verseCount="13" nextChapter="psalms_66.html" nextTitle="Psalms 66" prevChapter="psalms_64.html" prevTitle="Psalms 64" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Psalm &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Song of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Praise waiteth for thee, O God, in Sion: and unto thee shall the vow be performed.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">O thou that hearest prayer, unto thee shall all flesh come.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Iniquities prevail against me: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; our transgressions, thou shalt purge them away.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is the man whom&lt;/span&gt; thou choosest, and causest to approach &lt;span class='extra'&gt;unto thee, that&lt;/span&gt; he may dwell in thy courts: we shall be satisfied with the goodness of thy house, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of thy holy temple.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;By&lt;/span&gt; terrible things in righteousness wilt thou answer us, O God of our salvation; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;who art&lt;/span&gt; the confidence of all the ends of the earth, and of them that are afar off &lt;span class='extra'&gt;upon&lt;/span&gt; the sea:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Which by his strength setteth fast the mountains; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; girded with power:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Which stilleth the noise of the seas, the noise of their waves, and the tumult of the people.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">They also that dwell in the uttermost parts are afraid at thy tokens: thou makest the outgoings of the morning and evening to rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thou visitest the earth, and waterest it: thou greatly enrichest it with the river of God, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; is full of water: thou preparest them corn, when thou hast so provided for it.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thou waterest the ridges thereof abundantly: thou settlest the furrows thereof: thou makest it soft with showers: thou blessest the springing thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thou crownest the year with thy goodness; and thy paths drop fatness.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They drop &lt;span class='extra'&gt;upon&lt;/span&gt; the pastures of the wilderness: and the little hills rejoice on every side.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The pastures are clothed with flocks; the valleys also are covered over with corn; they shout for joy, they also sing.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>