<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="42" verseCount="11" nextChapter="psalms_43.html" nextTitle="Psalms 43" prevChapter="psalms_41.html" prevTitle="Psalms 41" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, Maschil, for the sons of Korah.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">As the hart panteth after the water brooks, so panteth my soul after thee, O God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">My soul thirsteth for God, for the living God: when shall I come and appear before God?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">My tears have been my meat day and night, while they continually say unto me, Where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy God?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">When I remember these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;, I pour out my soul in me: for I had gone with the multitude, I went with them to the house of God, with the voice of joy and praise, with a multitude that kept holyday.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Why art thou cast down, O my soul? and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;why&lt;/span&gt; art thou disquieted in me? hope thou in God: for I shall yet praise him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the help of his countenance.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">O my God, my soul is cast down within me: therefore will I remember thee from the land of Jordan, and of the Hermonites, from the hill Mizar.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Deep calleth unto deep at the noise of thy waterspouts: all thy waves and thy billows are gone over me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Yet&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will command his lovingkindness in the daytime, and in the night his song &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; with me, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; my prayer unto the God of my life.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I will say unto God my rock, Why hast thou forgotten me? why go I mourning because of the oppression of the enemy?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; with a sword in my bones, mine enemies reproach me; while they say daily unto me, Where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy God?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Why art thou cast down, O my soul? and why art thou disquieted within me? hope thou in God: for I shall yet praise him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;who is&lt;/span&gt; the health of my countenance, and my God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>