<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="56" verseCount="13" nextChapter="psalms_57.html" nextTitle="Psalms 57" prevChapter="psalms_55.html" prevTitle="Psalms 55" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician upon Jonath-elem-rechokim, Michtam of David, when the Philistines took him in Gath.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Be merciful unto me, O God: for man would swallow me up; he fighting daily oppresseth me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Mine enemies would daily swallow &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; up: for &lt;i&gt;they be&lt;/i&gt; many that fight against me, O thou most High.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">What time I am afraid, I will trust in thee.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">In God I will praise his word, in God I have put my trust; I will not fear what flesh can do unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Every day they wrest my words: all their thoughts &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; against me for evil.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">They gather themselves together, they hide themselves, they mark my steps, when they wait for my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Shall they escape by iniquity? in &lt;i&gt;thine&lt;/i&gt; anger cast down the people, O God.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Thou tellest my wanderings: put thou my tears into thy bottle: &lt;i&gt;are they&lt;/i&gt; not in thy book?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">When I cry &lt;i&gt;unto thee&lt;/i&gt;, then shall mine enemies turn back: this I know; for God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; for me.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">In God will I praise &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; word: in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will I praise &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; word.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">In God have I put my trust: I will not be afraid what man can do unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Thy vows &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; upon me, O God: I will render praises unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For thou hast delivered my soul from death: &lt;i&gt;wilt&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;thou deliver&lt;/i&gt; my feet from falling, that I may walk before God in the light of the living?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>