<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="39" verseCount="13" nextChapter="psalms_40.html" nextTitle="Psalms 40" prevChapter="psalms_38.html" prevTitle="Psalms 38" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to Jeduthun, A Psalm of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I said, I will take heed to my ways, that I sin not with my tongue: I will keep my mouth with a bridle, while the wicked is before me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I was dumb with silence, I held my peace, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; from good; and my sorrow was stirred.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">My heart was hot within me, while I was musing the fire burned: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; spake I with my tongue,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, make me to know mine end, and the measure of my days, what it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is; that&lt;/span&gt; I may know how frail I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Behold, thou hast made my days &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; an handbreadth; and mine age &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; as nothing before thee: verily every man at his best state &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; altogether vanity. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Surely every man walketh in a vain shew: surely they are disquieted in vain: he heapeth up &lt;span class="extra"&gt;riches&lt;/span&gt;, and knoweth not who shall gather them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And now, Lord, what wait I for? my hope &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in thee.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Deliver me from all my transgressions: make me not the reproach of the foolish.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I was dumb, I opened not my mouth; because thou didst &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Remove thy stroke away from me: I am consumed by the blow of thine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">When thou with rebukes dost correct man for iniquity, thou makest his beauty to consume away like a moth: surely every man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vanity. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Hear my prayer, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and give ear unto my cry; hold not thy peace at my tears: for I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; a stranger with thee, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; a sojourner, as all my fathers &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">O spare me, that I may recover strength, before I go hence, and be no more.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>