<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="132" verseCount="18" nextChapter="psalms_133.html" nextTitle="Psalms 133" prevChapter="psalms_131.html" prevTitle="Psalms 131" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Song of degrees.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, remember David, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; all his afflictions:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">How he sware unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; vowed unto the mighty &lt;i&gt;God&lt;/i&gt; of Jacob;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Surely I will not come into the tabernacle of my house, nor go up into my bed;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I will not give sleep to mine eyes, &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; slumber to mine eyelids,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Until I find out a place for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, an habitation for the mighty &lt;i&gt;God&lt;/i&gt; of Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Lo, we heard of it at Ephratah: we found it in the fields of the wood.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">We will go into his tabernacles: we will worship at his footstool.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Arise, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, into thy rest; thou, and the ark of thy strength.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Let thy priests be clothed with righteousness; and let thy saints shout for joy.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For thy servant David's sake turn not away the face of thine anointed.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath sworn &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; truth unto David; he will not turn from it; Of the fruit of thy body will I set upon thy throne.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">If thy children will keep my covenant and my testimony that I shall teach them, their children shall also sit upon thy throne for evermore.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath chosen Zion; he hath desired &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; for his habitation.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my rest for ever: here will I dwell; for I have desired it.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I will abundantly bless her provision: I will satisfy her poor with bread.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I will also clothe her priests with salvation: and her saints shall shout aloud for joy.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">There will I make the horn of David to bud: I have ordained a lamp for mine anointed.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">His enemies will I clothe with shame: but upon himself shall his crown flourish.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>