<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="57" verseCount="11" nextChapter="psalms_58.html" nextTitle="Psalms 58" prevChapter="psalms_56.html" prevTitle="Psalms 56" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, Al-taschith, Michtam of David, when he fled from Saul in the cave.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Be merciful unto me, O God, be merciful unto me: for my soul trusteth in thee: yea, in the shadow of thy wings will I make my refuge, until &lt;span class="extra"&gt;these&lt;/span&gt; calamities be overpast.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I will cry unto God most high; unto God that performeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;all things&lt;/span&gt; for me.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">He shall send from heaven, and save me &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the reproach of him that would swallow me up. Selah. God shall send forth his mercy and his truth.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">My soul &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; among lions: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; I lie &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even among&lt;/span&gt; them that are set on fire, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the sons of men, whose teeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; spears and arrows, and their tongue a sharp sword.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Be thou exalted, O God, above the heavens; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; thy glory &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; above all the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">They have prepared a net for my steps; my soul is bowed down: they have digged a pit before me, into the midst whereof they are fallen &lt;span class="extra"&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt;. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">My heart is fixed, O God, my heart is fixed: I will sing and give praise.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Awake up, my glory; awake, psaltery and harp: I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;myself&lt;/span&gt; will awake early.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I will praise thee, O Lord, among the people: I will sing unto thee among the nations.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For thy mercy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; great unto the heavens, and thy truth unto the clouds.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Be thou exalted, O God, above the heavens: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; thy glory &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; above all the earth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>