<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="86" verseCount="17" nextChapter="psalms_87.html" nextTitle="Psalms 87" prevChapter="psalms_85.html" prevTitle="Psalms 85" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Prayer of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Bow down thine ear, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hear me: for I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; poor and needy.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Preserve my soul; for I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; holy: O thou my God, save thy servant that trusteth in thee.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Be merciful unto me, O Lord: for I cry unto thee daily.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Rejoice the soul of thy servant: for unto thee, O Lord, do I lift up my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For thou, Lord, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; good, and ready to forgive; and plenteous in mercy unto all them that call upon thee.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Give ear, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, unto my prayer; and attend to the voice of my supplications.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">In the day of my trouble I will call upon thee: for thou wilt answer me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Among the gods &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none like unto thee, O Lord; neither &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are there any works&lt;/span&gt; like unto thy works.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">All nations whom thou hast made shall come and worship before thee, O Lord; and shall glorify thy name.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; great, and doest wondrous things: thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; God alone.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Teach me thy way, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; I will walk in thy truth: unite my heart to fear thy name.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I will praise thee, O Lord my God, with all my heart: and I will glorify thy name for evermore.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For great &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy mercy toward me: and thou hast delivered my soul from the lowest hell.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">O God, the proud are risen against me, and the assemblies of violent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; have sought after my soul; and have not set thee before them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But thou, O Lord, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; a God full of compassion, and gracious, longsuffering, and plenteous in mercy and truth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">O turn unto me, and have mercy upon me; give thy strength unto thy servant, and save the son of thine handmaid.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Shew me a token for good; that they which hate me may see &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and be ashamed: because thou, &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hast holpen me, and comforted me.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>