<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="105" verseCount="45" nextChapter="psalms_106.html" nextTitle="Psalms 106" prevChapter="psalms_104.html" prevTitle="Psalms 104" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O give thanks unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; call upon his name: make known his deeds among the people.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Sing unto him, sing psalms unto him: talk ye of all his wondrous works.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Glory ye in his holy name: let the heart of them rejoice that seek the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Seek the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and his strength: seek his face evermore.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Remember his marvellous works that he hath done; his wonders, and the judgments of his mouth;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">O ye seed of Abraham his servant, ye children of Jacob his chosen.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God: his judgments &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in all the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He hath remembered his covenant for ever, the word &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; he commanded to a thousand generations.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Which &lt;i&gt;covenant&lt;/i&gt; he made with Abraham, and his oath unto Isaac;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And confirmed the same unto Jacob for a law, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; to Israel &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an everlasting covenant:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Saying, Unto thee will I give the land of Canaan, the lot of your inheritance:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">When they were &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; a few men in number; yea, very few, and strangers in it.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">When they went from one nation to another, from &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; kingdom to another people;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">He suffered no man to do them wrong: yea, he reproved kings for their sakes;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;i&gt;Saying&lt;/i&gt;, Touch not mine anointed, and do my prophets no harm.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Moreover he called for a famine upon the land: he brake the whole staff of bread.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He sent a man before them, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; Joseph, &lt;i&gt;who&lt;/i&gt; was sold for a servant:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Whose feet they hurt with fetters: he was laid in iron:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Until the time that his word came: the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; tried him.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The king sent and loosed him; &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the ruler of the people, and let him go free.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">He made him lord of his house, and ruler of all his substance:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">To bind his princes at his pleasure; and teach his senators wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Israel also came into Egypt; and Jacob sojourned in the land of Ham.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And he increased his people greatly; and made them stronger than their enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">He turned their heart to hate his people, to deal subtilly with his servants.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">He sent Moses his servant; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Aaron whom he had chosen.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">They shewed his signs among them, and wonders in the land of Ham.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">He sent darkness, and made it dark; and they rebelled not against his word.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">He turned their waters into blood, and slew their fish.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Their land brought forth frogs in abundance, in the chambers of their kings.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">He spake, and there came divers sorts of flies, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; lice in all their coasts.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">He gave them hail for rain, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; flaming fire in their land.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">He smote their vines also and their fig trees; and brake the trees of their coasts.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">He spake, and the locusts came, and caterpillers, and that without number,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And did eat up all the herbs in their land, and devoured the fruit of their ground.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">He smote also all the firstborn in their land, the chief of all their strength.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">He brought them forth also with silver and gold: and &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; not one feeble &lt;i&gt;person&lt;/i&gt; among their tribes.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">Egypt was glad when they departed: for the fear of them fell upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">He spread a cloud for a covering; and fire to give light in the night.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">&lt;i&gt;The people&lt;/i&gt; asked, and he brought quails, and satisfied them with the bread of heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">He opened the rock, and the waters gushed out; they ran in the dry places &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; a river.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">For he remembered his holy promise, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Abraham his servant.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And he brought forth his people with joy, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; his chosen with gladness:</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And gave them the lands of the heathen: and they inherited the labour of the people;</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">That they might observe his statutes, and keep his laws. Praise ye the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>