<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="55" verseCount="23" nextChapter="psalms_56.html" nextTitle="Psalms 56" prevChapter="psalms_54.html" prevTitle="Psalms 54" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician on Neginoth, Maschil, &lt;i&gt;A Psalm&lt;/i&gt; of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Give ear to my prayer, O God; and hide not thyself from my supplication.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Attend unto me, and hear me: I mourn in my complaint, and make a noise;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Because of the voice of the enemy, because of the oppression of the wicked: for they cast iniquity upon me, and in wrath they hate me.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">My heart is sore pained within me: and the terrors of death are fallen upon me.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Fearfulness and trembling are come upon me, and horror hath overwhelmed me.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I said, Oh that I had wings like a dove! &lt;i&gt;for then&lt;/i&gt; would I fly away, and be at rest.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Lo, &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; would I wander far off, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; remain in the wilderness. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I would hasten my escape from the windy storm &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; tempest.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Destroy, O Lord, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; divide their tongues: for I have seen violence and strife in the city.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Day and night they go about it upon the walls thereof: mischief also and sorrow &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in the midst of it.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Wickedness &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the midst thereof: deceit and guile depart not from her streets.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For &lt;i&gt;it was&lt;/i&gt; not an enemy &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; reproached me; then I could have borne &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;: neither &lt;i&gt;was it&lt;/i&gt; he that hated me &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; did magnify &lt;i&gt;himself&lt;/i&gt; against me; then I would have hid myself from him:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But &lt;i&gt;it was&lt;/i&gt; thou, a man mine equal, my guide, and mine acquaintance.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">We took sweet counsel together, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; walked unto the house of God in company.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Let death seize upon them, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; let them go down quick into hell: for wickedness &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in their dwellings, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; among them.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">As for me, I will call upon God; and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall save me.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Evening, and morning, and at noon, will I pray, and cry aloud: and he shall hear my voice.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He hath delivered my soul in peace from the battle &lt;i&gt;that was&lt;/i&gt; against me: for there were many with me.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">God shall hear, and afflict them, even he that abideth of old. Selah. Because they have no changes, therefore they fear not God.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He hath put forth his hands against such as be at peace with him: he hath broken his covenant.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;i&gt;The words&lt;/i&gt; of his mouth were smoother than butter, but war &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; in his heart: his words were softer than oil, yet &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; they drawn swords.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Cast thy burden upon the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and he shall sustain thee: he shall never suffer the righteous to be moved.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But thou, O God, shalt bring them down into the pit of destruction: bloody and deceitful men shall not live out half their days; but I will trust in thee.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>