<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="81" verseCount="16" nextChapter="psalms_82.html" nextTitle="Psalms 82" prevChapter="psalms_80.html" prevTitle="Psalms 80" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician upon Gittith, &lt;i&gt;A Psalm&lt;/i&gt; of Asaph.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Sing aloud unto God our strength: make a joyful noise unto the God of Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Take a psalm, and bring hither the timbrel, the pleasant harp with the psaltery.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Blow up the trumpet in the new moon, in the time appointed, on our solemn feast day.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For this &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a statute for Israel, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; a law of the God of Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">This he ordained in Joseph &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a testimony, when he went out through the land of Egypt: &lt;i&gt;where&lt;/i&gt; I heard a language &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I understood not.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I removed his shoulder from the burden: his hands were delivered from the pots.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thou calledst in trouble, and I delivered thee; I answered thee in the secret place of thunder: I proved thee at the waters of Meribah. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Hear, O my people, and I will testify unto thee: O Israel, if thou wilt hearken unto me;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">There shall no strange god be in thee; neither shalt thou worship any strange god.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, which brought thee out of the land of Egypt: open thy mouth wide, and I will fill it.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But my people would not hearken to my voice; and Israel would none of me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">So I gave them up unto their own hearts' lust: &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; they walked in their own counsels.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Oh that my people had hearkened unto me, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Israel had walked in my ways!</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I should soon have subdued their enemies, and turned my hand against their adversaries.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The haters of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; should have submitted themselves unto him: but their time should have endured for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He should have fed them also with the finest of the wheat: and with honey out of the rock should I have satisfied thee.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>