<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="50" nextChapter="psalms_19.html" nextTitle="Psalms 19" prevChapter="psalms_17.html" prevTitle="Psalms 17" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, &lt;i&gt;A Psalm&lt;/i&gt; of David, the servant of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, who spake unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; the words of this song in the day &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; delivered him from the hand of all his enemies, and from the hand of Saul: And he said,</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I will love thee, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, my strength.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my rock, and my fortress, and my deliverer; my God, my strength, in whom I will trust; my buckler, and the horn of my salvation, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; my high tower.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I will call upon the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;who is worthy&lt;/i&gt; to be praised: so shall I be saved from mine enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The sorrows of death compassed me, and the floods of ungodly men made me afraid.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The sorrows of hell compassed me about: the snares of death prevented me.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">In my distress I called upon the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and cried unto my God: he heard my voice out of his temple, and my cry came before him, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; into his ears.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then the earth shook and trembled; the foundations also of the hills moved and were shaken, because he was wroth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">There went up a smoke out of his nostrils, and fire out of his mouth devoured: coals were kindled by it.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He bowed the heavens also, and came down: and darkness &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; under his feet.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he rode upon a cherub, and did fly: yea, he did fly upon the wings of the wind.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He made darkness his secret place; his pavilion round about him &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; dark waters &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; thick clouds of the skies.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">At the brightness &lt;i&gt;that was&lt;/i&gt; before him his thick clouds passed, hail &lt;i&gt;stones&lt;/i&gt; and coals of fire.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; also thundered in the heavens, and the Highest gave his voice; hail &lt;i&gt;stones&lt;/i&gt; and coals of fire.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Yea, he sent out his arrows, and scattered them; and he shot out lightnings, and discomfited them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Then the channels of waters were seen, and the foundations of the world were discovered at thy rebuke, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, at the blast of the breath of thy nostrils.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He sent from above, he took me, he drew me out of many waters.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He delivered me from my strong enemy, and from them which hated me: for they were too strong for me.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">They prevented me in the day of my calamity: but the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was my stay.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He brought me forth also into a large place; he delivered me, because he delighted in me.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; rewarded me according to my righteousness; according to the cleanness of my hands hath he recompensed me.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For I have kept the ways of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and have not wickedly departed from my God.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For all his judgments &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; before me, and I did not put away his statutes from me.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">I was also upright before him, and I kept myself from mine iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Therefore hath the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; recompensed me according to my righteousness, according to the cleanness of my hands in his eyesight.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">With the merciful thou wilt shew thyself merciful; with an upright man thou wilt shew thyself upright;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">With the pure thou wilt shew thyself pure; and with the froward thou wilt shew thyself froward.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For thou wilt save the afflicted people; but wilt bring down high looks.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">For thou wilt light my candle: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God will enlighten my darkness.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For by thee I have run through a troop; and by my God have I leaped over a wall.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;i&gt;As for&lt;/i&gt; God, his way &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; perfect: the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; is tried: he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a buckler to all those that trust in him.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">For who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; God save the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? or who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a rock save our God?</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; God that girdeth me with strength, and maketh my way perfect.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">He maketh my feet like hinds' &lt;i&gt;feet&lt;/i&gt;, and setteth me upon my high places.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">He teacheth my hands to war, so that a bow of steel is broken by mine arms.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Thou hast also given me the shield of thy salvation: and thy right hand hath holden me up, and thy gentleness hath made me great.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Thou hast enlarged my steps under me, that my feet did not slip.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">I have pursued mine enemies, and overtaken them: neither did I turn again till they were consumed.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">I have wounded them that they were not able to rise: they are fallen under my feet.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">For thou hast girded me with strength unto the battle: thou hast subdued under me those that rose up against me.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Thou hast also given me the necks of mine enemies; that I might destroy them that hate me.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">They cried, but &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; none to save &lt;i&gt;them: even&lt;/i&gt; unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, but he answered them not.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Then did I beat them small as the dust before the wind: I did cast them out as the dirt in the streets.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Thou hast delivered me from the strivings of the people; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; thou hast made me the head of the heathen: a people &lt;i&gt;whom&lt;/i&gt; I have not known shall serve me.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">As soon as they hear of me, they shall obey me: the strangers shall submit themselves unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">The strangers shall fade away, and be afraid out of their close places.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth; and blessed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; my rock; and let the God of my salvation be exalted.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; God that avengeth me, and subdueth the people under me.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">He delivereth me from mine enemies: yea, thou liftest me up above those that rise up against me: thou hast delivered me from the violent man.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">Therefore will I give thanks unto thee, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, among the heathen, and sing praises unto thy name.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">Great deliverance giveth he to his king; and sheweth mercy to his anointed, to David, and to his seed for evermore.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>