<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="69" verseCount="36" nextChapter="psalms_70.html" nextTitle="Psalms 70" prevChapter="psalms_68.html" prevTitle="Psalms 68" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician upon Shoshannim, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;A Psalm&lt;/span&gt; of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Save me, O God; for the waters are come in unto &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; soul.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I sink in deep mire, where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no standing: I am come into deep waters, where the floods overflow me.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I am weary of my crying: my throat is dried: mine eyes fail while I wait for my God.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They that hate me without a cause are more than the hairs of mine head: they that would destroy me, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; mine enemies wrongfully, are mighty: then I restored &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which I took not away.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">O God, thou knowest my foolishness; and my sins are not hid from thee.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Let not them that wait on thee, O Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, be ashamed for my sake: let not those that seek thee be confounded for my sake, O God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Because for thy sake I have borne reproach; shame hath covered my face.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I am become a stranger unto my brethren, and an alien unto my mother's children.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For the zeal of thine house hath eaten me up; and the reproaches of them that reproached thee are fallen upon me.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">When I wept, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and chastened&lt;/span&gt; my soul with fasting, that was to my reproach.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">I made sackcloth also my garment; and I became a proverb to them.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They that sit in the gate speak against me; and I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the song of the drunkards.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But as for me, my prayer &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unto thee, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; an acceptable time: O God, in the multitude of thy mercy hear me, in the truth of thy salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Deliver me out of the mire, and let me not sink: let me be delivered from them that hate me, and out of the deep waters.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Let not the waterflood overflow me, neither let the deep swallow me up, and let not the pit shut her mouth upon me.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Hear me, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for thy lovingkindness &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; good: turn unto me according to the multitude of thy tender mercies.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And hide not thy face from thy servant; for I am in trouble: hear me speedily.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Draw nigh unto my soul, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; redeem it: deliver me because of mine enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thou hast known my reproach, and my shame, and my dishonour: mine adversaries &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all before thee.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Reproach hath broken my heart; and I am full of heaviness: and I looked &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for some&lt;/span&gt; to take pity, but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; none; and for comforters, but I found none.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">They gave me also gall for my meat; and in my thirst they gave me vinegar to drink.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Let their table become a snare before them: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that which should have been&lt;/span&gt; for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; welfare, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;let it become&lt;/span&gt; a trap.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Let their eyes be darkened, that they see not; and make their loins continually to shake.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Pour out thine indignation upon them, and let thy wrathful anger take hold of them.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Let their habitation be desolate; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; let none dwell in their tents.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For they persecute &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; whom thou hast smitten; and they talk to the grief of those whom thou hast wounded.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Add iniquity unto their iniquity: and let them not come into thy righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Let them be blotted out of the book of the living, and not be written with the righteous.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">But I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; poor and sorrowful: let thy salvation, O God, set me up on high.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">I will praise the name of God with a song, and will magnify him with thanksgiving.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;This&lt;/span&gt; also shall please the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; better than an ox &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; bullock that hath horns and hoofs.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">The humble shall see &lt;span class="extra"&gt;this, and&lt;/span&gt; be glad: and your heart shall live that seek God.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">For the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; heareth the poor, and despiseth not his prisoners.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Let the heaven and earth praise him, the seas, and every thing that moveth therein.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">For God will save Zion, and will build the cities of Judah: that they may dwell there, and have it in possession.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">The seed also of his servants shall inherit it: and they that love his name shall dwell therein.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>