<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="32" verseCount="11" nextChapter="psalms_33.html" nextTitle="Psalms 33" prevChapter="psalms_31.html" prevTitle="Psalms 31" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;A Psalm&lt;/span&gt; of David, Maschil.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is he whose&lt;/span&gt; transgression &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; forgiven, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;whose&lt;/span&gt; sin &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; covered.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the man unto whom the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; imputeth not iniquity, and in whose spirit &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no guile.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">When I kept silence, my bones waxed old through my roaring all the day long.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For day and night thy hand was heavy upon me: my moisture is turned into the drought of summer. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I acknowledged my sin unto thee, and mine iniquity have I not hid. I said, I will confess my transgressions unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and thou forgavest the iniquity of my sin. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For this shall every one that is godly pray unto thee in a time when thou mayest be found: surely in the floods of great waters they shall not come nigh unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; my hiding place; thou shalt preserve me from trouble; thou shalt compass me about with songs of deliverance. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I will instruct thee and teach thee in the way which thou shalt go: I will guide thee with mine eye.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Be ye not as the horse, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; as the mule, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; have no understanding: whose mouth must be held in with bit and bridle, lest they come near unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Many sorrows &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; to the wicked: but he that trusteth in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, mercy shall compass him about.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Be glad in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and rejoice, ye righteous: and shout for joy, all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;ye that are&lt;/span&gt; upright in heart.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>