<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="109" verseCount="31" nextChapter="psalms_110.html" nextTitle="Psalms 110" prevChapter="psalms_108.html" prevTitle="Psalms 108" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Psalm of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hold not thy peace, O God of my praise;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For the mouth of the wicked and the mouth of the deceitful are opened against me: they have spoken against me with a lying tongue.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">They compassed me about also with words of hatred; and fought against me without a cause.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For my love they are my adversaries: but I &lt;i&gt;give myself unto&lt;/i&gt; prayer.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they have rewarded me evil for good, and hatred for my love.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Set thou a wicked man over him: and let Satan stand at his right hand.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">When he shall be judged, let him be condemned: and let his prayer become sin.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Let his days be few; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; let another take his office.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Let his children be fatherless, and his wife a widow.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Let his children be continually vagabonds, and beg: let them seek &lt;i&gt;their bread&lt;/i&gt; also out of their desolate places.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Let the extortioner catch all that he hath; and let the strangers spoil his labour.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Let there be none to extend mercy unto him: neither let there be any to favour his fatherless children.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Let his posterity be cut off; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; in the generation following let their name be blotted out.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Let the iniquity of his fathers be remembered with the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and let not the sin of his mother be blotted out.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Let them be before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; continually, that he may cut off the memory of them from the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Because that he remembered not to shew mercy, but persecuted the poor and needy man, that he might even slay the broken in heart.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">As he loved cursing, so let it come unto him: as he delighted not in blessing, so let it be far from him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">As he clothed himself with cursing like as with his garment, so let it come into his bowels like water, and like oil into his bones.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Let it be unto him as the garment &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; covereth him, and for a girdle wherewith he is girded continually.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;i&gt;Let&lt;/i&gt; this &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; the reward of mine adversaries from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and of them that speak evil against my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But do thou for me, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; the Lord, for thy name's sake: because thy mercy &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; good, deliver thou me.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; poor and needy, and my heart is wounded within me.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">I am gone like the shadow when it declineth: I am tossed up and down as the locust.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">My knees are weak through fasting; and my flesh faileth of fatness.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">I became also a reproach unto them: &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; they looked upon me they shaked their heads.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Help me, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God: O save me according to thy mercy:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">That they may know that this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy hand; &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thou, &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hast done it.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Let them curse, but bless thou: when they arise, let them be ashamed; but let thy servant rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Let mine adversaries be clothed with shame, and let them cover themselves with their own confusion, as with a mantle.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">I will greatly praise the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with my mouth; yea, I will praise him among the multitude.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">For he shall stand at the right hand of the poor, to save &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; from those that condemn his soul.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>