<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="136" verseCount="26" nextChapter="psalms_137.html" nextTitle="Psalms 137" prevChapter="psalms_135.html" prevTitle="Psalms 135" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O give thanks unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for &lt;i&gt;he is&lt;/i&gt; good: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">O give thanks unto the God of gods: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">O give thanks to the Lord of lords: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">To him who alone doeth great wonders: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">To him that by wisdom made the heavens: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">To him that stretched out the earth above the waters: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">To him that made great lights: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The sun to rule by day: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The moon and stars to rule by night: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">To him that smote Egypt in their firstborn: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And brought out Israel from among them: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">With a strong hand, and with a stretched out arm: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">To him which divided the Red sea into parts: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And made Israel to pass through the midst of it: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But overthrew Pharaoh and his host in the Red sea: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">To him which led his people through the wilderness: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">To him which smote great kings: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And slew famous kings: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Sihon king of the Amorites: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Og the king of Bashan: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And gave their land for an heritage: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;i&gt;Even&lt;/i&gt; an heritage unto Israel his servant: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Who remembered us in our low estate: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And hath redeemed us from our enemies: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Who giveth food to all flesh: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">O give thanks unto the God of heaven: for his mercy &lt;i&gt;endureth&lt;/i&gt; for ever.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>