<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="97" verseCount="12" nextChapter="psalms_98.html" nextTitle="Psalms 98" prevChapter="psalms_96.html" prevTitle="Psalms 96" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; reigneth; let the earth rejoice; let the multitude of isles be glad &lt;i&gt;thereof&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Clouds and darkness &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; round about him: righteousness and judgment &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the habitation of his throne.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">A fire goeth before him, and burneth up his enemies round about.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">His lightnings enlightened the world: the earth saw, and trembled.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The hills melted like wax at the presence of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, at the presence of the Lord of the whole earth.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The heavens declare his righteousness, and all the people see his glory.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Confounded be all they that serve graven images, that boast themselves of idols: worship him, all &lt;i&gt;ye&lt;/i&gt; gods.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Zion heard, and was glad; and the daughters of Judah rejoiced because of thy judgments, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For thou, &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; high above all the earth: thou art exalted far above all gods.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Ye that love the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hate evil: he preserveth the souls of his saints; he delivereth them out of the hand of the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Light is sown for the righteous, and gladness for the upright in heart.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Rejoice in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, ye righteous; and give thanks at the remembrance of his holiness.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>