<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="91" verseCount="16" nextChapter="psalms_92.html" nextTitle="Psalms 92" prevChapter="psalms_90.html" prevTitle="Psalms 90" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">He that dwelleth in the secret place of the most High shall abide under the shadow of the Almighty.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I will say of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;He is&lt;/span&gt; my refuge and my fortress: my God; in him will I trust.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Surely he shall deliver thee from the snare of the fowler, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; from the noisome pestilence.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He shall cover thee with his feathers, and under his wings shalt thou trust: his truth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be thy&lt;/span&gt; shield and buckler.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thou shalt not be afraid for the terror by night; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;nor&lt;/span&gt; for the arrow &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; flieth by day;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Nor&lt;/span&gt; for the pestilence &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; walketh in darkness; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;nor&lt;/span&gt; for the destruction &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; wasteth at noonday.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">A thousand shall fall at thy side, and ten thousand at thy right hand; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; it shall not come nigh thee.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Only with thine eyes shalt thou behold and see the reward of the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Because thou hast made the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which is&lt;/span&gt; my refuge, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the most High, thy habitation;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">There shall no evil befall thee, neither shall any plague come nigh thy dwelling.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For he shall give his angels charge over thee, to keep thee in all thy ways.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They shall bear thee up in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; hands, lest thou dash thy foot against a stone.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thou shalt tread upon the lion and adder: the young lion and the dragon shalt thou trample under feet.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Because he hath set his love upon me, therefore will I deliver him: I will set him on high, because he hath known my name.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He shall call upon me, and I will answer him: I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;will be&lt;/span&gt; with him in trouble; I will deliver him, and honour him.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">With long life will I satisfy him, and shew him my salvation.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>