<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="88" verseCount="18" nextChapter="psalms_89.html" nextTitle="Psalms 89" prevChapter="psalms_87.html" prevTitle="Psalms 87" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Song &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; Psalm for the sons of Korah, to the chief Musician upon Mahalath Leannoth, Maschil of Heman the Ezrahite.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of my salvation, I have cried day &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; night before thee:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Let my prayer come before thee: incline thine ear unto my cry;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For my soul is full of troubles: and my life draweth nigh unto the grave.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I am counted with them that go down into the pit: I am as a man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that hath&lt;/span&gt; no strength:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Free among the dead, like the slain that lie in the grave, whom thou rememberest no more: and they are cut off from thy hand.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thou hast laid me in the lowest pit, in darkness, in the deeps.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thy wrath lieth hard upon me, and thou hast afflicted &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; with all thy waves. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Thou hast put away mine acquaintance far from me; thou hast made me an abomination unto them: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;I am&lt;/span&gt; shut up, and I cannot come forth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Mine eye mourneth by reason of affliction: &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I have called daily upon thee, I have stretched out my hands unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Wilt thou shew wonders to the dead? shall the dead arise &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; praise thee? Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Shall thy lovingkindness be declared in the grave? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; thy faithfulness in destruction?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Shall thy wonders be known in the dark? and thy righteousness in the land of forgetfulness?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But unto thee have I cried, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and in the morning shall my prayer prevent thee.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, why castest thou off my soul? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;why&lt;/span&gt; hidest thou thy face from me?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; afflicted and ready to die from &lt;span class='extra'&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; youth up: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; I suffer thy terrors I am distracted.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thy fierce wrath goeth over me; thy terrors have cut me off.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">They came round about me daily like water; they compassed me about together.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Lover and friend hast thou put far from me, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; mine acquaintance into darkness.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>