<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="77" verseCount="20" nextChapter="psalms_78.html" nextTitle="Psalms 78" prevChapter="psalms_76.html" prevTitle="Psalms 76" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, to Jeduthun, A Psalm of Asaph.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I cried unto God with my voice, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto God with my voice; and he gave ear unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">In the day of my trouble I sought the Lord: my sore ran in the night, and ceased not: my soul refused to be comforted.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I remembered God, and was troubled: I complained, and my spirit was overwhelmed. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thou holdest mine eyes waking: I am so troubled that I cannot speak.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I have considered the days of old, the years of ancient times.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I call to remembrance my song in the night: I commune with mine own heart: and my spirit made diligent search.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Will the Lord cast off for ever? and will he be favourable no more?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Is his mercy clean gone for ever? doth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; promise fail for evermore?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Hath God forgotten to be gracious? hath he in anger shut up his tender mercies? Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And I said, This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my infirmity: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but I will remember&lt;/span&gt; the years of the right hand of the most High.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">I will remember the works of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: surely I will remember thy wonders of old.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I will meditate also of all thy work, and talk of thy doings.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thy way, O God, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the sanctuary: who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is so&lt;/span&gt; great a God as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; God?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; the God that doest wonders: thou hast declared thy strength among the people.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Thou hast with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thine&lt;/span&gt; arm redeemed thy people, the sons of Jacob and Joseph. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The waters saw thee, O God, the waters saw thee; they were afraid: the depths also were troubled.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The clouds poured out water: the skies sent out a sound: thine arrows also went abroad.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The voice of thy thunder &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in the heaven: the lightnings lightened the world: the earth trembled and shook.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thy way &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the sea, and thy path in the great waters, and thy footsteps are not known.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Thou leddest thy people like a flock by the hand of Moses and Aaron.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>