<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="18" nextChapter="psalms_11.html" nextTitle="Psalms 11" prevChapter="psalms_9.html" prevTitle="Psalms 9" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Why standest thou afar off, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt; hidest thou &lt;i&gt;thyself&lt;/i&gt; in times of trouble?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The wicked in &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; pride doth persecute the poor: let them be taken in the devices that they have imagined.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For the wicked boasteth of his heart's desire, and blesseth the covetous, &lt;i&gt;whom&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; abhorreth.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The wicked, through the pride of his countenance, will not seek &lt;i&gt;after God&lt;/i&gt;: God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not in all his thoughts.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">His ways are always grievous; thy judgments &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; far above out of his sight: &lt;i&gt;as for&lt;/i&gt; all his enemies, he puffeth at them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He hath said in his heart, I shall not be moved: for &lt;i&gt;I shall&lt;/i&gt; never &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; in adversity.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">His mouth is full of cursing and deceit and fraud: under his tongue &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; mischief and vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He sitteth in the lurking places of the villages: in the secret places doth he murder the innocent: his eyes are privily set against the poor.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He lieth in wait secretly as a lion in his den: he lieth in wait to catch the poor: he doth catch the poor, when he draweth him into his net.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He croucheth, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; humbleth himself, that the poor may fall by his strong ones.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He hath said in his heart, God hath forgotten: he hideth his face; he will never see &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Arise, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; O God, lift up thine hand: forget not the humble.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Wherefore doth the wicked contemn God? he hath said in his heart, Thou wilt not require &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou hast seen &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;; for thou beholdest mischief and spite, to requite &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; with thy hand: the poor committeth himself unto thee; thou art the helper of the fatherless.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Break thou the arm of the wicked and the evil &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;: seek out his wickedness &lt;i&gt;till&lt;/i&gt; thou find none.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; King for ever and ever: the heathen are perished out of his land.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou hast heard the desire of the humble: thou wilt prepare their heart, thou wilt cause thine ear to hear:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">To judge the fatherless and the oppressed, that the man of the earth may no more oppress.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>