<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="33" verseCount="22" nextChapter="psalms_34.html" nextTitle="Psalms 34" prevChapter="psalms_32.html" prevTitle="Psalms 32" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Rejoice in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, O ye righteous: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; praise is comely for the upright.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Praise the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with harp: sing unto him with the psaltery &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; an instrument of ten strings.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Sing unto him a new song; play skilfully with a loud noise.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; right; and all his works &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are done&lt;/span&gt; in truth.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">He loveth righteousness and judgment: the earth is full of the goodness of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">By the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; were the heavens made; and all the host of them by the breath of his mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He gathereth the waters of the sea together as an heap: he layeth up the depth in storehouses.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Let all the earth fear the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: let all the inhabitants of the world stand in awe of him.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For he spake, and it was &lt;span class='extra'&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;; he commanded, and it stood fast.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; bringeth the counsel of the heathen to nought: he maketh the devices of the people of none effect.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The counsel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; standeth for ever, the thoughts of his heart to all generations.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the nation whose God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;whom&lt;/span&gt; he hath chosen for his own inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; looketh from heaven; he beholdeth all the sons of men.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">From the place of his habitation he looketh upon all the inhabitants of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He fashioneth their hearts alike; he considereth all their works.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">There is no king saved by the multitude of an host: a mighty man is not delivered by much strength.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">An horse &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a vain thing for safety: neither shall he deliver &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; by his great strength.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Behold, the eye of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon them that fear him, upon them that hope in his mercy;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">To deliver their soul from death, and to keep them alive in famine.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Our soul waiteth for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our help and our shield.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For our heart shall rejoice in him, because we have trusted in his holy name.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Let thy mercy, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, be upon us, according as we hope in thee.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>