<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="30" verseCount="12" nextChapter="psalms_31.html" nextTitle="Psalms 31" prevChapter="psalms_29.html" prevTitle="Psalms 29" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Psalm &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Song &lt;span class='extra'&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; the dedication of the house of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I will extol thee, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for thou hast lifted me up, and hast not made my foes to rejoice over me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, I cried unto thee, and thou hast healed me.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou hast brought up my soul from the grave: thou hast kept me alive, that I should not go down to the pit.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Sing unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, O ye saints of his, and give thanks at the remembrance of his holiness.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For his anger &lt;span class='extra'&gt;endureth but&lt;/span&gt; a moment; in his favour &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; life: weeping may endure for a night, but joy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;cometh&lt;/span&gt; in the morning.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And in my prosperity I said, I shall never be moved.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, by thy favour thou hast made my mountain to stand strong: thou didst hide thy face, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; I was troubled.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I cried to thee, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; I made supplication.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">What profit &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; in my blood, when I go down to the pit? Shall the dust praise thee? shall it declare thy truth?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Hear, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and have mercy upon me: &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, be thou my helper.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thou hast turned for me my mourning into dancing: thou hast put off my sackcloth, and girded me with gladness;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">To the end that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; glory may sing praise to thee, and not be silent. O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, I will give thanks unto thee for ever.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>