<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="90" verseCount="17" nextChapter="psalms_91.html" nextTitle="Psalms 91" prevChapter="psalms_89.html" prevTitle="Psalms 89" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Prayer of Moses the man of God.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Lord, thou hast been our dwelling place in all generations.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Before the mountains were brought forth, or ever thou hadst formed the earth and the world, even from everlasting to everlasting, thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou turnest man to destruction; and sayest, Return, ye children of men.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For a thousand years in thy sight &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are but&lt;/span&gt; as yesterday when it is past, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; a watch in the night.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thou carriest them away as with a flood; they are &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; a sleep: in the morning &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they are&lt;/span&gt; like grass &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; groweth up.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">In the morning it flourisheth, and groweth up; in the evening it is cut down, and withereth.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For we are consumed by thine anger, and by thy wrath are we troubled.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Thou hast set our iniquities before thee, our secret &lt;span class='extra'&gt;sins&lt;/span&gt; in the light of thy countenance.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For all our days are passed away in thy wrath: we spend our years as a tale &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is told&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The days of our years &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; threescore years and ten; and if by reason of strength &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they be&lt;/span&gt; fourscore years, yet &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; their strength labour and sorrow; for it is soon cut off, and we fly away.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Who knoweth the power of thine anger? even according to thy fear, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so is&lt;/span&gt; thy wrath.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">So teach &lt;span class='extra'&gt;us&lt;/span&gt; to number our days, that we may apply &lt;span class='extra'&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; hearts unto wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Return, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, how long? and let it repent thee concerning thy servants.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">O satisfy us early with thy mercy; that we may rejoice and be glad all our days.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Make us glad according to the days &lt;span class='extra'&gt;wherein&lt;/span&gt; thou hast afflicted us, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the years &lt;span class='extra'&gt;wherein&lt;/span&gt; we have seen evil.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Let thy work appear unto thy servants, and thy glory unto their children.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And let the beauty of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God be upon us: and establish thou the work of our hands upon us; yea, the work of our hands establish thou it.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>