<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="50" verseCount="23" nextChapter="psalms_51.html" nextTitle="Psalms 51" prevChapter="psalms_49.html" prevTitle="Psalms 49" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Psalm of Asaph.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The mighty God, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hath spoken, and called the earth from the rising of the sun unto the going down thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Out of Zion, the perfection of beauty, God hath shined.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Our God shall come, and shall not keep silence: a fire shall devour before him, and it shall be very tempestuous round about him.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He shall call to the heavens from above, and to the earth, that he may judge his people.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Gather my saints together unto me; those that have made a covenant with me by sacrifice.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the heavens shall declare his righteousness: for God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; judge himself. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Hear, O my people, and I will speak; O Israel, and I will testify against thee: I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; God, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I will not reprove thee for thy sacrifices or thy burnt offerings, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to have been&lt;/span&gt; continually before me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I will take no bullock out of thy house, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;nor&lt;/span&gt; he goats out of thy folds.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For every beast of the forest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the cattle upon a thousand hills.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">I know all the fowls of the mountains: and the wild beasts of the field &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; mine.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">If I were hungry, I would not tell thee: for the world &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine, and the fulness thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Will I eat the flesh of bulls, or drink the blood of goats?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Offer unto God thanksgiving; and pay thy vows unto the most High:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And call upon me in the day of trouble: I will deliver thee, and thou shalt glorify me.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But unto the wicked God saith, What hast thou to do to declare my statutes, or &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thou shouldest take my covenant in thy mouth?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Seeing thou hatest instruction, and castest my words behind thee.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">When thou sawest a thief, then thou consentedst with him, and hast been partaker with adulterers.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thou givest thy mouth to evil, and thy tongue frameth deceit.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Thou sittest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; speakest against thy brother; thou slanderest thine own mother's son.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; hast thou done, and I kept silence; thou thoughtest that I was altogether &lt;span class='extra'&gt;such an one&lt;/span&gt; as thyself: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; I will reprove thee, and set &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; in order before thine eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Now consider this, ye that forget God, lest I tear &lt;span class='extra'&gt;you&lt;/span&gt; in pieces, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; none to deliver.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Whoso offereth praise glorifieth me: and to him that ordereth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; conversation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;aright&lt;/span&gt; will I shew the salvation of God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>