<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="78" verseCount="72" nextChapter="psalms_79.html" nextTitle="Psalms 79" prevChapter="psalms_77.html" prevTitle="Psalms 77" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">Maschil of Asaph.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Give ear, O my people, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; my law: incline your ears to the words of my mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I will open my mouth in a parable: I will utter dark sayings of old:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Which we have heard and known, and our fathers have told us.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">We will not hide &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; from their children, shewing to the generation to come the praises of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and his strength, and his wonderful works that he hath done.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For he established a testimony in Jacob, and appointed a law in Israel, which he commanded our fathers, that they should make them known to their children:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">That the generation to come might know &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them, even&lt;/span&gt; the children &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; should be born; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;who&lt;/span&gt; should arise and declare &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; to their children:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">That they might set their hope in God, and not forget the works of God, but keep his commandments:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And might not be as their fathers, a stubborn and rebellious generation; a generation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; set not their heart aright, and whose spirit was not stedfast with God.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The children of Ephraim, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; armed, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; carrying bows, turned back in the day of battle.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">They kept not the covenant of God, and refused to walk in his law;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And forgat his works, and his wonders that he had shewed them.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Marvellous things did he in the sight of their fathers, in the land of Egypt, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the field of Zoan.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He divided the sea, and caused them to pass through; and he made the waters to stand as an heap.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">In the daytime also he led them with a cloud, and all the night with a light of fire.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He clave the rocks in the wilderness, and gave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; drink as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;out of&lt;/span&gt; the great depths.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He brought streams also out of the rock, and caused waters to run down like rivers.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And they sinned yet more against him by provoking the most High in the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And they tempted God in their heart by asking meat for their lust.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Yea, they spake against God; they said, Can God furnish a table in the wilderness?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Behold, he smote the rock, that the waters gushed out, and the streams overflowed; can he give bread also? can he provide flesh for his people?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Therefore the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;, and was wroth: so a fire was kindled against Jacob, and anger also came up against Israel;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Because they believed not in God, and trusted not in his salvation:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Though he had commanded the clouds from above, and opened the doors of heaven,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And had rained down manna upon them to eat, and had given them of the corn of heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Man did eat angels' food: he sent them meat to the full.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">He caused an east wind to blow in the heaven: and by his power he brought in the south wind.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">He rained flesh also upon them as dust, and feathered fowls like as the sand of the sea:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he let &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; fall in the midst of their camp, round about their habitations.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">So they did eat, and were well filled: for he gave them their own desire;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">They were not estranged from their lust. But while their meat &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; yet in their mouths,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The wrath of God came upon them, and slew the fattest of them, and smote down the chosen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">For all this they sinned still, and believed not for his wondrous works.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Therefore their days did he consume in vanity, and their years in trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">When he slew them, then they sought him: and they returned and enquired early after God.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And they remembered that God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; their rock, and the high God their redeemer.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Nevertheless they did flatter him with their mouth, and they lied unto him with their tongues.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">For their heart was not right with him, neither were they stedfast in his covenant.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">But he, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; full of compassion, forgave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; iniquity, and destroyed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; not: yea, many a time turned he his anger away, and did not stir up all his wrath.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">For he remembered that they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were but&lt;/span&gt; flesh; a wind that passeth away, and cometh not again.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">How oft did they provoke him in the wilderness, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; grieve him in the desert!</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Yea, they turned back and tempted God, and limited the Holy One of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">They remembered not his hand, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;nor&lt;/span&gt; the day when he delivered them from the enemy.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">How he had wrought his signs in Egypt, and his wonders in the field of Zoan:</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And had turned their rivers into blood; and their floods, that they could not drink.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">He sent divers sorts of flies among them, which devoured them; and frogs, which destroyed them.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">He gave also their increase unto the caterpiller, and their labour unto the locust.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">He destroyed their vines with hail, and their sycomore trees with frost.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">He gave up their cattle also to the hail, and their flocks to hot thunderbolts.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">He cast upon them the fierceness of his anger, wrath, and indignation, and trouble, by sending evil angels &lt;span class='extra'&gt;among them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">He made a way to his anger; he spared not their soul from death, but gave their life over to the pestilence;</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And smote all the firstborn in Egypt; the chief of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; strength in the tabernacles of Ham:</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">But made his own people to go forth like sheep, and guided them in the wilderness like a flock.</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">And he led them on safely, so that they feared not: but the sea overwhelmed their enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">And he brought them to the border of his sanctuary, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even to&lt;/span&gt; this mountain, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; his right hand had purchased.</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">He cast out the heathen also before them, and divided them an inheritance by line, and made the tribes of Israel to dwell in their tents.</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">Yet they tempted and provoked the most high God, and kept not his testimonies:</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">But turned back, and dealt unfaithfully like their fathers: they were turned aside like a deceitful bow.</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">For they provoked him to anger with their high places, and moved him to jealousy with their graven images.</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">When God heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;, he was wroth, and greatly abhorred Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="60" id="v60">So that he forsook the tabernacle of Shiloh, the tent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; he placed among men;</verse>
      <verse number="61" id="v61">And delivered his strength into captivity, and his glory into the enemy's hand.</verse>
      <verse number="62" id="v62">He gave his people over also unto the sword; and was wroth with his inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="63" id="v63">The fire consumed their young men; and their maidens were not given to marriage.</verse>
      <verse number="64" id="v64">Their priests fell by the sword; and their widows made no lamentation.</verse>
      <verse number="65" id="v65">Then the Lord awaked as one out of sleep, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; like a mighty man that shouteth by reason of wine.</verse>
      <verse number="66" id="v66">And he smote his enemies in the hinder parts: he put them to a perpetual reproach.</verse>
      <verse number="67" id="v67">Moreover he refused the tabernacle of Joseph, and chose not the tribe of Ephraim:</verse>
      <verse number="68" id="v68">But chose the tribe of Judah, the mount Zion which he loved.</verse>
      <verse number="69" id="v69">And he built his sanctuary like high &lt;span class='extra'&gt;palaces&lt;/span&gt;, like the earth which he hath established for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="70" id="v70">He chose David also his servant, and took him from the sheepfolds:</verse>
      <verse number="71" id="v71">From following the ewes great with young he brought him to feed Jacob his people, and Israel his inheritance.</verse>
      <verse number="72" id="v72">So he fed them according to the integrity of his heart; and guided them by the skilfulness of his hands.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>