<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="147" verseCount="20" nextChapter="psalms_148.html" nextTitle="Psalms 148" prevChapter="psalms_146.html" prevTitle="Psalms 146" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Praise ye the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; good to sing praises unto our God; for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; pleasant; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; praise is comely.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; doth build up Jerusalem: he gathereth together the outcasts of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">He healeth the broken in heart, and bindeth up their wounds.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He telleth the number of the stars; he calleth them all by &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; names.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Great &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our Lord, and of great power: his understanding &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; infinite.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; lifteth up the meek: he casteth the wicked down to the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Sing unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with thanksgiving; sing praise upon the harp unto our God:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Who covereth the heaven with clouds, who prepareth rain for the earth, who maketh grass to grow upon the mountains.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He giveth to the beast his food, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to the young ravens which cry.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He delighteth not in the strength of the horse: he taketh not pleasure in the legs of a man.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; taketh pleasure in them that fear him, in those that hope in his mercy.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Praise the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, O Jerusalem; praise thy God, O Zion.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For he hath strengthened the bars of thy gates; he hath blessed thy children within thee.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">He maketh peace &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; thy borders, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; filleth thee with the finest of the wheat.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He sendeth forth his commandment &lt;span class="extra"&gt;upon&lt;/span&gt; earth: his word runneth very swiftly.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He giveth snow like wool: he scattereth the hoarfrost like ashes.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He casteth forth his ice like morsels: who can stand before his cold?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He sendeth out his word, and melteth them: he causeth his wind to blow, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the waters flow.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He sheweth his word unto Jacob, his statutes and his judgments unto Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He hath not dealt so with any nation: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as for his&lt;/span&gt; judgments, they have not known them. Praise ye the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>