<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="60" verseCount="12" nextChapter="psalms_61.html" nextTitle="Psalms 61" prevChapter="psalms_59.html" prevTitle="Psalms 59" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician upon Shushan-eduth, Michtam of David, to teach; when he strove with Aram-naharaim and with Aram-zobah, when Joab returned, and smote of Edom in the valley of salt twelve thousand.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O God, thou hast cast us off, thou hast scattered us, thou hast been displeased; O turn thyself to us again.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thou hast made the earth to tremble; thou hast broken it: heal the breaches thereof; for it shaketh.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou hast shewed thy people hard things: thou hast made us to drink the wine of astonishment.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thou hast given a banner to them that fear thee, that it may be displayed because of the truth. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">That thy beloved may be delivered; save &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; thy right hand, and hear me.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">God hath spoken in his holiness; I will rejoice, I will divide Shechem, and mete out the valley of Succoth.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Gilead &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine, and Manasseh &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine; Ephraim also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the strength of mine head; Judah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my lawgiver;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Moab &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my washpot; over Edom will I cast out my shoe: Philistia, triumph thou because of me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Who will bring me &lt;span class="extra"&gt;into&lt;/span&gt; the strong city? who will lead me into Edom?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Wilt&lt;/span&gt; not thou, O God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; hadst cast us off? and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thou&lt;/span&gt;, O God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; didst not go out with our armies?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Give us help from trouble: for vain &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the help of man.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Through God we shall do valiantly: for he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is that&lt;/span&gt; shall tread down our enemies.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>