<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="66" verseCount="20" nextChapter="psalms_67.html" nextTitle="Psalms 67" prevChapter="psalms_65.html" prevTitle="Psalms 65" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Song &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; Psalm.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Make a joyful noise unto God, all ye lands:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Sing forth the honour of his name: make his praise glorious.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Say unto God, How terrible &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art thou in&lt;/span&gt; thy works! through the greatness of thy power shall thine enemies submit themselves unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">All the earth shall worship thee, and shall sing unto thee; they shall sing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; thy name. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Come and see the works of God: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; terrible &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in his&lt;/span&gt; doing toward the children of men.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He turned the sea into dry &lt;span class="extra"&gt;land&lt;/span&gt;: they went through the flood on foot: there did we rejoice in him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He ruleth by his power for ever; his eyes behold the nations: let not the rebellious exalt themselves. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">O bless our God, ye people, and make the voice of his praise to be heard:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Which holdeth our soul in life, and suffereth not our feet to be moved.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For thou, O God, hast proved us: thou hast tried us, as silver is tried.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thou broughtest us into the net; thou laidst affliction upon our loins.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Thou hast caused men to ride over our heads; we went through fire and through water: but thou broughtest us out into a wealthy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">I will go into thy house with burnt offerings: I will pay thee my vows,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Which my lips have uttered, and my mouth hath spoken, when I was in trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I will offer unto thee burnt sacrifices of fatlings, with the incense of rams; I will offer bullocks with goats. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Come &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; hear, all ye that fear God, and I will declare what he hath done for my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">I cried unto him with my mouth, and he was extolled with my tongue.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">If I regard iniquity in my heart, the Lord will not hear &lt;span class="extra"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;But&lt;/span&gt; verily God hath heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt;; he hath attended to the voice of my prayer.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; God, which hath not turned away my prayer, nor his mercy from me.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>