<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="80" verseCount="19" nextChapter="psalms_81.html" nextTitle="Psalms 81" prevChapter="psalms_79.html" prevTitle="Psalms 79" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician upon Shoshannim-Eduth, A Psalm of Asaph.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Give ear, O Shepherd of Israel, thou that leadest Joseph like a flock; thou that dwellest &lt;span class="extra"&gt;between&lt;/span&gt; the cherubims, shine forth.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Before Ephraim and Benjamin and Manasseh stir up thy strength, and come &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; save us.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Turn us again, O God, and cause thy face to shine; and we shall be saved.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of hosts, how long wilt thou be angry against the prayer of thy people?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thou feedest them with the bread of tears; and givest them tears to drink in great measure.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thou makest us a strife unto our neighbours: and our enemies laugh among themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Turn us again, O God of hosts, and cause thy face to shine; and we shall be saved.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Thou hast brought a vine out of Egypt: thou hast cast out the heathen, and planted it.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thou preparedst &lt;span class="extra"&gt;room&lt;/span&gt; before it, and didst cause it to take deep root, and it filled the land.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The hills were covered with the shadow of it, and the boughs thereof &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were like&lt;/span&gt; the goodly cedars.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">She sent out her boughs unto the sea, and her branches unto the river.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Why hast thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; broken down her hedges, so that all they which pass by the way do pluck her?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The boar out of the wood doth waste it, and the wild beast of the field doth devour it.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Return, we beseech thee, O God of hosts: look down from heaven, and behold, and visit this vine;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the vineyard which thy right hand hath planted, and the branch &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thou madest strong for thyself.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; burned with fire, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; cut down: they perish at the rebuke of thy countenance.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Let thy hand be upon the man of thy right hand, upon the son of man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;whom&lt;/span&gt; thou madest strong for thyself.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">So will not we go back from thee: quicken us, and we will call upon thy name.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Turn us again, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of hosts, cause thy face to shine; and we shall be saved.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>