<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="102" verseCount="28" nextChapter="psalms_103.html" nextTitle="Psalms 103" prevChapter="psalms_101.html" prevTitle="Psalms 101" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Prayer of the afflicted, when he is overwhelmed, and poureth out his complaint before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hear my prayer, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and let my cry come unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Hide not thy face from me in the day &lt;span class="extra"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; I am in trouble; incline thine ear unto me: in the day &lt;span class="extra"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; I call answer me speedily.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For my days are consumed like smoke, and my bones are burned as an hearth.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">My heart is smitten, and withered like grass; so that I forget to eat my bread.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">By reason of the voice of my groaning my bones cleave to my skin.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I am like a pelican of the wilderness: I am like an owl of the desert.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">I watch, and am as a sparrow alone upon the house top.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Mine enemies reproach me all the day; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; they that are mad against me are sworn against me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For I have eaten ashes like bread, and mingled my drink with weeping,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Because of thine indignation and thy wrath: for thou hast lifted me up, and cast me down.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">My days &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; like a shadow that declineth; and I am withered like grass.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But thou, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, shalt endure for ever; and thy remembrance unto all generations.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thou shalt arise, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; have mercy upon Zion: for the time to favour her, yea, the set time, is come.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For thy servants take pleasure in her stones, and favour the dust thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So the heathen shall fear the name of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and all the kings of the earth thy glory.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">When the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall build up Zion, he shall appear in his glory.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He will regard the prayer of the destitute, and not despise their prayer.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">This shall be written for the generation to come: and the people which shall be created shall praise the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For he hath looked down from the height of his sanctuary; from heaven did the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; behold the earth;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">To hear the groaning of the prisoner; to loose those that are appointed to death;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">To declare the name of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in Zion, and his praise in Jerusalem;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">When the people are gathered together, and the kingdoms, to serve the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">He weakened my strength in the way; he shortened my days.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">I said, O my God, take me not away in the midst of my days: thy years &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; throughout all generations.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Of old hast thou laid the foundation of the earth: and the heavens &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the work of thy hands.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">They shall perish, but thou shalt endure: yea, all of them shall wax old like a garment; as a vesture shalt thou change them, and they shall be changed:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">But thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; the same, and thy years shall have no end.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The children of thy servants shall continue, and their seed shall be established before thee.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>