<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="71" verseCount="24" nextChapter="psalms_72.html" nextTitle="Psalms 72" prevChapter="psalms_70.html" prevTitle="Psalms 70" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In thee, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, do I put my trust: let me never be put to confusion.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Deliver me in thy righteousness, and cause me to escape: incline thine ear unto me, and save me.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Be thou my strong habitation, whereunto I may continually resort: thou hast given commandment to save me; for thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; my rock and my fortress.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Deliver me, O my God, out of the hand of the wicked, out of the hand of the unrighteous and cruel man.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; my hope, O Lord GOD: &lt;i&gt;thou art&lt;/i&gt; my trust from my youth.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">By thee have I been holden up from the womb: thou art he that took me out of my mother's bowels: my praise &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; continually of thee.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">I am as a wonder unto many; but thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; my strong refuge.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Let my mouth be filled &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; thy praise &lt;i&gt;and with&lt;/i&gt; thy honour all the day.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Cast me not off in the time of old age; forsake me not when my strength faileth.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For mine enemies speak against me; and they that lay wait for my soul take counsel together,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Saying, God hath forsaken him: persecute and take him; for &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none to deliver &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">O God, be not far from me: O my God, make haste for my help.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Let them be confounded &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; consumed that are adversaries to my soul; let them be covered &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; reproach and dishonour that seek my hurt.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But I will hope continually, and will yet praise thee more and more.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">My mouth shall shew forth thy righteousness &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; thy salvation all the day; for I know not the numbers &lt;i&gt;thereof&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I will go in the strength of the Lord GOD: I will make mention of thy righteousness, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; of thine only.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">O God, thou hast taught me from my youth: and hitherto have I declared thy wondrous works.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Now also when I am old and grayheaded, O God, forsake me not; until I have shewed thy strength unto &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; generation, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; thy power to every one &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; is to come.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thy righteousness also, O God, &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; very high, who hast done great things: O God, who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; like unto thee!</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;i&gt;Thou&lt;/i&gt;, which hast shewed me great and sore troubles, shalt quicken me again, and shalt bring me up again from the depths of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Thou shalt increase my greatness, and comfort me on every side.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">I will also praise thee with the psaltery, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; thy truth, O my God: unto thee will I sing with the harp, O thou Holy One of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">My lips shall greatly rejoice when I sing unto thee; and my soul, which thou hast redeemed.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">My tongue also shall talk of thy righteousness all the day long: for they are confounded, for they are brought unto shame, that seek my hurt.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>