<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="68" verseCount="35" nextChapter="psalms_69.html" nextTitle="Psalms 69" prevChapter="psalms_67.html" prevTitle="Psalms 67" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Psalm &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; Song of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Let God arise, let his enemies be scattered: let them also that hate him flee before him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">As smoke is driven away, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; drive &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; away: as wax melteth before the fire, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; let the wicked perish at the presence of God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But let the righteous be glad; let them rejoice before God: yea, let them exceedingly rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Sing unto God, sing praises to his name: extol him that rideth upon the heavens by his name JAH, and rejoice before him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">A father of the fatherless, and a judge of the widows, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; God in his holy habitation.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">God setteth the solitary in families: he bringeth out those which are bound with chains: but the rebellious dwell in a dry &lt;span class="extra"&gt;land&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">O God, when thou wentest forth before thy people, when thou didst march through the wilderness; Selah:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The earth shook, the heavens also dropped at the presence of God: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; Sinai itself &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was moved&lt;/span&gt; at the presence of God, the God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thou, O God, didst send a plentiful rain, whereby thou didst confirm thine inheritance, when it was weary.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thy congregation hath dwelt therein: thou, O God, hast prepared of thy goodness for the poor.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The Lord gave the word: great &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the company of those that published &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Kings of armies did flee apace: and she that tarried at home divided the spoil.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Though ye have lien among the pots, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yet shall ye be as&lt;/span&gt; the wings of a dove covered with silver, and her feathers with yellow gold.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">When the Almighty scattered kings in it, it was &lt;span class="extra"&gt;white&lt;/span&gt; as snow in Salmon.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The hill of God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is as&lt;/span&gt; the hill of Bashan; an high hill &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the hill of Bashan.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Why leap ye, ye high hills? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;this is&lt;/span&gt; the hill &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; God desireth to dwell in; yea, the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will dwell &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in it&lt;/span&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The chariots of God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; twenty thousand, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; thousands of angels: the Lord &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; among them, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as in&lt;/span&gt; Sinai, in the holy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;place&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thou hast ascended on high, thou hast led captivity captive: thou hast received gifts for men; yea, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the rebellious also, that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God might dwell &lt;span class="extra"&gt;among them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the Lord, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;who&lt;/span&gt; daily loadeth us &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with benefits, even&lt;/span&gt; the God of our salvation. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;He that is&lt;/span&gt; our God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the God of salvation; and unto &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; the Lord &lt;span class="extra"&gt;belong&lt;/span&gt; the issues from death.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But God shall wound the head of his enemies, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the hairy scalp of such an one as goeth on still in his trespasses.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The Lord said, I will bring again from Bashan, I will bring &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my people&lt;/span&gt; again from the depths of the sea:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">That thy foot may be dipped in the blood of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thine&lt;/span&gt; enemies, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the tongue of thy dogs in the same.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">They have seen thy goings, O God; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the goings of my God, my King, in the sanctuary.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The singers went before, the players on instruments &lt;span class="extra"&gt;followed&lt;/span&gt; after; among &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them were&lt;/span&gt; the damsels playing with timbrels.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Bless ye God in the congregations, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the Lord, from the fountain of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">There &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; little Benjamin &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; their ruler, the princes of Judah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; their council, the princes of Zebulun, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the princes of Naphtali.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Thy God hath commanded thy strength: strengthen, O God, that which thou hast wrought for us.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Because of thy temple at Jerusalem shall kings bring presents unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Rebuke the company of spearmen, the multitude of the bulls, with the calves of the people, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;till every one&lt;/span&gt; submit himself with pieces of silver: scatter thou the people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; delight in war.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Princes shall come out of Egypt; Ethiopia shall soon stretch out her hands unto God.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Sing unto God, ye kingdoms of the earth; O sing praises unto the Lord; Selah:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">To him that rideth upon the heavens of heavens, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which were&lt;/span&gt; of old; lo, he doth send out his voice, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and that&lt;/span&gt; a mighty voice.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Ascribe ye strength unto God: his excellency &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; over Israel, and his strength &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the clouds.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">O God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thou art&lt;/span&gt; terrible out of thy holy places: the God of Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he that giveth strength and power unto &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; people. Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>