<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="140" verseCount="13" nextChapter="psalms_141.html" nextTitle="Psalms 141" prevChapter="psalms_139.html" prevTitle="Psalms 139" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician, A Psalm of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Deliver me, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, from the evil man: preserve me from the violent man;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Which imagine mischiefs in &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; heart; continually are they gathered together &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; war.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">They have sharpened their tongues like a serpent; adders' poison &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; under their lips. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Keep me, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, from the hands of the wicked; preserve me from the violent man; who have purposed to overthrow my goings.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The proud have hid a snare for me, and cords; they have spread a net by the wayside; they have set gins for me. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I said unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; my God: hear the voice of my supplications, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; the Lord, the strength of my salvation, thou hast covered my head in the day of battle.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Grant not, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the desires of the wicked: further not his wicked device; &lt;i&gt;lest&lt;/i&gt; they exalt themselves. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;i&gt;As for&lt;/i&gt; the head of those that compass me about, let the mischief of their own lips cover them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Let burning coals fall upon them: let them be cast into the fire; into deep pits, that they rise not up again.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Let not an evil speaker be established in the earth: evil shall hunt the violent man to overthrow &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I know that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will maintain the cause of the afflicted, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the right of the poor.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Surely the righteous shall give thanks unto thy name: the upright shall dwell in thy presence.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>