<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="17" nextChapter="psalms_8.html" nextTitle="Psalms 8" prevChapter="psalms_6.html" prevTitle="Psalms 6" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">Shiggaion of David, which he sang unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, concerning the words of Cush the Benjamite.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, in thee do I put my trust: save me from all them that persecute me, and deliver me:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Lest he tear my soul like a lion, rending &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; in pieces, while &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none to deliver.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, if I have done this; if there be iniquity in my hands;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">If I have rewarded evil unto him that was at peace with me; (yea, I have delivered him that without cause is mine enemy:)</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Let the enemy persecute my soul, and take &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;; yea, let him tread down my life upon the earth, and lay mine honour in the dust. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Arise, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in thine anger, lift up thyself because of the rage of mine enemies: and awake for me &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the judgment &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thou hast commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">So shall the congregation of the people compass thee about: for their sakes therefore return thou on high.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall judge the people: judge me, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, according to my righteousness, and according to mine integrity &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; in me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Oh let the wickedness of the wicked come to an end; but establish the just: for the righteous God trieth the hearts and reins.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">My defence &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; of God, which saveth the upright in heart.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">God judgeth the righteous, and God is angry &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with the wicked&lt;/span&gt; every day.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">If he turn not, he will whet his sword; he hath bent his bow, and made it ready.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He hath also prepared for him the instruments of death; he ordaineth his arrows against the persecutors.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Behold, he travaileth with iniquity, and hath conceived mischief, and brought forth falsehood.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He made a pit, and digged it, and is fallen into the ditch &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; he made.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">His mischief shall return upon his own head, and his violent dealing shall come down upon his own pate.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">I will praise the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; according to his righteousness: and will sing praise to the name of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; most high.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>