<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="12" nextChapter="psalms_3.html" nextTitle="Psalms 3" prevChapter="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms 1" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Why do the heathen rage, and the people imagine a vain thing?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The kings of the earth set themselves, and the rulers take counsel together, against the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and against his anointed, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Let us break their bands asunder, and cast away their cords from us.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He that sitteth in the heavens shall laugh: the Lord shall have them in derision.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then shall he speak unto them in his wrath, and vex them in his sore displeasure.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Yet have I set my king upon my holy hill of Zion.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">I will declare the decree: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath said unto me, Thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; my Son; this day have I begotten thee.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Ask of me, and I shall give &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt; the heathen &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; thine inheritance, and the uttermost parts of the earth &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; thy possession.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thou shalt break them with a rod of iron; thou shalt dash them in pieces like a potter's vessel.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Be wise now therefore, O ye kings: be instructed, ye judges of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Serve the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with fear, and rejoice with trembling.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Kiss the Son, lest he be angry, and ye perish &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; the way, when his wrath is kindled but a little. Blessed &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; all they that put their trust in him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>