<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="44" verseCount="26" nextChapter="psalms_45.html" nextTitle="Psalms 45" prevChapter="psalms_43.html" prevTitle="Psalms 43" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">To the chief Musician for the sons of Korah, Maschil.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">We have heard with our ears, O God, our fathers have told us, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;what&lt;/span&gt; work thou didst in their days, in the times of old.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;How&lt;/span&gt; thou didst drive out the heathen with thy hand, and plantedst them; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;how&lt;/span&gt; thou didst afflict the people, and cast them out.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For they got not the land in possession by their own sword, neither did their own arm save them: but thy right hand, and thine arm, and the light of thy countenance, because thou hadst a favour unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thou art my King, O God: command deliverances for Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Through thee will we push down our enemies: through thy name will we tread them under that rise up against us.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For I will not trust in my bow, neither shall my sword save me.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But thou hast saved us from our enemies, and hast put them to shame that hated us.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">In God we boast all the day long, and praise thy name for ever. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But thou hast cast off, and put us to shame; and goest not forth with our armies.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thou makest us to turn back from the enemy: and they which hate us spoil for themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thou hast given us like sheep &lt;span class='extra'&gt;appointed&lt;/span&gt; for meat; and hast scattered us among the heathen.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Thou sellest thy people for nought, and dost not increase &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thy wealth&lt;/span&gt; by their price.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thou makest us a reproach to our neighbours, a scorn and a derision to them that are round about us.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou makest us a byword among the heathen, a shaking of the head among the people.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">My confusion &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; continually before me, and the shame of my face hath covered me,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For the voice of him that reproacheth and blasphemeth; by reason of the enemy and avenger.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">All this is come upon us; yet have we not forgotten thee, neither have we dealt falsely in thy covenant.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Our heart is not turned back, neither have our steps declined from thy way;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Though thou hast sore broken us in the place of dragons, and covered us with the shadow of death.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">If we have forgotten the name of our God, or stretched out our hands to a strange god;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Shall not God search this out? for he knoweth the secrets of the heart.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Yea, for thy sake are we killed all the day long; we are counted as sheep for the slaughter.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Awake, why sleepest thou, O Lord? arise, cast &lt;span class='extra'&gt;us&lt;/span&gt; not off for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Wherefore hidest thou thy face, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; forgettest our affliction and our oppression?</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For our soul is bowed down to the dust: our belly cleaveth unto the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Arise for our help, and redeem us for thy mercies' sake.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>