<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="17" verseCount="15" nextChapter="psalms_18.html" nextTitle="Psalms 18" prevChapter="psalms_16.html" prevTitle="Psalms 16" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">A Prayer of David.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hear the right, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, attend unto my cry, give ear unto my prayer, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that goeth&lt;/span&gt; not out of feigned lips.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Let my sentence come forth from thy presence; let thine eyes behold the things that are equal.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou hast proved mine heart; thou hast visited &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; in the night; thou hast tried me, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; shalt find nothing; I am purposed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; my mouth shall not transgress.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Concerning the works of men, by the word of thy lips I have kept &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me from&lt;/span&gt; the paths of the destroyer.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Hold up my goings in thy paths, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; my footsteps slip not.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I have called upon thee, for thou wilt hear me, O God: incline thine ear unto me, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and hear&lt;/span&gt; my speech.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Shew thy marvellous lovingkindness, O thou that savest by thy right hand them which put their trust &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in thee&lt;/span&gt; from those that rise up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;against them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Keep me as the apple of the eye, hide me under the shadow of thy wings,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">From the wicked that oppress me, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; my deadly enemies, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;who&lt;/span&gt; compass me about.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">They are inclosed in their own fat: with their mouth they speak proudly.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">They have now compassed us in our steps: they have set their eyes bowing down to the earth;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Like as a lion &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; is greedy of his prey, and as it were a young lion lurking in secret places.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Arise, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, disappoint him, cast him down: deliver my soul from the wicked, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which is&lt;/span&gt; thy sword:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">From men &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which are&lt;/span&gt; thy hand, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, from men of the world, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which have&lt;/span&gt; their portion in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; life, and whose belly thou fillest with thy hid &lt;span class='extra'&gt;treasure&lt;/span&gt;: they are full of children, and leave the rest of their &lt;span class='extra'&gt;substance&lt;/span&gt; to their babes.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">As for me, I will behold thy face in righteousness: I shall be satisfied, when I awake, with thy likeness.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>