<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="107" verseCount="43" nextChapter="psalms_108.html" nextTitle="Psalms 108" prevChapter="psalms_106.html" prevTitle="Psalms 106" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O give thanks unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; good: for his mercy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;endureth&lt;/span&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Let the redeemed of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; say &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;, whom he hath redeemed from the hand of the enemy;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And gathered them out of the lands, from the east, and from the west, from the north, and from the south.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They wandered in the wilderness in a solitary way; they found no city to dwell in.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Hungry and thirsty, their soul fainted in them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Then they cried unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in their trouble, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he delivered them out of their distresses.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he led them forth by the right way, that they might go to a city of habitation.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Oh that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; would praise the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; his goodness, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; his wonderful works to the children of men!</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For he satisfieth the longing soul, and filleth the hungry soul with goodness.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Such as sit in darkness and in the shadow of death, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; bound in affliction and iron;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Because they rebelled against the words of God, and contemned the counsel of the most High:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore he brought down their heart with labour; they fell down, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; none to help.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then they cried unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in their trouble, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he saved them out of their distresses.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">He brought them out of darkness and the shadow of death, and brake their bands in sunder.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Oh that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; would praise the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; his goodness, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; his wonderful works to the children of men!</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For he hath broken the gates of brass, and cut the bars of iron in sunder.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Fools because of their transgression, and because of their iniquities, are afflicted.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Their soul abhorreth all manner of meat; and they draw near unto the gates of death.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Then they cry unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in their trouble, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he saveth them out of their distresses.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He sent his word, and healed them, and delivered &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; from their destructions.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Oh that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; would praise the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; his goodness, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; his wonderful works to the children of men!</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And let them sacrifice the sacrifices of thanksgiving, and declare his works with rejoicing.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">They that go down to the sea in ships, that do business in great waters;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">These see the works of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and his wonders in the deep.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For he commandeth, and raiseth the stormy wind, which lifteth up the waves thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">They mount up to the heaven, they go down again to the depths: their soul is melted because of trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">They reel to and fro, and stagger like a drunken man, and are at their wits' end.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Then they cry unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in their trouble, and he bringeth them out of their distresses.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">He maketh the storm a calm, so that the waves thereof are still.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Then are they glad because they be quiet; so he bringeth them unto their desired haven.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Oh that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; would praise the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; his goodness, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; his wonderful works to the children of men!</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Let them exalt him also in the congregation of the people, and praise him in the assembly of the elders.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">He turneth rivers into a wilderness, and the watersprings into dry ground;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">A fruitful land into barrenness, for the wickedness of them that dwell therein.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">He turneth the wilderness into a standing water, and dry ground into watersprings.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And there he maketh the hungry to dwell, that they may prepare a city for habitation;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And sow the fields, and plant vineyards, which may yield fruits of increase.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">He blesseth them also, so that they are multiplied greatly; and suffereth not their cattle to decrease.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Again, they are minished and brought low through oppression, affliction, and sorrow.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">He poureth contempt upon princes, and causeth them to wander in the wilderness, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;where there is&lt;/span&gt; no way.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Yet setteth he the poor on high from affliction, and maketh &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; families like a flock.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">The righteous shall see &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and rejoice: and all iniquity shall stop her mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Whoso &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; wise, and will observe these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;, even they shall understand the lovingkindness of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>