<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="19" name="Psalms" bookPage="psalms.html" title="Psalms" chapterCount="150" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="proverbs_1.html" nextTitle="Proverbs" prevBook="job_1.html" prevTitle="Job">
    <chapter number="74" verseCount="23" nextChapter="psalms_75.html" nextTitle="Psalms 75" prevChapter="psalms_73.html" prevTitle="Psalms 73" chapterPage="psalms_">
      <caption id="c0">Maschil of Asaph.</caption>
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O God, why hast thou cast &lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt; off for ever? &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt; doth thine anger smoke against the sheep of thy pasture?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Remember thy congregation, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; thou hast purchased of old; the rod of thine inheritance, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; thou hast redeemed; this mount Zion, wherein thou hast dwelt.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Lift up thy feet unto the perpetual desolations; &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; all &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the enemy hath done wickedly in the sanctuary.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thine enemies roar in the midst of thy congregations; they set up their ensigns &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; signs.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;i&gt;A man&lt;/i&gt; was famous according as he had lifted up axes upon the thick trees.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But now they break down the carved work thereof at once with axes and hammers.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">They have cast fire into thy sanctuary, they have defiled &lt;i&gt;by casting down&lt;/i&gt; the dwelling place of thy name to the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">They said in their hearts, Let us destroy them together: they have burned up all the synagogues of God in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">We see not our signs: &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no more any prophet: neither &lt;i&gt;is there&lt;/i&gt; among us any that knoweth how long.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">O God, how long shall the adversary reproach? shall the enemy blaspheme thy name for ever?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Why withdrawest thou thy hand, even thy right hand? pluck &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; out of thy bosom.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my King of old, working salvation in the midst of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thou didst divide the sea by thy strength: thou brakest the heads of the dragons in the waters.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou brakest the heads of leviathan in pieces, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; gavest him &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; meat to the people inhabiting the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Thou didst cleave the fountain and the flood: thou driedst up mighty rivers.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The day &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thine, the night also &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thine: thou hast prepared the light and the sun.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thou hast set all the borders of the earth: thou hast made summer and winter.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Remember this, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the enemy hath reproached, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the foolish people have blasphemed thy name.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">O deliver not the soul of thy turtledove unto the multitude &lt;i&gt;of the wicked&lt;/i&gt;: forget not the congregation of thy poor for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Have respect unto the covenant: for the dark places of the earth are full of the habitations of cruelty.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">O let not the oppressed return ashamed: let the poor and needy praise thy name.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Arise, O God, plead thine own cause: remember how the foolish man reproacheth thee daily.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Forget not the voice of thine enemies: the tumult of those that rise up against thee increaseth continually.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>