<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="24" verseCount="34" nextChapter="proverbs_25.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 25" prevChapter="proverbs_23.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 23" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Be not thou envious against evil men, neither desire to be with them.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For their heart studieth destruction, and their lips talk of mischief.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Through wisdom is an house builded; and by understanding it is established:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And by knowledge shall the chambers be filled with all precious and pleasant riches.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">A wise man &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; strong; yea, a man of knowledge increaseth strength.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For by wise counsel thou shalt make thy war: and in multitude of counsellors &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; safety.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Wisdom &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; too high for a fool: he openeth not his mouth in the gate.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He that deviseth to do evil shall be called a mischievous person.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The thought of foolishness &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; sin: and the scorner &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an abomination to men.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;i&gt;If&lt;/i&gt; thou faint in the day of adversity, thy strength &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; small.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">If thou forbear to deliver &lt;i&gt;them that are&lt;/i&gt; drawn unto death, and &lt;i&gt;those that are&lt;/i&gt; ready to be slain;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">If thou sayest, Behold, we knew it not; doth not he that pondereth the heart consider &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;? and he that keepeth thy soul, doth &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; he know &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;? and shall &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; he render to &lt;i&gt;every&lt;/i&gt; man according to his works?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">My son, eat thou honey, because &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; good; and the honeycomb, &lt;i&gt;which is&lt;/i&gt; sweet to thy taste:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">So &lt;i&gt;shall&lt;/i&gt; the knowledge of wisdom &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; unto thy soul: when thou hast found &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, then there shall be a reward, and thy expectation shall not be cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Lay not wait, O wicked &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;, against the dwelling of the righteous; spoil not his resting place:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For a just &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; falleth seven times, and riseth up again: but the wicked shall fall into mischief.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Rejoice not when thine enemy falleth, and let not thine heart be glad when he stumbleth:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Lest the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; see &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and it displease him, and he turn away his wrath from him.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Fret not thyself because of evil &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;, neither be thou envious at the wicked;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For there shall be no reward to the evil &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;; the candle of the wicked shall be put out.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">My son, fear thou the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; and the king: &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; meddle not with them that are given to change:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For their calamity shall rise suddenly; and who knoweth the ruin of them both?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">These &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; also &lt;i&gt;belong&lt;/i&gt; to the wise. &lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; not good to have respect of persons in judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">He that saith unto the wicked, Thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; righteous; him shall the people curse, nations shall abhor him:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">But to them that rebuke &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; shall be delight, and a good blessing shall come upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;i&gt;Every man&lt;/i&gt; shall kiss &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; lips that giveth a right answer.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Prepare thy work without, and make it fit for thyself in the field; and afterwards build thine house.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Be not a witness against thy neighbour without cause; and deceive &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; with thy lips.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Say not, I will do so to him as he hath done to me: I will render to the man according to his work.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">I went by the field of the slothful, and by the vineyard of the man void of understanding;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And, lo, it was all grown over with thorns, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; nettles had covered the face thereof, and the stone wall thereof was broken down.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Then I saw, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; considered &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; well: I looked upon &lt;i&gt;it, and&lt;/i&gt; received instruction.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;i&gt;Yet&lt;/i&gt; a little sleep, a little slumber, a little folding of the hands to sleep:</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">So shall thy poverty come &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; one that travelleth; and thy want as an armed man.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>