<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="33" nextChapter="proverbs_16.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 16" prevChapter="proverbs_14.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 14" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">A soft answer turneth away wrath: but grievous words stir up anger.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The tongue of the wise useth knowledge aright: but the mouth of fools poureth out foolishness.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The eyes of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in every place, beholding the evil and the good.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">A wholesome tongue &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a tree of life: but perverseness therein &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a breach in the spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">A fool despiseth his father's instruction: but he that regardeth reproof is prudent.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">In the house of the righteous &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; much treasure: but in the revenues of the wicked is trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The lips of the wise disperse knowledge: but the heart of the foolish &lt;span class="extra"&gt;doeth&lt;/span&gt; not so.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The sacrifice of the wicked &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an abomination to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but the prayer of the upright &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his delight.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The way of the wicked &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an abomination unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but he loveth him that followeth after righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Correction &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; grievous unto him that forsaketh the way: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he that hateth reproof shall die.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Hell and destruction &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: how much more then the hearts of the children of men?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">A scorner loveth not one that reproveth him: neither will he go unto the wise.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">A merry heart maketh a cheerful countenance: but by sorrow of the heart the spirit is broken.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The heart of him that hath understanding seeketh knowledge: but the mouth of fools feedeth on foolishness.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">All the days of the afflicted &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; evil: but he that is of a merry heart &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hath&lt;/span&gt; a continual feast.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Better &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; little with the fear of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; than great treasure and trouble therewith.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Better &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a dinner of herbs where love is, than a stalled ox and hatred therewith.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">A wrathful man stirreth up strife: but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he that is&lt;/span&gt; slow to anger appeaseth strife.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The way of the slothful &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man is&lt;/span&gt; as an hedge of thorns: but the way of the righteous &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; made plain.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">A wise son maketh a glad father: but a foolish man despiseth his mother.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Folly &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; joy to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him that is&lt;/span&gt; destitute of wisdom: but a man of understanding walketh uprightly.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Without counsel purposes are disappointed: but in the multitude of counsellors they are established.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">A man hath joy by the answer of his mouth: and a word &lt;span class="extra"&gt;spoken&lt;/span&gt; in due season, how good &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt;!</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The way of life &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; above to the wise, that he may depart from hell beneath.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will destroy the house of the proud: but he will establish the border of the widow.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The thoughts of the wicked &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; an abomination to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the words&lt;/span&gt; of the pure &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; pleasant words.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">He that is greedy of gain troubleth his own house; but he that hateth gifts shall live.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The heart of the righteous studieth to answer: but the mouth of the wicked poureth out evil things.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; far from the wicked: but he heareth the prayer of the righteous.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The light of the eyes rejoiceth the heart: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; a good report maketh the bones fat.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The ear that heareth the reproof of life abideth among the wise.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">He that refuseth instruction despiseth his own soul: but he that heareth reproof getteth understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">The fear of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the instruction of wisdom; and before honour &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; humility.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>