<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="27" nextChapter="proverbs_8.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 8" prevChapter="proverbs_6.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 6" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">My son, keep my words, and lay up my commandments with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Keep my commandments, and live; and my law as the apple of thine eye.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Bind them upon thy fingers, write them upon the table of thine heart.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Say unto wisdom, Thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; my sister; and call understanding &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; kinswoman:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">That they may keep thee from the strange woman, from the stranger &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; flattereth with her words.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">For at the window of my house I looked through my casement,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And beheld among the simple ones, I discerned among the youths, a young man void of understanding,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Passing through the street near her corner; and he went the way to her house,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">In the twilight, in the evening, in the black and dark night:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And, behold, there met him a woman &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; the attire of an harlot, and subtil of heart.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">(She &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; loud and stubborn; her feet abide not in her house:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Now &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is she&lt;/span&gt; without, now in the streets, and lieth in wait at every corner.)</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">So she caught him, and kissed him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; with an impudent face said unto him,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;I have&lt;/span&gt; peace offerings with me; this day have I payed my vows.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Therefore came I forth to meet thee, diligently to seek thy face, and I have found thee.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I have decked my bed with coverings of tapestry, with carved &lt;span class="extra"&gt;works&lt;/span&gt;, with fine linen of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">I have perfumed my bed with myrrh, aloes, and cinnamon.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Come, let us take our fill of love until the morning: let us solace ourselves with loves.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For the goodman &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not at home, he is gone a long journey:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He hath taken a bag of money with him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; will come home at the day appointed.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">With her much fair speech she caused him to yield, with the flattering of her lips she forced him.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">He goeth after her straightway, as an ox goeth to the slaughter, or as a fool to the correction of the stocks;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Till a dart strike through his liver; as a bird hasteth to the snare, and knoweth not that it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; for his life.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">Hearken unto me now therefore, O ye children, and attend to the words of my mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Let not thine heart decline to her ways, go not astray in her paths.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For she hath cast down many wounded: yea, many strong &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; have been slain by her.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Her house &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the way to hell, going down to the chambers of death.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>