<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="23" verseCount="35" nextChapter="proverbs_24.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 24" prevChapter="proverbs_22.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 22" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">When thou sittest to eat with a ruler, consider diligently what &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; before thee:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And put a knife to thy throat, if thou &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; a man given to appetite.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Be not desirous of his dainties: for they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; deceitful meat.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Labour not to be rich: cease from thine own wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Wilt thou set thine eyes upon that which is not? for &lt;i&gt;riches&lt;/i&gt; certainly make themselves wings; they fly away as an eagle toward heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Eat thou not the bread of &lt;i&gt;him that hath&lt;/i&gt; an evil eye, neither desire thou his dainty meats:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For as he thinketh in his heart, so &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he: Eat and drink, saith he to thee; but his heart &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The morsel &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; thou hast eaten shalt thou vomit up, and lose thy sweet words.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Speak not in the ears of a fool: for he will despise the wisdom of thy words.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Remove not the old landmark; and enter not into the fields of the fatherless:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For their redeemer &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; mighty; he shall plead their cause with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Apply thine heart unto instruction, and thine ears to the words of knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Withhold not correction from the child: for &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; thou beatest him with the rod, he shall not die.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou shalt beat him with the rod, and shalt deliver his soul from hell.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">My son, if thine heart be wise, my heart shall rejoice, even mine.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Yea, my reins shall rejoice, when thy lips speak right things.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Let not thine heart envy sinners: but &lt;i&gt;be thou&lt;/i&gt; in the fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; all the day long.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For surely there is an end; and thine expectation shall not be cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Hear thou, my son, and be wise, and guide thine heart in the way.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Be not among winebibbers; among riotous eaters of flesh:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For the drunkard and the glutton shall come to poverty: and drowsiness shall clothe &lt;i&gt;a man&lt;/i&gt; with rags.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Hearken unto thy father that begat thee, and despise not thy mother when she is old.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Buy the truth, and sell &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not; &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; wisdom, and instruction, and understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The father of the righteous shall greatly rejoice: and he that begetteth a wise &lt;i&gt;child&lt;/i&gt; shall have joy of him.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Thy father and thy mother shall be glad, and she that bare thee shall rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">My son, give me thine heart, and let thine eyes observe my ways.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For a whore &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a deep ditch; and a strange woman &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a narrow pit.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">She also lieth in wait as &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a prey, and increaseth the transgressors among men.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Who hath woe? who hath sorrow? who hath contentions? who hath babbling? who hath wounds without cause? who hath redness of eyes?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">They that tarry long at the wine; they that go to seek mixed wine.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Look not thou upon the wine when it is red, when it giveth his colour in the cup, &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; it moveth itself aright.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">At the last it biteth like a serpent, and stingeth like an adder.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Thine eyes shall behold strange women, and thine heart shall utter perverse things.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Yea, thou shalt be as he that lieth down in the midst of the sea, or as he that lieth upon the top of a mast.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">They have stricken me, &lt;i&gt;shalt thou say, and&lt;/i&gt; I was not sick; they have beaten me, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; I felt &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not: when shall I awake? I will seek it yet again.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>