<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="24" nextChapter="proverbs_19.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 19" prevChapter="proverbs_17.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 17" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Through desire a man, having separated himself, seeketh &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; intermeddleth with all wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">A fool hath no delight in understanding, but that his heart may discover itself.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">When the wicked cometh, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; cometh also contempt, and with ignominy reproach.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The words of a man's mouth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are as&lt;/span&gt; deep waters, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the wellspring of wisdom &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; a flowing brook.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; not good to accept the person of the wicked, to overthrow the righteous in judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">A fool's lips enter into contention, and his mouth calleth for strokes.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">A fool's mouth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his destruction, and his lips &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the snare of his soul.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The words of a talebearer &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; as wounds, and they go down into the innermost parts of the belly.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He also that is slothful in his work is brother to him that is a great waster.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The name of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a strong tower: the righteous runneth into it, and is safe.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The rich man's wealth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his strong city, and as an high wall in his own conceit.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Before destruction the heart of man is haughty, and before honour &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; humility.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He that answereth a matter before he heareth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; folly and shame unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The spirit of a man will sustain his infirmity; but a wounded spirit who can bear?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The heart of the prudent getteth knowledge; and the ear of the wise seeketh knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">A man's gift maketh room for him, and bringeth him before great men.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;He that is&lt;/span&gt; first in his own cause &lt;span class='extra'&gt;seemeth&lt;/span&gt; just; but his neighbour cometh and searcheth him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The lot causeth contentions to cease, and parteth between the mighty.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">A brother offended &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is harder to be won&lt;/span&gt; than a strong city: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; contentions &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; like the bars of a castle.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">A man's belly shall be satisfied with the fruit of his mouth; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; with the increase of his lips shall he be filled.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Death and life &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in the power of the tongue: and they that love it shall eat the fruit thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Whoso&lt;/span&gt; findeth a wife findeth a good &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thing&lt;/span&gt;, and obtaineth favour of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The poor useth intreaties; but the rich answereth roughly.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">A man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that hath&lt;/span&gt; friends must shew himself friendly: and there is a friend &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; sticketh closer than a brother.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>