<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="33" nextChapter="proverbs_17.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 17" prevChapter="proverbs_15.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 15" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The preparations of the heart in man, and the answer of the tongue, &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">All the ways of a man &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; clean in his own eyes; but the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; weigheth the spirits.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Commit thy works unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and thy thoughts shall be established.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath made all &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; for himself: yea, even the wicked for the day of evil.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Every one &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; proud in heart &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an abomination to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;i&gt;though&lt;/i&gt; hand &lt;i&gt;join&lt;/i&gt; in hand, he shall not be unpunished.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">By mercy and truth iniquity is purged: and by the fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; depart from evil.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">When a man's ways please the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, he maketh even his enemies to be at peace with him.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Better &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a little with righteousness than great revenues without right.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">A man's heart deviseth his way: but the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; directeth his steps.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">A divine sentence &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the lips of the king: his mouth transgresseth not in judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">A just weight and balance &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s: all the weights of the bag &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; his work.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; an abomination to kings to commit wickedness: for the throne is established by righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Righteous lips &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the delight of kings; and they love him that speaketh right.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The wrath of a king &lt;i&gt;is as&lt;/i&gt; messengers of death: but a wise man will pacify it.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">In the light of the king's countenance &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; life; and his favour &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as a cloud of the latter rain.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">How much better &lt;i&gt;is it&lt;/i&gt; to get wisdom than gold! and to get understanding rather to be chosen than silver!</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The highway of the upright &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; to depart from evil: he that keepeth his way preserveth his soul.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Pride &lt;i&gt;goeth&lt;/i&gt; before destruction, and an haughty spirit before a fall.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Better &lt;i&gt;it is to be&lt;/i&gt; of an humble spirit with the lowly, than to divide the spoil with the proud.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He that handleth a matter wisely shall find good: and whoso trusteth in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, happy &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The wise in heart shall be called prudent: and the sweetness of the lips increaseth learning.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Understanding &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a wellspring of life unto him that hath it: but the instruction of fools &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; folly.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The heart of the wise teacheth his mouth, and addeth learning to his lips.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Pleasant words &lt;i&gt;are as&lt;/i&gt; an honeycomb, sweet to the soul, and health to the bones.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">There is a way that seemeth right unto a man, but the end thereof &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the ways of death.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">He that laboureth laboureth for himself; for his mouth craveth it of him.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">An ungodly man diggeth up evil: and in his lips &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; as a burning fire.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">A froward man soweth strife: and a whisperer separateth chief friends.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">A violent man enticeth his neighbour, and leadeth him into the way &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; not good.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">He shutteth his eyes to devise froward things: moving his lips he bringeth evil to pass.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The hoary head &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a crown of glory, &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; it be found in the way of righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;i&gt;He that is&lt;/i&gt; slow to anger &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; better than the mighty; and he that ruleth his spirit than he that taketh a city.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">The lot is cast into the lap; but the whole disposing thereof &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>