<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="25" verseCount="28" nextChapter="proverbs_26.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 26" prevChapter="proverbs_24.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 24" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; also proverbs of Solomon, which the men of Hezekiah king of Judah copied out.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; the glory of God to conceal a thing: but the honour of kings &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; to search out a matter.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The heaven for height, and the earth for depth, and the heart of kings &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unsearchable.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Take away the dross from the silver, and there shall come forth a vessel for the finer.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Take away the wicked &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; before the king, and his throne shall be established in righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Put not forth thyself in the presence of the king, and stand not in the place of great &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For better &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; that it be said unto thee, Come up hither; than that thou shouldest be put lower in the presence of the prince whom thine eyes have seen.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Go not forth hastily to strive, lest &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thou know not&lt;/span&gt; what to do in the end thereof, when thy neighbour hath put thee to shame.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Debate thy cause with thy neighbour &lt;span class="extra"&gt;himself&lt;/span&gt;; and discover not a secret to another:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Lest he that heareth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; put thee to shame, and thine infamy turn not away.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">A word fitly spoken &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is like&lt;/span&gt; apples of gold in pictures of silver.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; an earring of gold, and an ornament of fine gold, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so is&lt;/span&gt; a wise reprover upon an obedient ear.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">As the cold of snow in the time of harvest, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so is&lt;/span&gt; a faithful messenger to them that send him: for he refresheth the soul of his masters.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Whoso boasteth himself of a false gift &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is like&lt;/span&gt; clouds and wind without rain.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">By long forbearing is a prince persuaded, and a soft tongue breaketh the bone.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Hast thou found honey? eat so much as is sufficient for thee, lest thou be filled therewith, and vomit it.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Withdraw thy foot from thy neighbour's house; lest he be weary of thee, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; hate thee.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">A man that beareth false witness against his neighbour &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a maul, and a sword, and a sharp arrow.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Confidence in an unfaithful man in time of trouble &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is like&lt;/span&gt; a broken tooth, and a foot out of joint.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; he that taketh away a garment in cold weather, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and as&lt;/span&gt; vinegar upon nitre, so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he that singeth songs to an heavy heart.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">If thine enemy be hungry, give him bread to eat; and if he be thirsty, give him water to drink:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For thou shalt heap coals of fire upon his head, and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall reward thee.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The north wind driveth away rain: so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;doth&lt;/span&gt; an angry countenance a backbiting tongue.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; better to dwell in the corner of the housetop, than with a brawling woman and in a wide house.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; cold waters to a thirsty soul, so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; good news from a far country.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">A righteous man falling down before the wicked &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is as&lt;/span&gt; a troubled fountain, and a corrupt spring.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; not good to eat much honey: so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for men&lt;/span&gt; to search their own glory &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is not&lt;/span&gt; glory.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">He that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hath&lt;/span&gt; no rule over his own spirit &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is like&lt;/span&gt; a city &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; broken down, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; without walls.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>