<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="35" nextChapter="proverbs_7.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 7" prevChapter="proverbs_5.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 5" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">My son, if thou be surety for thy friend, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; thou hast stricken thy hand with a stranger,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thou art snared with the words of thy mouth, thou art taken with the words of thy mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Do this now, my son, and deliver thyself, when thou art come into the hand of thy friend; go, humble thyself, and make sure thy friend.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Give not sleep to thine eyes, nor slumber to thine eyelids.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Deliver thyself as a roe from the hand &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of the hunter&lt;/span&gt;, and as a bird from the hand of the fowler.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Go to the ant, thou sluggard; consider her ways, and be wise:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Which having no guide, overseer, or ruler,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Provideth her meat in the summer, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; gathereth her food in the harvest.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">How long wilt thou sleep, O sluggard? when wilt thou arise out of thy sleep?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Yet&lt;/span&gt; a little sleep, a little slumber, a little folding of the hands to sleep:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">So shall thy poverty come as one that travelleth, and thy want as an armed man.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">A naughty person, a wicked man, walketh with a froward mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He winketh with his eyes, he speaketh with his feet, he teacheth with his fingers;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Frowardness &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in his heart, he deviseth mischief continually; he soweth discord.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Therefore shall his calamity come suddenly; suddenly shall he be broken without remedy.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">These six &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; doth the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hate: yea, seven &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; an abomination unto him:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">A proud look, a lying tongue, and hands that shed innocent blood,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">An heart that deviseth wicked imaginations, feet that be swift in running to mischief,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">A false witness &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; speaketh lies, and he that soweth discord among brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">My son, keep thy father's commandment, and forsake not the law of thy mother:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Bind them continually upon thine heart, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; tie them about thy neck.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">When thou goest, it shall lead thee; when thou sleepest, it shall keep thee; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; thou awakest, it shall talk with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For the commandment &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a lamp; and the law &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; light; and reproofs of instruction &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the way of life:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">To keep thee from the evil woman, from the flattery of the tongue of a strange woman.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Lust not after her beauty in thine heart; neither let her take thee with her eyelids.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For by means of a whorish woman &lt;span class="extra"&gt;a man is brought&lt;/span&gt; to a piece of bread: and the adulteress will hunt for the precious life.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Can a man take fire in his bosom, and his clothes not be burned?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Can one go upon hot coals, and his feet not be burned?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">So he that goeth in to his neighbour's wife; whosoever toucheth her shall not be innocent.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Men&lt;/span&gt; do not despise a thief, if he steal to satisfy his soul when he is hungry;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">But &lt;span class="extra"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; he be found, he shall restore sevenfold; he shall give all the substance of his house.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;But&lt;/span&gt; whoso committeth adultery with a woman lacketh understanding: he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; doeth it destroyeth his own soul.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">A wound and dishonour shall he get; and his reproach shall not be wiped away.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">For jealousy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the rage of a man: therefore he will not spare in the day of vengeance.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">He will not regard any ransom; neither will he rest content, though thou givest many gifts.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>