<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="33" nextChapter="proverbs_2.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 2" prevChapter="psalms_150.html" prevTitle="Psalms 150" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The proverbs of Solomon the son of David, king of Israel;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">To know wisdom and instruction; to perceive the words of understanding;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">To receive the instruction of wisdom, justice, and judgment, and equity;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">To give subtilty to the simple, to the young man knowledge and discretion.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">A wise &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; will hear, and will increase learning; and a man of understanding shall attain unto wise counsels:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">To understand a proverb, and the interpretation; the words of the wise, and their dark sayings.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">The fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the beginning of knowledge: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; fools despise wisdom and instruction.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">My son, hear the instruction of thy father, and forsake not the law of thy mother:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For they &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; an ornament of grace unto thy head, and chains about thy neck.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">My son, if sinners entice thee, consent thou not.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">If they say, Come with us, let us lay wait for blood, let us lurk privily for the innocent without cause:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Let us swallow them up alive as the grave; and whole, as those that go down into the pit:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">We shall find all precious substance, we shall fill our houses with spoil:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Cast in thy lot among us; let us all have one purse:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">My son, walk not thou in the way with them; refrain thy foot from their path:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For their feet run to evil, and make haste to shed blood.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Surely in vain the net is spread in the sight of any bird.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And they lay wait for their &lt;i&gt;own&lt;/i&gt; blood; they lurk privily for their &lt;i&gt;own&lt;/i&gt; lives.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">So &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the ways of every one that is greedy of gain; &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; taketh away the life of the owners thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">Wisdom crieth without; she uttereth her voice in the streets:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">She crieth in the chief place of concourse, in the openings of the gates: in the city she uttereth her words, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">How long, ye simple ones, will ye love simplicity? and the scorners delight in their scorning, and fools hate knowledge?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Turn you at my reproof: behold, I will pour out my spirit unto you, I will make known my words unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">Because I have called, and ye refused; I have stretched out my hand, and no man regarded;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">But ye have set at nought all my counsel, and would none of my reproof:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">I also will laugh at your calamity; I will mock when your fear cometh;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">When your fear cometh as desolation, and your destruction cometh as a whirlwind; when distress and anguish cometh upon you.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Then shall they call upon me, but I will not answer; they shall seek me early, but they shall not find me:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For that they hated knowledge, and did not choose the fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">They would none of my counsel: they despised all my reproof.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Therefore shall they eat of the fruit of their own way, and be filled with their own devices.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">For the turning away of the simple shall slay them, and the prosperity of fools shall destroy them.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">But whoso hearkeneth unto me shall dwell safely, and shall be quiet from fear of evil.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>