<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="28" nextChapter="proverbs_13.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 13" prevChapter="proverbs_11.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 11" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Whoso loveth instruction loveth knowledge: but he that hateth reproof &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; brutish.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">A good &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; obtaineth favour of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but a man of wicked devices will he condemn.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">A man shall not be established by wickedness: but the root of the righteous shall not be moved.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">A virtuous woman &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a crown to her husband: but she that maketh ashamed &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as rottenness in his bones.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The thoughts of the righteous &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; right: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; the counsels of the wicked &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; deceit.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The words of the wicked &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; to lie in wait for blood: but the mouth of the upright shall deliver them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The wicked are overthrown, and &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; not: but the house of the righteous shall stand.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">A man shall be commended according to his wisdom: but he that is of a perverse heart shall be despised.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;i&gt;He that is&lt;/i&gt; despised, and hath a servant, &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; better than he that honoureth himself, and lacketh bread.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">A righteous &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; regardeth the life of his beast: but the tender mercies of the wicked &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; cruel.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He that tilleth his land shall be satisfied with bread: but he that followeth vain &lt;i&gt;persons is&lt;/i&gt; void of understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The wicked desireth the net of evil &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;: but the root of the righteous yieldeth &lt;i&gt;fruit&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The wicked is snared by the transgression of &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; lips: but the just shall come out of trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">A man shall be satisfied with good by the fruit of &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; mouth: and the recompence of a man's hands shall be rendered unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The way of a fool &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; right in his own eyes: but he that hearkeneth unto counsel &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; wise.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">A fool's wrath is presently known: but a prudent &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; covereth shame.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;i&gt;He that&lt;/i&gt; speaketh truth sheweth forth righteousness: but a false witness deceit.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">There is that speaketh like the piercings of a sword: but the tongue of the wise &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; health.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The lip of truth shall be established for ever: but a lying tongue &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; but for a moment.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Deceit &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the heart of them that imagine evil: but to the counsellors of peace &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; joy.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">There shall no evil happen to the just: but the wicked shall be filled with mischief.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Lying lips &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; abomination to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but they that deal truly &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; his delight.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">A prudent man concealeth knowledge: but the heart of fools proclaimeth foolishness.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The hand of the diligent shall bear rule: but the slothful shall be under tribute.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Heaviness in the heart of man maketh it stoop: but a good word maketh it glad.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The righteous &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; more excellent than his neighbour: but the way of the wicked seduceth them.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The slothful &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; roasteth not that which he took in hunting: but the substance of a diligent man &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; precious.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">In the way of righteousness &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; life; and &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the pathway &lt;i&gt;thereof there is&lt;/i&gt; no death.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>