<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="35" nextChapter="proverbs_15.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 15" prevChapter="proverbs_13.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 13" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Every wise woman buildeth her house: but the foolish plucketh it down with her hands.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">He that walketh in his uprightness feareth the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he that is&lt;/span&gt; perverse in his ways despiseth him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">In the mouth of the foolish &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a rod of pride: but the lips of the wise shall preserve them.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Where no oxen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt;, the crib &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; clean: but much increase &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; by the strength of the ox.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">A faithful witness will not lie: but a false witness will utter lies.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">A scorner seeketh wisdom, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;findeth it&lt;/span&gt; not: but knowledge &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; easy unto him that understandeth.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Go from the presence of a foolish man, when thou perceivest not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in him&lt;/span&gt; the lips of knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The wisdom of the prudent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; to understand his way: but the folly of fools &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; deceit.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Fools make a mock at sin: but among the righteous &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; favour.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The heart knoweth his own bitterness; and a stranger doth not intermeddle with his joy.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The house of the wicked shall be overthrown: but the tabernacle of the upright shall flourish.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">There is a way which seemeth right unto a man, but the end thereof &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the ways of death.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Even in laughter the heart is sorrowful; and the end of that mirth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; heaviness.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The backslider in heart shall be filled with his own ways: and a good man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be satisfied&lt;/span&gt; from himself.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The simple believeth every word: but the prudent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; looketh well to his going.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">A wise &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; feareth, and departeth from evil: but the fool rageth, and is confident.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;He that is&lt;/span&gt; soon angry dealeth foolishly: and a man of wicked devices is hated.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The simple inherit folly: but the prudent are crowned with knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The evil bow before the good; and the wicked at the gates of the righteous.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The poor is hated even of his own neighbour: but the rich &lt;span class='extra'&gt;hath&lt;/span&gt; many friends.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">He that despiseth his neighbour sinneth: but he that hath mercy on the poor, happy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Do they not err that devise evil? but mercy and truth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; to them that devise good.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">In all labour there is profit: but the talk of the lips &lt;span class='extra'&gt;tendeth&lt;/span&gt; only to penury.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The crown of the wise &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; their riches: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; the foolishness of fools &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; folly.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">A true witness delivereth souls: but a deceitful &lt;span class='extra'&gt;witness&lt;/span&gt; speaketh lies.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">In the fear of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; strong confidence: and his children shall have a place of refuge.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The fear of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a fountain of life, to depart from the snares of death.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">In the multitude of people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the king's honour: but in the want of people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the destruction of the prince.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;He that is&lt;/span&gt; slow to wrath &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; of great understanding: but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he that is&lt;/span&gt; hasty of spirit exalteth folly.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">A sound heart &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the life of the flesh: but envy the rottenness of the bones.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">He that oppresseth the poor reproacheth his Maker: but he that honoureth him hath mercy on the poor.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">The wicked is driven away in his wickedness: but the righteous hath hope in his death.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Wisdom resteth in the heart of him that hath understanding: but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which is&lt;/span&gt; in the midst of fools is made known.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Righteousness exalteth a nation: but sin &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a reproach to any people.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">The king's favour &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; toward a wise servant: but his wrath is &lt;span class='extra'&gt;against&lt;/span&gt; him that causeth shame.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>