<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="25" nextChapter="proverbs_14.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 14" prevChapter="proverbs_12.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 12" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">A wise son &lt;span class="extra"&gt;heareth&lt;/span&gt; his father's instruction: but a scorner heareth not rebuke.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">A man shall eat good by the fruit of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; mouth: but the soul of the transgressors &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall eat&lt;/span&gt; violence.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">He that keepeth his mouth keepeth his life: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; he that openeth wide his lips shall have destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The soul of the sluggard desireth, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hath&lt;/span&gt; nothing: but the soul of the diligent shall be made fat.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">A righteous &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; hateth lying: but a wicked &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; is loathsome, and cometh to shame.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Righteousness keepeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him that is&lt;/span&gt; upright in the way: but wickedness overthroweth the sinner.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">There is that maketh himself rich, yet &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hath&lt;/span&gt; nothing: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; that maketh himself poor, yet &lt;span class="extra"&gt;hath&lt;/span&gt; great riches.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The ransom of a man's life &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; his riches: but the poor heareth not rebuke.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The light of the righteous rejoiceth: but the lamp of the wicked shall be put out.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Only by pride cometh contention: but with the well advised &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Wealth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;gotten&lt;/span&gt; by vanity shall be diminished: but he that gathereth by labour shall increase.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Hope deferred maketh the heart sick: but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; the desire cometh, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; a tree of life.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Whoso despiseth the word shall be destroyed: but he that feareth the commandment shall be rewarded.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The law of the wise &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a fountain of life, to depart from the snares of death.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Good understanding giveth favour: but the way of transgressors &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; hard.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Every prudent &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; dealeth with knowledge: but a fool layeth open &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; folly.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">A wicked messenger falleth into mischief: but a faithful ambassador &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; health.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Poverty and shame &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be to&lt;/span&gt; him that refuseth instruction: but he that regardeth reproof shall be honoured.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The desire accomplished is sweet to the soul: but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; abomination to fools to depart from evil.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He that walketh with wise &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; shall be wise: but a companion of fools shall be destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Evil pursueth sinners: but to the righteous good shall be repayed.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">A good &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; leaveth an inheritance to his children's children: and the wealth of the sinner &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; laid up for the just.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Much food &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is in&lt;/span&gt; the tillage of the poor: but there is &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; destroyed for want of judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">He that spareth his rod hateth his son: but he that loveth him chasteneth him betimes.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The righteous eateth to the satisfying of his soul: but the belly of the wicked shall want.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>