<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="29" verseCount="27" nextChapter="proverbs_30.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 30" prevChapter="proverbs_28.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 28" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">He, that being often reproved hardeneth &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; neck, shall suddenly be destroyed, and that without remedy.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">When the righteous are in authority, the people rejoice: but when the wicked beareth rule, the people mourn.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Whoso loveth wisdom rejoiceth his father: but he that keepeth company with harlots spendeth &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; substance.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The king by judgment establisheth the land: but he that receiveth gifts overthroweth it.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">A man that flattereth his neighbour spreadeth a net for his feet.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">In the transgression of an evil man &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; a snare: but the righteous doth sing and rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The righteous considereth the cause of the poor: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; the wicked regardeth not to know &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Scornful men bring a city into a snare: but wise &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; turn away wrath.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;i&gt;If&lt;/i&gt; a wise man contendeth with a foolish man, whether he rage or laugh, &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no rest.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The bloodthirsty hate the upright: but the just seek his soul.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">A fool uttereth all his mind: but a wise &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; keepeth it in till afterwards.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">If a ruler hearken to lies, all his servants &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The poor and the deceitful man meet together: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; lighteneth both their eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The king that faithfully judgeth the poor, his throne shall be established for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The rod and reproof give wisdom: but a child left &lt;i&gt;to himself&lt;/i&gt; bringeth his mother to shame.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">When the wicked are multiplied, transgression increaseth: but the righteous shall see their fall.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Correct thy son, and he shall give thee rest; yea, he shall give delight unto thy soul.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Where &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no vision, the people perish: but he that keepeth the law, happy &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">A servant will not be corrected by words: for though he understand he will not answer.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Seest thou a man &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; hasty in his words? &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; more hope of a fool than of him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">He that delicately bringeth up his servant from a child shall have him become &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; son at the length.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">An angry man stirreth up strife, and a furious man aboundeth in transgression.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">A man's pride shall bring him low: but honour shall uphold the humble in spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Whoso is partner with a thief hateth his own soul: he heareth cursing, and bewrayeth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The fear of man bringeth a snare: but whoso putteth his trust in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be safe.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Many seek the ruler's favour; but &lt;i&gt;every&lt;/i&gt; man's judgment &lt;i&gt;cometh&lt;/i&gt; from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">An unjust man &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an abomination to the just: and &lt;i&gt;he that is&lt;/i&gt; upright in the way &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; abomination to the wicked.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>