<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="21" verseCount="31" nextChapter="proverbs_22.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 22" prevChapter="proverbs_20.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 20" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The king's heart &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the hand of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; the rivers of water: he turneth it whithersoever he will.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Every way of a man &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; right in his own eyes: but the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; pondereth the hearts.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">To do justice and judgment &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; more acceptable to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; than sacrifice.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">An high look, and a proud heart, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the plowing of the wicked, &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; sin.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The thoughts of the diligent &lt;i&gt;tend&lt;/i&gt; only to plenteousness; but of every one &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; hasty only to want.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The getting of treasures by a lying tongue &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a vanity tossed to and fro of them that seek death.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The robbery of the wicked shall destroy them; because they refuse to do judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The way of man &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; froward and strange: but &lt;i&gt;as for&lt;/i&gt; the pure, his work &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; right.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; better to dwell in a corner of the housetop, than with a brawling woman in a wide house.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The soul of the wicked desireth evil: his neighbour findeth no favour in his eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">When the scorner is punished, the simple is made wise: and when the wise is instructed, he receiveth knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The righteous &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; wisely considereth the house of the wicked: &lt;i&gt;but God&lt;/i&gt; overthroweth the wicked for &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; wickedness.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Whoso stoppeth his ears at the cry of the poor, he also shall cry himself, but shall not be heard.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">A gift in secret pacifieth anger: and a reward in the bosom strong wrath.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; joy to the just to do judgment: but destruction &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; to the workers of iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The man that wandereth out of the way of understanding shall remain in the congregation of the dead.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He that loveth pleasure &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; a poor man: he that loveth wine and oil shall not be rich.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The wicked &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; a ransom for the righteous, and the transgressor for the upright.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; better to dwell in the wilderness, than with a contentious and an angry woman.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; treasure to be desired and oil in the dwelling of the wise; but a foolish man spendeth it up.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">He that followeth after righteousness and mercy findeth life, righteousness, and honour.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">A wise &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; scaleth the city of the mighty, and casteth down the strength of the confidence thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Whoso keepeth his mouth and his tongue keepeth his soul from troubles.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Proud &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; haughty scorner &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his name, who dealeth in proud wrath.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The desire of the slothful killeth him; for his hands refuse to labour.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">He coveteth greedily all the day long: but the righteous giveth and spareth not.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The sacrifice of the wicked &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; abomination: how much more, &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; he bringeth it with a wicked mind?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">A false witness shall perish: but the man that heareth speaketh constantly.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">A wicked man hardeneth his face: but &lt;i&gt;as for&lt;/i&gt; the upright, he directeth his way.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; no wisdom nor understanding nor counsel against the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The horse &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; prepared against the day of battle: but safety &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>