<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="27" verseCount="27" nextChapter="proverbs_28.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 28" prevChapter="proverbs_26.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 26" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Boast not thyself of to morrow; for thou knowest not what a day may bring forth.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Let another man praise thee, and not thine own mouth; a stranger, and not thine own lips.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">A stone &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; heavy, and the sand weighty; but a fool's wrath &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; heavier than them both.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Wrath &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; cruel, and anger &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; outrageous; but who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; able to stand before envy?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Open rebuke &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; better than secret love.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Faithful &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the wounds of a friend; but the kisses of an enemy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; deceitful.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The full soul loatheth an honeycomb; but to the hungry soul every bitter thing is sweet.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">As a bird that wandereth from her nest, so &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a man that wandereth from his place.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Ointment and perfume rejoice the heart: so &lt;span class='extra'&gt;doth&lt;/span&gt; the sweetness of a man's friend by hearty counsel.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thine own friend, and thy father's friend, forsake not; neither go into thy brother's house in the day of thy calamity: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; better &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a neighbour &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; near than a brother far off.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">My son, be wise, and make my heart glad, that I may answer him that reproacheth me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">A prudent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; foreseeth the evil, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; hideth himself; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; the simple pass on, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; are punished.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Take his garment that is surety for a stranger, and take a pledge of him for a strange woman.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">He that blesseth his friend with a loud voice, rising early in the morning, it shall be counted a curse to him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">A continual dropping in a very rainy day and a contentious woman are alike.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Whosoever hideth her hideth the wind, and the ointment of his right hand, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; bewrayeth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;itself&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Iron sharpeneth iron; so a man sharpeneth the countenance of his friend.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Whoso keepeth the fig tree shall eat the fruit thereof: so he that waiteth on his master shall be honoured.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">As in water face &lt;span class='extra'&gt;answereth&lt;/span&gt; to face, so the heart of man to man.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Hell and destruction are never full; so the eyes of man are never satisfied.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; the fining pot for silver, and the furnace for gold; so &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a man to his praise.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Though thou shouldest bray a fool in a mortar among wheat with a pestle, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;yet&lt;/span&gt; will not his foolishness depart from him.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Be thou diligent to know the state of thy flocks, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; look well to thy herds.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For riches &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not for ever: and doth the crown &lt;span class='extra'&gt;endure&lt;/span&gt; to every generation?</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The hay appeareth, and the tender grass sheweth itself, and herbs of the mountains are gathered.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The lambs &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; for thy clothing, and the goats &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the price of the field.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thou shalt have&lt;/span&gt; goats' milk enough for thy food, for the food of thy household, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the maintenance for thy maidens.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>