<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="31" verseCount="31" nextChapter="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes 1" prevChapter="proverbs_30.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 30" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The words of king Lemuel, the prophecy that his mother taught him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">What, my son? and what, the son of my womb? and what, the son of my vows?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Give not thy strength unto women, nor thy ways to that which destroyeth kings.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; not for kings, O Lemuel, &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; not for kings to drink wine; nor for princes strong drink:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Lest they drink, and forget the law, and pervert the judgment of any of the afflicted.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Give strong drink unto him that is ready to perish, and wine unto those that be of heavy hearts.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Let him drink, and forget his poverty, and remember his misery no more.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Open thy mouth for the dumb in the cause of all such as are appointed to destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Open thy mouth, judge righteously, and plead the cause of the poor and needy.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Who can find a virtuous woman? for her price &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; far above rubies.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The heart of her husband doth safely trust in her, so that he shall have no need of spoil.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">She will do him good and not evil all the days of her life.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">She seeketh wool, and flax, and worketh willingly with her hands.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">She is like the merchants' ships; she bringeth her food from afar.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">She riseth also while it is yet night, and giveth meat to her household, and a portion to her maidens.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">She considereth a field, and buyeth it: with the fruit of her hands she planteth a vineyard.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">She girdeth her loins with strength, and strengtheneth her arms.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">She perceiveth that her merchandise &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; good: her candle goeth not out by night.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">She layeth her hands to the spindle, and her hands hold the distaff.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">She stretcheth out her hand to the poor; yea, she reacheth forth her hands to the needy.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">She is not afraid of the snow for her household: for all her household &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; clothed with scarlet.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">She maketh herself coverings of tapestry; her clothing &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; silk and purple.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Her husband is known in the gates, when he sitteth among the elders of the land.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">She maketh fine linen, and selleth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;; and delivereth girdles unto the merchant.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Strength and honour &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; her clothing; and she shall rejoice in time to come.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">She openeth her mouth with wisdom; and in her tongue &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the law of kindness.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">She looketh well to the ways of her household, and eateth not the bread of idleness.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Her children arise up, and call her blessed; her husband &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt;, and he praiseth her.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Many daughters have done virtuously, but thou excellest them all.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Favour &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; deceitful, and beauty &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; vain: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; a woman &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; feareth the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, she shall be praised.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Give her of the fruit of her hands; and let her own works praise her in the gates.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>