<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="29" nextChapter="proverbs_23.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 23" prevChapter="proverbs_21.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 21" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">A &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; name &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; rather to be chosen than great riches, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; loving favour rather than silver and gold.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The rich and poor meet together: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the maker of them all.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">A prudent &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; foreseeth the evil, and hideth himself: but the simple pass on, and are punished.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">By humility &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; riches, and honour, and life.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thorns &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; snares &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in the way of the froward: he that doth keep his soul shall be far from them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Train up a child in the way he should go: and when he is old, he will not depart from it.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The rich ruleth over the poor, and the borrower &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; servant to the lender.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He that soweth iniquity shall reap vanity: and the rod of his anger shall fail.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He that hath a bountiful eye shall be blessed; for he giveth of his bread to the poor.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Cast out the scorner, and contention shall go out; yea, strife and reproach shall cease.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He that loveth pureness of heart, &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; the grace of his lips the king &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; his friend.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The eyes of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; preserve knowledge, and he overthroweth the words of the transgressor.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The slothful &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; saith, &lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; a lion without, I shall be slain in the streets.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The mouth of strange women &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a deep pit: he that is abhorred of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall fall therein.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Foolishness &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; bound in the heart of a child; &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; the rod of correction shall drive it far from him.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He that oppresseth the poor to increase his &lt;i&gt;riches, and&lt;/i&gt; he that giveth to the rich, &lt;i&gt;shall&lt;/i&gt; surely &lt;i&gt;come&lt;/i&gt; to want.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Bow down thine ear, and hear the words of the wise, and apply thine heart unto my knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; a pleasant thing if thou keep them within thee; they shall withal be fitted in thy lips.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">That thy trust may be in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I have made known to thee this day, even to thee.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Have not I written to thee excellent things in counsels and knowledge,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">That I might make thee know the certainty of the words of truth; that thou mightest answer the words of truth to them that send unto thee?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Rob not the poor, because he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; poor: neither oppress the afflicted in the gate:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will plead their cause, and spoil the soul of those that spoiled them.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Make no friendship with an angry man; and with a furious man thou shalt not go:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Lest thou learn his ways, and get a snare to thy soul.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Be not thou &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; of them that strike hands, &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; of them that are sureties for debts.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">If thou hast nothing to pay, why should he take away thy bed from under thee?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Remove not the ancient landmark, which thy fathers have set.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Seest thou a man diligent in his business? he shall stand before kings; he shall not stand before mean &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>