<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="26" verseCount="28" nextChapter="proverbs_27.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 27" prevChapter="proverbs_25.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 25" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">As snow in summer, and as rain in harvest, so honour is not seemly for a fool.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">As the bird by wandering, as the swallow by flying, so the curse causeless shall not come.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">A whip for the horse, a bridle for the ass, and a rod for the fool's back.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Answer not a fool according to his folly, lest thou also be like unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Answer a fool according to his folly, lest he be wise in his own conceit.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He that sendeth a message by the hand of a fool cutteth off the feet, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; drinketh damage.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The legs of the lame are not equal: so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a parable in the mouth of fools.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">As he that bindeth a stone in a sling, so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he that giveth honour to a fool.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; a thorn goeth up into the hand of a drunkard, so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a parable in the mouth of fools.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The great &lt;span class="extra"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; that formed all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; both rewardeth the fool, and rewardeth transgressors.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">As a dog returneth to his vomit, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; a fool returneth to his folly.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Seest thou a man wise in his own conceit? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; more hope of a fool than of him.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The slothful &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; saith, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;There is&lt;/span&gt; a lion in the way; a lion &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the streets.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; the door turneth upon his hinges, so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;doth&lt;/span&gt; the slothful upon his bed.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The slothful hideth his hand in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; bosom; it grieveth him to bring it again to his mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The sluggard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; wiser in his own conceit than seven men that can render a reason.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He that passeth by, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; meddleth with strife &lt;span class="extra"&gt;belonging&lt;/span&gt; not to him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is like&lt;/span&gt; one that taketh a dog by the ears.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">As a mad &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; who casteth firebrands, arrows, and death,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">So &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; deceiveth his neighbour, and saith, Am not I in sport?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Where no wood is, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there&lt;/span&gt; the fire goeth out: so where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no talebearer, the strife ceaseth.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; coals &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; to burning coals, and wood to fire; so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a contentious man to kindle strife.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The words of a talebearer &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; as wounds, and they go down into the innermost parts of the belly.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Burning lips and a wicked heart &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are like&lt;/span&gt; a potsherd covered with silver dross.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">He that hateth dissembleth with his lips, and layeth up deceit within him;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">When he speaketh fair, believe him not: for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there are&lt;/span&gt; seven abominations in his heart.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Whose&lt;/span&gt; hatred is covered by deceit, his wickedness shall be shewed before the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;whole&lt;/span&gt; congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Whoso diggeth a pit shall fall therein: and he that rolleth a stone, it will return upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">A lying tongue hateth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;those that are&lt;/span&gt; afflicted by it; and a flattering mouth worketh ruin.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>