<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="17" verseCount="28" nextChapter="proverbs_18.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 18" prevChapter="proverbs_16.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 16" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Better &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a dry morsel, and quietness therewith, than an house full of sacrifices &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; strife.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">A wise servant shall have rule over a son that causeth shame, and shall have part of the inheritance among the brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The fining pot &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; for silver, and the furnace for gold: but the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; trieth the hearts.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">A wicked doer giveth heed to false lips; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; a liar giveth ear to a naughty tongue.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Whoso mocketh the poor reproacheth his Maker: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he that is glad at calamities shall not be unpunished.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Children's children &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the crown of old men; and the glory of children &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Excellent speech becometh not a fool: much less do lying lips a prince.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">A gift &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is as&lt;/span&gt; a precious stone in the eyes of him that hath it: whithersoever it turneth, it prospereth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He that covereth a transgression seeketh love; but he that repeateth a matter separateth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;very&lt;/span&gt; friends.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">A reproof entereth more into a wise man than an hundred stripes into a fool.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">An evil &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; seeketh only rebellion: therefore a cruel messenger shall be sent against him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Let a bear robbed of her whelps meet a man, rather than a fool in his folly.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Whoso rewardeth evil for good, evil shall not depart from his house.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The beginning of strife &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is as&lt;/span&gt; when one letteth out water: therefore leave off contention, before it be meddled with.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He that justifieth the wicked, and he that condemneth the just, even they both &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; abomination to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Wherefore &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; a price in the hand of a fool to get wisdom, seeing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he hath&lt;/span&gt; no heart &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to it&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">A friend loveth at all times, and a brother is born for adversity.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">A man void of understanding striketh hands, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; becometh surety in the presence of his friend.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He loveth transgression that loveth strife: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he that exalteth his gate seeketh destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He that hath a froward heart findeth no good: and he that hath a perverse tongue falleth into mischief.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">He that begetteth a fool &lt;span class="extra"&gt;doeth it&lt;/span&gt; to his sorrow: and the father of a fool hath no joy.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">A merry heart doeth good &lt;span class="extra"&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; a medicine: but a broken spirit drieth the bones.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">A wicked &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; taketh a gift out of the bosom to pervert the ways of judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Wisdom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; before him that hath understanding; but the eyes of a fool &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in the ends of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">A foolish son &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a grief to his father, and bitterness to her that bare him.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Also to punish the just &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not good, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;nor&lt;/span&gt; to strike princes for equity.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">He that hath knowledge spareth his words: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; a man of understanding is of an excellent spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Even a fool, when he holdeth his peace, is counted wise: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he that shutteth his lips &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is esteemed&lt;/span&gt; a man of understanding.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>