<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="18" nextChapter="proverbs_10.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 10" prevChapter="proverbs_8.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 8" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Wisdom hath builded her house, she hath hewn out her seven pillars:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">She hath killed her beasts; she hath mingled her wine; she hath also furnished her table.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">She hath sent forth her maidens: she crieth upon the highest places of the city,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Whoso &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; simple, let him turn in hither: &lt;i&gt;as for&lt;/i&gt; him that wanteth understanding, she saith to him,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Come, eat of my bread, and drink of the wine &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; I have mingled.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Forsake the foolish, and live; and go in the way of understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He that reproveth a scorner getteth to himself shame: and he that rebuketh a wicked &lt;i&gt;man getteth&lt;/i&gt; himself a blot.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Reprove not a scorner, lest he hate thee: rebuke a wise man, and he will love thee.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Give &lt;i&gt;instruction&lt;/i&gt; to a wise &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;, and he will be yet wiser: teach a just &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;, and he will increase in learning.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the beginning of wisdom: and the knowledge of the holy &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For by me thy days shall be multiplied, and the years of thy life shall be increased.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">If thou be wise, thou shalt be wise for thyself: but &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; thou scornest, thou alone shalt bear &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">A foolish woman &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; clamorous: &lt;i&gt;she is&lt;/i&gt; simple, and knoweth nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For she sitteth at the door of her house, on a seat in the high places of the city,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">To call passengers who go right on their ways:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Whoso &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; simple, let him turn in hither: and &lt;i&gt;as for&lt;/i&gt; him that wanteth understanding, she saith to him,</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Stolen waters are sweet, and bread &lt;i&gt;eaten&lt;/i&gt; in secret is pleasant.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But he knoweth not that the dead &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; there; &lt;i&gt;and that&lt;/i&gt; her guests &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in the depths of hell.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>