<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="32" nextChapter="proverbs_11.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 11" prevChapter="proverbs_9.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 9" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The proverbs of Solomon. A wise son maketh a glad father: but a foolish son &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the heaviness of his mother.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Treasures of wickedness profit nothing: but righteousness delivereth from death.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will not suffer the soul of the righteous to famish: but he casteth away the substance of the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He becometh poor that dealeth &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; a slack hand: but the hand of the diligent maketh rich.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">He that gathereth in summer &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a wise son: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; he that sleepeth in harvest &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a son that causeth shame.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Blessings &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; upon the head of the just: but violence covereth the mouth of the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The memory of the just &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; blessed: but the name of the wicked shall rot.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The wise in heart will receive commandments: but a prating fool shall fall.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He that walketh uprightly walketh surely: but he that perverteth his ways shall be known.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He that winketh with the eye causeth sorrow: but a prating fool shall fall.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The mouth of a righteous &lt;i&gt;man is&lt;/i&gt; a well of life: but violence covereth the mouth of the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Hatred stirreth up strifes: but love covereth all sins.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">In the lips of him that hath understanding wisdom is found: but a rod &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; for the back of him that is void of understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Wise &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; lay up knowledge: but the mouth of the foolish &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; near destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The rich man's wealth &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his strong city: the destruction of the poor &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; their poverty.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The labour of the righteous &lt;i&gt;tendeth&lt;/i&gt; to life: the fruit of the wicked to sin.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He &lt;i&gt;is in&lt;/i&gt; the way of life that keepeth instruction: but he that refuseth reproof erreth.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He that hideth hatred &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; lying lips, and he that uttereth a slander, &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a fool.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">In the multitude of words there wanteth not sin: but he that refraineth his lips &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; wise.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The tongue of the just &lt;i&gt;is as&lt;/i&gt; choice silver: the heart of the wicked &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; little worth.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The lips of the righteous feed many: but fools die for want of wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The blessing of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, it maketh rich, and he addeth no sorrow with it.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; as sport to a fool to do mischief: but a man of understanding hath wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The fear of the wicked, it shall come upon him: but the desire of the righteous shall be granted.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">As the whirlwind passeth, so &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the wicked no &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt;: but the righteous &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an everlasting foundation.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">As vinegar to the teeth, and as smoke to the eyes, so &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the sluggard to them that send him.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; prolongeth days: but the years of the wicked shall be shortened.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The hope of the righteous &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; gladness: but the expectation of the wicked shall perish.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The way of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; strength to the upright: but destruction &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; to the workers of iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The righteous shall never be removed: but the wicked shall not inhabit the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The mouth of the just bringeth forth wisdom: but the froward tongue shall be cut out.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">The lips of the righteous know what is acceptable: but the mouth of the wicked &lt;i&gt;speaketh&lt;/i&gt; frowardness.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>