<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="36" nextChapter="proverbs_9.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 9" prevChapter="proverbs_7.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 7" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Doth not wisdom cry? and understanding put forth her voice?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">She standeth in the top of high places, by the way in the places of the paths.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">She crieth at the gates, at the entry of the city, at the coming in at the doors.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Unto you, O men, I call; and my voice &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; to the sons of man.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">O ye simple, understand wisdom: and, ye fools, be ye of an understanding heart.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Hear; for I will speak of excellent things; and the opening of my lips &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; right things.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For my mouth shall speak truth; and wickedness &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an abomination to my lips.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">All the words of my mouth &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in righteousness; &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; nothing froward or perverse in them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">They &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; all plain to him that understandeth, and right to them that find knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Receive my instruction, and not silver; and knowledge rather than choice gold.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For wisdom &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; better than rubies; and all the things that may be desired are not to be compared to it.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I wisdom dwell with prudence, and find out knowledge of witty inventions.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; to hate evil: pride, and arrogancy, and the evil way, and the froward mouth, do I hate.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Counsel &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; mine, and sound wisdom: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; understanding; I have strength.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">By me kings reign, and princes decree justice.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">By me princes rule, and nobles, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; all the judges of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">I love them that love me; and those that seek me early shall find me.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Riches and honour &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; with me; &lt;i&gt;yea&lt;/i&gt;, durable riches and righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">My fruit &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; better than gold, yea, than fine gold; and my revenue than choice silver.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">I lead in the way of righteousness, in the midst of the paths of judgment:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">That I may cause those that love me to inherit substance; and I will fill their treasures.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; possessed me in the beginning of his way, before his works of old.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">I was set up from everlasting, from the beginning, or ever the earth was.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">When &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; no depths, I was brought forth; when &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; no fountains abounding with water.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Before the mountains were settled, before the hills was I brought forth:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">While as yet he had not made the earth, nor the fields, nor the highest part of the dust of the world.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">When he prepared the heavens, I &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; there: when he set a compass upon the face of the depth:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">When he established the clouds above: when he strengthened the fountains of the deep:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">When he gave to the sea his decree, that the waters should not pass his commandment: when he appointed the foundations of the earth:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Then I was by him, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; one brought up &lt;i&gt;with him&lt;/i&gt;: and I was daily &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; delight, rejoicing always before him;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Rejoicing in the habitable part of his earth; and my delights &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with the sons of men.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Now therefore hearken unto me, O ye children: for blessed &lt;i&gt;are they that&lt;/i&gt; keep my ways.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Hear instruction, and be wise, and refuse it not.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Blessed &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the man that heareth me, watching daily at my gates, waiting at the posts of my doors.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">For whoso findeth me findeth life, and shall obtain favour of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">But he that sinneth against me wrongeth his own soul: all they that hate me love death.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>