<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="19" verseCount="29" nextChapter="proverbs_20.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 20" prevChapter="proverbs_18.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 18" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Better &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the poor that walketh in his integrity, than &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he that is&lt;/span&gt; perverse in his lips, and is a fool.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Also, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the soul &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; without knowledge, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; not good; and he that hasteth with &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; feet sinneth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The foolishness of man perverteth his way: and his heart fretteth against the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Wealth maketh many friends; but the poor is separated from his neighbour.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">A false witness shall not be unpunished, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he that&lt;/span&gt; speaketh lies shall not escape.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Many will intreat the favour of the prince: and every man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a friend to him that giveth gifts.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">All the brethren of the poor do hate him: how much more do his friends go far from him? he pursueth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them with&lt;/span&gt; words, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yet&lt;/span&gt; they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; wanting &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to him&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He that getteth wisdom loveth his own soul: he that keepeth understanding shall find good.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">A false witness shall not be unpunished, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he that&lt;/span&gt; speaketh lies shall perish.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Delight is not seemly for a fool; much less for a servant to have rule over princes.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The discretion of a man deferreth his anger; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; his glory to pass over a transgression.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The king's wrath &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; as the roaring of a lion; but his favour &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; as dew upon the grass.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">A foolish son &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the calamity of his father: and the contentions of a wife &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; a continual dropping.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">House and riches &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the inheritance of fathers: and a prudent wife &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; from the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Slothfulness casteth into a deep sleep; and an idle soul shall suffer hunger.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He that keepeth the commandment keepeth his own soul; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; he that despiseth his ways shall die.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He that hath pity upon the poor lendeth unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and that which he hath given will he pay him again.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Chasten thy son while there is hope, and let not thy soul spare for his crying.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">A man of great wrath shall suffer punishment: for if thou deliver &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, yet thou must do it again.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Hear counsel, and receive instruction, that thou mayest be wise in thy latter end.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;There are&lt;/span&gt; many devices in a man's heart; nevertheless the counsel of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that shall stand.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The desire of a man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his kindness: and a poor man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; better than a liar.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The fear of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;tendeth&lt;/span&gt; to life: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he that hath it&lt;/span&gt; shall abide satisfied; he shall not be visited with evil.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">A slothful &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; hideth his hand in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; bosom, and will not so much as bring it to his mouth again.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Smite a scorner, and the simple will beware: and reprove one that hath understanding, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; he will understand knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">He that wasteth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; father, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; chaseth away &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; mother, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a son that causeth shame, and bringeth reproach.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Cease, my son, to hear the instruction &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that causeth&lt;/span&gt; to err from the words of knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">An ungodly witness scorneth judgment: and the mouth of the wicked devoureth iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Judgments are prepared for scorners, and stripes for the back of fools.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>