<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="30" nextChapter="proverbs_21.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 21" prevChapter="proverbs_19.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 19" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Wine &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a mocker, strong drink &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; raging: and whosoever is deceived thereby is not wise.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The fear of a king &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as the roaring of a lion: &lt;i&gt;whoso&lt;/i&gt; provoketh him to anger sinneth &lt;i&gt;against&lt;/i&gt; his own soul.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; an honour for a man to cease from strife: but every fool will be meddling.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The sluggard will not plow by reason of the cold; &lt;i&gt;therefore&lt;/i&gt; shall he beg in harvest, and &lt;i&gt;have&lt;/i&gt; nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Counsel in the heart of man &lt;i&gt;is like&lt;/i&gt; deep water; but a man of understanding will draw it out.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Most men will proclaim every one his own goodness: but a faithful man who can find?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The just &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; walketh in his integrity: his children &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; blessed after him.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">A king that sitteth in the throne of judgment scattereth away all evil with his eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Who can say, I have made my heart clean, I am pure from my sin?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Divers weights, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; divers measures, both of them &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; alike abomination to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Even a child is known by his doings, whether his work &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; pure, and whether &lt;i&gt;it be&lt;/i&gt; right.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The hearing ear, and the seeing eye, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath made even both of them.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Love not sleep, lest thou come to poverty; open thine eyes, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; thou shalt be satisfied with bread.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; naught, &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; naught, saith the buyer: but when he is gone his way, then he boasteth.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">There is gold, and a multitude of rubies: but the lips of knowledge &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; a precious jewel.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Take his garment that is surety &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a stranger: and take a pledge of him for a strange woman.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Bread of deceit &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; sweet to a man; but afterwards his mouth shall be filled with gravel.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;i&gt;Every&lt;/i&gt; purpose is established by counsel: and with good advice make war.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He that goeth about &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; a talebearer revealeth secrets: therefore meddle not with him that flattereth with his lips.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Whoso curseth his father or his mother, his lamp shall be put out in obscure darkness.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">An inheritance &lt;i&gt;may be&lt;/i&gt; gotten hastily at the beginning; but the end thereof shall not be blessed.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Say not thou, I will recompense evil; &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; wait on the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and he shall save thee.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Divers weights &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; an abomination unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and a false balance &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not good.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Man's goings &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; how can a man then understand his own way?</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; a snare to the man &lt;i&gt;who&lt;/i&gt; devoureth &lt;i&gt;that which is&lt;/i&gt; holy, and after vows to make enquiry.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">A wise king scattereth the wicked, and bringeth the wheel over them.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The spirit of man &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the candle of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, searching all the inward parts of the belly.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Mercy and truth preserve the king: and his throne is upholden by mercy.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The glory of young men &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; their strength: and the beauty of old men &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the gray head.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The blueness of a wound cleanseth away evil: so &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; stripes the inward parts of the belly.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>