<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="23" nextChapter="proverbs_6.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 6" prevChapter="proverbs_4.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 4" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">My son, attend unto my wisdom, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; bow thine ear to my understanding:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That thou mayest regard discretion, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thy lips may keep knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">For the lips of a strange woman drop &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; an honeycomb, and her mouth &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; smoother than oil:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But her end is bitter as wormwood, sharp as a twoedged sword.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Her feet go down to death; her steps take hold on hell.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Lest thou shouldest ponder the path of life, her ways are moveable, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thou canst not know &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Hear me now therefore, O ye children, and depart not from the words of my mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Remove thy way far from her, and come not nigh the door of her house:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Lest thou give thine honour unto others, and thy years unto the cruel:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Lest strangers be filled with thy wealth; and thy labours &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; in the house of a stranger;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And thou mourn at the last, when thy flesh and thy body are consumed,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And say, How have I hated instruction, and my heart despised reproof;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And have not obeyed the voice of my teachers, nor inclined mine ear to them that instructed me!</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I was almost in all evil in the midst of the congregation and assembly.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Drink waters out of thine own cistern, and running waters out of thine own well.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Let thy fountains be dispersed abroad, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; rivers of waters in the streets.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Let them be only thine own, and not strangers' with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Let thy fountain be blessed: and rejoice with the wife of thy youth.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;i&gt;Let her be as&lt;/i&gt; the loving hind and pleasant roe; let her breasts satisfy thee at all times; and be thou ravished always with her love.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And why wilt thou, my son, be ravished with a strange woman, and embrace the bosom of a stranger?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For the ways of man &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; before the eyes of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and he pondereth all his goings.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">His own iniquities shall take the wicked himself, and he shall be holden with the cords of his sins.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">He shall die without instruction; and in the greatness of his folly he shall go astray.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>