<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="31" nextChapter="proverbs_12.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 12" prevChapter="proverbs_10.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 10" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">A false balance &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; abomination to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but a just weight &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his delight.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;i&gt;When&lt;/i&gt; pride cometh, then cometh shame: but with the lowly &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The integrity of the upright shall guide them: but the perverseness of transgressors shall destroy them.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Riches profit not in the day of wrath: but righteousness delivereth from death.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The righteousness of the perfect shall direct his way: but the wicked shall fall by his own wickedness.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The righteousness of the upright shall deliver them: but transgressors shall be taken in &lt;i&gt;their own&lt;/i&gt; naughtiness.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">When a wicked man dieth, &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; expectation shall perish: and the hope of unjust &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; perisheth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The righteous is delivered out of trouble, and the wicked cometh in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">An hypocrite with &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; mouth destroyeth his neighbour: but through knowledge shall the just be delivered.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">When it goeth well with the righteous, the city rejoiceth: and when the wicked perish, &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; shouting.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">By the blessing of the upright the city is exalted: but it is overthrown by the mouth of the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">He that is void of wisdom despiseth his neighbour: but a man of understanding holdeth his peace.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">A talebearer revealeth secrets: but he that is of a faithful spirit concealeth the matter.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Where no counsel &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt;, the people fall: but in the multitude of counsellors &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; safety.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He that is surety for a stranger shall smart &lt;i&gt;for it&lt;/i&gt;: and he that hateth suretiship is sure.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">A gracious woman retaineth honour: and strong &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; retain riches.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The merciful man doeth good to his own soul: but &lt;i&gt;he that is&lt;/i&gt; cruel troubleth his own flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The wicked worketh a deceitful work: but to him that soweth righteousness &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; a sure reward.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">As righteousness &lt;i&gt;tendeth&lt;/i&gt; to life: so he that pursueth evil &lt;i&gt;pursueth it&lt;/i&gt; to his own death.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">They that are of a froward heart &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; abomination to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but &lt;i&gt;such as are&lt;/i&gt; upright in &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; way &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; his delight.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;i&gt;Though&lt;/i&gt; hand &lt;i&gt;join&lt;/i&gt; in hand, the wicked shall not be unpunished: but the seed of the righteous shall be delivered.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;i&gt;As&lt;/i&gt; a jewel of gold in a swine's snout, &lt;i&gt;so is&lt;/i&gt; a fair woman which is without discretion.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The desire of the righteous &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; only good: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; the expectation of the wicked &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; wrath.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">There is that scattereth, and yet increaseth; and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; that withholdeth more than is meet, but &lt;i&gt;it tendeth&lt;/i&gt; to poverty.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The liberal soul shall be made fat: and he that watereth shall be watered also himself.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">He that withholdeth corn, the people shall curse him: but blessing &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; upon the head of him that selleth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">He that diligently seeketh good procureth favour: but he that seeketh mischief, it shall come unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">He that trusteth in his riches shall fall: but the righteous shall flourish as a branch.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">He that troubleth his own house shall inherit the wind: and the fool &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; servant to the wise of heart.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">The fruit of the righteous &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a tree of life; and he that winneth souls &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; wise.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Behold, the righteous shall be recompensed in the earth: much more the wicked and the sinner.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>