<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="35" nextChapter="proverbs_4.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 4" prevChapter="proverbs_2.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 2" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">My son, forget not my law; but let thine heart keep my commandments:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For length of days, and long life, and peace, shall they add to thee.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Let not mercy and truth forsake thee: bind them about thy neck; write them upon the table of thine heart:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">So shalt thou find favour and good understanding in the sight of God and man.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Trust in the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with all thine heart; and lean not unto thine own understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">In all thy ways acknowledge him, and he shall direct thy paths.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Be not wise in thine own eyes: fear the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and depart from evil.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">It shall be health to thy navel, and marrow to thy bones.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Honour the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with thy substance, and with the firstfruits of all thine increase:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">So shall thy barns be filled with plenty, and thy presses shall burst out with new wine.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">My son, despise not the chastening of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; neither be weary of his correction:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For whom the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; loveth he correcteth; even as a father the son &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in whom&lt;/span&gt; he delighteth.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Happy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; findeth wisdom, and the man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; getteth understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For the merchandise of it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; better than the merchandise of silver, and the gain thereof than fine gold.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">She &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; more precious than rubies: and all the things thou canst desire are not to be compared unto her.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Length of days &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in her right hand; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; in her left hand riches and honour.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Her ways &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; ways of pleasantness, and all her paths &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; peace.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">She &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a tree of life to them that lay hold upon her: and happy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is every one&lt;/span&gt; that retaineth her.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; by wisdom hath founded the earth; by understanding hath he established the heavens.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">By his knowledge the depths are broken up, and the clouds drop down the dew.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">My son, let not them depart from thine eyes: keep sound wisdom and discretion:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">So shall they be life unto thy soul, and grace to thy neck.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Then shalt thou walk in thy way safely, and thy foot shall not stumble.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">When thou liest down, thou shalt not be afraid: yea, thou shalt lie down, and thy sleep shall be sweet.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Be not afraid of sudden fear, neither of the desolation of the wicked, when it cometh.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be thy confidence, and shall keep thy foot from being taken.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">Withhold not good from them to whom it is due, when it is in the power of thine hand to do &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Say not unto thy neighbour, Go, and come again, and to morrow I will give; when thou hast it by thee.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Devise not evil against thy neighbour, seeing he dwelleth securely by thee.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">Strive not with a man without cause, if he have done thee no harm.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">Envy thou not the oppressor, and choose none of his ways.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">For the froward &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; abomination to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but his secret &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with the righteous.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">The curse of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the house of the wicked: but he blesseth the habitation of the just.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Surely he scorneth the scorners: but he giveth grace unto the lowly.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">The wise shall inherit glory: but shame shall be the promotion of fools.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>