<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="20" name="Proverbs" bookPage="proverbs.html" title="Proverbs" chapterCount="31" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes" prevBook="psalms_1.html" prevTitle="Psalms">
    <chapter number="30" verseCount="33" nextChapter="proverbs_31.html" nextTitle="Proverbs 31" prevChapter="proverbs_29.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 29" chapterPage="proverbs_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The words of Agur the son of Jakeh, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the prophecy: the man spake unto Ithiel, even unto Ithiel and Ucal,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Surely I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; more brutish than &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; man, and have not the understanding of a man.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I neither learned wisdom, nor have the knowledge of the holy.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Who hath ascended up into heaven, or descended? who hath gathered the wind in his fists? who hath bound the waters in a garment? who hath established all the ends of the earth? what &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his name, and what &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his son's name, if thou canst tell?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Every word of God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; pure: he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a shield unto them that put their trust in him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Add thou not unto his words, lest he reprove thee, and thou be found a liar.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Two &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; have I required of thee; deny me &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; not before I die:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Remove far from me vanity and lies: give me neither poverty nor riches; feed me with food convenient for me:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Lest I be full, and deny &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt;, and say, Who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? or lest I be poor, and steal, and take the name of my God &lt;i&gt;in vain&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Accuse not a servant unto his master, lest he curse thee, and thou be found guilty.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; a generation &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; curseth their father, and doth not bless their mother.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; a generation &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; pure in their own eyes, and &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; is not washed from their filthiness.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; a generation, O how lofty are their eyes! and their eyelids are lifted up.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; a generation, whose teeth &lt;i&gt;are as&lt;/i&gt; swords, and their jaw teeth &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; knives, to devour the poor from off the earth, and the needy from &lt;i&gt;among&lt;/i&gt; men.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The horseleach hath two daughters, &lt;i&gt;crying&lt;/i&gt;, Give, give. There are three &lt;i&gt;things that&lt;/i&gt; are never satisfied, &lt;i&gt;yea&lt;/i&gt;, four &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; say not, &lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; enough:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The grave; and the barren womb; the earth &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; is not filled with water; and the fire &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; saith not, &lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; enough.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The eye &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; mocketh at &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; father, and despiseth to obey &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; mother, the ravens of the valley shall pick it out, and the young eagles shall eat it.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">There be three &lt;i&gt;things which&lt;/i&gt; are too wonderful for me, yea, four which I know not:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The way of an eagle in the air; the way of a serpent upon a rock; the way of a ship in the midst of the sea; and the way of a man with a maid.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Such &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the way of an adulterous woman; she eateth, and wipeth her mouth, and saith, I have done no wickedness.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For three &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; the earth is disquieted, and for four &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; it cannot bear:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For a servant when he reigneth; and a fool when he is filled with meat;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For an odious &lt;i&gt;woman&lt;/i&gt; when she is married; and an handmaid that is heir to her mistress.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">There be four &lt;i&gt;things which are&lt;/i&gt; little upon the earth, but they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; exceeding wise:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The ants &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; a people not strong, yet they prepare their meat in the summer;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The conies &lt;i&gt;are but&lt;/i&gt; a feeble folk, yet make they their houses in the rocks;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">The locusts have no king, yet go they forth all of them by bands;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The spider taketh hold with her hands, and is in kings' palaces.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">There be three &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; which go well, yea, four are comely in going:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">A lion &lt;i&gt;which is&lt;/i&gt; strongest among beasts, and turneth not away for any;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">A greyhound; an he goat also; and a king, against whom &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no rising up.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">If thou hast done foolishly in lifting up thyself, or if thou hast thought evil, &lt;i&gt;lay&lt;/i&gt; thine hand upon thy mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Surely the churning of milk bringeth forth butter, and the wringing of the nose bringeth forth blood: so the forcing of wrath bringeth forth strife.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>