<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="21" name="Ecclesiastes" bookPage="ecclesiastes.html" title="Ecclesiastes" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon" prevBook="proverbs_1.html" prevTitle="Proverbs">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="16" nextChapter="ecclesiastes_5.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes 5" prevChapter="ecclesiastes_3.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes 3" chapterPage="ecclesiastes_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">So I returned, and considered all the oppressions that are done under the sun: and behold the tears of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;such as were&lt;/span&gt; oppressed, and they had no comforter; and on the side of their oppressors &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; power; but they had no comforter.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Wherefore I praised the dead which are already dead more than the living which are yet alive.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Yea, better &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is he&lt;/span&gt; than both they, which hath not yet been, who hath not seen the evil work that is done under the sun.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Again, I considered all travail, and every right work, that for this a man is envied of his neighbour. This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; also vanity and vexation of spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The fool foldeth his hands together, and eateth his own flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Better &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an handful &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; quietness, than both the hands full &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; travail and vexation of spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Then I returned, and I saw vanity under the sun.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">There is one &lt;span class="extra"&gt;alone&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; not a second; yea, he hath neither child nor brother: yet &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; no end of all his labour; neither is his eye satisfied with riches; neither &lt;span class="extra"&gt;saith he&lt;/span&gt;, For whom do I labour, and bereave my soul of good? This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; also vanity, yea, it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a sore travail.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Two &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; better than one; because they have a good reward for their labour.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For if they fall, the one will lift up his fellow: but woe to him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; alone when he falleth; for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he hath&lt;/span&gt; not another to help him up.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Again, if two lie together, then they have heat: but how can one be warm &lt;span class="extra"&gt;alone&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And if one prevail against him, two shall withstand him; and a threefold cord is not quickly broken.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Better &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a poor and a wise child than an old and foolish king, who will no more be admonished.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For out of prison he cometh to reign; whereas also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he that is&lt;/span&gt; born in his kingdom becometh poor.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I considered all the living which walk under the sun, with the second child that shall stand up in his stead.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;There is&lt;/span&gt; no end of all the people, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of all that have been before them: they also that come after shall not rejoice in him. Surely this also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vanity and vexation of spirit.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>