<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="21" name="Ecclesiastes" bookPage="ecclesiastes.html" title="Ecclesiastes" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon" prevBook="proverbs_1.html" prevTitle="Proverbs">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="26" nextChapter="ecclesiastes_3.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes 3" prevChapter="ecclesiastes_1.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes 1" chapterPage="ecclesiastes_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I said in mine heart, Go to now, I will prove thee with mirth, therefore enjoy pleasure: and, behold, this also &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I said of laughter, &lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; mad: and of mirth, What doeth it?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I sought in mine heart to give myself unto wine, yet acquainting mine heart with wisdom; and to lay hold on folly, till I might see what &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; that good for the sons of men, which they should do under the heaven all the days of their life.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I made me great works; I builded me houses; I planted me vineyards:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I made me gardens and orchards, and I planted trees in them of all &lt;i&gt;kind of&lt;/i&gt; fruits:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I made me pools of water, to water therewith the wood that bringeth forth trees:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">I got &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; servants and maidens, and had servants born in my house; also I had great possessions of great and small cattle above all that were in Jerusalem before me:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I gathered me also silver and gold, and the peculiar treasure of kings and of the provinces: I gat me men singers and women singers, and the delights of the sons of men, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; musical instruments, and that of all sorts.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">So I was great, and increased more than all that were before me in Jerusalem: also my wisdom remained with me.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And whatsoever mine eyes desired I kept not from them, I withheld not my heart from any joy; for my heart rejoiced in all my labour: and this was my portion of all my labour.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then I looked on all the works that my hands had wrought, and on the labour that I had laboured to do: and, behold, all &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; vanity and vexation of spirit, and &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; no profit under the sun.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And I turned myself to behold wisdom, and madness, and folly: for what &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; the man &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; that cometh after the king? &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; that which hath been already done.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then I saw that wisdom excelleth folly, as far as light excelleth darkness.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The wise man's eyes &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in his head; but the fool walketh in darkness: and I myself perceived also that one event happeneth to them all.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Then said I in my heart, As it happeneth to the fool, so it happeneth even to me; and why was I then more wise? Then I said in my heart, that this also &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no remembrance of the wise more than of the fool for ever; seeing that which now &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the days to come shall all be forgotten. And how dieth the wise &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;? as the fool.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Therefore I hated life; because the work that is wrought under the sun &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; grievous unto me: for all &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; vanity and vexation of spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Yea, I hated all my labour which I had taken under the sun: because I should leave it unto the man that shall be after me.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And who knoweth whether he shall be a wise &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; or a fool? yet shall he have rule over all my labour wherein I have laboured, and wherein I have shewed myself wise under the sun. This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; also vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Therefore I went about to cause my heart to despair of all the labour which I took under the sun.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For there is a man whose labour &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in wisdom, and in knowledge, and in equity; yet to a man that hath not laboured therein shall he leave it &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; his portion. This also &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; vanity and a great evil.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For what hath man of all his labour, and of the vexation of his heart, wherein he hath laboured under the sun?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For all his days &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; sorrows, and his travail grief; yea, his heart taketh not rest in the night. This is also vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; nothing better for a man, &lt;i&gt;than&lt;/i&gt; that he should eat and drink, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; he should make his soul enjoy good in his labour. This also I saw, that it &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; from the hand of God.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For who can eat, or who else can hasten &lt;i&gt;hereunto&lt;/i&gt;, more than I?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For &lt;i&gt;God&lt;/i&gt; giveth to a man that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; good in his sight wisdom, and knowledge, and joy: but to the sinner he giveth travail, to gather and to heap up, that he may give to &lt;i&gt;him that is&lt;/i&gt; good before God. This also &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; vanity and vexation of spirit.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>