<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="21" name="Ecclesiastes" bookPage="ecclesiastes.html" title="Ecclesiastes" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon" prevBook="proverbs_1.html" prevTitle="Proverbs">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="12" nextChapter="ecclesiastes_7.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes 7" prevChapter="ecclesiastes_5.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes 5" chapterPage="ecclesiastes_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">There is an evil which I have seen under the sun, and it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; common among men:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">A man to whom God hath given riches, wealth, and honour, so that he wanteth nothing for his soul of all that he desireth, yet God giveth him not power to eat thereof, but a stranger eateth it: this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vanity, and it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an evil disease.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">If a man beget an hundred &lt;span class='extra'&gt;children&lt;/span&gt;, and live many years, so that the days of his years be many, and his soul be not filled with good, and also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; he have no burial; I say, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; an untimely birth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; better than he.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For he cometh in with vanity, and departeth in darkness, and his name shall be covered with darkness.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Moreover he hath not seen the sun, nor known &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any thing&lt;/span&gt;: this hath more rest than the other.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Yea, though he live a thousand years twice &lt;span class='extra'&gt;told&lt;/span&gt;, yet hath he seen no good: do not all go to one place?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">All the labour of man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; for his mouth, and yet the appetite is not filled.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For what hath the wise more than the fool? what hath the poor, that knoweth to walk before the living?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Better &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the sight of the eyes than the wandering of the desire: this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; also vanity and vexation of spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">That which hath been is named already, and it is known that it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; man: neither may he contend with him that is mightier than he.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Seeing there be many things that increase vanity, what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; man the better?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For who knoweth what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; good for man in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; life, all the days of his vain life which he spendeth as a shadow? for who can tell a man what shall be after him under the sun?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>