<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="21" name="Ecclesiastes" bookPage="ecclesiastes.html" title="Ecclesiastes" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon" prevBook="proverbs_1.html" prevTitle="Proverbs">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="22" nextChapter="ecclesiastes_4.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes 4" prevChapter="ecclesiastes_2.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes 2" chapterPage="ecclesiastes_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">To every &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thing there is&lt;/span&gt; a season, and a time to every purpose under the heaven:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">A time to be born, and a time to die; a time to plant, and a time to pluck up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which is&lt;/span&gt; planted;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">A time to kill, and a time to heal; a time to break down, and a time to build up;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">A time to weep, and a time to laugh; a time to mourn, and a time to dance;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">A time to cast away stones, and a time to gather stones together; a time to embrace, and a time to refrain from embracing;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">A time to get, and a time to lose; a time to keep, and a time to cast away;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">A time to rend, and a time to sew; a time to keep silence, and a time to speak;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">A time to love, and a time to hate; a time of war, and a time of peace.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">What profit hath he that worketh in that wherein he laboureth?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I have seen the travail, which God hath given to the sons of men to be exercised in it.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He hath made every &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thing&lt;/span&gt; beautiful in his time: also he hath set the world in their heart, so that no man can find out the work that God maketh from the beginning to the end.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I know that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no good in them, but for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;a man&lt;/span&gt; to rejoice, and to do good in his life.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And also that every man should eat and drink, and enjoy the good of all his labour, it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the gift of God.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I know that, whatsoever God doeth, it shall be for ever: nothing can be put to it, nor any thing taken from it: and God doeth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; should fear before him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">That which hath been is now; and that which is to be hath already been; and God requireth that which is past.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And moreover I saw under the sun the place of judgment, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; wickedness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; there; and the place of righteousness, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; iniquity &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; there.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">I said in mine heart, God shall judge the righteous and the wicked: for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; a time there for every purpose and for every work.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">I said in mine heart concerning the estate of the sons of men, that God might manifest them, and that they might see that they themselves are beasts.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For that which befalleth the sons of men befalleth beasts; even one thing befalleth them: as the one dieth, so dieth the other; yea, they have all one breath; so that a man hath no preeminence above a beast: for all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">All go unto one place; all are of the dust, and all turn to dust again.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Who knoweth the spirit of man that goeth upward, and the spirit of the beast that goeth downward to the earth?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Wherefore I perceive that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; nothing better, than that a man should rejoice in his own works; for that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his portion: for who shall bring him to see what shall be after him?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>