<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="21" name="Ecclesiastes" bookPage="ecclesiastes.html" title="Ecclesiastes" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon" prevBook="proverbs_1.html" prevTitle="Proverbs">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="18" nextChapter="ecclesiastes_2.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes 2" prevChapter="proverbs_31.html" prevTitle="Proverbs 31" chapterPage="ecclesiastes_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The words of the Preacher, the son of David, king in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Vanity of vanities, saith the Preacher, vanity of vanities; all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">What profit hath a man of all his labour which he taketh under the sun?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;One&lt;/span&gt; generation passeth away, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;another&lt;/span&gt; generation cometh: but the earth abideth for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The sun also ariseth, and the sun goeth down, and hasteth to his place where he arose.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The wind goeth toward the south, and turneth about unto the north; it whirleth about continually, and the wind returneth again according to his circuits.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">All the rivers run into the sea; yet the sea &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not full; unto the place from whence the rivers come, thither they return again.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">All things &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; full of labour; man cannot utter &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;: the eye is not satisfied with seeing, nor the ear filled with hearing.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The thing that hath been, it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is that&lt;/span&gt; which shall be; and that which is done &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; that which shall be done: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no new &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thing&lt;/span&gt; under the sun.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Is there &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; thing whereof it may be said, See, this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; new? it hath been already of old time, which was before us.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;There is&lt;/span&gt; no remembrance of former &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;; neither shall there be &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; remembrance of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; that are to come with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;those&lt;/span&gt; that shall come after.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">I the Preacher was king over Israel in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And I gave my heart to seek and search out by wisdom concerning all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; that are done under heaven: this sore travail hath God given to the sons of man to be exercised therewith.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I have seen all the works that are done under the sun; and, behold, all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vanity and vexation of spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;That which is&lt;/span&gt; crooked cannot be made straight: and that which is wanting cannot be numbered.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I communed with mine own heart, saying, Lo, I am come to great estate, and have gotten more wisdom than all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they&lt;/span&gt; that have been before me in Jerusalem: yea, my heart had great experience of wisdom and knowledge.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And I gave my heart to know wisdom, and to know madness and folly: I perceived that this also is vexation of spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For in much wisdom &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; much grief: and he that increaseth knowledge increaseth sorrow.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>