<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="21" name="Ecclesiastes" bookPage="ecclesiastes.html" title="Ecclesiastes" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon" prevBook="proverbs_1.html" prevTitle="Proverbs">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="20" nextChapter="ecclesiastes_6.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes 6" prevChapter="ecclesiastes_4.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes 4" chapterPage="ecclesiastes_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Keep thy foot when thou goest to the house of God, and be more ready to hear, than to give the sacrifice of fools: for they consider not that they do evil.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Be not rash with thy mouth, and let not thine heart be hasty to utter &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; thing before God: for God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in heaven, and thou upon earth: therefore let thy words be few.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For a dream cometh through the multitude of business; and a fool's voice &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is known&lt;/span&gt; by multitude of words.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">When thou vowest a vow unto God, defer not to pay it; for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he hath&lt;/span&gt; no pleasure in fools: pay that which thou hast vowed.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Better &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt; that thou shouldest not vow, than that thou shouldest vow and not pay.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Suffer not thy mouth to cause thy flesh to sin; neither say thou before the angel, that it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; an error: wherefore should God be angry at thy voice, and destroy the work of thine hands?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For in the multitude of dreams and many words &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there are&lt;/span&gt; also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;divers&lt;/span&gt; vanities: but fear thou God.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">If thou seest the oppression of the poor, and violent perverting of judgment and justice in a province, marvel not at the matter: for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he that is&lt;/span&gt; higher than the highest regardeth; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; higher than they.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Moreover the profit of the earth is for all: the king &lt;span class='extra'&gt;himself&lt;/span&gt; is served by the field.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He that loveth silver shall not be satisfied with silver; nor he that loveth abundance with increase: this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; also vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">When goods increase, they are increased that eat them: and what good &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; to the owners thereof, saving the beholding &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of them&lt;/span&gt; with their eyes?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The sleep of a labouring man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; sweet, whether he eat little or much: but the abundance of the rich will not suffer him to sleep.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">There is a sore evil &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; I have seen under the sun, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;namely&lt;/span&gt;, riches kept for the owners thereof to their hurt.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But those riches perish by evil travail: and he begetteth a son, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; nothing in his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">As he came forth of his mother's womb, naked shall he return to go as he came, and shall take nothing of his labour, which he may carry away in his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And this also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a sore evil, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; in all points as he came, so shall he go: and what profit hath he that hath laboured for the wind?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">All his days also he eateth in darkness, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he hath&lt;/span&gt; much sorrow and wrath with his sickness.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Behold &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which I have seen: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; good and comely &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for one&lt;/span&gt; to eat and to drink, and to enjoy the good of all his labour that he taketh under the sun all the days of his life, which God giveth him: for it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his portion.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Every man also to whom God hath given riches and wealth, and hath given him power to eat thereof, and to take his portion, and to rejoice in his labour; this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the gift of God.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For he shall not much remember the days of his life; because God answereth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; in the joy of his heart.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>