<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="21" name="Ecclesiastes" bookPage="ecclesiastes.html" title="Ecclesiastes" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon" prevBook="proverbs_1.html" prevTitle="Proverbs">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="17" nextChapter="ecclesiastes_9.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes 9" prevChapter="ecclesiastes_7.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes 7" chapterPage="ecclesiastes_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as the wise &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;? and who knoweth the interpretation of a thing? a man's wisdom maketh his face to shine, and the boldness of his face shall be changed.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I &lt;i&gt;counsel thee&lt;/i&gt; to keep the king's commandment, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; in regard of the oath of God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Be not hasty to go out of his sight: stand not in an evil thing; for he doeth whatsoever pleaseth him.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Where the word of a king &lt;i&gt;is, there is&lt;/i&gt; power: and who may say unto him, What doest thou?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Whoso keepeth the commandment shall feel no evil thing: and a wise man's heart discerneth both time and judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Because to every purpose there is time and judgment, therefore the misery of man &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; great upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For he knoweth not that which shall be: for who can tell him when it shall be?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; no man that hath power over the spirit to retain the spirit; neither &lt;i&gt;hath he&lt;/i&gt; power in the day of death: and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no discharge in &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; war; neither shall wickedness deliver those that are given to it.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">All this have I seen, and applied my heart unto every work that is done under the sun: &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; a time wherein one man ruleth over another to his own hurt.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And so I saw the wicked buried, who had come and gone from the place of the holy, and they were forgotten in the city where they had so done: this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; also vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Because sentence against an evil work is not executed speedily, therefore the heart of the sons of men is fully set in them to do evil.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Though a sinner do evil an hundred times, and his &lt;i&gt;days&lt;/i&gt; be prolonged, yet surely I know that it shall be well with them that fear God, which fear before him:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But it shall not be well with the wicked, neither shall he prolong &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; days, &lt;i&gt;which are&lt;/i&gt; as a shadow; because he feareth not before God.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">There is a vanity which is done upon the earth; that there be just &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;, unto whom it happeneth according to the work of the wicked; again, there be wicked &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;, to whom it happeneth according to the work of the righteous: I said that this also &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Then I commended mirth, because a man hath no better thing under the sun, than to eat, and to drink, and to be merry: for that shall abide with him of his labour the days of his life, which God giveth him under the sun.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">When I applied mine heart to know wisdom, and to see the business that is done upon the earth: (for also &lt;i&gt;there is that&lt;/i&gt; neither day nor night seeth sleep with his eyes:)</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then I beheld all the work of God, that a man cannot find out the work that is done under the sun: because though a man labour to seek &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; out, yet he shall not find &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;; yea further; though a wise &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; think to know &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, yet shall he not be able to find &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>