<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="21" name="Ecclesiastes" bookPage="ecclesiastes.html" title="Ecclesiastes" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon" prevBook="proverbs_1.html" prevTitle="Proverbs">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="14" nextChapter="song_of_solomon_1.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon 1" prevChapter="ecclesiastes_11.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes 11" chapterPage="ecclesiastes_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Remember now thy Creator in the days of thy youth, while the evil days come not, nor the years draw nigh, when thou shalt say, I have no pleasure in them;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">While the sun, or the light, or the moon, or the stars, be not darkened, nor the clouds return after the rain:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">In the day when the keepers of the house shall tremble, and the strong men shall bow themselves, and the grinders cease because they are few, and those that look out of the windows be darkened,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the doors shall be shut in the streets, when the sound of the grinding is low, and he shall rise up at the voice of the bird, and all the daughters of musick shall be brought low;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; they shall be afraid of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which is&lt;/span&gt; high, and fears &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; in the way, and the almond tree shall flourish, and the grasshopper shall be a burden, and desire shall fail: because man goeth to his long home, and the mourners go about the streets:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Or ever the silver cord be loosed, or the golden bowl be broken, or the pitcher be broken at the fountain, or the wheel broken at the cistern.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then shall the dust return to the earth as it was: and the spirit shall return unto God who gave it.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Vanity of vanities, saith the preacher; all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And moreover, because the preacher was wise, he still taught the people knowledge; yea, he gave good heed, and sought out, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; set in order many proverbs.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The preacher sought to find out acceptable words: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which was&lt;/span&gt; written &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; upright, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; words of truth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The words of the wise &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; as goads, and as nails fastened &lt;span class='extra'&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; the masters of assemblies, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; are given from one shepherd.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And further, by these, my son, be admonished: of making many books &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no end; and much study &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a weariness of the flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Let us hear the conclusion of the whole matter: Fear God, and keep his commandments: for this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the whole &lt;span class='extra'&gt;duty&lt;/span&gt; of man.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For God shall bring every work into judgment, with every secret thing, whether &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt; good, or whether &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt; evil.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>