<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="21" name="Ecclesiastes" bookPage="ecclesiastes.html" title="Ecclesiastes" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon" prevBook="proverbs_1.html" prevTitle="Proverbs">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="10" nextChapter="ecclesiastes_12.html" nextTitle="Ecclesiastes 12" prevChapter="ecclesiastes_10.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes 10" chapterPage="ecclesiastes_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Cast thy bread upon the waters: for thou shalt find it after many days.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Give a portion to seven, and also to eight; for thou knowest not what evil shall be upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">If the clouds be full of rain, they empty &lt;span class="extra"&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt; upon the earth: and if the tree fall toward the south, or toward the north, in the place where the tree falleth, there it shall be.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He that observeth the wind shall not sow; and he that regardeth the clouds shall not reap.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">As thou knowest not what &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the way of the spirit, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;nor&lt;/span&gt; how the bones &lt;span class="extra"&gt;do grow&lt;/span&gt; in the womb of her that is with child: even so thou knowest not the works of God who maketh all.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">In the morning sow thy seed, and in the evening withhold not thine hand: for thou knowest not whether shall prosper, either this or that, or whether they both &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; alike good.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Truly the light &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; sweet, and a pleasant &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thing it is&lt;/span&gt; for the eyes to behold the sun:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But if a man live many years, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; rejoice in them all; yet let him remember the days of darkness; for they shall be many. All that cometh &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Rejoice, O young man, in thy youth; and let thy heart cheer thee in the days of thy youth, and walk in the ways of thine heart, and in the sight of thine eyes: but know thou, that for all these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; God will bring thee into judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Therefore remove sorrow from thy heart, and put away evil from thy flesh: for childhood and youth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; vanity.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>