<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="22" name="Song of Solomon" bookPage="songofsolomon.html" title="Song of Solomon" chapterCount="8" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="isaiah_1.html" nextTitle="Isaiah" prevBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="16" nextChapter="song_of_solomon_5.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon 5" prevChapter="song_of_solomon_3.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon 3" chapterPage="song_of_solomon_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Behold, thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; fair, my love; behold, thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; fair; thou &lt;i&gt;hast&lt;/i&gt; doves' eyes within thy locks: thy hair &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as a flock of goats, that appear from mount Gilead.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thy teeth &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; like a flock &lt;i&gt;of sheep that are even&lt;/i&gt; shorn, which came up from the washing; whereof every one bear twins, and none &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; barren among them.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thy lips &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; like a thread of scarlet, and thy speech &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; comely: thy temples &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; like a piece of a pomegranate within thy locks.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thy neck &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; like the tower of David builded for an armoury, whereon there hang a thousand bucklers, all shields of mighty men.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thy two breasts &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; like two young roes that are twins, which feed among the lilies.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Until the day break, and the shadows flee away, I will get me to the mountain of myrrh, and to the hill of frankincense.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; all fair, my love; &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no spot in thee.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Come with me from Lebanon, &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; spouse, with me from Lebanon: look from the top of Amana, from the top of Shenir and Hermon, from the lions' dens, from the mountains of the leopards.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thou hast ravished my heart, my sister, &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; spouse; thou hast ravished my heart with one of thine eyes, with one chain of thy neck.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">How fair is thy love, my sister, &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; spouse! how much better is thy love than wine! and the smell of thine ointments than all spices!</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thy lips, O &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; spouse, drop &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; the honeycomb: honey and milk &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; under thy tongue; and the smell of thy garments &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; like the smell of Lebanon.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">A garden inclosed &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my sister, &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; spouse; a spring shut up, a fountain sealed.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thy plants &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; an orchard of pomegranates, with pleasant fruits; camphire, with spikenard,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Spikenard and saffron; calamus and cinnamon, with all trees of frankincense; myrrh and aloes, with all the chief spices:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">A fountain of gardens, a well of living waters, and streams from Lebanon.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Awake, O north wind; and come, thou south; blow upon my garden, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the spices thereof may flow out. Let my beloved come into his garden, and eat his pleasant fruits.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>