<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="22" name="Song of Solomon" bookPage="songofsolomon.html" title="Song of Solomon" chapterCount="8" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="isaiah_1.html" nextTitle="Isaiah" prevBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="13" nextChapter="song_of_solomon_7.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon 7" prevChapter="song_of_solomon_5.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon 5" chapterPage="song_of_solomon_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Whither is thy beloved gone, O thou fairest among women? whither is thy beloved turned aside? that we may seek him with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">My beloved is gone down into his garden, to the beds of spices, to feed in the gardens, and to gather lilies.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; my beloved's, and my beloved &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; mine: he feedeth among the lilies.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; beautiful, O my love, as Tirzah, comely as Jerusalem, terrible as &lt;i&gt;an army&lt;/i&gt; with banners.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Turn away thine eyes from me, for they have overcome me: thy hair &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as a flock of goats that appear from Gilead.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thy teeth &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; as a flock of sheep which go up from the washing, whereof every one beareth twins, and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; not one barren among them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">As a piece of a pomegranate &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; thy temples within thy locks.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">There are threescore queens, and fourscore concubines, and virgins without number.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">My dove, my undefiled is &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; one; she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; one of her mother, she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the choice &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; of her that bare her. The daughters saw her, and blessed her; &lt;i&gt;yea&lt;/i&gt;, the queens and the concubines, and they praised her.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; she &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; looketh forth as the morning, fair as the moon, clear as the sun, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; terrible as &lt;i&gt;an army&lt;/i&gt; with banners?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">I went down into the garden of nuts to see the fruits of the valley, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; to see whether the vine flourished, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the pomegranates budded.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Or ever I was aware, my soul made me &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; the chariots of Ammi-nadib.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Return, return, O Shulamite; return, return, that we may look upon thee. What will ye see in the Shulamite? As it were the company of two armies.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>