<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="22" name="Song of Solomon" bookPage="songofsolomon.html" title="Song of Solomon" chapterCount="8" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="isaiah_1.html" nextTitle="Isaiah" prevBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="16" nextChapter="song_of_solomon_6.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon 6" prevChapter="song_of_solomon_4.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon 4" chapterPage="song_of_solomon_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I am come into my garden, my sister, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; spouse: I have gathered my myrrh with my spice; I have eaten my honeycomb with my honey; I have drunk my wine with my milk: eat, O friends; drink, yea, drink abundantly, O beloved.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">I sleep, but my heart waketh: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; the voice of my beloved that knocketh, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Open to me, my sister, my love, my dove, my undefiled: for my head is filled with dew, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; my locks with the drops of the night.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I have put off my coat; how shall I put it on? I have washed my feet; how shall I defile them?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">My beloved put in his hand by the hole &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of the door&lt;/span&gt;, and my bowels were moved for him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I rose up to open to my beloved; and my hands dropped &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; myrrh, and my fingers &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; sweet smelling myrrh, upon the handles of the lock.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I opened to my beloved; but my beloved had withdrawn himself, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; was gone: my soul failed when he spake: I sought him, but I could not find him; I called him, but he gave me no answer.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The watchmen that went about the city found me, they smote me, they wounded me; the keepers of the walls took away my veil from me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I charge you, O daughters of Jerusalem, if ye find my beloved, that ye tell him, that I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; sick of love.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">What &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy beloved more than &lt;span class="extra"&gt;another&lt;/span&gt; beloved, O thou fairest among women? what &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy beloved more than &lt;span class="extra"&gt;another&lt;/span&gt; beloved, that thou dost so charge us?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">My beloved &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; white and ruddy, the chiefest among ten thousand.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">His head &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is as&lt;/span&gt; the most fine gold, his locks &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; bushy, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; black as a raven.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">His eyes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the eyes&lt;/span&gt; of doves by the rivers of waters, washed with milk, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; fitly set.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">His cheeks &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; as a bed of spices, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; sweet flowers: his lips &lt;span class="extra"&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; lilies, dropping sweet smelling myrrh.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">His hands &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are as&lt;/span&gt; gold rings set with the beryl: his belly &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is as&lt;/span&gt; bright ivory overlaid &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; sapphires.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">His legs &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are as&lt;/span&gt; pillars of marble, set upon sockets of fine gold: his countenance &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; as Lebanon, excellent as the cedars.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">His mouth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; most sweet: yea, he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; altogether lovely. This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my beloved, and this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my friend, O daughters of Jerusalem.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>