<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="22" name="Song of Solomon" bookPage="songofsolomon.html" title="Song of Solomon" chapterCount="8" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="isaiah_1.html" nextTitle="Isaiah" prevBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="13" nextChapter="song_of_solomon_8.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon 8" prevChapter="song_of_solomon_6.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon 6" chapterPage="song_of_solomon_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">How beautiful are thy feet with shoes, O prince's daughter! the joints of thy thighs &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; like jewels, the work of the hands of a cunning workman.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thy navel &lt;i&gt;is like&lt;/i&gt; a round goblet, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; wanteth not liquor: thy belly &lt;i&gt;is like&lt;/i&gt; an heap of wheat set about with lilies.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thy two breasts &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; like two young roes &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; twins.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thy neck &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as a tower of ivory; thine eyes &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; the fishpools in Heshbon, by the gate of Bath-rabbim: thy nose &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as the tower of Lebanon which looketh toward Damascus.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thine head upon thee &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; like Carmel, and the hair of thine head like purple; the king &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; held in the galleries.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">How fair and how pleasant art thou, O love, for delights!</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">This thy stature is like to a palm tree, and thy breasts to clusters &lt;i&gt;of grapes&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I said, I will go up to the palm tree, I will take hold of the boughs thereof: now also thy breasts shall be as clusters of the vine, and the smell of thy nose like apples;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the roof of thy mouth like the best wine for my beloved, that goeth &lt;i&gt;down&lt;/i&gt; sweetly, causing the lips of those that are asleep to speak.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; my beloved's, and his desire &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; toward me.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Come, my beloved, let us go forth into the field; let us lodge in the villages.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Let us get up early to the vineyards; let us see if the vine flourish, &lt;i&gt;whether&lt;/i&gt; the tender grape appear, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the pomegranates bud forth: there will I give thee my loves.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The mandrakes give a smell, and at our gates &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; all manner of pleasant &lt;i&gt;fruits&lt;/i&gt;, new and old, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; I have laid up for thee, O my beloved.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>