<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="22" name="Song of Solomon" bookPage="songofsolomon.html" title="Song of Solomon" chapterCount="8" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="isaiah_1.html" nextTitle="Isaiah" prevBook="ecclesiastes_1.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="17" nextChapter="song_of_solomon_2.html" nextTitle="Song of Solomon 2" prevChapter="ecclesiastes_12.html" prevTitle="Ecclesiastes 12" chapterPage="song_of_solomon_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The song of songs, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Solomon's.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Let him kiss me with the kisses of his mouth: for thy love &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; better than wine.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Because of the savour of thy good ointments thy name &lt;i&gt;is as&lt;/i&gt; ointment poured forth, therefore do the virgins love thee.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Draw me, we will run after thee: the king hath brought me into his chambers: we will be glad and rejoice in thee, we will remember thy love more than wine: the upright love thee.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; black, but comely, O ye daughters of Jerusalem, as the tents of Kedar, as the curtains of Solomon.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Look not upon me, because I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; black, because the sun hath looked upon me: my mother's children were angry with me; they made me the keeper of the vineyards; &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; mine own vineyard have I not kept.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Tell me, O thou whom my soul loveth, where thou feedest, where thou makest &lt;i&gt;thy flock&lt;/i&gt; to rest at noon: for why should I be as one that turneth aside by the flocks of thy companions?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">If thou know not, O thou fairest among women, go thy way forth by the footsteps of the flock, and feed thy kids beside the shepherds' tents.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I have compared thee, O my love, to a company of horses in Pharaoh's chariots.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thy cheeks are comely with rows &lt;i&gt;of jewels&lt;/i&gt;, thy neck with chains &lt;i&gt;of gold&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">We will make thee borders of gold with studs of silver.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">While the king &lt;i&gt;sitteth&lt;/i&gt; at his table, my spikenard sendeth forth the smell thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">A bundle of myrrh &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my wellbeloved unto me; he shall lie all night betwixt my breasts.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">My beloved &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; unto me &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; a cluster of camphire in the vineyards of En-gedi.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Behold, thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; fair, my love; behold, thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; fair; thou &lt;i&gt;hast&lt;/i&gt; doves' eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Behold, thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; fair, my beloved, yea, pleasant: also our bed &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; green.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The beams of our house &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; cedar, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; our rafters of fir.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>