<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="45" verseCount="25" nextChapter="isaiah_46.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 46" prevChapter="isaiah_44.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 44" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to his anointed, to Cyrus, whose right hand I have holden, to subdue nations before him; and I will loose the loins of kings, to open before him the two leaved gates; and the gates shall not be shut;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I will go before thee, and make the crooked places straight: I will break in pieces the gates of brass, and cut in sunder the bars of iron:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I will give thee the treasures of darkness, and hidden riches of secret places, that thou mayest know that I, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which call &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt; by thy name, &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For Jacob my servant's sake, and Israel mine elect, I have even called thee by thy name: I have surnamed thee, though thou hast not known me.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none else, &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no God beside me: I girded thee, though thou hast not known me:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">That they may know from the rising of the sun, and from the west, that &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none beside me. I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none else.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">I form the light, and create darkness: I make peace, and create evil: I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; do all these &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Drop down, ye heavens, from above, and let the skies pour down righteousness: let the earth open, and let them bring forth salvation, and let righteousness spring up together; I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have created it.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Woe unto him that striveth with his Maker! &lt;i&gt;Let&lt;/i&gt; the potsherd &lt;i&gt;strive&lt;/i&gt; with the potsherds of the earth. Shall the clay say to him that fashioneth it, What makest thou? or thy work, He hath no hands?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Woe unto him that saith unto &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; father, What begettest thou? or to the woman, What hast thou brought forth?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the Holy One of Israel, and his Maker, Ask me of things to come concerning my sons, and concerning the work of my hands command ye me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I have made the earth, and created man upon it: I, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; my hands, have stretched out the heavens, and all their host have I commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">I have raised him up in righteousness, and I will direct all his ways: he shall build my city, and he shall let go my captives, not for price nor reward, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, The labour of Egypt, and merchandise of Ethiopia and of the Sabeans, men of stature, shall come over unto thee, and they shall be thine: they shall come after thee; in chains they shall come over, and they shall fall down unto thee, they shall make supplication unto thee, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;, Surely God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in thee; and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none else, &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no God.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Verily thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; a God that hidest thyself, O God of Israel, the Saviour.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">They shall be ashamed, and also confounded, all of them: they shall go to confusion together &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; makers of idols.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;i&gt;But&lt;/i&gt; Israel shall be saved in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; with an everlasting salvation: ye shall not be ashamed nor confounded world without end.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that created the heavens; God himself that formed the earth and made it; he hath established it, he created it not in vain, he formed it to be inhabited: I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none else.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">I have not spoken in secret, in a dark place of the earth: I said not unto the seed of Jacob, Seek ye me in vain: I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; speak righteousness, I declare things that are right.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">Assemble yourselves and come; draw near together, ye &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; escaped of the nations: they have no knowledge that set up the wood of their graven image, and pray unto a god &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; cannot save.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Tell ye, and bring &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; near; yea, let them take counsel together: who hath declared this from ancient time? &lt;i&gt;who&lt;/i&gt; hath told it from that time? &lt;i&gt;have&lt;/i&gt; not I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no God else beside me; a just God and a Saviour; &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none beside me.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Look unto me, and be ye saved, all the ends of the earth: for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; God, and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none else.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">I have sworn by myself, the word is gone out of my mouth &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; righteousness, and shall not return, That unto me every knee shall bow, every tongue shall swear.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Surely, shall &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; say, in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have I righteousness and strength: &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to him shall &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; come; and all that are incensed against him shall be ashamed.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">In the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall all the seed of Israel be justified, and shall glory.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>