<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="37" verseCount="38" nextChapter="isaiah_38.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 38" prevChapter="isaiah_36.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 36" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, when king Hezekiah heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, that he rent his clothes, and covered himself with sackcloth, and went into the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he sent Eliakim, who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; over the household, and Shebna the scribe, and the elders of the priests covered with sackcloth, unto Isaiah the prophet the son of Amoz.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they said unto him, Thus saith Hezekiah, This day &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a day of trouble, and of rebuke, and of blasphemy: for the children are come to the birth, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; not strength to bring forth.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">It may be the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God will hear the words of Rab-shakeh, whom the king of Assyria his master hath sent to reproach the living God, and will reprove the words which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God hath heard: wherefore lift up &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; prayer for the remnant that is left.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">So the servants of king Hezekiah came to Isaiah.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And Isaiah said unto them, Thus shall ye say unto your master, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Be not afraid of the words that thou hast heard, wherewith the servants of the king of Assyria have blasphemed me.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Behold, I will send a blast upon him, and he shall hear a rumour, and return to his own land; and I will cause him to fall by the sword in his own land.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">So Rab-shakeh returned, and found the king of Assyria warring against Libnah: for he had heard that he was departed from Lachish.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he heard say concerning Tirhakah king of Ethiopia, He is come forth to make war with thee. And when he heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, he sent messengers to Hezekiah, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thus shall ye speak to Hezekiah king of Judah, saying, Let not thy God, in whom thou trustest, deceive thee, saying, Jerusalem shall not be given into the hand of the king of Assyria.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Behold, thou hast heard what the kings of Assyria have done to all lands by destroying them utterly; and shalt thou be delivered?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Have the gods of the nations delivered them which my fathers have destroyed, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; Gozan, and Haran, and Rezeph, and the children of Eden which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in Telassar?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the king of Hamath, and the king of Arphad, and the king of the city of Sepharvaim, Hena, and Ivah?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And Hezekiah received the letter from the hand of the messengers, and read it: and Hezekiah went up unto the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and spread it before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Hezekiah prayed unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, God of Israel, that dwellest &lt;span class="extra"&gt;between&lt;/span&gt; the cherubims, thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; the God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; thou alone, of all the kingdoms of the earth: thou hast made heaven and earth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Incline thine ear, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and hear; open thine eyes, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and see: and hear all the words of Sennacherib, which hath sent to reproach the living God.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Of a truth, &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the kings of Assyria have laid waste all the nations, and their countries,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And have cast their gods into the fire: for they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; no gods, but the work of men's hands, wood and stone: therefore they have destroyed them.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Now therefore, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, save us from his hand, that all the kingdoms of the earth may know that thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; thou only.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Then Isaiah the son of Amoz sent unto Hezekiah, saying, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, Whereas thou hast prayed to me against Sennacherib king of Assyria:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the word which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken concerning him; The virgin, the daughter of Zion, hath despised thee, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; laughed thee to scorn; the daughter of Jerusalem hath shaken her head at thee.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Whom hast thou reproached and blasphemed? and against whom hast thou exalted &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; voice, and lifted up thine eyes on high? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; against the Holy One of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">By thy servants hast thou reproached the Lord, and hast said, By the multitude of my chariots am I come up to the height of the mountains, to the sides of Lebanon; and I will cut down the tall cedars thereof, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the choice fir trees thereof: and I will enter into the height of his border, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the forest of his Carmel.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">I have digged, and drunk water; and with the sole of my feet have I dried up all the rivers of the besieged places.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Hast thou not heard long ago, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;how&lt;/span&gt; I have done it; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; of ancient times, that I have formed it? now have I brought it to pass, that thou shouldest be to lay waste defenced cities &lt;span class="extra"&gt;into&lt;/span&gt; ruinous heaps.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Therefore their inhabitants &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; of small power, they were dismayed and confounded: they were &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the grass of the field, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the green herb, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the grass on the housetops, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as corn&lt;/span&gt; blasted before it be grown up.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">But I know thy abode, and thy going out, and thy coming in, and thy rage against me.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Because thy rage against me, and thy tumult, is come up into mine ears, therefore will I put my hook in thy nose, and my bridle in thy lips, and I will turn thee back by the way by which thou camest.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a sign unto thee, Ye shall eat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; year such as groweth of itself; and the second year that which springeth of the same: and in the third year sow ye, and reap, and plant vineyards, and eat the fruit thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And the remnant that is escaped of the house of Judah shall again take root downward, and bear fruit upward:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">For out of Jerusalem shall go forth a remnant, and they that escape out of mount Zion: the zeal of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts shall do this.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; concerning the king of Assyria, He shall not come into this city, nor shoot an arrow there, nor come before it with shields, nor cast a bank against it.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">By the way that he came, by the same shall he return, and shall not come into this city, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">For I will defend this city to save it for mine own sake, and for my servant David's sake.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Then the angel of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; went forth, and smote in the camp of the Assyrians a hundred and fourscore and five thousand: and when they arose early in the morning, behold, they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; all dead corpses.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37" newPara="true">So Sennacherib king of Assyria departed, and went and returned, and dwelt at Nineveh.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And it came to pass, as he was worshipping in the house of Nisroch his god, that Adrammelech and Sharezer his sons smote him with the sword; and they escaped into the land of Armenia: and Esarhaddon his son reigned in his stead.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>