<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="40" verseCount="31" nextChapter="isaiah_41.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 41" prevChapter="isaiah_39.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 39" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Comfort ye, comfort ye my people, saith your God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speak ye comfortably to Jerusalem, and cry unto her, that her warfare is accomplished, that her iniquity is pardoned: for she hath received of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s hand double for all her sins.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">The voice of him that crieth in the wilderness, Prepare ye the way of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, make straight in the desert a highway for our God.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Every valley shall be exalted, and every mountain and hill shall be made low: and the crooked shall be made straight, and the rough places plain:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the glory of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be revealed, and all flesh shall see &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; together: for the mouth of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The voice said, Cry. And he said, What shall I cry? All flesh &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; grass, and all the goodliness thereof &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as the flower of the field:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The grass withereth, the flower fadeth: because the spirit of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; bloweth upon it: surely the people &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; grass.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The grass withereth, the flower fadeth: but the word of our God shall stand for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">O Zion, that bringest good tidings, get thee up into the high mountain; O Jerusalem, that bringest good tidings, lift up thy voice with strength; lift &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; up, be not afraid; say unto the cities of Judah, Behold your God!</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Behold, the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; will come with strong &lt;i&gt;hand&lt;/i&gt;, and his arm shall rule for him: behold, his reward &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with him, and his work before him.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He shall feed his flock like a shepherd: he shall gather the lambs with his arm, and carry &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in his bosom, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; shall gently lead those that are with young.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Who hath measured the waters in the hollow of his hand, and meted out heaven with the span, and comprehended the dust of the earth in a measure, and weighed the mountains in scales, and the hills in a balance?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Who hath directed the Spirit of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, or &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; his counsellor hath taught him?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">With whom took he counsel, and &lt;i&gt;who&lt;/i&gt; instructed him, and taught him in the path of judgment, and taught him knowledge, and shewed to him the way of understanding?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Behold, the nations &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; as a drop of a bucket, and are counted as the small dust of the balance: behold, he taketh up the isles as a very little thing.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Lebanon &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not sufficient to burn, nor the beasts thereof sufficient for a burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">All nations before him &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; as nothing; and they are counted to him less than nothing, and vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">To whom then will ye liken God? or what likeness will ye compare unto him?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The workman melteth a graven image, and the goldsmith spreadeth it over with gold, and casteth silver chains.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; so impoverished that he hath no oblation chooseth a tree &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; will not rot; he seeketh unto him a cunning workman to prepare a graven image, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; shall not be moved.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Have ye not known? have ye not heard? hath it not been told you from the beginning? have ye not understood from the foundations of the earth?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; he that sitteth upon the circle of the earth, and the inhabitants thereof &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; as grasshoppers; that stretcheth out the heavens as a curtain, and spreadeth them out as a tent to dwell in:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">That bringeth the princes to nothing; he maketh the judges of the earth as vanity.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Yea, they shall not be planted; yea, they shall not be sown: yea, their stock shall not take root in the earth: and he shall also blow upon them, and they shall wither, and the whirlwind shall take them away as stubble.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">To whom then will ye liken me, or shall I be equal? saith the Holy One.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Lift up your eyes on high, and behold who hath created these &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt;, that bringeth out their host by number: he calleth them all by names by the greatness of his might, for that &lt;i&gt;he is&lt;/i&gt; strong in power; not one faileth.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Why sayest thou, O Jacob, and speakest, O Israel, My way is hid from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and my judgment is passed over from my God?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">Hast thou not known? hast thou not heard, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the everlasting God, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the Creator of the ends of the earth, fainteth not, neither is weary? &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no searching of his understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">He giveth power to the faint; and to &lt;i&gt;them that have&lt;/i&gt; no might he increaseth strength.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Even the youths shall faint and be weary, and the young men shall utterly fall:</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">But they that wait upon the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall renew &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; strength; they shall mount up with wings as eagles; they shall run, and not be weary; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; they shall walk, and not faint.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>