<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="22" nextChapter="isaiah_3.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 3" prevChapter="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 1" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word that Isaiah the son of Amoz saw concerning Judah and Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And it shall come to pass in the last days, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the mountain of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s house shall be established in the top of the mountains, and shall be exalted above the hills; and all nations shall flow unto it.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And many people shall go and say, Come ye, and let us go up to the mountain of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to the house of the God of Jacob; and he will teach us of his ways, and we will walk in his paths: for out of Zion shall go forth the law, and the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; from Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he shall judge among the nations, and shall rebuke many people: and they shall beat their swords into plowshares, and their spears into pruninghooks: nation shall not lift up sword against nation, neither shall they learn war any more.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">O house of Jacob, come ye, and let us walk in the light of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Therefore thou hast forsaken thy people the house of Jacob, because they be replenished from the east, and &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; soothsayers like the Philistines, and they please themselves in the children of strangers.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Their land also is full of silver and gold, neither &lt;i&gt;is there any&lt;/i&gt; end of their treasures; their land is also full of horses, neither &lt;i&gt;is there any&lt;/i&gt; end of their chariots:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Their land also is full of idols; they worship the work of their own hands, that which their own fingers have made:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the mean man boweth down, and the great man humbleth himself: therefore forgive them not.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Enter into the rock, and hide thee in the dust, for fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and for the glory of his majesty.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The lofty looks of man shall be humbled, and the haughtiness of men shall be bowed down, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; alone shall be exalted in that day.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For the day of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; upon every &lt;i&gt;one that is&lt;/i&gt; proud and lofty, and upon every &lt;i&gt;one that is&lt;/i&gt; lifted up; and he shall be brought low:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And upon all the cedars of Lebanon, &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; high and lifted up, and upon all the oaks of Bashan,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And upon all the high mountains, and upon all the hills &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; lifted up,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And upon every high tower, and upon every fenced wall,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And upon all the ships of Tarshish, and upon all pleasant pictures.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the loftiness of man shall be bowed down, and the haughtiness of men shall be made low: and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; alone shall be exalted in that day.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the idols he shall utterly abolish.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And they shall go into the holes of the rocks, and into the caves of the earth, for fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and for the glory of his majesty, when he ariseth to shake terribly the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">In that day a man shall cast his idols of silver, and his idols of gold, which they made &lt;i&gt;each one&lt;/i&gt; for himself to worship, to the moles and to the bats;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">To go into the clefts of the rocks, and into the tops of the ragged rocks, for fear of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and for the glory of his majesty, when he ariseth to shake terribly the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Cease ye from man, whose breath &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in his nostrils: for wherein is he to be accounted of?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>