<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="38" verseCount="22" nextChapter="isaiah_39.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 39" prevChapter="isaiah_37.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 37" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In those days was Hezekiah sick unto death. And Isaiah the prophet the son of Amoz came unto him, and said unto him, Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Set thine house in order: for thou shalt die, and not live.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then Hezekiah turned his face toward the wall, and prayed unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And said, Remember now, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I beseech thee, how I have walked before thee in truth and with a perfect heart, and have done &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which is&lt;/span&gt; good in thy sight. And Hezekiah wept sore.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Then came the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to Isaiah, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Go, and say to Hezekiah, Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the God of David thy father, I have heard thy prayer, I have seen thy tears: behold, I will add unto thy days fifteen years.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I will deliver thee and this city out of the hand of the king of Assyria: and I will defend this city.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a sign unto thee from the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will do this thing that he hath spoken;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Behold, I will bring again the shadow of the degrees, which is gone down in the sun dial of Ahaz, ten degrees backward. So the sun returned ten degrees, by which degrees it was gone down.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">The writing of Hezekiah king of Judah, when he had been sick, and was recovered of his sickness:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I said in the cutting off of my days, I shall go to the gates of the grave: I am deprived of the residue of my years.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">I said, I shall not see the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in the land of the living: I shall behold man no more with the inhabitants of the world.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Mine age is departed, and is removed from me as a shepherd's tent: I have cut off like a weaver my life: he will cut me off with pining sickness: from day &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to night wilt thou make an end of me.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">I reckoned till morning, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt;, as a lion, so will he break all my bones: from day &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to night wilt thou make an end of me.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Like a crane &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; a swallow, so did I chatter: I did mourn as a dove: mine eyes fail &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with looking&lt;/span&gt; upward: O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I am oppressed; undertake for me.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">What shall I say? he hath both spoken unto me, and himself hath done &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;: I shall go softly all my years in the bitterness of my soul.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">O Lord, by these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things men&lt;/span&gt; live, and in all these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things is&lt;/span&gt; the life of my spirit: so wilt thou recover me, and make me to live.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Behold, for peace I had great bitterness: but thou hast in love to my soul &lt;span class='extra'&gt;delivered it&lt;/span&gt; from the pit of corruption: for thou hast cast all my sins behind thy back.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For the grave cannot praise thee, death can &lt;span class='extra'&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; celebrate thee: they that go down into the pit cannot hope for thy truth.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The living, the living, he shall praise thee, as I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; this day: the father to the children shall make known thy truth.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was ready&lt;/span&gt; to save me: therefore we will sing my songs to the stringed instruments all the days of our life in the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For Isaiah had said, Let them take a lump of figs, and lay &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; for a plaister upon the boil, and he shall recover.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Hezekiah also had said, What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the sign that I shall go up to the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>