<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="21" nextChapter="isaiah_10.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 10" prevChapter="isaiah_8.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 8" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Nevertheless the dimness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; such as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; in her vexation, when at the first he lightly afflicted the land of Zebulun and the land of Naphtali, and afterward did more grievously afflict &lt;span class='extra'&gt;her by&lt;/span&gt; the way of the sea, beyond Jordan, in Galilee of the nations.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The people that walked in darkness have seen a great light: they that dwell in the land of the shadow of death, upon them hath the light shined.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou hast multiplied the nation, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; not increased the joy: they joy before thee according to the joy in harvest, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; rejoice when they divide the spoil.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For thou hast broken the yoke of his burden, and the staff of his shoulder, the rod of his oppressor, as in the day of Midian.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For every battle of the warrior &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with confused noise, and garments rolled in blood; but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; shall be with burning &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; fuel of fire.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For unto us a child is born, unto us a son is given: and the government shall be upon his shoulder: and his name shall be called Wonderful, Counsellor, The mighty God, The everlasting Father, The Prince of Peace.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Of the increase of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; government and peace &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; no end, upon the throne of David, and upon his kingdom, to order it, and to establish it with judgment and with justice from henceforth even for ever. The zeal of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts will perform this.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">The Lord sent a word into Jacob, and it hath lighted upon Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And all the people shall know, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; Ephraim and the inhabitant of Samaria, that say in the pride and stoutness of heart,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The bricks are fallen down, but we will build with hewn stones: the sycomores are cut down, but we will change &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them into&lt;/span&gt; cedars.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Therefore the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall set up the adversaries of Rezin against him, and join his enemies together;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The Syrians before, and the Philistines behind; and they shall devour Israel with open mouth. For all this his anger is not turned away, but his hand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; stretched out still.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">For the people turneth not unto him that smiteth them, neither do they seek the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Therefore the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will cut off from Israel head and tail, branch and rush, in one day.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The ancient and honourable, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the head; and the prophet that teacheth lies, he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the tail.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For the leaders of this people cause &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; to err; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they that are&lt;/span&gt; led of them &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Therefore the Lord shall have no joy in their young men, neither shall have mercy on their fatherless and widows: for every one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an hypocrite and an evildoer, and every mouth speaketh folly. For all this his anger is not turned away, but his hand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; stretched out still.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">For wickedness burneth as the fire: it shall devour the briers and thorns, and shall kindle in the thickets of the forest, and they shall mount up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; the lifting up of smoke.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Through the wrath of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts is the land darkened, and the people shall be as the fuel of the fire: no man shall spare his brother.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And he shall snatch on the right hand, and be hungry; and he shall eat on the left hand, and they shall not be satisfied: they shall eat every man the flesh of his own arm:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Manasseh, Ephraim; and Ephraim, Manasseh: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; they together &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; against Judah. For all this his anger is not turned away, but his hand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; stretched out still.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>