<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="25" verseCount="12" nextChapter="isaiah_26.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 26" prevChapter="isaiah_24.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 24" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; my God; I will exalt thee, I will praise thy name; for thou hast done wonderful &lt;i&gt;things; thy&lt;/i&gt; counsels of old &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; faithfulness &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; truth.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For thou hast made of a city an heap; &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; a defenced city a ruin: a palace of strangers to be no city; it shall never be built.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Therefore shall the strong people glorify thee, the city of the terrible nations shall fear thee.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For thou hast been a strength to the poor, a strength to the needy in his distress, a refuge from the storm, a shadow from the heat, when the blast of the terrible ones &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as a storm &lt;i&gt;against&lt;/i&gt; the wall.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thou shalt bring down the noise of strangers, as the heat in a dry place; &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the heat with the shadow of a cloud: the branch of the terrible ones shall be brought low.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And in this mountain shall the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts make unto all people a feast of fat things, a feast of wines on the lees, of fat things full of marrow, of wines on the lees well refined.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he will destroy in this mountain the face of the covering cast over all people, and the vail that is spread over all nations.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He will swallow up death in victory; and the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; will wipe away tears from off all faces; and the rebuke of his people shall he take away from off all the earth: for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And it shall be said in that day, Lo, this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; our God; we have waited for him, and he will save us: this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; we have waited for him, we will be glad and rejoice in his salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For in this mountain shall the hand of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; rest, and Moab shall be trodden down under him, even as straw is trodden down for the dunghill.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he shall spread forth his hands in the midst of them, as he that swimmeth spreadeth forth &lt;i&gt;his hands&lt;/i&gt; to swim: and he shall bring down their pride together with the spoils of their hands.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the fortress of the high fort of thy walls shall he bring down, lay low, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; bring to the ground, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to the dust.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>