<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="25" nextChapter="isaiah_23.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 23" prevChapter="isaiah_21.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 21" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The burden of the valley of vision. What aileth thee now, that thou art wholly gone up to the housetops?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thou that art full of stirs, a tumultuous city, a joyous city: thy slain &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men are&lt;/span&gt; not slain with the sword, nor dead in battle.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">All thy rulers are fled together, they are bound by the archers: all that are found in thee are bound together, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; have fled from far.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Therefore said I, Look away from me; I will weep bitterly, labour not to comfort me, because of the spoiling of the daughter of my people.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; a day of trouble, and of treading down, and of perplexity by the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts in the valley of vision, breaking down the walls, and of crying to the mountains.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Elam bare the quiver with chariots of men &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; horsemen, and Kir uncovered the shield.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And it shall come to pass, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thy choicest valleys shall be full of chariots, and the horsemen shall set themselves in array at the gate.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And he discovered the covering of Judah, and thou didst look in that day to the armour of the house of the forest.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Ye have seen also the breaches of the city of David, that they are many: and ye gathered together the waters of the lower pool.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And ye have numbered the houses of Jerusalem, and the houses have ye broken down to fortify the wall.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Ye made also a ditch between the two walls for the water of the old pool: but ye have not looked unto the maker thereof, neither had respect unto him that fashioned it long ago.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And in that day did the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts call to weeping, and to mourning, and to baldness, and to girding with sackcloth:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And behold joy and gladness, slaying oxen, and killing sheep, eating flesh, and drinking wine: let us eat and drink; for to morrow we shall die.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And it was revealed in mine ears by the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, Surely this iniquity shall not be purged from you till ye die, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, Go, get thee unto this treasurer, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto Shebna, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; over the house, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and say&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">What hast thou here? and whom hast thou here, that thou hast hewed thee out a sepulchre here, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; he that heweth him out a sepulchre on high, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; that graveth an habitation for himself in a rock?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Behold, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will carry thee away with a mighty captivity, and will surely cover thee.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He will surely violently turn and toss thee &lt;span class='extra'&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; a ball into a large country: there shalt thou die, and there the chariots of thy glory &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the shame of thy lord's house.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And I will drive thee from thy station, and from thy state shall he pull thee down.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And it shall come to pass in that day, that I will call my servant Eliakim the son of Hilkiah:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And I will clothe him with thy robe, and strengthen him with thy girdle, and I will commit thy government into his hand: and he shall be a father to the inhabitants of Jerusalem, and to the house of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the key of the house of David will I lay upon his shoulder; so he shall open, and none shall shut; and he shall shut, and none shall open.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And I will fasten him &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; a nail in a sure place; and he shall be for a glorious throne to his father's house.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they shall hang upon him all the glory of his father's house, the offspring and the issue, all vessels of small quantity, from the vessels of cups, even to all the vessels of flagons.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">In that day, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, shall the nail that is fastened in the sure place be removed, and be cut down, and fall; and the burden that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; upon it shall be cut off: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>