<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="32" verseCount="20" nextChapter="isaiah_33.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 33" prevChapter="isaiah_31.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 31" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Behold, a king shall reign in righteousness, and princes shall rule in judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And a man shall be as an hiding place from the wind, and a covert from the tempest; as rivers of water in a dry place, as the shadow of a great rock in a weary land.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the eyes of them that see shall not be dim, and the ears of them that hear shall hearken.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The heart also of the rash shall understand knowledge, and the tongue of the stammerers shall be ready to speak plainly.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The vile person shall be no more called liberal, nor the churl said &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; bountiful.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For the vile person will speak villany, and his heart will work iniquity, to practise hypocrisy, and to utter error against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to make empty the soul of the hungry, and he will cause the drink of the thirsty to fail.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The instruments also of the churl &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; evil: he deviseth wicked devices to destroy the poor with lying words, even when the needy speaketh right.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But the liberal deviseth liberal things; and by liberal things shall he stand.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Rise up, ye women that are at ease; hear my voice, ye careless daughters; give ear unto my speech.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Many days and years shall ye be troubled, ye careless women: for the vintage shall fail, the gathering shall not come.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Tremble, ye women that are at ease; be troubled, ye careless ones: strip you, and make you bare, and gird &lt;span class='extra'&gt;sackcloth&lt;/span&gt; upon &lt;span class='extra'&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; loins.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They shall lament for the teats, for the pleasant fields, for the fruitful vine.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Upon the land of my people shall come up thorns &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; briers; yea, upon all the houses of joy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the joyous city:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Because the palaces shall be forsaken; the multitude of the city shall be left; the forts and towers shall be for dens for ever, a joy of wild asses, a pasture of flocks;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Until the spirit be poured upon us from on high, and the wilderness be a fruitful field, and the fruitful field be counted for a forest.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Then judgment shall dwell in the wilderness, and righteousness remain in the fruitful field.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the work of righteousness shall be peace; and the effect of righteousness quietness and assurance for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And my people shall dwell in a peaceable habitation, and in sure dwellings, and in quiet resting places;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">When it shall hail, coming down on the forest; and the city shall be low in a low place.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; ye that sow beside all waters, that send forth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thither&lt;/span&gt; the feet of the ox and the ass.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>