<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="19" verseCount="25" nextChapter="isaiah_20.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 20" prevChapter="isaiah_18.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 18" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The burden of Egypt. Behold, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; rideth upon a swift cloud, and shall come into Egypt: and the idols of Egypt shall be moved at his presence, and the heart of Egypt shall melt in the midst of it.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And I will set the Egyptians against the Egyptians: and they shall fight every one against his brother, and every one against his neighbour; city against city, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; kingdom against kingdom.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the spirit of Egypt shall fail in the midst thereof; and I will destroy the counsel thereof: and they shall seek to the idols, and to the charmers, and to them that have familiar spirits, and to the wizards.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the Egyptians will I give over into the hand of a cruel lord; and a fierce king shall rule over them, saith the Lord, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the waters shall fail from the sea, and the river shall be wasted and dried up.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And they shall turn the rivers far away; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the brooks of defence shall be emptied and dried up: the reeds and flags shall wither.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The paper reeds by the brooks, by the mouth of the brooks, and every thing sown by the brooks, shall wither, be driven away, and be no &lt;span class='extra'&gt;more&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The fishers also shall mourn, and all they that cast angle into the brooks shall lament, and they that spread nets upon the waters shall languish.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Moreover they that work in fine flax, and they that weave networks, shall be confounded.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they shall be broken in the purposes thereof, all that make sluices &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; ponds for fish.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Surely the princes of Zoan &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; fools, the counsel of the wise counsellors of Pharaoh is become brutish: how say ye unto Pharaoh, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the son of the wise, the son of ancient kings?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they? where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; thy wise &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;? and let them tell thee now, and let them know what the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts hath purposed upon Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The princes of Zoan are become fools, the princes of Noph are deceived; they have also seduced Egypt, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even they that are&lt;/span&gt; the stay of the tribes thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath mingled a perverse spirit in the midst thereof: and they have caused Egypt to err in every work thereof, as a drunken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; staggereth in his vomit.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Neither shall there be &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; work for Egypt, which the head or tail, branch or rush, may do.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">In that day shall Egypt be like unto women: and it shall be afraid and fear because of the shaking of the hand of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, which he shaketh over it.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the land of Judah shall be a terror unto Egypt, every one that maketh mention thereof shall be afraid in himself, because of the counsel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, which he hath determined against it.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">In that day shall five cities in the land of Egypt speak the language of Canaan, and swear to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; one shall be called, The city of destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">In that day shall there be an altar to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the midst of the land of Egypt, and a pillar at the border thereof to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And it shall be for a sign and for a witness unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts in the land of Egypt: for they shall cry unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; because of the oppressors, and he shall send them a saviour, and a great one, and he shall deliver them.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be known to Egypt, and the Egyptians shall know the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in that day, and shall do sacrifice and oblation; yea, they shall vow a vow unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and perform &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall smite Egypt: he shall smite and heal &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;: and they shall return &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and he shall be intreated of them, and shall heal them.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">In that day shall there be a highway out of Egypt to Assyria, and the Assyrian shall come into Egypt, and the Egyptian into Assyria, and the Egyptians shall serve with the Assyrians.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">In that day shall Israel be the third with Egypt and with Assyria, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; a blessing in the midst of the land:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Whom the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts shall bless, saying, Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; Egypt my people, and Assyria the work of my hands, and Israel mine inheritance.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>