<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="26" nextChapter="isaiah_4.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 4" prevChapter="isaiah_2.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 2" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">For, behold, the Lord, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, doth take away from Jerusalem and from Judah the stay and the staff, the whole stay of bread, and the whole stay of water,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The mighty man, and the man of war, the judge, and the prophet, and the prudent, and the ancient,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The captain of fifty, and the honourable man, and the counsellor, and the cunning artificer, and the eloquent orator.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And I will give children &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; their princes, and babes shall rule over them.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the people shall be oppressed, every one by another, and every one by his neighbour: the child shall behave himself proudly against the ancient, and the base against the honourable.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">When a man shall take hold of his brother of the house of his father, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;, Thou hast clothing, be thou our ruler, and &lt;i&gt;let&lt;/i&gt; this ruin &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; under thy hand:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">In that day shall he swear, saying, I will not be an healer; for in my house &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; neither bread nor clothing: make me not a ruler of the people.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For Jerusalem is ruined, and Judah is fallen: because their tongue and their doings &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; against the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to provoke the eyes of his glory.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">The shew of their countenance doth witness against them; and they declare their sin as Sodom, they hide &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not. Woe unto their soul! for they have rewarded evil unto themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Say ye to the righteous, that &lt;i&gt;it shall be&lt;/i&gt; well &lt;i&gt;with him&lt;/i&gt;: for they shall eat the fruit of their doings.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Woe unto the wicked! &lt;i&gt;it shall be&lt;/i&gt; ill &lt;i&gt;with him&lt;/i&gt;: for the reward of his hands shall be given him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">&lt;i&gt;As for&lt;/i&gt; my people, children &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; their oppressors, and women rule over them. O my people, they which lead thee cause &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt; to err, and destroy the way of thy paths.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; standeth up to plead, and standeth to judge the people.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will enter into judgment with the ancients of his people, and the princes thereof: for ye have eaten up the vineyard; the spoil of the poor &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in your houses.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">What mean ye &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; ye beat my people to pieces, and grind the faces of the poor? saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Moreover the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; saith, Because the daughters of Zion are haughty, and walk with stretched forth necks and wanton eyes, walking and mincing &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; they go, and making a tinkling with their feet:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Therefore the Lord will smite with a scab the crown of the head of the daughters of Zion, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will discover their secret parts.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">In that day the Lord will take away the bravery of &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; tinkling ornaments &lt;i&gt;about their feet&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; cauls, and &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; round tires like the moon,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The chains, and the bracelets, and the mufflers,</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The bonnets, and the ornaments of the legs, and the headbands, and the tablets, and the earrings,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The rings, and nose jewels,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The changeable suits of apparel, and the mantles, and the wimples, and the crisping pins,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The glasses, and the fine linen, and the hoods, and the vails.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And it shall come to pass, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; instead of sweet smell there shall be stink; and instead of a girdle a rent; and instead of well set hair baldness; and instead of a stomacher a girding of sackcloth; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; burning instead of beauty.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Thy men shall fall by the sword, and thy mighty in the war.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And her gates shall lament and mourn; and she &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; desolate shall sit upon the ground.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>