<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="65" verseCount="25" nextChapter="isaiah_66.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 66" prevChapter="isaiah_64.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 64" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I am sought of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them that&lt;/span&gt; asked not &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for me&lt;/span&gt;; I am found of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them that&lt;/span&gt; sought me not: I said, Behold me, behold me, unto a nation &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; was not called by my name.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I have spread out my hands all the day unto a rebellious people, which walketh in a way &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that was&lt;/span&gt; not good, after their own thoughts;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">A people that provoketh me to anger continually to my face; that sacrificeth in gardens, and burneth incense upon altars of brick;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Which remain among the graves, and lodge in the monuments, which eat swine's flesh, and broth of abominable &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things is in&lt;/span&gt; their vessels;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Which say, Stand by thyself, come not near to me; for I am holier than thou. These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; a smoke in my nose, a fire that burneth all the day.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Behold, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; written before me: I will not keep silence, but will recompense, even recompense into their bosom,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Your iniquities, and the iniquities of your fathers together, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which have burned incense upon the mountains, and blasphemed me upon the hills: therefore will I measure their former work into their bosom.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, As the new wine is found in the cluster, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; saith, Destroy it not; for a blessing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in it: so will I do for my servants' sakes, that I may not destroy them all.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And I will bring forth a seed out of Jacob, and out of Judah an inheritor of my mountains: and mine elect shall inherit it, and my servants shall dwell there.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Sharon shall be a fold of flocks, and the valley of Achor a place for the herds to lie down in, for my people that have sought me.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">But ye &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they that forsake the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that forget my holy mountain, that prepare a table for that troop, and that furnish the drink offering unto that number.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore will I number you to the sword, and ye shall all bow down to the slaughter: because when I called, ye did not answer; when I spake, ye did not hear; but did evil before mine eyes, and did choose &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; wherein I delighted not.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, Behold, my servants shall eat, but ye shall be hungry: behold, my servants shall drink, but ye shall be thirsty: behold, my servants shall rejoice, but ye shall be ashamed:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Behold, my servants shall sing for joy of heart, but ye shall cry for sorrow of heart, and shall howl for vexation of spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And ye shall leave your name for a curse unto my chosen: for the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; shall slay thee, and call his servants by another name:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">That he who blesseth himself in the earth shall bless himself in the God of truth; and he that sweareth in the earth shall swear by the God of truth; because the former troubles are forgotten, and because they are hid from mine eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">For, behold, I create new heavens and a new earth: and the former shall not be remembered, nor come into mind.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But be ye glad and rejoice for ever &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in that&lt;/span&gt; which I create: for, behold, I create Jerusalem a rejoicing, and her people a joy.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And I will rejoice in Jerusalem, and joy in my people: and the voice of weeping shall be no more heard in her, nor the voice of crying.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">There shall be no more thence an infant of days, nor an old man that hath not filled his days: for the child shall die an hundred years old; but the sinner &lt;span class="extra"&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; an hundred years old shall be accursed.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they shall build houses, and inhabit &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;; and they shall plant vineyards, and eat the fruit of them.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">They shall not build, and another inhabit; they shall not plant, and another eat: for as the days of a tree &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the days of my people, and mine elect shall long enjoy the work of their hands.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">They shall not labour in vain, nor bring forth for trouble; for they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the seed of the blessed of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and their offspring with them.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And it shall come to pass, that before they call, I will answer; and while they are yet speaking, I will hear.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The wolf and the lamb shall feed together, and the lion shall eat straw like the bullock: and dust &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the serpent's meat. They shall not hurt nor destroy in all my holy mountain, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>