<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="9" nextChapter="isaiah_16.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 16" prevChapter="isaiah_14.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 14" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The burden of Moab. Because in the night Ar of Moab is laid waste, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; brought to silence; because in the night Kir of Moab is laid waste, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; brought to silence;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">He is gone up to Bajith, and to Dibon, the high places, to weep: Moab shall howl over Nebo, and over Medeba: on all their heads &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; baldness, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; every beard cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">In their streets they shall gird themselves with sackcloth: on the tops of their houses, and in their streets, every one shall howl, weeping abundantly.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Heshbon shall cry, and Elealeh: their voice shall be heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto Jahaz: therefore the armed soldiers of Moab shall cry out; his life shall be grievous unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">My heart shall cry out for Moab; his fugitives &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall flee&lt;/span&gt; unto Zoar, an heifer of three years old: for by the mounting up of Luhith with weeping shall they go it up; for in the way of Horonaim they shall raise up a cry of destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For the waters of Nimrim shall be desolate: for the hay is withered away, the grass faileth, there is no green thing.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Therefore the abundance they have gotten, and that which they have laid up, shall they carry away to the brook of the willows.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For the cry is gone round about the borders of Moab; the howling thereof unto Eglaim, and the howling thereof unto Beer-elim.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For the waters of Dimon shall be full of blood: for I will bring more upon Dimon, lions upon him that escapeth of Moab, and upon the remnant of the land.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>