<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="61" verseCount="11" nextChapter="isaiah_62.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 62" prevChapter="isaiah_60.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 60" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The Spirit of the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; upon me; because the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath anointed me to preach good tidings unto the meek; he hath sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to &lt;i&gt;them that are&lt;/i&gt; bound;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">To proclaim the acceptable year of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the day of vengeance of our God; to comfort all that mourn;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">To appoint unto them that mourn in Zion, to give unto them beauty for ashes, the oil of joy for mourning, the garment of praise for the spirit of heaviness; that they might be called trees of righteousness, the planting of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that he might be glorified.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And they shall build the old wastes, they shall raise up the former desolations, and they shall repair the waste cities, the desolations of many generations.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And strangers shall stand and feed your flocks, and the sons of the alien &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; your plowmen and your vinedressers.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But ye shall be named the Priests of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; shall call you the Ministers of our God: ye shall eat the riches of the Gentiles, and in their glory shall ye boast yourselves.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">For your shame &lt;i&gt;ye shall have&lt;/i&gt; double; and &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; confusion they shall rejoice in their portion: therefore in their land they shall possess the double: everlasting joy shall be unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; love judgment, I hate robbery for burnt offering; and I will direct their work in truth, and I will make an everlasting covenant with them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And their seed shall be known among the Gentiles, and their offspring among the people: all that see them shall acknowledge them, that they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the seed &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath blessed.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I will greatly rejoice in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, my soul shall be joyful in my God; for he hath clothed me with the garments of salvation, he hath covered me with the robe of righteousness, as a bridegroom decketh &lt;i&gt;himself&lt;/i&gt; with ornaments, and as a bride adorneth &lt;i&gt;herself&lt;/i&gt; with her jewels.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For as the earth bringeth forth her bud, and as the garden causeth the things that are sown in it to spring forth; so the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; will cause righteousness and praise to spring forth before all the nations.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>