<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="30" verseCount="33" nextChapter="isaiah_31.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 31" prevChapter="isaiah_29.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 29" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Woe to the rebellious children, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that take counsel, but not of me; and that cover with a covering, but not of my spirit, that they may add sin to sin:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That walk to go down into Egypt, and have not asked at my mouth; to strengthen themselves in the strength of Pharaoh, and to trust in the shadow of Egypt!</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Therefore shall the strength of Pharaoh be your shame, and the trust in the shadow of Egypt &lt;span class="extra"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; confusion.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For his princes were at Zoan, and his ambassadors came to Hanes.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They were all ashamed of a people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; could not profit them, nor be an help nor profit, but a shame, and also a reproach.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The burden of the beasts of the south: into the land of trouble and anguish, from whence &lt;span class="extra"&gt;come&lt;/span&gt; the young and old lion, the viper and fiery flying serpent, they will carry their riches upon the shoulders of young asses, and their treasures upon the bunches of camels, to a people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shall not profit &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For the Egyptians shall help in vain, and to no purpose: therefore have I cried concerning this, Their strength &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; to sit still.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Now go, write it before them in a table, and note it in a book, that it may be for the time to come for ever and ever:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">That this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a rebellious people, lying children, children &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; will not hear the law of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Which say to the seers, See not; and to the prophets, Prophesy not unto us right things, speak unto us smooth things, prophesy deceits:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Get you out of the way, turn aside out of the path, cause the Holy One of Israel to cease from before us.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Wherefore thus saith the Holy One of Israel, Because ye despise this word, and trust in oppression and perverseness, and stay thereon:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Therefore this iniquity shall be to you as a breach ready to fall, swelling out in a high wall, whose breaking cometh suddenly at an instant.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he shall break it as the breaking of the potters' vessel that is broken in pieces; he shall not spare: so that there shall not be found in the bursting of it a sherd to take fire from the hearth, or to take water &lt;span class="extra"&gt;withal&lt;/span&gt; out of the pit.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For thus saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, the Holy One of Israel; In returning and rest shall ye be saved; in quietness and in confidence shall be your strength: and ye would not.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But ye said, No; for we will flee upon horses; therefore shall ye flee: and, We will ride upon the swift; therefore shall they that pursue you be swift.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">One thousand &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall flee&lt;/span&gt; at the rebuke of one; at the rebuke of five shall ye flee: till ye be left as a beacon upon the top of a mountain, and as an ensign on an hill.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And therefore will the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; wait, that he may be gracious unto you, and therefore will he be exalted, that he may have mercy upon you: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a God of judgment: blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all they that wait for him.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For the people shall dwell in Zion at Jerusalem: thou shalt weep no more: he will be very gracious unto thee at the voice of thy cry; when he shall hear it, he will answer thee.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;though&lt;/span&gt; the Lord give you the bread of adversity, and the water of affliction, yet shall not thy teachers be removed into a corner any more, but thine eyes shall see thy teachers:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And thine ears shall hear a word behind thee, saying, This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the way, walk ye in it, when ye turn to the right hand, and when ye turn to the left.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Ye shall defile also the covering of thy graven images of silver, and the ornament of thy molten images of gold: thou shalt cast them away as a menstruous cloth; thou shalt say unto it, Get thee hence.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Then shall he give the rain of thy seed, that thou shalt sow the ground withal; and bread of the increase of the earth, and it shall be fat and plenteous: in that day shall thy cattle feed in large pastures.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The oxen likewise and the young asses that ear the ground shall eat clean provender, which hath been winnowed with the shovel and with the fan.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And there shall be upon every high mountain, and upon every high hill, rivers &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; streams of waters in the day of the great slaughter, when the towers fall.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Moreover the light of the moon shall be as the light of the sun, and the light of the sun shall be sevenfold, as the light of seven days, in the day that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; bindeth up the breach of his people, and healeth the stroke of their wound.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">Behold, the name of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; cometh from far, burning &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; his anger, and the burden &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thereof is&lt;/span&gt; heavy: his lips are full of indignation, and his tongue as a devouring fire:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And his breath, as an overflowing stream, shall reach to the midst of the neck, to sift the nations with the sieve of vanity: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; a bridle in the jaws of the people, causing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; to err.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Ye shall have a song, as in the night &lt;span class="extra"&gt;when&lt;/span&gt; a holy solemnity is kept; and gladness of heart, as when one goeth with a pipe to come into the mountain of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to the mighty One of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall cause his glorious voice to be heard, and shall shew the lighting down of his arm, with the indignation of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; anger, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; the flame of a devouring fire, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; scattering, and tempest, and hailstones.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">For through the voice of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall the Assyrian be beaten down, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; smote with a rod.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; every place where the grounded staff shall pass, which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall lay upon him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; shall be with tabrets and harps: and in battles of shaking will he fight with it.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">For Tophet &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; ordained of old; yea, for the king it is prepared; he hath made &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; deep &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; large: the pile thereof &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; fire and much wood; the breath of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, like a stream of brimstone, doth kindle it.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>