<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="34" nextChapter="isaiah_11.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 11" prevChapter="isaiah_9.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 9" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Woe unto them that decree unrighteous decrees, and that write grievousness &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; they have prescribed;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">To turn aside the needy from judgment, and to take away the right from the poor of my people, that widows may be their prey, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; they may rob the fatherless!</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And what will ye do in the day of visitation, and in the desolation &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; shall come from far? to whom will ye flee for help? and where will ye leave your glory?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Without me they shall bow down under the prisoners, and they shall fall under the slain. For all this his anger is not turned away, but his hand &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; stretched out still.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">O Assyrian, the rod of mine anger, and the staff in their hand is mine indignation.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I will send him against an hypocritical nation, and against the people of my wrath will I give him a charge, to take the spoil, and to take the prey, and to tread them down like the mire of the streets.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Howbeit he meaneth not so, neither doth his heart think so; but &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; in his heart to destroy and cut off nations not a few.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For he saith, &lt;i&gt;Are&lt;/i&gt; not my princes altogether kings?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;i&gt;Is&lt;/i&gt; not Calno as Carchemish? &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not Hamath as Arpad? &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not Samaria as Damascus?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">As my hand hath found the kingdoms of the idols, and whose graven images did excel them of Jerusalem and of Samaria;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Shall I not, as I have done unto Samaria and her idols, so do to Jerusalem and her idols?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Wherefore it shall come to pass, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; when the Lord hath performed his whole work upon mount Zion and on Jerusalem, I will punish the fruit of the stout heart of the king of Assyria, and the glory of his high looks.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For he saith, By the strength of my hand I have done &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and by my wisdom; for I am prudent: and I have removed the bounds of the people, and have robbed their treasures, and I have put down the inhabitants like a valiant &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And my hand hath found as a nest the riches of the people: and as one gathereth eggs &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; left, have I gathered all the earth; and there was none that moved the wing, or opened the mouth, or peeped.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Shall the axe boast itself against him that heweth therewith? &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; shall the saw magnify itself against him that shaketh it? as if the rod should shake &lt;i&gt;itself&lt;/i&gt; against them that lift it up, &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; as if the staff should lift up &lt;i&gt;itself, as if it were&lt;/i&gt; no wood.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Therefore shall the Lord, the Lord of hosts, send among his fat ones leanness; and under his glory he shall kindle a burning like the burning of a fire.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the light of Israel shall be for a fire, and his Holy One for a flame: and it shall burn and devour his thorns and his briers in one day;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And shall consume the glory of his forest, and of his fruitful field, both soul and body: and they shall be as when a standardbearer fainteth.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the rest of the trees of his forest shall be few, that a child may write them.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And it shall come to pass in that day, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the remnant of Israel, and such as are escaped of the house of Jacob, shall no more again stay upon him that smote them; but shall stay upon the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the Holy One of Israel, in truth.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The remnant shall return, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the remnant of Jacob, unto the mighty God.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For though thy people Israel be as the sand of the sea, &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; a remnant of them shall return: the consumption decreed shall overflow with righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts shall make a consumption, even determined, in the midst of all the land.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, O my people that dwellest in Zion, be not afraid of the Assyrian: he shall smite thee with a rod, and shall lift up his staff against thee, after the manner of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For yet a very little while, and the indignation shall cease, and mine anger in their destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts shall stir up a scourge for him according to the slaughter of Midian at the rock of Oreb: and &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; his rod &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; upon the sea, so shall he lift it up after the manner of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And it shall come to pass in that day, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; his burden shall be taken away from off thy shoulder, and his yoke from off thy neck, and the yoke shall be destroyed because of the anointing.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">He is come to Aiath, he is passed to Migron; at Michmash he hath laid up his carriages:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">They are gone over the passage: they have taken up their lodging at Geba; Ramah is afraid; Gibeah of Saul is fled.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Lift up thy voice, O daughter of Gallim: cause it to be heard unto Laish, O poor Anathoth.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Madmenah is removed; the inhabitants of Gebim gather themselves to flee.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">As yet shall he remain at Nob that day: he shall shake his hand &lt;i&gt;against&lt;/i&gt; the mount of the daughter of Zion, the hill of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Behold, the Lord, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, shall lop the bough with terror: and the high ones of stature &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; hewn down, and the haughty shall be humbled.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And he shall cut down the thickets of the forest with iron, and Lebanon shall fall by a mighty one.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>