<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="32" nextChapter="isaiah_15.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 15" prevChapter="isaiah_13.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 13" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">For the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will have mercy on Jacob, and will yet choose Israel, and set them in their own land: and the strangers shall be joined with them, and they shall cleave to the house of Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the people shall take them, and bring them to their place: and the house of Israel shall possess them in the land of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for servants and handmaids: and they shall take them captives, whose captives they were; and they shall rule over their oppressors.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And it shall come to pass in the day that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall give thee rest from thy sorrow, and from thy fear, and from the hard bondage wherein thou wast made to serve,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">That thou shalt take up this proverb against the king of Babylon, and say, How hath the oppressor ceased! the golden city ceased!</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath broken the staff of the wicked, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the sceptre of the rulers.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He who smote the people in wrath with a continual stroke, he that ruled the nations in anger, is persecuted, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; none hindereth.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The whole earth is at rest, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; is quiet: they break forth into singing.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Yea, the fir trees rejoice at thee, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the cedars of Lebanon, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Since thou art laid down, no feller is come up against us.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Hell from beneath is moved for thee to meet &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt; at thy coming: it stirreth up the dead for thee, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all the chief ones of the earth; it hath raised up from their thrones all the kings of the nations.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">All they shall speak and say unto thee, Art thou also become weak as we? art thou become like unto us?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thy pomp is brought down to the grave, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the noise of thy viols: the worm is spread under thee, and the worms cover thee.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">How art thou fallen from heaven, O Lucifer, son of the morning! &lt;span class="extra"&gt;how&lt;/span&gt; art thou cut down to the ground, which didst weaken the nations!</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For thou hast said in thine heart, I will ascend into heaven, I will exalt my throne above the stars of God: I will sit also upon the mount of the congregation, in the sides of the north:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I will ascend above the heights of the clouds; I will be like the most High.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Yet thou shalt be brought down to hell, to the sides of the pit.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">They that see thee shall narrowly look upon thee, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; consider thee, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;saying, Is&lt;/span&gt; this the man that made the earth to tremble, that did shake kingdoms;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;That&lt;/span&gt; made the world as a wilderness, and destroyed the cities thereof; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; opened not the house of his prisoners?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">All the kings of the nations, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all of them, lie in glory, every one in his own house.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But thou art cast out of thy grave like an abominable branch, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and as&lt;/span&gt; the raiment of those that are slain, thrust through with a sword, that go down to the stones of the pit; as a carcase trodden under feet.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Thou shalt not be joined with them in burial, because thou hast destroyed thy land, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; slain thy people: the seed of evildoers shall never be renowned.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Prepare slaughter for his children for the iniquity of their fathers; that they do not rise, nor possess the land, nor fill the face of the world with cities.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For I will rise up against them, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, and cut off from Babylon the name, and remnant, and son, and nephew, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">I will also make it a possession for the bittern, and pools of water: and I will sweep it with the besom of destruction, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts hath sworn, saying, Surely as I have thought, so shall it come to pass; and as I have purposed, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; shall it stand:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">That I will break the Assyrian in my land, and upon my mountains tread him under foot: then shall his yoke depart from off them, and his burden depart from off their shoulders.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the purpose that is purposed upon the whole earth: and this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the hand that is stretched out upon all the nations.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts hath purposed, and who shall disannul &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;? and his hand &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; stretched out, and who shall turn it back?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">In the year that king Ahaz died was this burden.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">Rejoice not thou, whole Palestina, because the rod of him that smote thee is broken: for out of the serpent's root shall come forth a cockatrice, and his fruit &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a fiery flying serpent.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the firstborn of the poor shall feed, and the needy shall lie down in safety: and I will kill thy root with famine, and he shall slay thy remnant.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Howl, O gate; cry, O city; thou, whole Palestina, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; dissolved: for there shall come from the north a smoke, and none &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; alone in his appointed times.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">What shall &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; then answer the messengers of the nation? That the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath founded Zion, and the poor of his people shall trust in it.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>