<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="14" nextChapter="isaiah_17.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 17" prevChapter="isaiah_15.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 15" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Send ye the lamb to the ruler of the land from Sela to the wilderness, unto the mount of the daughter of Zion.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For it shall be, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt;, as a wandering bird cast out of the nest, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; the daughters of Moab shall be at the fords of Arnon.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Take counsel, execute judgment; make thy shadow as the night in the midst of the noonday; hide the outcasts; bewray not him that wandereth.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Let mine outcasts dwell with thee, Moab; be thou a covert to them from the face of the spoiler: for the extortioner is at an end, the spoiler ceaseth, the oppressors are consumed out of the land.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And in mercy shall the throne be established: and he shall sit upon it in truth in the tabernacle of David, judging, and seeking judgment, and hasting righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">We have heard of the pride of Moab; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; very proud: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of his haughtiness, and his pride, and his wrath: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; his lies &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; so.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Therefore shall Moab howl for Moab, every one shall howl: for the foundations of Kir-hareseth shall ye mourn; surely &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they are&lt;/span&gt; stricken.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For the fields of Heshbon languish, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the vine of Sibmah: the lords of the heathen have broken down the principal plants thereof, they are come &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto Jazer, they wandered &lt;span class='extra'&gt;through&lt;/span&gt; the wilderness: her branches are stretched out, they are gone over the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Therefore I will bewail with the weeping of Jazer the vine of Sibmah: I will water thee with my tears, O Heshbon, and Elealeh: for the shouting for thy summer fruits and for thy harvest is fallen.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And gladness is taken away, and joy out of the plentiful field; and in the vineyards there shall be no singing, neither shall there be shouting: the treaders shall tread out no wine in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; presses; I have made &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their vintage&lt;/span&gt; shouting to cease.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Wherefore my bowels shall sound like an harp for Moab, and mine inward parts for Kir-haresh.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And it shall come to pass, when it is seen that Moab is weary on the high place, that he shall come to his sanctuary to pray; but he shall not prevail.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the word that the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken concerning Moab since that time.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But now the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken, saying, Within three years, as the years of an hireling, and the glory of Moab shall be contemned, with all that great multitude; and the remnant &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; very small &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; feeble.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>