<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="58" verseCount="14" nextChapter="isaiah_59.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 59" prevChapter="isaiah_57.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 57" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Cry aloud, spare not, lift up thy voice like a trumpet, and shew my people their transgression, and the house of Jacob their sins.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Yet they seek me daily, and delight to know my ways, as a nation that did righteousness, and forsook not the ordinance of their God: they ask of me the ordinances of justice; they take delight in approaching to God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Wherefore have we fasted, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;say they&lt;/span&gt;, and thou seest not? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;wherefore&lt;/span&gt; have we afflicted our soul, and thou takest no knowledge? Behold, in the day of your fast ye find pleasure, and exact all your labours.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Behold, ye fast for strife and debate, and to smite with the fist of wickedness: ye shall not fast as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;ye do this&lt;/span&gt; day, to make your voice to be heard on high.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Is it such a fast that I have chosen? a day for a man to afflict his soul? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt; to bow down his head as a bulrush, and to spread sackcloth and ashes &lt;span class='extra'&gt;under him&lt;/span&gt;? wilt thou call this a fast, and an acceptable day to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; not this the fast that I have chosen? to loose the bands of wickedness, to undo the heavy burdens, and to let the oppressed go free, and that ye break every yoke?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is it&lt;/span&gt; not to deal thy bread to the hungry, and that thou bring the poor that are cast out to thy house? when thou seest the naked, that thou cover him; and that thou hide not thyself from thine own flesh?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Then shall thy light break forth as the morning, and thine health shall spring forth speedily: and thy righteousness shall go before thee; the glory of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be thy rereward.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then shalt thou call, and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall answer; thou shalt cry, and he shall say, Here I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt;. If thou take away from the midst of thee the yoke, the putting forth of the finger, and speaking vanity;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; thou draw out thy soul to the hungry, and satisfy the afflicted soul; then shall thy light rise in obscurity, and thy darkness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; as the noonday:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall guide thee continually, and satisfy thy soul in drought, and make fat thy bones: and thou shalt be like a watered garden, and like a spring of water, whose waters fail not.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they that shall be&lt;/span&gt; of thee shall build the old waste places: thou shalt raise up the foundations of many generations; and thou shalt be called, The repairer of the breach, The restorer of paths to dwell in.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">If thou turn away thy foot from the sabbath, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; doing thy pleasure on my holy day; and call the sabbath a delight, the holy of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, honourable; and shalt honour him, not doing thine own ways, nor finding thine own pleasure, nor speaking &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thine own&lt;/span&gt; words:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then shalt thou delight thyself in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and I will cause thee to ride upon the high places of the earth, and feed thee with the heritage of Jacob thy father: for the mouth of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>