<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="33" verseCount="24" nextChapter="isaiah_34.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 34" prevChapter="isaiah_32.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 32" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Woe to thee that spoilest, and thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;wast&lt;/span&gt; not spoiled; and dealest treacherously, and they dealt not treacherously with thee! when thou shalt cease to spoil, thou shalt be spoiled; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; when thou shalt make an end to deal treacherously, they shall deal treacherously with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, be gracious unto us; we have waited for thee: be thou their arm every morning, our salvation also in the time of trouble.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">At the noise of the tumult the people fled; at the lifting up of thyself the nations were scattered.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And your spoil shall be gathered &lt;span class="extra"&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; the gathering of the caterpiller: as the running to and fro of locusts shall he run upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; is exalted; for he dwelleth on high: he hath filled Zion with judgment and righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And wisdom and knowledge shall be the stability of thy times, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; strength of salvation: the fear of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his treasure.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Behold, their valiant ones shall cry without: the ambassadors of peace shall weep bitterly.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The highways lie waste, the wayfaring man ceaseth: he hath broken the covenant, he hath despised the cities, he regardeth no man.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The earth mourneth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; languisheth: Lebanon is ashamed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; hewn down: Sharon is like a wilderness; and Bashan and Carmel shake off &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their fruits&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Now will I rise, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; now will I be exalted; now will I lift up myself.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Ye shall conceive chaff, ye shall bring forth stubble: your breath, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; fire, shall devour you.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the people shall be &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the burnings of lime: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; thorns cut up shall they be burned in the fire.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Hear, ye &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; far off, what I have done; and, ye &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; near, acknowledge my might.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The sinners in Zion are afraid; fearfulness hath surprised the hypocrites. Who among us shall dwell with the devouring fire? who among us shall dwell with everlasting burnings?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He that walketh righteously, and speaketh uprightly; he that despiseth the gain of oppressions, that shaketh his hands from holding of bribes, that stoppeth his ears from hearing of blood, and shutteth his eyes from seeing evil;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He shall dwell on high: his place of defence &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the munitions of rocks: bread shall be given him; his waters &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; sure.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thine eyes shall see the king in his beauty: they shall behold the land that is very far off.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thine heart shall meditate terror. Where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the scribe? where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the receiver? where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he that counted the towers?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thou shalt not see a fierce people, a people of a deeper speech than thou canst perceive; of a stammering tongue, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that thou canst&lt;/span&gt; not understand.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Look upon Zion, the city of our solemnities: thine eyes shall see Jerusalem a quiet habitation, a tabernacle &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shall not be taken down; not one of the stakes thereof shall ever be removed, neither shall any of the cords thereof be broken.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But there the glorious &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;will be&lt;/span&gt; unto us a place of broad rivers &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; streams; wherein shall go no galley with oars, neither shall gallant ship pass thereby.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our judge, the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our lawgiver, the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our king; he will save us.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Thy tacklings are loosed; they could not well strengthen their mast, they could not spread the sail: then is the prey of a great spoil divided; the lame take the prey.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the inhabitant shall not say, I am sick: the people that dwell therein &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; forgiven &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; iniquity.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>