<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="48" verseCount="22" nextChapter="isaiah_49.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 49" prevChapter="isaiah_47.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 47" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hear ye this, O house of Jacob, which are called by the name of Israel, and are come forth out of the waters of Judah, which swear by the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and make mention of the God of Israel, &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; not in truth, nor in righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For they call themselves of the holy city, and stay themselves upon the God of Israel; The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his name.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I have declared the former things from the beginning; and they went forth out of my mouth, and I shewed them; I did &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; suddenly, and they came to pass.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Because I knew that thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; obstinate, and thy neck &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an iron sinew, and thy brow brass;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I have even from the beginning declared &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to thee; before it came to pass I shewed &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; thee: lest thou shouldest say, Mine idol hath done them, and my graven image, and my molten image, hath commanded them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thou hast heard, see all this; and will not ye declare &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;? I have shewed thee new things from this time, even hidden things, and thou didst not know them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">They are created now, and not from the beginning; even before the day when thou heardest them not; lest thou shouldest say, Behold, I knew them.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Yea, thou heardest not; yea, thou knewest not; yea, from that time &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thine ear was not opened: for I knew that thou wouldest deal very treacherously, and wast called a transgressor from the womb.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">For my name's sake will I defer mine anger, and for my praise will I refrain for thee, that I cut thee not off.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Behold, I have refined thee, but not with silver; I have chosen thee in the furnace of affliction.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For mine own sake, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; for mine own sake, will I do &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;: for how should &lt;i&gt;my name&lt;/i&gt; be polluted? and I will not give my glory unto another.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Hearken unto me, O Jacob and Israel, my called; I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; he; I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the first, I also &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the last.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Mine hand also hath laid the foundation of the earth, and my right hand hath spanned the heavens: &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; I call unto them, they stand up together.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">All ye, assemble yourselves, and hear; which among them hath declared these &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt;? The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath loved him: he will do his pleasure on Babylon, and his arm &lt;i&gt;shall be on&lt;/i&gt; the Chaldeans.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; I, have spoken; yea, I have called him: I have brought him, and he shall make his way prosperous.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Come ye near unto me, hear ye this; I have not spoken in secret from the beginning; from the time that it was, there &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I: and now the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, and his Spirit, hath sent me.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thy Redeemer, the Holy One of Israel; I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God which teacheth thee to profit, which leadeth thee by the way &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thou shouldest go.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">O that thou hadst hearkened to my commandments! then had thy peace been as a river, and thy righteousness as the waves of the sea:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thy seed also had been as the sand, and the offspring of thy bowels like the gravel thereof; his name should not have been cut off nor destroyed from before me.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">Go ye forth of Babylon, flee ye from the Chaldeans, with a voice of singing declare ye, tell this, utter it &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to the end of the earth; say ye, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath redeemed his servant Jacob.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they thirsted not &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; he led them through the deserts: he caused the waters to flow out of the rock for them: he clave the rock also, and the waters gushed out.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; no peace, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, unto the wicked.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>