<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="66" verseCount="24" nextChapter="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 1" prevChapter="isaiah_65.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 65" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, The heaven &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my throne, and the earth &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my footstool: where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the house that ye build unto me? and where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the place of my rest?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For all those &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; hath mine hand made, and all those &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; have been, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but to this &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; will I look, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;him that is&lt;/i&gt; poor and of a contrite spirit, and trembleth at my word.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">He that killeth an ox &lt;i&gt;is as if&lt;/i&gt; he slew a man; he that sacrificeth a lamb, &lt;i&gt;as if&lt;/i&gt; he cut off a dog's neck; he that offereth an oblation, &lt;i&gt;as if he offered&lt;/i&gt; swine's blood; he that burneth incense, &lt;i&gt;as if&lt;/i&gt; he blessed an idol. Yea, they have chosen their own ways, and their soul delighteth in their abominations.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I also will choose their delusions, and will bring their fears upon them; because when I called, none did answer; when I spake, they did not hear: but they did evil before mine eyes, and chose &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; in which I delighted not.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Hear the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, ye that tremble at his word; Your brethren that hated you, that cast you out for my name's sake, said, Let the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be glorified: but he shall appear to your joy, and they shall be ashamed.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">A voice of noise from the city, a voice from the temple, a voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that rendereth recompence to his enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Before she travailed, she brought forth; before her pain came, she was delivered of a man child.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Who hath heard such a thing? who hath seen such things? Shall the earth be made to bring forth in one day? &lt;i&gt;or&lt;/i&gt; shall a nation be born at once? for as soon as Zion travailed, she brought forth her children.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Shall I bring to the birth, and not cause to bring forth? saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: shall I cause to bring forth, and shut &lt;i&gt;the womb&lt;/i&gt;? saith thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Rejoice ye with Jerusalem, and be glad with her, all ye that love her: rejoice for joy with her, all ye that mourn for her:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">That ye may suck, and be satisfied with the breasts of her consolations; that ye may milk out, and be delighted with the abundance of her glory.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Behold, I will extend peace to her like a river, and the glory of the Gentiles like a flowing stream: then shall ye suck, ye shall be borne upon &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; sides, and be dandled upon &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; knees.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">As one whom his mother comforteth, so will I comfort you; and ye shall be comforted in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And when ye see &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt;, your heart shall rejoice, and your bones shall flourish like an herb: and the hand of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be known toward his servants, and &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; indignation toward his enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For, behold, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will come with fire, and with his chariots like a whirlwind, to render his anger with fury, and his rebuke with flames of fire.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For by fire and by his sword will the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; plead with all flesh: and the slain of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be many.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">They that sanctify themselves, and purify themselves in the gardens behind one &lt;i&gt;tree&lt;/i&gt; in the midst, eating swine's flesh, and the abomination, and the mouse, shall be consumed together, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For I &lt;i&gt;know&lt;/i&gt; their works and their thoughts: it shall come, that I will gather all nations and tongues; and they shall come, and see my glory.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And I will set a sign among them, and I will send those that escape of them unto the nations, &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; Tarshish, Pul, and Lud, that draw the bow, &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; Tubal, and Javan, &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; the isles afar off, that have not heard my fame, neither have seen my glory; and they shall declare my glory among the Gentiles.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And they shall bring all your brethren &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; an offering unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; out of all nations upon horses, and in chariots, and in litters, and upon mules, and upon swift beasts, to my holy mountain Jerusalem, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as the children of Israel bring an offering in a clean vessel into the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And I will also take of them for priests &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; for Levites, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For as the new heavens and the new earth, which I will make, shall remain before me, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, so shall your seed and your name remain.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And it shall come to pass, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; from one new moon to another, and from one sabbath to another, shall all flesh come to worship before me, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they shall go forth, and look upon the carcases of the men that have transgressed against me: for their worm shall not die, neither shall their fire be quenched; and they shall be an abhorring unto all flesh.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>