<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="7" nextChapter="isaiah_19.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 19" prevChapter="isaiah_17.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 17" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Woe to the land shadowing with wings, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; beyond the rivers of Ethiopia:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That sendeth ambassadors by the sea, even in vessels of bulrushes upon the waters, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Go, ye swift messengers, to a nation scattered and peeled, to a people terrible from their beginning hitherto; a nation meted out and trodden down, whose land the rivers have spoiled!</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">All ye inhabitants of the world, and dwellers on the earth, see ye, when he lifteth up an ensign on the mountains; and when he bloweth a trumpet, hear ye.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For so the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, I will take my rest, and I will consider in my dwelling place like a clear heat upon herbs, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; like a cloud of dew in the heat of harvest.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For afore the harvest, when the bud is perfect, and the sour grape is ripening in the flower, he shall both cut off the sprigs with pruning hooks, and take away &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; cut down the branches.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">They shall be left together unto the fowls of the mountains, and to the beasts of the earth: and the fowls shall summer upon them, and all the beasts of the earth shall winter upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">In that time shall the present be brought unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts of a people scattered and peeled, and from a people terrible from their beginning hitherto; a nation meted out and trodden under foot, whose land the rivers have spoiled, to the place of the name of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the mount Zion.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>