<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="50" verseCount="11" nextChapter="isaiah_51.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 51" prevChapter="isaiah_49.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 49" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the bill of your mother's divorcement, whom I have put away? or which of my creditors &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt; to whom I have sold you? Behold, for your iniquities have ye sold yourselves, and for your transgressions is your mother put away.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Wherefore, when I came, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was there&lt;/span&gt; no man? when I called, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was there&lt;/span&gt; none to answer? Is my hand shortened at all, that it cannot redeem? or have I no power to deliver? behold, at my rebuke I dry up the sea, I make the rivers a wilderness: their fish stinketh, because &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no water, and dieth for thirst.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I clothe the heavens with blackness, and I make sackcloth their covering.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; hath given me the tongue of the learned, that I should know how to speak a word in season to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him that is&lt;/span&gt; weary: he wakeneth morning by morning, he wakeneth mine ear to hear as the learned.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">The Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; hath opened mine ear, and I was not rebellious, neither turned away back.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I gave my back to the smiters, and my cheeks to them that plucked off the hair: I hid not my face from shame and spitting.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">For the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; will help me; therefore shall I not be confounded: therefore have I set my face like a flint, and I know that I shall not be ashamed.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;He is&lt;/span&gt; near that justifieth me; who will contend with me? let us stand together: who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine adversary? let him come near to me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Behold, the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; will help me; who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shall condemn me? lo, they all shall wax old as a garment; the moth shall eat them up.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; among you that feareth the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that obeyeth the voice of his servant, that walketh &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; darkness, and hath no light? let him trust in the name of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and stay upon his God.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Behold, all ye that kindle a fire, that compass &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yourselves&lt;/span&gt; about with sparks: walk in the light of your fire, and in the sparks &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; ye have kindled. This shall ye have of mine hand; ye shall lie down in sorrow.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>