<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="54" verseCount="17" nextChapter="isaiah_55.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 55" prevChapter="isaiah_53.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 53" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Sing, O barren, thou &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; didst not bear; break forth into singing, and cry aloud, thou &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; didst not travail with child: for more &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the children of the desolate than the children of the married wife, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Enlarge the place of thy tent, and let them stretch forth the curtains of thine habitations: spare not, lengthen thy cords, and strengthen thy stakes;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For thou shalt break forth on the right hand and on the left; and thy seed shall inherit the Gentiles, and make the desolate cities to be inhabited.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Fear not; for thou shalt not be ashamed: neither be thou confounded; for thou shalt not be put to shame: for thou shalt forget the shame of thy youth, and shalt not remember the reproach of thy widowhood any more.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For thy Maker &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thine husband; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his name; and thy Redeemer the Holy One of Israel; The God of the whole earth shall he be called.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath called thee as a woman forsaken and grieved in spirit, and a wife of youth, when thou wast refused, saith thy God.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For a small moment have I forsaken thee; but with great mercies will I gather thee.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">In a little wrath I hid my face from thee for a moment; but with everlasting kindness will I have mercy on thee, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy Redeemer.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For this &lt;i&gt;is as&lt;/i&gt; the waters of Noah unto me: for &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; I have sworn that the waters of Noah should no more go over the earth; so have I sworn that I would not be wroth with thee, nor rebuke thee.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For the mountains shall depart, and the hills be removed; but my kindness shall not depart from thee, neither shall the covenant of my peace be removed, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that hath mercy on thee.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">O thou afflicted, tossed with tempest, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; not comforted, behold, I will lay thy stones with fair colours, and lay thy foundations with sapphires.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I will make thy windows of agates, and thy gates of carbuncles, and all thy borders of pleasant stones.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And all thy children &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; taught of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and great &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the peace of thy children.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">In righteousness shalt thou be established: thou shalt be far from oppression; for thou shalt not fear: and from terror; for it shall not come near thee.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Behold, they shall surely gather together, &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; not by me: whosoever shall gather together against thee shall fall for thy sake.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Behold, I have created the smith that bloweth the coals in the fire, and that bringeth forth an instrument for his work; and I have created the waster to destroy.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">No weapon that is formed against thee shall prosper; and every tongue &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; shall rise against thee in judgment thou shalt condemn. This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the heritage of the servants of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and their righteousness &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; of me, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>