<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="35" verseCount="10" nextChapter="isaiah_36.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 36" prevChapter="isaiah_34.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 34" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The wilderness and the solitary place shall be glad for them; and the desert shall rejoice, and blossom as the rose.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">It shall blossom abundantly, and rejoice even with joy and singing: the glory of Lebanon shall be given unto it, the excellency of Carmel and Sharon, they shall see the glory of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the excellency of our God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Strengthen ye the weak hands, and confirm the feeble knees.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Say to them &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; of a fearful heart, Be strong, fear not: behold, your God will come &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; vengeance, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; God &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; a recompence; he will come and save you.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then the eyes of the blind shall be opened, and the ears of the deaf shall be unstopped.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Then shall the lame &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; leap as an hart, and the tongue of the dumb sing: for in the wilderness shall waters break out, and streams in the desert.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the parched ground shall become a pool, and the thirsty land springs of water: in the habitation of dragons, where each lay, &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; grass with reeds and rushes.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And an highway shall be there, and a way, and it shall be called The way of holiness; the unclean shall not pass over it; but it &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; for those: the wayfaring men, though fools, shall not err &lt;i&gt;therein&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">No lion shall be there, nor &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; ravenous beast shall go up thereon, it shall not be found there; but the redeemed shall walk &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the ransomed of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall return, and come to Zion with songs and everlasting joy upon their heads: they shall obtain joy and gladness, and sorrow and sighing shall flee away.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>