<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="23" name="Isaiah" bookPage="isaiah.html" title="Isaiah" chapterCount="66" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="jeremiah_1.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah" prevBook="song_of_solomon_1.html" prevTitle="Song of Solomon">
    <chapter number="34" verseCount="17" nextChapter="isaiah_35.html" nextTitle="Isaiah 35" prevChapter="isaiah_33.html" prevTitle="Isaiah 33" chapterPage="isaiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Come near, ye nations, to hear; and hearken, ye people: let the earth hear, and all that is therein; the world, and all things that come forth of it.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For the indignation of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon all nations, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; fury upon all their armies: he hath utterly destroyed them, he hath delivered them to the slaughter.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Their slain also shall be cast out, and their stink shall come up out of their carcases, and the mountains shall be melted with their blood.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And all the host of heaven shall be dissolved, and the heavens shall be rolled together as a scroll: and all their host shall fall down, as the leaf falleth off from the vine, and as a falling &lt;span class="extra"&gt;fig&lt;/span&gt; from the fig tree.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For my sword shall be bathed in heaven: behold, it shall come down upon Idumea, and upon the people of my curse, to judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The sword of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; is filled with blood, it is made fat with fatness, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; with the blood of lambs and goats, with the fat of the kidneys of rams: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath a sacrifice in Bozrah, and a great slaughter in the land of Idumea.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the unicorns shall come down with them, and the bullocks with the bulls; and their land shall be soaked with blood, and their dust made fat with fatness.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; the day of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s vengeance, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the year of recompences for the controversy of Zion.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the streams thereof shall be turned into pitch, and the dust thereof into brimstone, and the land thereof shall become burning pitch.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">It shall not be quenched night nor day; the smoke thereof shall go up for ever: from generation to generation it shall lie waste; none shall pass through it for ever and ever.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">But the cormorant and the bittern shall possess it; the owl also and the raven shall dwell in it: and he shall stretch out upon it the line of confusion, and the stones of emptiness.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They shall call the nobles thereof to the kingdom, but none &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; there, and all her princes shall be nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And thorns shall come up in her palaces, nettles and brambles in the fortresses thereof: and it shall be an habitation of dragons, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; a court for owls.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The wild beasts of the desert shall also meet with the wild beasts of the island, and the satyr shall cry to his fellow; the screech owl also shall rest there, and find for herself a place of rest.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">There shall the great owl make her nest, and lay, and hatch, and gather under her shadow: there shall the vultures also be gathered, every one with her mate.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Seek ye out of the book of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and read: no one of these shall fail, none shall want her mate: for my mouth it hath commanded, and his spirit it hath gathered them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he hath cast the lot for them, and his hand hath divided it unto them by line: they shall possess it for ever, from generation to generation shall they dwell therein.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>