<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="22" nextChapter="jeremiah_15.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 15" prevChapter="jeremiah_13.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 13" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that came to Jeremiah concerning the dearth.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Judah mourneth, and the gates thereof languish; they are black unto the ground; and the cry of Jerusalem is gone up.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And their nobles have sent their little ones to the waters: they came to the pits, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; found no water; they returned with their vessels empty; they were ashamed and confounded, and covered their heads.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Because the ground is chapt, for there was no rain in the earth, the plowmen were ashamed, they covered their heads.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Yea, the hind also calved in the field, and forsook &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, because there was no grass.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the wild asses did stand in the high places, they snuffed up the wind like dragons; their eyes did fail, because &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; no grass.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, though our iniquities testify against us, do thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; for thy name's sake: for our backslidings are many; we have sinned against thee.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">O the hope of Israel, the saviour thereof in time of trouble, why shouldest thou be as a stranger in the land, and as a wayfaring man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; turneth aside to tarry for a night?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Why shouldest thou be as a man astonied, as a mighty man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; cannot save? yet thou, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; in the midst of us, and we are called by thy name; leave us not.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto this people, Thus have they loved to wander, they have not refrained their feet, therefore the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; doth not accept them; he will now remember their iniquity, and visit their sins.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then said the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto me, Pray not for this people for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; good.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">When they fast, I will not hear their cry; and when they offer burnt offering and an oblation, I will not accept them: but I will consume them by the sword, and by the famine, and by the pestilence.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Then said I, Ah, Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;! behold, the prophets say unto them, Ye shall not see the sword, neither shall ye have famine; but I will give you assured peace in this place.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, The prophets prophesy lies in my name: I sent them not, neither have I commanded them, neither spake unto them: they prophesy unto you a false vision and divination, and a thing of nought, and the deceit of their heart.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; concerning the prophets that prophesy in my name, and I sent them not, yet they say, Sword and famine shall not be in this land; By sword and famine shall those prophets be consumed.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the people to whom they prophesy shall be cast out in the streets of Jerusalem because of the famine and the sword; and they shall have none to bury them, them, their wives, nor their sons, nor their daughters: for I will pour their wickedness upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Therefore thou shalt say this word unto them; Let mine eyes run down with tears night and day, and let them not cease: for the virgin daughter of my people is broken with a great breach, with a very grievous blow.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">If I go forth into the field, then behold the slain with the sword! and if I enter into the city, then behold them that are sick with famine! yea, both the prophet and the priest go about into a land that they know not.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Hast thou utterly rejected Judah? hath thy soul lothed Zion? why hast thou smitten us, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no healing for us? we looked for peace, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no good; and for the time of healing, and behold trouble!</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">We acknowledge, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, our wickedness, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the iniquity of our fathers: for we have sinned against thee.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Do not abhor &lt;span class="extra"&gt;us&lt;/span&gt;, for thy name's sake, do not disgrace the throne of thy glory: remember, break not thy covenant with us.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Are there &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; among the vanities of the Gentiles that can cause rain? or can the heavens give showers? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; not thou he, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God? therefore we will wait upon thee: for thou hast made all these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>