<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="37" verseCount="21" nextChapter="jeremiah_38.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 38" prevChapter="jeremiah_36.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 36" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And king Zedekiah the son of Josiah reigned instead of Coniah the son of Jehoiakim, whom Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon made king in the land of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">But neither he, nor his servants, nor the people of the land, did hearken unto the words of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which he spake by the prophet Jeremiah.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Zedekiah the king sent Jehucal the son of Shelemiah and Zephaniah the son of Maaseiah the priest to the prophet Jeremiah, saying, Pray now unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God for us.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Now Jeremiah came in and went out among the people: for they had not put him into prison.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then Pharaoh's army was come forth out of Egypt: and when the Chaldeans that besieged Jerusalem heard tidings of them, they departed from Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Then came the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto the prophet Jeremiah, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the God of Israel; Thus shall ye say to the king of Judah, that sent you unto me to enquire of me; Behold, Pharaoh's army, which is come forth to help you, shall return to Egypt into their own land.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the Chaldeans shall come again, and fight against this city, and take it, and burn it with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; Deceive not yourselves, saying, The Chaldeans shall surely depart from us: for they shall not depart.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For though ye had smitten the whole army of the Chaldeans that fight against you, and there remained &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; wounded men among them, &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; should they rise up every man in his tent, and burn this city with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And it came to pass, that when the army of the Chaldeans was broken up from Jerusalem for fear of Pharaoh's army,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Then Jeremiah went forth out of Jerusalem to go into the land of Benjamin, to separate himself thence in the midst of the people.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And when he was in the gate of Benjamin, a captain of the ward &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; there, whose name &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Irijah, the son of Shelemiah, the son of Hananiah; and he took Jeremiah the prophet, saying, Thou fallest away to the Chaldeans.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then said Jeremiah, &lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; false; I fall not away to the Chaldeans. But he hearkened not to him: so Irijah took Jeremiah, and brought him to the princes.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Wherefore the princes were wroth with Jeremiah, and smote him, and put him in prison in the house of Jonathan the scribe: for they had made that the prison.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">When Jeremiah was entered into the dungeon, and into the cabins, and Jeremiah had remained there many days;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then Zedekiah the king sent, and took him out: and the king asked him secretly in his house, and said, Is there &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; word from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;? And Jeremiah said, There is: for, said he, thou shalt be delivered into the hand of the king of Babylon.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Moreover Jeremiah said unto king Zedekiah, What have I offended against thee, or against thy servants, or against this people, that ye have put me in prison?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Where &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; now your prophets which prophesied unto you, saying, The king of Babylon shall not come against you, nor against this land?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Therefore hear now, I pray thee, O my lord the king: let my supplication, I pray thee, be accepted before thee; that thou cause me not to return to the house of Jonathan the scribe, lest I die there.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then Zedekiah the king commanded that they should commit Jeremiah into the court of the prison, and that they should give him daily a piece of bread out of the bakers' street, until all the bread in the city were spent. Thus Jeremiah remained in the court of the prison.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>