<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="30" nextChapter="jeremiah_7.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 7" prevChapter="jeremiah_5.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 5" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O ye children of Benjamin, gather yourselves to flee out of the midst of Jerusalem, and blow the trumpet in Tekoa, and set up a sign of fire in Beth-haccerem: for evil appeareth out of the north, and great destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I have likened the daughter of Zion to a comely and delicate &lt;span class='extra'&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The shepherds with their flocks shall come unto her; they shall pitch &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; tents against her round about; they shall feed every one in his place.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Prepare ye war against her; arise, and let us go up at noon. Woe unto us! for the day goeth away, for the shadows of the evening are stretched out.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Arise, and let us go by night, and let us destroy her palaces.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">For thus hath the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts said, Hew ye down trees, and cast a mount against Jerusalem: this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the city to be visited; she &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; wholly oppression in the midst of her.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">As a fountain casteth out her waters, so she casteth out her wickedness: violence and spoil is heard in her; before me continually &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; grief and wounds.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Be thou instructed, O Jerusalem, lest my soul depart from thee; lest I make thee desolate, a land not inhabited.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, They shall throughly glean the remnant of Israel as a vine: turn back thine hand as a grapegatherer into the baskets.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">To whom shall I speak, and give warning, that they may hear? behold, their ear &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; uncircumcised, and they cannot hearken: behold, the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; is unto them a reproach; they have no delight in it.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Therefore I am full of the fury of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; I am weary with holding in: I will pour it out upon the children abroad, and upon the assembly of young men together: for even the husband with the wife shall be taken, the aged with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him that is&lt;/span&gt; full of days.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And their houses shall be turned unto others, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with their&lt;/span&gt; fields and wives together: for I will stretch out my hand upon the inhabitants of the land, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For from the least of them even unto the greatest of them every one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; given to covetousness; and from the prophet even unto the priest every one dealeth falsely.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">They have healed also the hurt &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of the daughter&lt;/span&gt; of my people slightly, saying, Peace, peace; when &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no peace.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Were they ashamed when they had committed abomination? nay, they were not at all ashamed, neither could they blush: therefore they shall fall among them that fall: at the time &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; I visit them they shall be cast down, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Stand ye in the ways, and see, and ask for the old paths, where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the good way, and walk therein, and ye shall find rest for your souls. But they said, We will not walk &lt;span class='extra'&gt;therein&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Also I set watchmen over you, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Hearken to the sound of the trumpet. But they said, We will not hearken.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Therefore hear, ye nations, and know, O congregation, what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; among them.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Hear, O earth: behold, I will bring evil upon this people, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the fruit of their thoughts, because they have not hearkened unto my words, nor to my law, but rejected it.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">To what purpose cometh there to me incense from Sheba, and the sweet cane from a far country? your burnt offerings &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not acceptable, nor your sacrifices sweet unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Behold, I will lay stumblingblocks before this people, and the fathers and the sons together shall fall upon them; the neighbour and his friend shall perish.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Behold, a people cometh from the north country, and a great nation shall be raised from the sides of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">They shall lay hold on bow and spear; they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; cruel, and have no mercy; their voice roareth like the sea; and they ride upon horses, set in array as men for war against thee, O daughter of Zion.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">We have heard the fame thereof: our hands wax feeble: anguish hath taken hold of us, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; pain, as of a woman in travail.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Go not forth into the field, nor walk by the way; for the sword of the enemy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; fear &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; on every side.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">O daughter of my people, gird &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt; with sackcloth, and wallow thyself in ashes: make thee mourning, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; an only son, most bitter lamentation: for the spoiler shall suddenly come upon us.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">I have set thee &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a tower &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; a fortress among my people, that thou mayest know and try their way.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">They &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all grievous revolters, walking with slanders: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they are&lt;/span&gt; brass and iron; they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all corrupters.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The bellows are burned, the lead is consumed of the fire; the founder melteth in vain: for the wicked are not plucked away.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Reprobate silver shall &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; call them, because the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath rejected them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>