<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="19" verseCount="15" nextChapter="jeremiah_20.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 20" prevChapter="jeremiah_18.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 18" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Go and get a potter's earthen bottle, and &lt;i&gt;take&lt;/i&gt; of the ancients of the people, and of the ancients of the priests;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And go forth unto the valley of the son of Hinnom, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; by the entry of the east gate, and proclaim there the words that I shall tell thee,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And say, Hear ye the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, O kings of Judah, and inhabitants of Jerusalem; Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; Behold, I will bring evil upon this place, the which whosoever heareth, his ears shall tingle.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Because they have forsaken me, and have estranged this place, and have burned incense in it unto other gods, whom neither they nor their fathers have known, nor the kings of Judah, and have filled this place with the blood of innocents;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They have built also the high places of Baal, to burn their sons with fire &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; burnt offerings unto Baal, which I commanded not, nor spake &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, neither came &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; into my mind:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Therefore, behold, the days come, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that this place shall no more be called Tophet, nor The valley of the son of Hinnom, but The valley of slaughter.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And I will make void the counsel of Judah and Jerusalem in this place; and I will cause them to fall by the sword before their enemies, and by the hands of them that seek their lives: and their carcases will I give to be meat for the fowls of the heaven, and for the beasts of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I will make this city desolate, and an hissing; every one that passeth thereby shall be astonished and hiss because of all the plagues thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And I will cause them to eat the flesh of their sons and the flesh of their daughters, and they shall eat every one the flesh of his friend in the siege and straitness, wherewith their enemies, and they that seek their lives, shall straiten them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then shalt thou break the bottle in the sight of the men that go with thee,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And shalt say unto them, Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; Even so will I break this people and this city, as &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; breaketh a potter's vessel, that cannot be made whole again: and they shall bury &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in Tophet, till &lt;i&gt;there be&lt;/i&gt; no place to bury.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Thus will I do unto this place, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and to the inhabitants thereof, and &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; make this city as Tophet:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the houses of Jerusalem, and the houses of the kings of Judah, shall be defiled as the place of Tophet, because of all the houses upon whose roofs they have burned incense unto all the host of heaven, and have poured out drink offerings unto other gods.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then came Jeremiah from Tophet, whither the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had sent him to prophesy; and he stood in the court of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s house; and said to all the people,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; Behold, I will bring upon this city and upon all her towns all the evil that I have pronounced against it, because they have hardened their necks, that they might not hear my words.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>