<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="50" verseCount="46" nextChapter="jeremiah_51.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 51" prevChapter="jeremiah_49.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 49" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake against Babylon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; against the land of the Chaldeans by Jeremiah the prophet.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Declare ye among the nations, and publish, and set up a standard; publish, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; conceal not: say, Babylon is taken, Bel is confounded, Merodach is broken in pieces; her idols are confounded, her images are broken in pieces.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For out of the north there cometh up a nation against her, which shall make her land desolate, and none shall dwell therein: they shall remove, they shall depart, both man and beast.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">In those days, and in that time, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the children of Israel shall come, they and the children of Judah together, going and weeping: they shall go, and seek the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They shall ask the way to Zion with their faces thitherward, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Come, and let us join ourselves to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in a perpetual covenant &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shall not be forgotten.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">My people hath been lost sheep: their shepherds have caused them to go astray, they have turned them away &lt;span class="extra"&gt;on&lt;/span&gt; the mountains: they have gone from mountain to hill, they have forgotten their restingplace.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">All that found them have devoured them: and their adversaries said, We offend not, because they have sinned against the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the habitation of justice, even the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the hope of their fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Remove out of the midst of Babylon, and go forth out of the land of the Chaldeans, and be as the he goats before the flocks.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">For, lo, I will raise and cause to come up against Babylon an assembly of great nations from the north country: and they shall set themselves in array against her; from thence she shall be taken: their arrows &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; as of a mighty expert man; none shall return in vain.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And Chaldea shall be a spoil: all that spoil her shall be satisfied, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Because ye were glad, because ye rejoiced, O ye destroyers of mine heritage, because ye are grown fat as the heifer at grass, and bellow as bulls;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Your mother shall be sore confounded; she that bare you shall be ashamed: behold, the hindermost of the nations &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a wilderness, a dry land, and a desert.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Because of the wrath of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; it shall not be inhabited, but it shall be wholly desolate: every one that goeth by Babylon shall be astonished, and hiss at all her plagues.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Put yourselves in array against Babylon round about: all ye that bend the bow, shoot at her, spare no arrows: for she hath sinned against the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Shout against her round about: she hath given her hand: her foundations are fallen, her walls are thrown down: for it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the vengeance of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: take vengeance upon her; as she hath done, do unto her.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Cut off the sower from Babylon, and him that handleth the sickle in the time of harvest: for fear of the oppressing sword they shall turn every one to his people, and they shall flee every one to his own land.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a scattered sheep; the lions have driven &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; away: first the king of Assyria hath devoured him; and last this Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon hath broken his bones.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; Behold, I will punish the king of Babylon and his land, as I have punished the king of Assyria.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And I will bring Israel again to his habitation, and he shall feed on Carmel and Bashan, and his soul shall be satisfied upon mount Ephraim and Gilead.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">In those days, and in that time, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the iniquity of Israel shall be sought for, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; none; and the sins of Judah, and they shall not be found: for I will pardon them whom I reserve.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Go up against the land of Merathaim, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; against it, and against the inhabitants of Pekod: waste and utterly destroy after them, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and do according to all that I have commanded thee.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">A sound of battle &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the land, and of great destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">How is the hammer of the whole earth cut asunder and broken! how is Babylon become a desolation among the nations!</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">I have laid a snare for thee, and thou art also taken, O Babylon, and thou wast not aware: thou art found, and also caught, because thou hast striven against the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath opened his armoury, and hath brought forth the weapons of his indignation: for this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the work of the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts in the land of the Chaldeans.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Come against her from the utmost border, open her storehouses: cast her up as heaps, and destroy her utterly: let nothing of her be left.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Slay all her bullocks; let them go down to the slaughter: woe unto them! for their day is come, the time of their visitation.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The voice of them that flee and escape out of the land of Babylon, to declare in Zion the vengeance of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, the vengeance of his temple.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Call together the archers against Babylon: all ye that bend the bow, camp against it round about; let none thereof escape: recompense her according to her work; according to all that she hath done, do unto her: for she hath been proud against the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, against the Holy One of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Therefore shall her young men fall in the streets, and all her men of war shall be cut off in that day, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Behold, I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; against thee, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;O thou&lt;/span&gt; most proud, saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts: for thy day is come, the time &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; I will visit thee.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And the most proud shall stumble and fall, and none shall raise him up: and I will kindle a fire in his cities, and it shall devour all round about him.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; The children of Israel and the children of Judah &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; oppressed together: and all that took them captives held them fast; they refused to let them go.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Their Redeemer &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; strong; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his name: he shall throughly plead their cause, that he may give rest to the land, and disquiet the inhabitants of Babylon.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35" newPara="true">A sword &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the Chaldeans, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and upon the inhabitants of Babylon, and upon her princes, and upon her wise &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">A sword &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon the liars; and they shall dote: a sword &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon her mighty men; and they shall be dismayed.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">A sword &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon their horses, and upon their chariots, and upon all the mingled people that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in the midst of her; and they shall become as women: a sword &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon her treasures; and they shall be robbed.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">A drought &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon her waters; and they shall be dried up: for it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the land of graven images, and they are mad upon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; idols.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Therefore the wild beasts of the desert with the wild beasts of the islands shall dwell &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there&lt;/span&gt;, and the owls shall dwell therein: and it shall be no more inhabited for ever; neither shall it be dwelt in from generation to generation.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">As God overthrew Sodom and Gomorrah and the neighbour &lt;span class="extra"&gt;cities&lt;/span&gt; thereof, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; shall no man abide there, neither shall any son of man dwell therein.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Behold, a people shall come from the north, and a great nation, and many kings shall be raised up from the coasts of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">They shall hold the bow and the lance: they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; cruel, and will not shew mercy: their voice shall roar like the sea, and they shall ride upon horses, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;every one&lt;/span&gt; put in array, like a man to the battle, against thee, O daughter of Babylon.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">The king of Babylon hath heard the report of them, and his hands waxed feeble: anguish took hold of him, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; pangs as of a woman in travail.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">Behold, he shall come up like a lion from the swelling of Jordan unto the habitation of the strong: but I will make them suddenly run away from her: and who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a chosen &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man, that&lt;/span&gt; I may appoint over her? for who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; like me? and who will appoint me the time? and who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; that shepherd that will stand before me?</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">Therefore hear ye the counsel of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that he hath taken against Babylon; and his purposes, that he hath purposed against the land of the Chaldeans: Surely the least of the flock shall draw them out: surely he shall make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; habitation desolate with them.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">At the noise of the taking of Babylon the earth is moved, and the cry is heard among the nations.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>