<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="47" verseCount="7" nextChapter="jeremiah_48.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 48" prevChapter="jeremiah_46.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 46" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that came to Jeremiah the prophet against the Philistines, before that Pharaoh smote Gaza.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, waters rise up out of the north, and shall be an overflowing flood, and shall overflow the land, and all that is therein; the city, and them that dwell therein: then the men shall cry, and all the inhabitants of the land shall howl.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">At the noise of the stamping of the hoofs of his strong &lt;span class="extra"&gt;horses&lt;/span&gt;, at the rushing of his chariots, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and at&lt;/span&gt; the rumbling of his wheels, the fathers shall not look back to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; children for feebleness of hands;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Because of the day that cometh to spoil all the Philistines, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to cut off from Tyrus and Zidon every helper that remaineth: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will spoil the Philistines, the remnant of the country of Caphtor.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Baldness is come upon Gaza; Ashkelon is cut off &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; the remnant of their valley: how long wilt thou cut thyself?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">O thou sword of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, how long &lt;span class="extra"&gt;will it be&lt;/span&gt; ere thou be quiet? put up thyself into thy scabbard, rest, and be still.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">How can it be quiet, seeing the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath given it a charge against Ashkelon, and against the sea shore? there hath he appointed it.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>