<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="42" verseCount="22" nextChapter="jeremiah_43.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 43" prevChapter="jeremiah_41.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 41" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then all the captains of the forces, and Johanan the son of Kareah, and Jezaniah the son of Hoshaiah, and all the people from the least even unto the greatest, came near,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And said unto Jeremiah the prophet, Let, we beseech thee, our supplication be accepted before thee, and pray for us unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; for all this remnant; (for we are left &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; a few of many, as thine eyes do behold us:)</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">That the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God may shew us the way wherein we may walk, and the thing that we may do.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Then Jeremiah the prophet said unto them, I have heard &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;; behold, I will pray unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God according to your words; and it shall come to pass, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; whatsoever thing the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall answer you, I will declare &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; unto you; I will keep nothing back from you.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then they said to Jeremiah, The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; be a true and faithful witness between us, if we do not even according to all things for the which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God shall send thee to us.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Whether &lt;i&gt;it be&lt;/i&gt; good, or whether &lt;i&gt;it be&lt;/i&gt; evil, we will obey the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, to whom we send thee; that it may be well with us, when we obey the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And it came to pass after ten days, that the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto Jeremiah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then called he Johanan the son of Kareah, and all the captains of the forces which &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; with him, and all the people from the least even to the greatest,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And said unto them, Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the God of Israel, unto whom ye sent me to present your supplication before him;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">If ye will still abide in this land, then will I build you, and not pull &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; down, and I will plant you, and not pluck &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; up: for I repent me of the evil that I have done unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Be not afraid of the king of Babylon, of whom ye are afraid; be not afraid of him, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; with you to save you, and to deliver you from his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I will shew mercies unto you, that he may have mercy upon you, and cause you to return to your own land.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">But if ye say, We will not dwell in this land, neither obey the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Saying, No; but we will go into the land of Egypt, where we shall see no war, nor hear the sound of the trumpet, nor have hunger of bread; and there will we dwell:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And now therefore hear the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, ye remnant of Judah; Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; If ye wholly set your faces to enter into Egypt, and go to sojourn there;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Then it shall come to pass, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the sword, which ye feared, shall overtake you there in the land of Egypt, and the famine, whereof ye were afraid, shall follow close after you there in Egypt; and there ye shall die.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">So shall it be with all the men that set their faces to go into Egypt to sojourn there; they shall die by the sword, by the famine, and by the pestilence: and none of them shall remain or escape from the evil that I will bring upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; As mine anger and my fury hath been poured forth upon the inhabitants of Jerusalem; so shall my fury be poured forth upon you, when ye shall enter into Egypt: and ye shall be an execration, and an astonishment, and a curse, and a reproach; and ye shall see this place no more.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath said concerning you, O ye remnant of Judah; Go ye not into Egypt: know certainly that I have admonished you this day.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For ye dissembled in your hearts, when ye sent me unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, saying, Pray for us unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God; and according unto all that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God shall say, so declare unto us, and we will do &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And &lt;i&gt;now&lt;/i&gt; I have this day declared &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to you; but ye have not obeyed the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, nor any &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt; for the which he hath sent me unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Now therefore know certainly that ye shall die by the sword, by the famine, and by the pestilence, in the place whither ye desire to go &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; to sojourn.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>