<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="25" verseCount="38" nextChapter="jeremiah_26.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 26" prevChapter="jeremiah_24.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 24" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word that came to Jeremiah concerning all the people of Judah in the fourth year of Jehoiakim the son of Josiah king of Judah, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the first year of Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The which Jeremiah the prophet spake unto all the people of Judah, and to all the inhabitants of Jerusalem, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">From the thirteenth year of Josiah the son of Amon king of Judah, even unto this day, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the three and twentieth year, the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath come unto me, and I have spoken unto you, rising early and speaking; but ye have not hearkened.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath sent unto you all his servants the prophets, rising early and sending &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;; but ye have not hearkened, nor inclined your ear to hear.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They said, Turn ye again now every one from his evil way, and from the evil of your doings, and dwell in the land that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath given unto you and to your fathers for ever and ever:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And go not after other gods to serve them, and to worship them, and provoke me not to anger with the works of your hands; and I will do you no hurt.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Yet ye have not hearkened unto me, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; that ye might provoke me to anger with the works of your hands to your own hurt.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; Because ye have not heard my words,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Behold, I will send and take all the families of the north, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and Nebuchadrezzar the king of Babylon, my servant, and will bring them against this land, and against the inhabitants thereof, and against all these nations round about, and will utterly destroy them, and make them an astonishment, and an hissing, and perpetual desolations.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Moreover I will take from them the voice of mirth, and the voice of gladness, the voice of the bridegroom, and the voice of the bride, the sound of the millstones, and the light of the candle.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And this whole land shall be a desolation, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; an astonishment; and these nations shall serve the king of Babylon seventy years.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And it shall come to pass, when seventy years are accomplished, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; I will punish the king of Babylon, and that nation, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, for their iniquity, and the land of the Chaldeans, and will make it perpetual desolations.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And I will bring upon that land all my words which I have pronounced against it, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all that is written in this book, which Jeremiah hath prophesied against all the nations.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For many nations and great kings shall serve themselves of them also: and I will recompense them according to their deeds, and according to the works of their own hands.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">For thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel unto me; Take the wine cup of this fury at my hand, and cause all the nations, to whom I send thee, to drink it.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And they shall drink, and be moved, and be mad, because of the sword that I will send among them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then took I the cup at the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s hand, and made all the nations to drink, unto whom the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had sent me:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;To wit&lt;/span&gt;, Jerusalem, and the cities of Judah, and the kings thereof, and the princes thereof, to make them a desolation, an astonishment, an hissing, and a curse; as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; this day;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Pharaoh king of Egypt, and his servants, and his princes, and all his people;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And all the mingled people, and all the kings of the land of Uz, and all the kings of the land of the Philistines, and Ashkelon, and Azzah, and Ekron, and the remnant of Ashdod,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Edom, and Moab, and the children of Ammon,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And all the kings of Tyrus, and all the kings of Zidon, and the kings of the isles which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; beyond the sea,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Dedan, and Tema, and Buz, and all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; in the utmost corners,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And all the kings of Arabia, and all the kings of the mingled people that dwell in the desert,</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And all the kings of Zimri, and all the kings of Elam, and all the kings of the Medes,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And all the kings of the north, far and near, one with another, and all the kingdoms of the world, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; upon the face of the earth: and the king of Sheshach shall drink after them.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Therefore thou shalt say unto them, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; Drink ye, and be drunken, and spue, and fall, and rise no more, because of the sword which I will send among you.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And it shall be, if they refuse to take the cup at thine hand to drink, then shalt thou say unto them, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; Ye shall certainly drink.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For, lo, I begin to bring evil on the city which is called by my name, and should ye be utterly unpunished? Ye shall not be unpunished: for I will call for a sword upon all the inhabitants of the earth, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Therefore prophesy thou against them all these words, and say unto them, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall roar from on high, and utter his voice from his holy habitation; he shall mightily roar upon his habitation; he shall give a shout, as they that tread &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the grapes&lt;/span&gt;, against all the inhabitants of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">A noise shall come &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to the ends of the earth; for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath a controversy with the nations, he will plead with all flesh; he will give them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; wicked to the sword, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, Behold, evil shall go forth from nation to nation, and a great whirlwind shall be raised up from the coasts of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And the slain of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be at that day from &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; end of the earth even unto the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; end of the earth: they shall not be lamented, neither gathered, nor buried; they shall be dung upon the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">Howl, ye shepherds, and cry; and wallow yourselves &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in the ashes&lt;/span&gt;, ye principal of the flock: for the days of your slaughter and of your dispersions are accomplished; and ye shall fall like a pleasant vessel.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And the shepherds shall have no way to flee, nor the principal of the flock to escape.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">A voice of the cry of the shepherds, and an howling of the principal of the flock, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be heard&lt;/span&gt;: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoiled their pasture.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And the peaceable habitations are cut down because of the fierce anger of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">He hath forsaken his covert, as the lion: for their land is desolate because of the fierceness of the oppressor, and because of his fierce anger.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>