<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="18" nextChapter="jeremiah_21.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 21" prevChapter="jeremiah_19.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 19" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now Pashur the son of Immer the priest, who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; also chief governor in the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, heard that Jeremiah prophesied these things.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then Pashur smote Jeremiah the prophet, and put him in the stocks that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the high gate of Benjamin, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; by the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And it came to pass on the morrow, that Pashur brought forth Jeremiah out of the stocks. Then said Jeremiah unto him, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath not called thy name Pashur, but Magor-missabib.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Behold, I will make thee a terror to thyself, and to all thy friends: and they shall fall by the sword of their enemies, and thine eyes shall behold &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;: and I will give all Judah into the hand of the king of Babylon, and he shall carry them captive into Babylon, and shall slay them with the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Moreover I will deliver all the strength of this city, and all the labours thereof, and all the precious things thereof, and all the treasures of the kings of Judah will I give into the hand of their enemies, which shall spoil them, and take them, and carry them to Babylon.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And thou, Pashur, and all that dwell in thine house shall go into captivity: and thou shalt come to Babylon, and there thou shalt die, and shalt be buried there, thou, and all thy friends, to whom thou hast prophesied lies.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou hast deceived me, and I was deceived: thou art stronger than I, and hast prevailed: I am in derision daily, every one mocketh me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For since I spake, I cried out, I cried violence and spoil; because the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was made a reproach unto me, and a derision, daily.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then I said, I will not make mention of him, nor speak any more in his name. But &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his word&lt;/span&gt; was in mine heart as a burning fire shut up in my bones, and I was weary with forbearing, and I could not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;stay&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">For I heard the defaming of many, fear on every side. Report, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;say they&lt;/span&gt;, and we will report it. All my familiars watched for my halting, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Peradventure he will be enticed, and we shall prevail against him, and we shall take our revenge on him.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with me as a mighty terrible one: therefore my persecutors shall stumble, and they shall not prevail: they shall be greatly ashamed; for they shall not prosper: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; everlasting confusion shall never be forgotten.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, that triest the righteous, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; seest the reins and the heart, let me see thy vengeance on them: for unto thee have I opened my cause.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Sing unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, praise ye the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for he hath delivered the soul of the poor from the hand of evildoers.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Cursed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the day wherein I was born: let not the day wherein my mother bare me be blessed.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Cursed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the man who brought tidings to my father, saying, A man child is born unto thee; making him very glad.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And let that man be as the cities which the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; overthrew, and repented not: and let him hear the cry in the morning, and the shouting at noontide;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Because he slew me not from the womb; or that my mother might have been my grave, and her womb &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; always great &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with me&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Wherefore came I forth out of the womb to see labour and sorrow, that my days should be consumed with shame?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>