<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="27" nextChapter="jeremiah_14.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 14" prevChapter="jeremiah_12.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 12" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto me, Go and get thee a linen girdle, and put it upon thy loins, and put it not in water.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">So I got a girdle according to the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on my loins.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me the second time, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Take the girdle that thou hast got, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon thy loins, and arise, go to Euphrates, and hide it there in a hole of the rock.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">So I went, and hid it by Euphrates, as the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commanded me.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And it came to pass after many days, that the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, Arise, go to Euphrates, and take the girdle from thence, which I commanded thee to hide there.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then I went to Euphrates, and digged, and took the girdle from the place where I had hid it: and, behold, the girdle was marred, it was profitable for nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, After this manner will I mar the pride of Judah, and the great pride of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">This evil people, which refuse to hear my words, which walk in the imagination of their heart, and walk after other gods, to serve them, and to worship them, shall even be as this girdle, which is good for nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For as the girdle cleaveth to the loins of a man, so have I caused to cleave unto me the whole house of Israel and the whole house of Judah, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; that they might be unto me for a people, and for a name, and for a praise, and for a glory: but they would not hear.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Therefore thou shalt speak unto them this word; Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of Israel, Every bottle shall be filled with wine: and they shall say unto thee, Do we not certainly know that every bottle shall be filled with wine?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then shalt thou say unto them, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Behold, I will fill all the inhabitants of this land, even the kings that sit upon David's throne, and the priests, and the prophets, and all the inhabitants of Jerusalem, with drunkenness.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And I will dash them one against another, even the fathers and the sons together, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: I will not pity, nor spare, nor have mercy, but destroy them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Hear ye, and give ear; be not proud: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Give glory to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, before he cause darkness, and before your feet stumble upon the dark mountains, and, while ye look for light, he turn it into the shadow of death, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; gross darkness.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But if ye will not hear it, my soul shall weep in secret places for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; pride; and mine eye shall weep sore, and run down with tears, because the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s flock is carried away captive.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Say unto the king and to the queen, Humble yourselves, sit down: for your principalities shall come down, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the crown of your glory.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The cities of the south shall be shut up, and none shall open &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;: Judah shall be carried away captive all of it, it shall be wholly carried away captive.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Lift up your eyes, and behold them that come from the north: where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the flock &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; was given thee, thy beautiful flock?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">What wilt thou say when he shall punish thee? for thou hast taught them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; captains, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; as chief over thee: shall not sorrows take thee, as a woman in travail?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And if thou say in thine heart, Wherefore come these things upon me? For the greatness of thine iniquity are thy skirts discovered, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; thy heels made bare.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Can the Ethiopian change his skin, or the leopard his spots? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; may ye also do good, that are accustomed to do evil.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Therefore will I scatter them as the stubble that passeth away by the wind of the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy lot, the portion of thy measures from me, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; because thou hast forgotten me, and trusted in falsehood.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Therefore will I discover thy skirts upon thy face, that thy shame may appear.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">I have seen thine adulteries, and thy neighings, the lewdness of thy whoredom, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; thine abominations on the hills in the fields. Woe unto thee, O Jerusalem! wilt thou not be made clean? when &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall it&lt;/span&gt; once &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>