<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="25" nextChapter="jeremiah_11.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 11" prevChapter="jeremiah_9.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 9" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hear ye the word which the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; speaketh unto you, O house of Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Learn not the way of the heathen, and be not dismayed at the signs of heaven; for the heathen are dismayed at them.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For the customs of the people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; vain: for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; cutteth a tree out of the forest, the work of the hands of the workman, with the axe.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They deck it with silver and with gold; they fasten it with nails and with hammers, that it move not.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; upright as the palm tree, but speak not: they must needs be borne, because they cannot go. Be not afraid of them; for they cannot do evil, neither also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt; in them to do good.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Forasmuch as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none like unto thee, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; thou &lt;span class="extra"&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; great, and thy name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; great in might.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Who would not fear thee, O King of nations? for to thee doth it appertain: forasmuch as among all the wise &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; of the nations, and in all their kingdoms, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none like unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But they are altogether brutish and foolish: the stock &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a doctrine of vanities.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Silver spread into plates is brought from Tarshish, and gold from Uphaz, the work of the workman, and of the hands of the founder: blue and purple &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; their clothing: they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all the work of cunning &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the true God, he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the living God, and an everlasting king: at his wrath the earth shall tremble, and the nations shall not be able to abide his indignation.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thus shall ye say unto them, The gods that have not made the heavens and the earth, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; they shall perish from the earth, and from under these heavens.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">He hath made the earth by his power, he hath established the world by his wisdom, and hath stretched out the heavens by his discretion.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">When he uttereth his voice, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; a multitude of waters in the heavens, and he causeth the vapours to ascend from the ends of the earth; he maketh lightnings with rain, and bringeth forth the wind out of his treasures.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Every man is brutish in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; knowledge: every founder is confounded by the graven image: for his molten image &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; falsehood, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no breath in them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">They &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; vanity, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the work of errors: in the time of their visitation they shall perish.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The portion of Jacob &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not like them: for he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the former of all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;; and Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the rod of his inheritance: The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his name.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Gather up thy wares out of the land, O inhabitant of the fortress.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Behold, I will sling out the inhabitants of the land at this once, and will distress them, that they may find &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it so&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">Woe is me for my hurt! my wound is grievous: but I said, Truly this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a grief, and I must bear it.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">My tabernacle is spoiled, and all my cords are broken: my children are gone forth of me, and they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none to stretch forth my tent any more, and to set up my curtains.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For the pastors are become brutish, and have not sought the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: therefore they shall not prosper, and all their flocks shall be scattered.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Behold, the noise of the bruit is come, and a great commotion out of the north country, to make the cities of Judah desolate, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; a den of dragons.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I know that the way of man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not in himself: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; not in man that walketh to direct his steps.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, correct me, but with judgment; not in thine anger, lest thou bring me to nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Pour out thy fury upon the heathen that know thee not, and upon the families that call not on thy name: for they have eaten up Jacob, and devoured him, and consumed him, and have made his habitation desolate.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>