<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="26" nextChapter="jeremiah_10.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 10" prevChapter="jeremiah_8.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 8" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Oh that my head were waters, and mine eyes a fountain of tears, that I might weep day and night for the slain of the daughter of my people!</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Oh that I had in the wilderness a lodging place of wayfaring men; that I might leave my people, and go from them! for they &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; all adulterers, an assembly of treacherous men.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they bend their tongues &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; their bow &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; lies: but they are not valiant for the truth upon the earth; for they proceed from evil to evil, and they know not me, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Take ye heed every one of his neighbour, and trust ye not in any brother: for every brother will utterly supplant, and every neighbour will walk with slanders.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they will deceive every one his neighbour, and will not speak the truth: they have taught their tongue to speak lies, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; weary themselves to commit iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thine habitation &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the midst of deceit; through deceit they refuse to know me, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, Behold, I will melt them, and try them; for how shall I do for the daughter of my people?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Their tongue &lt;i&gt;is as&lt;/i&gt; an arrow shot out; it speaketh deceit: &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; speaketh peaceably to his neighbour with his mouth, but in heart he layeth his wait.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Shall I not visit them for these &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt;? saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: shall not my soul be avenged on such a nation as this?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For the mountains will I take up a weeping and wailing, and for the habitations of the wilderness a lamentation, because they are burned up, so that none can pass through &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;; neither can &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; hear the voice of the cattle; both the fowl of the heavens and the beast are fled; they are gone.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I will make Jerusalem heaps, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; a den of dragons; and I will make the cities of Judah desolate, without an inhabitant.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the wise man, that may understand this? and &lt;i&gt;who is he&lt;/i&gt; to whom the mouth of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken, that he may declare it, for what the land perisheth &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; is burned up like a wilderness, that none passeth through?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; saith, Because they have forsaken my law which I set before them, and have not obeyed my voice, neither walked therein;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But have walked after the imagination of their own heart, and after Baalim, which their fathers taught them:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; Behold, I will feed them, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; this people, with wormwood, and give them water of gall to drink.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I will scatter them also among the heathen, whom neither they nor their fathers have known: and I will send a sword after them, till I have consumed them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, Consider ye, and call for the mourning women, that they may come; and send for cunning &lt;i&gt;women&lt;/i&gt;, that they may come:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And let them make haste, and take up a wailing for us, that our eyes may run down with tears, and our eyelids gush out with waters.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For a voice of wailing is heard out of Zion, How are we spoiled! we are greatly confounded, because we have forsaken the land, because our dwellings have cast &lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt; out.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Yet hear the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, O ye women, and let your ear receive the word of his mouth, and teach your daughters wailing, and every one her neighbour lamentation.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For death is come up into our windows, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; is entered into our palaces, to cut off the children from without, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the young men from the streets.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Speak, Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Even the carcases of men shall fall as dung upon the open field, and as the handful after the harvestman, and none shall gather &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Let not the wise &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; glory in his wisdom, neither let the mighty &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; glory in his might, let not the rich &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; glory in his riches:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But let him that glorieth glory in this, that he understandeth and knoweth me, that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which exercise lovingkindness, judgment, and righteousness, in the earth: for in these &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; I delight, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">Behold, the days come, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that I will punish all &lt;i&gt;them which are&lt;/i&gt; circumcised with the uncircumcised;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Egypt, and Judah, and Edom, and the children of Ammon, and Moab, and all &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; in the utmost corners, that dwell in the wilderness: for all &lt;i&gt;these&lt;/i&gt; nations &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; uncircumcised, and all the house of Israel &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; uncircumcised in the heart.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>