<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="49" verseCount="39" nextChapter="jeremiah_50.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 50" prevChapter="jeremiah_48.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 48" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Concerning the Ammonites, thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; Hath Israel no sons? hath he no heir? why &lt;span class='extra'&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; doth their king inherit Gad, and his people dwell in his cities?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Therefore, behold, the days come, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that I will cause an alarm of war to be heard in Rabbah of the Ammonites; and it shall be a desolate heap, and her daughters shall be burned with fire: then shall Israel be heir unto them that were his heirs, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Howl, O Heshbon, for Ai is spoiled: cry, ye daughters of Rabbah, gird you with sackcloth; lament, and run to and fro by the hedges; for their king shall go into captivity, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; his priests and his princes together.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Wherefore gloriest thou in the valleys, thy flowing valley, O backsliding daughter? that trusted in her treasures, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Who shall come unto me?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Behold, I will bring a fear upon thee, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, from all those that be about thee; and ye shall be driven out every man right forth; and none shall gather up him that wandereth.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And afterward I will bring again the captivity of the children of Ammon, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Concerning Edom, thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; wisdom no more in Teman? is counsel perished from the prudent? is their wisdom vanished?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Flee ye, turn back, dwell deep, O inhabitants of Dedan; for I will bring the calamity of Esau upon him, the time &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; I will visit him.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">If grapegatherers come to thee, would they not leave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; gleaning grapes? if thieves by night, they will destroy till they have enough.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But I have made Esau bare, I have uncovered his secret places, and he shall not be able to hide himself: his seed is spoiled, and his brethren, and his neighbours, and he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Leave thy fatherless children, I will preserve &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; alive; and let thy widows trust in me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, they whose judgment &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; not to drink of the cup have assuredly drunken; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; thou he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shall altogether go unpunished? thou shalt not go unpunished, but thou shalt surely drink &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For I have sworn by myself, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that Bozrah shall become a desolation, a reproach, a waste, and a curse; and all the cities thereof shall be perpetual wastes.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I have heard a rumour from the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and an ambassador is sent unto the heathen, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, Gather ye together, and come against her, and rise up to the battle.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For, lo, I will make thee small among the heathen, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; despised among men.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thy terribleness hath deceived thee, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the pride of thine heart, O thou that dwellest in the clefts of the rock, that holdest the height of the hill: though thou shouldest make thy nest as high as the eagle, I will bring thee down from thence, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Also Edom shall be a desolation: every one that goeth by it shall be astonished, and shall hiss at all the plagues thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">As in the overthrow of Sodom and Gomorrah and the neighbour &lt;span class='extra'&gt;cities&lt;/span&gt; thereof, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, no man shall abide there, neither shall a son of man dwell in it.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Behold, he shall come up like a lion from the swelling of Jordan against the habitation of the strong: but I will suddenly make him run away from her: and who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a chosen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man, that&lt;/span&gt; I may appoint over her? for who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; like me? and who will appoint me the time? and who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; that shepherd that will stand before me?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Therefore hear the counsel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that he hath taken against Edom; and his purposes, that he hath purposed against the inhabitants of Teman: Surely the least of the flock shall draw them out: surely he shall make their habitations desolate with them.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The earth is moved at the noise of their fall, at the cry the noise thereof was heard in the Red sea.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Behold, he shall come up and fly as the eagle, and spread his wings over Bozrah: and at that day shall the heart of the mighty men of Edom be as the heart of a woman in her pangs.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">Concerning Damascus. Hamath is confounded, and Arpad: for they have heard evil tidings: they are fainthearted; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; sorrow on the sea; it cannot be quiet.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Damascus is waxed feeble, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; turneth herself to flee, and fear hath seized on &lt;span class='extra'&gt;her&lt;/span&gt;: anguish and sorrows have taken her, as a woman in travail.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">How is the city of praise not left, the city of my joy!</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Therefore her young men shall fall in her streets, and all the men of war shall be cut off in that day, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And I will kindle a fire in the wall of Damascus, and it shall consume the palaces of Ben-hadad.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">Concerning Kedar, and concerning the kingdoms of Hazor, which Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon shall smite, thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; Arise ye, go up to Kedar, and spoil the men of the east.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Their tents and their flocks shall they take away: they shall take to themselves their curtains, and all their vessels, and their camels; and they shall cry unto them, Fear &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; on every side.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">Flee, get you far off, dwell deep, O ye inhabitants of Hazor, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon hath taken counsel against you, and hath conceived a purpose against you.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Arise, get you up unto the wealthy nation, that dwelleth without care, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which have neither gates nor bars, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; dwell alone.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And their camels shall be a booty, and the multitude of their cattle a spoil: and I will scatter into all winds them &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; in the utmost corners; and I will bring their calamity from all sides thereof, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And Hazor shall be a dwelling for dragons, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; a desolation for ever: there shall no man abide there, nor &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; son of man dwell in it.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">The word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that came to Jeremiah the prophet against Elam in the beginning of the reign of Zedekiah king of Judah, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; Behold, I will break the bow of Elam, the chief of their might.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And upon Elam will I bring the four winds from the four quarters of heaven, and will scatter them toward all those winds; and there shall be no nation whither the outcasts of Elam shall not come.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">For I will cause Elam to be dismayed before their enemies, and before them that seek their life: and I will bring evil upon them, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; my fierce anger, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and I will send the sword after them, till I have consumed them:</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And I will set my throne in Elam, and will destroy from thence the king and the princes, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39" newPara="true">But it shall come to pass in the latter days, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; I will bring again the captivity of Elam, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>