<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="46" verseCount="28" nextChapter="jeremiah_47.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 47" prevChapter="jeremiah_45.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 45" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which came to Jeremiah the prophet against the Gentiles;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Against Egypt, against the army of Pharaoh-necho king of Egypt, which was by the river Euphrates in Carchemish, which Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon smote in the fourth year of Jehoiakim the son of Josiah king of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Order ye the buckler and shield, and draw near to battle.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Harness the horses; and get up, ye horsemen, and stand forth with &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; helmets; furbish the spears, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; put on the brigandines.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Wherefore have I seen them dismayed &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; turned away back? and their mighty ones are beaten down, and are fled apace, and look not back: &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; fear &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; round about, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Let not the swift flee away, nor the mighty man escape; they shall stumble, and fall toward the north by the river Euphrates.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; this &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; cometh up as a flood, whose waters are moved as the rivers?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Egypt riseth up like a flood, and &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; waters are moved like the rivers; and he saith, I will go up, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; will cover the earth; I will destroy the city and the inhabitants thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Come up, ye horses; and rage, ye chariots; and let the mighty men come forth; the Ethiopians and the Libyans, that handle the shield; and the Lydians, that handle &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; bend the bow.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the day of the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, a day of vengeance, that he may avenge him of his adversaries: and the sword shall devour, and it shall be satiate and made drunk with their blood: for the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; of hosts hath a sacrifice in the north country by the river Euphrates.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Go up into Gilead, and take balm, O virgin, the daughter of Egypt: in vain shalt thou use many medicines; &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; thou shalt not be cured.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The nations have heard of thy shame, and thy cry hath filled the land: for the mighty man hath stumbled against the mighty, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; they are fallen both together.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">The word that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake to Jeremiah the prophet, how Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon should come &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; smite the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Declare ye in Egypt, and publish in Migdol, and publish in Noph and in Tahpanhes: say ye, Stand fast, and prepare thee; for the sword shall devour round about thee.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Why are thy valiant &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; swept away? they stood not, because the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; did drive them.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He made many to fall, yea, one fell upon another: and they said, Arise, and let us go again to our own people, and to the land of our nativity, from the oppressing sword.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">They did cry there, Pharaoh king of Egypt &lt;i&gt;is but&lt;/i&gt; a noise; he hath passed the time appointed.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;i&gt;As&lt;/i&gt; I live, saith the King, whose name &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, Surely as Tabor &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; among the mountains, and as Carmel by the sea, &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; shall he come.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">O thou daughter dwelling in Egypt, furnish thyself to go into captivity: for Noph shall be waste and desolate without an inhabitant.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Egypt &lt;i&gt;is like&lt;/i&gt; a very fair heifer, &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; destruction cometh; it cometh out of the north.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Also her hired men &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in the midst of her like fatted bullocks; for they also are turned back, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; are fled away together: they did not stand, because the day of their calamity was come upon them, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the time of their visitation.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The voice thereof shall go like a serpent; for they shall march with an army, and come against her with axes, as hewers of wood.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">They shall cut down her forest, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, though it cannot be searched; because they are more than the grasshoppers, and &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; innumerable.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The daughter of Egypt shall be confounded; she shall be delivered into the hand of the people of the north.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel, saith; Behold, I will punish the multitude of No, and Pharaoh, and Egypt, with their gods, and their kings; even Pharaoh, and &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; them that trust in him:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And I will deliver them into the hand of those that seek their lives, and into the hand of Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon, and into the hand of his servants: and afterward it shall be inhabited, as in the days of old, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">But fear not thou, O my servant Jacob, and be not dismayed, O Israel: for, behold, I will save thee from afar off, and thy seed from the land of their captivity; and Jacob shall return, and be in rest and at ease, and none shall make &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; afraid.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Fear thou not, O Jacob my servant, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; with thee; for I will make a full end of all the nations whither I have driven thee: but I will not make a full end of thee, but correct thee in measure; yet will I not leave thee wholly unpunished.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>