<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="22" nextChapter="jeremiah_9.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 9" prevChapter="jeremiah_7.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 7" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">At that time, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, they shall bring out the bones of the kings of Judah, and the bones of his princes, and the bones of the priests, and the bones of the prophets, and the bones of the inhabitants of Jerusalem, out of their graves:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And they shall spread them before the sun, and the moon, and all the host of heaven, whom they have loved, and whom they have served, and after whom they have walked, and whom they have sought, and whom they have worshipped: they shall not be gathered, nor be buried; they shall be for dung upon the face of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And death shall be chosen rather than life by all the residue of them that remain of this evil family, which remain in all the places whither I have driven them, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Moreover thou shalt say unto them, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; Shall they fall, and not arise? shall he turn away, and not return?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Why &lt;span class="extra"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; is this people of Jerusalem slidden back by a perpetual backsliding? they hold fast deceit, they refuse to return.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I hearkened and heard, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; they spake not aright: no man repented him of his wickedness, saying, What have I done? every one turned to his course, as the horse rusheth into the battle.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Yea, the stork in the heaven knoweth her appointed times; and the turtle and the crane and the swallow observe the time of their coming; but my people know not the judgment of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">How do ye say, We &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; wise, and the law of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with us? Lo, certainly in vain made he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;; the pen of the scribes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in vain.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The wise &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; are ashamed, they are dismayed and taken: lo, they have rejected the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and what wisdom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in them?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Therefore will I give their wives unto others, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; their fields to them that shall inherit &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;: for every one from the least even unto the greatest is given to covetousness, from the prophet even unto the priest every one dealeth falsely.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For they have healed the hurt of the daughter of my people slightly, saying, Peace, peace; when &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no peace.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Were they ashamed when they had committed abomination? nay, they were not at all ashamed, neither could they blush: therefore shall they fall among them that fall: in the time of their visitation they shall be cast down, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">I will surely consume them, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; no grapes on the vine, nor figs on the fig tree, and the leaf shall fade; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the things that&lt;/span&gt; I have given them shall pass away from them.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Why do we sit still? assemble yourselves, and let us enter into the defenced cities, and let us be silent there: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God hath put us to silence, and given us water of gall to drink, because we have sinned against the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">We looked for peace, but no good &lt;span class="extra"&gt;came; and&lt;/span&gt; for a time of health, and behold trouble!</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The snorting of his horses was heard from Dan: the whole land trembled at the sound of the neighing of his strong ones; for they are come, and have devoured the land, and all that is in it; the city, and those that dwell therein.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For, behold, I will send serpents, cockatrices, among you, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;will&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; charmed, and they shall bite you, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;When&lt;/span&gt; I would comfort myself against sorrow, my heart &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; faint in me.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Behold the voice of the cry of the daughter of my people because of them that dwell in a far country: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; not the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in Zion? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not her king in her? Why have they provoked me to anger with their graven images, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; with strange vanities?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The harvest is past, the summer is ended, and we are not saved.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For the hurt of the daughter of my people am I hurt; I am black; astonishment hath taken hold on me.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Is there&lt;/span&gt; no balm in Gilead; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; no physician there? why then is not the health of the daughter of my people recovered?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>