<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="48" verseCount="47" nextChapter="jeremiah_49.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 49" prevChapter="jeremiah_47.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 47" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Against Moab thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; Woe unto Nebo! for it is spoiled: Kiriathaim is confounded &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; taken: Misgab is confounded and dismayed.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;i&gt;There shall be&lt;/i&gt; no more praise of Moab: in Heshbon they have devised evil against it; come, and let us cut it off from &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; a nation. Also thou shalt be cut down, O Madmen; the sword shall pursue thee.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">A voice of crying &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; from Horonaim, spoiling and great destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Moab is destroyed; her little ones have caused a cry to be heard.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For in the going up of Luhith continual weeping shall go up; for in the going down of Horonaim the enemies have heard a cry of destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Flee, save your lives, and be like the heath in the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">For because thou hast trusted in thy works and in thy treasures, thou shalt also be taken: and Chemosh shall go forth into captivity &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; his priests and his princes together.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the spoiler shall come upon every city, and no city shall escape: the valley also shall perish, and the plain shall be destroyed, as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Give wings unto Moab, that it may flee and get away: for the cities thereof shall be desolate, without any to dwell therein.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Cursed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; he that doeth the work of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; deceitfully, and cursed &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; he that keepeth back his sword from blood.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Moab hath been at ease from his youth, and he hath settled on his lees, and hath not been emptied from vessel to vessel, neither hath he gone into captivity: therefore his taste remained in him, and his scent is not changed.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore, behold, the days come, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that I will send unto him wanderers, that shall cause him to wander, and shall empty his vessels, and break their bottles.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Moab shall be ashamed of Chemosh, as the house of Israel was ashamed of Beth-el their confidence.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">How say ye, We &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; mighty and strong men for the war?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Moab is spoiled, and gone up &lt;i&gt;out of&lt;/i&gt; her cities, and his chosen young men are gone down to the slaughter, saith the King, whose name &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The calamity of Moab &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; near to come, and his affliction hasteth fast.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">All ye that are about him, bemoan him; and all ye that know his name, say, How is the strong staff broken, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the beautiful rod!</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thou daughter that dost inhabit Dibon, come down from &lt;i&gt;thy&lt;/i&gt; glory, and sit in thirst; for the spoiler of Moab shall come upon thee, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; he shall destroy thy strong holds.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">O inhabitant of Aroer, stand by the way, and espy; ask him that fleeth, and her that escapeth, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; say, What is done?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Moab is confounded; for it is broken down: howl and cry; tell ye it in Arnon, that Moab is spoiled,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And judgment is come upon the plain country; upon Holon, and upon Jahazah, and upon Mephaath,</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And upon Dibon, and upon Nebo, and upon Beth-diblathaim,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And upon Kiriathaim, and upon Beth-gamul, and upon Beth-meon,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And upon Kerioth, and upon Bozrah, and upon all the cities of the land of Moab, far or near.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The horn of Moab is cut off, and his arm is broken, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">Make ye him drunken: for he magnified &lt;i&gt;himself&lt;/i&gt; against the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: Moab also shall wallow in his vomit, and he also shall be in derision.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For was not Israel a derision unto thee? was he found among thieves? for since thou spakest of him, thou skippedst for joy.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">O ye that dwell in Moab, leave the cities, and dwell in the rock, and be like the dove &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; maketh her nest in the sides of the hole's mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">We have heard the pride of Moab, (he is exceeding proud) his loftiness, and his arrogancy, and his pride, and the haughtiness of his heart.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">I know his wrath, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; but &lt;i&gt;it shall&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; so; his lies shall not so effect &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Therefore will I howl for Moab, and I will cry out for all Moab; &lt;i&gt;mine heart&lt;/i&gt; shall mourn for the men of Kir-heres.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">O vine of Sibmah, I will weep for thee with the weeping of Jazer: thy plants are gone over the sea, they reach &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to the sea of Jazer: the spoiler is fallen upon thy summer fruits and upon thy vintage.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And joy and gladness is taken from the plentiful field, and from the land of Moab; and I have caused wine to fail from the winepresses: none shall tread with shouting; &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; shouting &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; no shouting.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">From the cry of Heshbon &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; unto Elealeh, &lt;i&gt;and even&lt;/i&gt; unto Jahaz, have they uttered their voice, from Zoar &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; unto Horonaim, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; an heifer of three years old: for the waters also of Nimrim shall be desolate.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Moreover I will cause to cease in Moab, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, him that offereth in the high places, and him that burneth incense to his gods.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Therefore mine heart shall sound for Moab like pipes, and mine heart shall sound like pipes for the men of Kir-heres: because the riches &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; he hath gotten are perished.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">For every head &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; bald, and every beard clipped: upon all the hands &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; cuttings, and upon the loins sackcloth.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;i&gt;There shall be&lt;/i&gt; lamentation generally upon all the housetops of Moab, and in the streets thereof: for I have broken Moab like a vessel wherein &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; no pleasure, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">They shall howl, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;, How is it broken down! how hath Moab turned the back with shame! so shall Moab be a derision and a dismaying to all them about him.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">For thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, he shall fly as an eagle, and shall spread his wings over Moab.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Kerioth is taken, and the strong holds are surprised, and the mighty men's hearts in Moab at that day shall be as the heart of a woman in her pangs.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And Moab shall be destroyed from &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; a people, because he hath magnified &lt;i&gt;himself&lt;/i&gt; against the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Fear, and the pit, and the snare, &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; upon thee, O inhabitant of Moab, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">He that fleeth from the fear shall fall into the pit; and he that getteth up out of the pit shall be taken in the snare: for I will bring upon it, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; upon Moab, the year of their visitation, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">They that fled stood under the shadow of Heshbon because of the force: but a fire shall come forth out of Heshbon, and a flame from the midst of Sihon, and shall devour the corner of Moab, and the crown of the head of the tumultuous ones.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">Woe be unto thee, O Moab! the people of Chemosh perisheth: for thy sons are taken captives, and thy daughters captives.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47" newPara="true">Yet will I bring again the captivity of Moab in the latter days, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. Thus far &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the judgment of Moab.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>