<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="25" nextChapter="jeremiah_4.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 4" prevChapter="jeremiah_2.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 2" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">They say, If a man put away his wife, and she go from him, and become another man's, shall he return unto her again? shall not that land be greatly polluted? but thou hast played the harlot with many lovers; yet return again to me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Lift up thine eyes unto the high places, and see where thou hast not been lien with. In the ways hast thou sat for them, as the Arabian in the wilderness; and thou hast polluted the land with thy whoredoms and with thy wickedness.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Therefore the showers have been withholden, and there hath been no latter rain; and thou hadst a whore's forehead, thou refusedst to be ashamed.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Wilt thou not from this time cry unto me, My father, thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; the guide of my youth?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Will he reserve &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his anger&lt;/span&gt; for ever? will he keep &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to the end? Behold, thou hast spoken and done evil things as thou couldest.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said also unto me in the days of Josiah the king, Hast thou seen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which backsliding Israel hath done? she is gone up upon every high mountain and under every green tree, and there hath played the harlot.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And I said after she had done all these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;, Turn thou unto me. But she returned not. And her treacherous sister Judah saw &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I saw, when for all the causes whereby backsliding Israel committed adultery I had put her away, and given her a bill of divorce; yet her treacherous sister Judah feared not, but went and played the harlot also.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And it came to pass through the lightness of her whoredom, that she defiled the land, and committed adultery with stones and with stocks.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And yet for all this her treacherous sister Judah hath not turned unto me with her whole heart, but feignedly, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, The backsliding Israel hath justified herself more than treacherous Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Go and proclaim these words toward the north, and say, Return, thou backsliding Israel, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; I will not cause mine anger to fall upon you: for I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; merciful, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; I will not keep &lt;span class='extra'&gt;anger&lt;/span&gt; for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Only acknowledge thine iniquity, that thou hast transgressed against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God, and hast scattered thy ways to the strangers under every green tree, and ye have not obeyed my voice, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Turn, O backsliding children, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for I am married unto you: and I will take you one of a city, and two of a family, and I will bring you to Zion:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And I will give you pastors according to mine heart, which shall feed you with knowledge and understanding.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And it shall come to pass, when ye be multiplied and increased in the land, in those days, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, they shall say no more, The ark of the covenant of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: neither shall it come to mind: neither shall they remember it; neither shall they visit &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;; neither shall &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; be done any more.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">At that time they shall call Jerusalem the throne of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and all the nations shall be gathered unto it, to the name of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to Jerusalem: neither shall they walk any more after the imagination of their evil heart.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">In those days the house of Judah shall walk with the house of Israel, and they shall come together out of the land of the north to the land that I have given for an inheritance unto your fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But I said, How shall I put thee among the children, and give thee a pleasant land, a goodly heritage of the hosts of nations? and I said, Thou shalt call me, My father; and shalt not turn away from me.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">Surely &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; a wife treacherously departeth from her husband, so have ye dealt treacherously with me, O house of Israel, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">A voice was heard upon the high places, weeping &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; supplications of the children of Israel: for they have perverted their way, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; they have forgotten the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Return, ye backsliding children, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; I will heal your backslidings. Behold, we come unto thee; for thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Truly in vain &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is salvation hoped for&lt;/span&gt; from the hills, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and from&lt;/span&gt; the multitude of mountains: truly in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the salvation of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For shame hath devoured the labour of our fathers from our youth; their flocks and their herds, their sons and their daughters.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">We lie down in our shame, and our confusion covereth us: for we have sinned against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, we and our fathers, from our youth even unto this day, and have not obeyed the voice of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>