<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="31" nextChapter="jeremiah_6.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 6" prevChapter="jeremiah_4.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 4" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Run ye to and fro through the streets of Jerusalem, and see now, and know, and seek in the broad places thereof, if ye can find a man, if there be &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; that executeth judgment, that seeketh the truth; and I will pardon it.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And though they say, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth; surely they swear falsely.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not thine eyes upon the truth? thou hast stricken them, but they have not grieved; thou hast consumed them, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; they have refused to receive correction: they have made their faces harder than a rock; they have refused to return.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Therefore I said, Surely these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; poor; they are foolish: for they know not the way of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;nor&lt;/span&gt; the judgment of their God.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I will get me unto the great men, and will speak unto them; for they have known the way of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the judgment of their God: but these have altogether broken the yoke, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; burst the bonds.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Wherefore a lion out of the forest shall slay them, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; a wolf of the evenings shall spoil them, a leopard shall watch over their cities: every one that goeth out thence shall be torn in pieces: because their transgressions are many, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; their backslidings are increased.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">How shall I pardon thee for this? thy children have forsaken me, and sworn by &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them that are&lt;/span&gt; no gods: when I had fed them to the full, they then committed adultery, and assembled themselves by troops in the harlots' houses.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">They were &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; fed horses in the morning: every one neighed after his neighbour's wife.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Shall I not visit for these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;? saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and shall not my soul be avenged on such a nation as this?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Go ye up upon her walls, and destroy; but make not a full end: take away her battlements; for they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For the house of Israel and the house of Judah have dealt very treacherously against me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They have belied the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and said, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; not he; neither shall evil come upon us; neither shall we see sword nor famine:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the prophets shall become wind, and the word &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not in them: thus shall it be done unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Wherefore thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of hosts, Because ye speak this word, behold, I will make my words in thy mouth fire, and this people wood, and it shall devour them.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Lo, I will bring a nation upon you from far, O house of Israel, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a mighty nation, it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an ancient nation, a nation whose language thou knowest not, neither understandest what they say.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Their quiver &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; as an open sepulchre, they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all mighty men.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And they shall eat up thine harvest, and thy bread, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; thy sons and thy daughters should eat: they shall eat up thy flocks and thine herds: they shall eat up thy vines and thy fig trees: they shall impoverish thy fenced cities, wherein thou trustedst, with the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Nevertheless in those days, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I will not make a full end with you.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And it shall come to pass, when ye shall say, Wherefore doeth the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God all these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; unto us? then shalt thou answer them, Like as ye have forsaken me, and served strange gods in your land, so shall ye serve strangers in a land &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; not yours.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Declare this in the house of Jacob, and publish it in Judah, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Hear now this, O foolish people, and without understanding; which have eyes, and see not; which have ears, and hear not:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Fear ye not me? saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: will ye not tremble at my presence, which have placed the sand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the bound of the sea by a perpetual decree, that it cannot pass it: and though the waves thereof toss themselves, yet can they not prevail; though they roar, yet can they not pass over it?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But this people hath a revolting and a rebellious heart; they are revolted and gone.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Neither say they in their heart, Let us now fear the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, that giveth rain, both the former and the latter, in his season: he reserveth unto us the appointed weeks of the harvest.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">Your iniquities have turned away these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;, and your sins have withholden good &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; from you.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For among my people are found wicked &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;: they lay wait, as he that setteth snares; they set a trap, they catch men.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">As a cage is full of birds, so &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; their houses full of deceit: therefore they are become great, and waxen rich.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">They are waxen fat, they shine: yea, they overpass the deeds of the wicked: they judge not the cause, the cause of the fatherless, yet they prosper; and the right of the needy do they not judge.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Shall I not visit for these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;? saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: shall not my soul be avenged on such a nation as this?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">A wonderful and horrible thing is committed in the land;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The prophets prophesy falsely, and the priests bear rule by their means; and my people love &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to have it&lt;/span&gt; so: and what will ye do in the end thereof?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>