<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="24" name="Jeremiah" bookPage="jeremiah.html" title="Jeremiah" chapterCount="52" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="lamentations_1.html" nextTitle="Lamentations" prevBook="isaiah_1.html" prevTitle="Isaiah">
    <chapter number="35" verseCount="19" nextChapter="jeremiah_36.html" nextTitle="Jeremiah 36" prevChapter="jeremiah_34.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 34" chapterPage="jeremiah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word which came unto Jeremiah from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in the days of Jehoiakim the son of Josiah king of Judah, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Go unto the house of the Rechabites, and speak unto them, and bring them into the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, into one of the chambers, and give them wine to drink.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Then I took Jaazaniah the son of Jeremiah, the son of Habaziniah, and his brethren, and all his sons, and the whole house of the Rechabites;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And I brought them into the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, into the chamber of the sons of Hanan, the son of Igdaliah, a man of God, which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; by the chamber of the princes, which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; above the chamber of Maaseiah the son of Shallum, the keeper of the door:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And I set before the sons of the house of the Rechabites pots full of wine, and cups, and I said unto them, Drink ye wine.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But they said, We will drink no wine: for Jonadab the son of Rechab our father commanded us, saying, Ye shall drink no wine, &lt;i&gt;neither&lt;/i&gt; ye, nor your sons for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Neither shall ye build house, nor sow seed, nor plant vineyard, nor have &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt;: but all your days ye shall dwell in tents; that ye may live many days in the land where ye &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; strangers.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Thus have we obeyed the voice of Jonadab the son of Rechab our father in all that he hath charged us, to drink no wine all our days, we, our wives, our sons, nor our daughters;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Nor to build houses for us to dwell in: neither have we vineyard, nor field, nor seed:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But we have dwelt in tents, and have obeyed, and done according to all that Jonadab our father commanded us.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But it came to pass, when Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon came up into the land, that we said, Come, and let us go to Jerusalem for fear of the army of the Chaldeans, and for fear of the army of the Syrians: so we dwell at Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Then came the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto Jeremiah, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; Go and tell the men of Judah and the inhabitants of Jerusalem, Will ye not receive instruction to hearken to my words? saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The words of Jonadab the son of Rechab, that he commanded his sons not to drink wine, are performed; for unto this day they drink none, but obey their father's commandment: notwithstanding I have spoken unto you, rising early and speaking; but ye hearkened not unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I have sent also unto you all my servants the prophets, rising up early and sending &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;, saying, Return ye now every man from his evil way, and amend your doings, and go not after other gods to serve them, and ye shall dwell in the land which I have given to you and to your fathers: but ye have not inclined your ear, nor hearkened unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Because the sons of Jonadab the son of Rechab have performed the commandment of their father, which he commanded them; but this people hath not hearkened unto me:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of hosts, the God of Israel; Behold, I will bring upon Judah and upon all the inhabitants of Jerusalem all the evil that I have pronounced against them: because I have spoken unto them, but they have not heard; and I have called unto them, but they have not answered.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And Jeremiah said unto the house of the Rechabites, Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; Because ye have obeyed the commandment of Jonadab your father, and kept all his precepts, and done according unto all that he hath commanded you:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel; Jonadab the son of Rechab shall not want a man to stand before me for ever.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>