<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="25" name="Lamentations" bookPage="lamentations.html" title="Lamentations" chapterCount="5" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezekiel_1.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel" prevBook="jeremiah_1.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="22" nextChapter="ezekiel_1.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 1" prevChapter="lamentations_4.html" prevTitle="Lamentations 4" chapterPage="lamentations_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Remember, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, what is come upon us: consider, and behold our reproach.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Our inheritance is turned to strangers, our houses to aliens.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">We are orphans and fatherless, our mothers &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; as widows.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">We have drunken our water for money; our wood is sold unto us.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Our necks &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; under persecution: we labour, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; have no rest.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">We have given the hand &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; the Egyptians, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and to&lt;/span&gt; the Assyrians, to be satisfied with bread.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Our fathers have sinned, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and are&lt;/span&gt; not; and we have borne their iniquities.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Servants have ruled over us: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none that doth deliver &lt;span class="extra"&gt;us&lt;/span&gt; out of their hand.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">We gat our bread with &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the peril of&lt;/span&gt; our lives because of the sword of the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Our skin was black like an oven because of the terrible famine.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">They ravished the women in Zion, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the maids in the cities of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Princes are hanged up by their hand: the faces of elders were not honoured.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">They took the young men to grind, and the children fell under the wood.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The elders have ceased from the gate, the young men from their musick.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The joy of our heart is ceased; our dance is turned into mourning.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The crown is fallen &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; our head: woe unto us, that we have sinned!</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For this our heart is faint; for these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; our eyes are dim.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Because of the mountain of Zion, which is desolate, the foxes walk upon it.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thou, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, remainest for ever; thy throne from generation to generation.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Wherefore dost thou forget us for ever, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; forsake us so long time?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Turn thou us unto thee, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and we shall be turned; renew our days as of old.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But thou hast utterly rejected us; thou art very wroth against us.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>