<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="25" name="Lamentations" bookPage="lamentations.html" title="Lamentations" chapterCount="5" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezekiel_1.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel" prevBook="jeremiah_1.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="66" nextChapter="lamentations_4.html" nextTitle="Lamentations 4" prevChapter="lamentations_2.html" prevTitle="Lamentations 2" chapterPage="lamentations_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the man &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; hath seen affliction by the rod of his wrath.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">He hath led me, and brought &lt;i&gt;me into&lt;/i&gt; darkness, but not &lt;i&gt;into&lt;/i&gt; light.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Surely against me is he turned; he turneth his hand &lt;i&gt;against me&lt;/i&gt; all the day.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">My flesh and my skin hath he made old; he hath broken my bones.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">He hath builded against me, and compassed &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; with gall and travail.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He hath set me in dark places, as &lt;i&gt;they that be&lt;/i&gt; dead of old.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He hath hedged me about, that I cannot get out: he hath made my chain heavy.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Also when I cry and shout, he shutteth out my prayer.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">He hath inclosed my ways with hewn stone, he hath made my paths crooked.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; unto me &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; a bear lying in wait, &lt;i&gt;and as&lt;/i&gt; a lion in secret places.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He hath turned aside my ways, and pulled me in pieces: he hath made me desolate.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">He hath bent his bow, and set me as a mark for the arrow.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He hath caused the arrows of his quiver to enter into my reins.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I was a derision to all my people; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; their song all the day.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He hath filled me with bitterness, he hath made me drunken with wormwood.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He hath also broken my teeth with gravel stones, he hath covered me with ashes.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And thou hast removed my soul far off from peace: I forgat prosperity.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And I said, My strength and my hope is perished from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Remembering mine affliction and my misery, the wormwood and the gall.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">My soul hath &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; still in remembrance, and is humbled in me.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">This I recall to my mind, therefore have I hope.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">&lt;i&gt;It is of&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s mercies that we are not consumed, because his compassions fail not.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;i&gt;They are&lt;/i&gt; new every morning: great &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy faithfulness.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; my portion, saith my soul; therefore will I hope in him.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; good unto them that wait for him, to the soul &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; seeketh him.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; good that &lt;i&gt;a man&lt;/i&gt; should both hope and quietly wait for the salvation of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; good for a man that he bear the yoke in his youth.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">He sitteth alone and keepeth silence, because he hath borne &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">He putteth his mouth in the dust; if so be there may be hope.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">He giveth &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; cheek to him that smiteth him: he is filled full with reproach.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">For the Lord will not cast off for ever:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">But though he cause grief, yet will he have compassion according to the multitude of his mercies.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">For he doth not afflict willingly nor grieve the children of men.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">To crush under his feet all the prisoners of the earth,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">To turn aside the right of a man before the face of the most High,</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">To subvert a man in his cause, the Lord approveth not.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37" newPara="true">Who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; saith, and it cometh to pass, &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; the Lord commandeth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not?</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">Out of the mouth of the most High proceedeth not evil and good?</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Wherefore doth a living man complain, a man for the punishment of his sins?</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Let us search and try our ways, and turn again to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Let us lift up our heart with &lt;i&gt;our&lt;/i&gt; hands unto God in the heavens.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">We have transgressed and have rebelled: thou hast not pardoned.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Thou hast covered with anger, and persecuted us: thou hast slain, thou hast not pitied.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">Thou hast covered thyself with a cloud, that &lt;i&gt;our&lt;/i&gt; prayer should not pass through.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">Thou hast made us &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; the offscouring and refuse in the midst of the people.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">All our enemies have opened their mouths against us.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">Fear and a snare is come upon us, desolation and destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">Mine eye runneth down with rivers of water for the destruction of the daughter of my people.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">Mine eye trickleth down, and ceaseth not, without any intermission,</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">Till the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; look down, and behold from heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">Mine eye affecteth mine heart because of all the daughters of my city.</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">Mine enemies chased me sore, like a bird, without cause.</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">They have cut off my life in the dungeon, and cast a stone upon me.</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">Waters flowed over mine head; &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; I said, I am cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55" newPara="true">I called upon thy name, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, out of the low dungeon.</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">Thou hast heard my voice: hide not thine ear at my breathing, at my cry.</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">Thou drewest near in the day &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I called upon thee: thou saidst, Fear not.</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">O Lord, thou hast pleaded the causes of my soul; thou hast redeemed my life.</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou hast seen my wrong: judge thou my cause.</verse>
      <verse number="60" id="v60">Thou hast seen all their vengeance &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; all their imaginations against me.</verse>
      <verse number="61" id="v61">Thou hast heard their reproach, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; all their imaginations against me;</verse>
      <verse number="62" id="v62">The lips of those that rose up against me, and their device against me all the day.</verse>
      <verse number="63" id="v63">Behold their sitting down, and their rising up; I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; their musick.</verse>
      <verse number="64" id="v64" newPara="true">Render unto them a recompence, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, according to the work of their hands.</verse>
      <verse number="65" id="v65">Give them sorrow of heart, thy curse unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="66" id="v66">Persecute and destroy them in anger from under the heavens of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>