<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="25" name="Lamentations" bookPage="lamentations.html" title="Lamentations" chapterCount="5" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezekiel_1.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel" prevBook="jeremiah_1.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="22" nextChapter="lamentations_5.html" nextTitle="Lamentations 5" prevChapter="lamentations_3.html" prevTitle="Lamentations 3" chapterPage="lamentations_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">How is the gold become dim! &lt;span class='extra'&gt;how&lt;/span&gt; is the most fine gold changed! the stones of the sanctuary are poured out in the top of every street.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The precious sons of Zion, comparable to fine gold, how are they esteemed as earthen pitchers, the work of the hands of the potter!</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Even the sea monsters draw out the breast, they give suck to their young ones: the daughter of my people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is become&lt;/span&gt; cruel, like the ostriches in the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The tongue of the sucking child cleaveth to the roof of his mouth for thirst: the young children ask bread, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; no man breaketh &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They that did feed delicately are desolate in the streets: they that were brought up in scarlet embrace dunghills.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For the punishment of the iniquity of the daughter of my people is greater than the punishment of the sin of Sodom, that was overthrown as in a moment, and no hands stayed on her.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Her Nazarites were purer than snow, they were whiter than milk, they were more ruddy in body than rubies, their polishing &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; of sapphire:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Their visage is blacker than a coal; they are not known in the streets: their skin cleaveth to their bones; it is withered, it is become like a stick.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;They that be&lt;/span&gt; slain with the sword are better than &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they that be&lt;/span&gt; slain with hunger: for these pine away, stricken through for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;want of&lt;/span&gt; the fruits of the field.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The hands of the pitiful women have sodden their own children: they were their meat in the destruction of the daughter of my people.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath accomplished his fury; he hath poured out his fierce anger, and hath kindled a fire in Zion, and it hath devoured the foundations thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The kings of the earth, and all the inhabitants of the world, would not have believed that the adversary and the enemy should have entered into the gates of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">For the sins of her prophets, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the iniquities of her priests, that have shed the blood of the just in the midst of her,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">They have wandered &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; blind &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; in the streets, they have polluted themselves with blood, so that men could not touch their garments.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">They cried unto them, Depart ye; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; unclean; depart, depart, touch not: when they fled away and wandered, they said among the heathen, They shall no more sojourn &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The anger of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath divided them; he will no more regard them: they respected not the persons of the priests, they favoured not the elders.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">As for us, our eyes as yet failed for our vain help: in our watching we have watched for a nation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; could not save &lt;span class='extra'&gt;us&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">They hunt our steps, that we cannot go in our streets: our end is near, our days are fulfilled; for our end is come.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Our persecutors are swifter than the eagles of the heaven: they pursued us upon the mountains, they laid wait for us in the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The breath of our nostrils, the anointed of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, was taken in their pits, of whom we said, Under his shadow we shall live among the heathen.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Rejoice and be glad, O daughter of Edom, that dwellest in the land of Uz; the cup also shall pass through unto thee: thou shalt be drunken, and shalt make thyself naked.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">The punishment of thine iniquity is accomplished, O daughter of Zion; he will no more carry thee away into captivity: he will visit thine iniquity, O daughter of Edom; he will discover thy sins.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>