<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="25" name="Lamentations" bookPage="lamentations.html" title="Lamentations" chapterCount="5" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezekiel_1.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel" prevBook="jeremiah_1.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="22" nextChapter="lamentations_2.html" nextTitle="Lamentations 2" prevChapter="jeremiah_52.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah 52" chapterPage="lamentations_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">How doth the city sit solitary, &lt;i&gt;that was&lt;/i&gt; full of people! &lt;i&gt;how&lt;/i&gt; is she become as a widow! she &lt;i&gt;that was&lt;/i&gt; great among the nations, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; princess among the provinces, &lt;i&gt;how&lt;/i&gt; is she become tributary!</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">She weepeth sore in the night, and her tears &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; on her cheeks: among all her lovers she hath none to comfort &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt;: all her friends have dealt treacherously with her, they are become her enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Judah is gone into captivity because of affliction, and because of great servitude: she dwelleth among the heathen, she findeth no rest: all her persecutors overtook her between the straits.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The ways of Zion do mourn, because none come to the solemn feasts: all her gates are desolate: her priests sigh, her virgins are afflicted, and she &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in bitterness.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Her adversaries are the chief, her enemies prosper; for the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath afflicted her for the multitude of her transgressions: her children are gone into captivity before the enemy.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And from the daughter of Zion all her beauty is departed: her princes are become like harts &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; find no pasture, and they are gone without strength before the pursuer.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Jerusalem remembered in the days of her affliction and of her miseries all her pleasant things that she had in the days of old, when her people fell into the hand of the enemy, and none did help her: the adversaries saw her, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; did mock at her sabbaths.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Jerusalem hath grievously sinned; therefore she is removed: all that honoured her despise her, because they have seen her nakedness: yea, she sigheth, and turneth backward.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Her filthiness &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in her skirts; she remembereth not her last end; therefore she came down wonderfully: she had no comforter. O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, behold my affliction: for the enemy hath magnified &lt;i&gt;himself&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The adversary hath spread out his hand upon all her pleasant things: for she hath seen &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the heathen entered into her sanctuary, whom thou didst command &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; they should not enter into thy congregation.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">All her people sigh, they seek bread; they have given their pleasant things for meat to relieve the soul: see, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and consider; for I am become vile.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">&lt;i&gt;Is it&lt;/i&gt; nothing to you, all ye that pass by? behold, and see if there be any sorrow like unto my sorrow, which is done unto me, wherewith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath afflicted &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; in the day of his fierce anger.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">From above hath he sent fire into my bones, and it prevaileth against them: he hath spread a net for my feet, he hath turned me back: he hath made me desolate &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; faint all the day.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The yoke of my transgressions is bound by his hand: they are wreathed, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; come up upon my neck: he hath made my strength to fall, the Lord hath delivered me into &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; hands, &lt;i&gt;from whom&lt;/i&gt; I am not able to rise up.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The Lord hath trodden under foot all my mighty &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; in the midst of me: he hath called an assembly against me to crush my young men: the Lord hath trodden the virgin, the daughter of Judah, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; in a winepress.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For these &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; I weep; mine eye, mine eye runneth down with water, because the comforter that should relieve my soul is far from me: my children are desolate, because the enemy prevailed.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Zion spreadeth forth her hands, &lt;i&gt;and there is&lt;/i&gt; none to comfort her: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath commanded concerning Jacob, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; his adversaries &lt;i&gt;should be&lt;/i&gt; round about him: Jerusalem is as a menstruous woman among them.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; is righteous; for I have rebelled against his commandment: hear, I pray you, all people, and behold my sorrow: my virgins and my young men are gone into captivity.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">I called for my lovers, &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; they deceived me: my priests and mine elders gave up the ghost in the city, while they sought their meat to relieve their souls.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Behold, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; in distress: my bowels are troubled; mine heart is turned within me; for I have grievously rebelled: abroad the sword bereaveth, at home &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; as death.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">They have heard that I sigh: &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none to comfort me: all mine enemies have heard of my trouble; they are glad that thou hast done &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;: thou wilt bring the day &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; thou hast called, and they shall be like unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Let all their wickedness come before thee; and do unto them, as thou hast done unto me for all my transgressions: for my sighs &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; many, and my heart &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; faint.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>