<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="25" name="Lamentations" bookPage="lamentations.html" title="Lamentations" chapterCount="5" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="ezekiel_1.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel" prevBook="jeremiah_1.html" prevTitle="Jeremiah">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="22" nextChapter="lamentations_3.html" nextTitle="Lamentations 3" prevChapter="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations 1" chapterPage="lamentations_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">How hath the Lord covered the daughter of Zion with a cloud in his anger, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; cast down from heaven unto the earth the beauty of Israel, and remembered not his footstool in the day of his anger!</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The Lord hath swallowed up all the habitations of Jacob, and hath not pitied: he hath thrown down in his wrath the strong holds of the daughter of Judah; he hath brought &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; down to the ground: he hath polluted the kingdom and the princes thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">He hath cut off in &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; fierce anger all the horn of Israel: he hath drawn back his right hand from before the enemy, and he burned against Jacob like a flaming fire, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; devoureth round about.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He hath bent his bow like an enemy: he stood with his right hand as an adversary, and slew all &lt;i&gt;that were&lt;/i&gt; pleasant to the eye in the tabernacle of the daughter of Zion: he poured out his fury like fire.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The Lord was as an enemy: he hath swallowed up Israel, he hath swallowed up all her palaces: he hath destroyed his strong holds, and hath increased in the daughter of Judah mourning and lamentation.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he hath violently taken away his tabernacle, as &lt;i&gt;if it were of&lt;/i&gt; a garden: he hath destroyed his places of the assembly: the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath caused the solemn feasts and sabbaths to be forgotten in Zion, and hath despised in the indignation of his anger the king and the priest.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The Lord hath cast off his altar, he hath abhorred his sanctuary, he hath given up into the hand of the enemy the walls of her palaces; they have made a noise in the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as in the day of a solemn feast.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath purposed to destroy the wall of the daughter of Zion: he hath stretched out a line, he hath not withdrawn his hand from destroying: therefore he made the rampart and the wall to lament; they languished together.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Her gates are sunk into the ground; he hath destroyed and broken her bars: her king and her princes &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; among the Gentiles: the law &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; no &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt;; her prophets also find no vision from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The elders of the daughter of Zion sit upon the ground, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; keep silence: they have cast up dust upon their heads; they have girded themselves with sackcloth: the virgins of Jerusalem hang down their heads to the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Mine eyes do fail with tears, my bowels are troubled, my liver is poured upon the earth, for the destruction of the daughter of my people; because the children and the sucklings swoon in the streets of the city.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They say to their mothers, Where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; corn and wine? when they swooned as the wounded in the streets of the city, when their soul was poured out into their mothers' bosom.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">What thing shall I take to witness for thee? what thing shall I liken to thee, O daughter of Jerusalem? what shall I equal to thee, that I may comfort thee, O virgin daughter of Zion? for thy breach &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; great like the sea: who can heal thee?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thy prophets have seen vain and foolish things for thee: and they have not discovered thine iniquity, to turn away thy captivity; but have seen for thee false burdens and causes of banishment.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">All that pass by clap &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; hands at thee; they hiss and wag their head at the daughter of Jerusalem, &lt;i&gt;saying, Is&lt;/i&gt; this the city that &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; call The perfection of beauty, The joy of the whole earth?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">All thine enemies have opened their mouth against thee: they hiss and gnash the teeth: they say, We have swallowed &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; up: certainly this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the day that we looked for; we have found, we have seen &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath done &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; which he had devised; he hath fulfilled his word that he had commanded in the days of old: he hath thrown down, and hath not pitied: and he hath caused &lt;i&gt;thine&lt;/i&gt; enemy to rejoice over thee, he hath set up the horn of thine adversaries.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Their heart cried unto the Lord, O wall of the daughter of Zion, let tears run down like a river day and night: give thyself no rest; let not the apple of thine eye cease.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Arise, cry out in the night: in the beginning of the watches pour out thine heart like water before the face of the Lord: lift up thy hands toward him for the life of thy young children, that faint for hunger in the top of every street.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">Behold, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and consider to whom thou hast done this. Shall the women eat their fruit, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; children of a span long? shall the priest and the prophet be slain in the sanctuary of the Lord?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The young and the old lie on the ground in the streets: my virgins and my young men are fallen by the sword; thou hast slain &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in the day of thine anger; thou hast killed, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; not pitied.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Thou hast called as in a solemn day my terrors round about, so that in the day of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s anger none escaped nor remained: those that I have swaddled and brought up hath mine enemy consumed.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>