<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="27" verseCount="36" nextChapter="ezekiel_28.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 28" prevChapter="ezekiel_26.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 26" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came again unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Now, thou son of man, take up a lamentation for Tyrus;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And say unto Tyrus, O thou that art situate at the entry of the sea, &lt;i&gt;which art&lt;/i&gt; a merchant of the people for many isles, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; O Tyrus, thou hast said, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; of perfect beauty.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thy borders &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in the midst of the seas, thy builders have perfected thy beauty.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They have made all thy &lt;i&gt;ship&lt;/i&gt; boards of fir trees of Senir: they have taken cedars from Lebanon to make masts for thee.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;i&gt;Of&lt;/i&gt; the oaks of Bashan have they made thine oars; the company of the Ashurites have made thy benches &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; ivory, &lt;i&gt;brought&lt;/i&gt; out of the isles of Chittim.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Fine linen with broidered work from Egypt was that which thou spreadest forth to be thy sail; blue and purple from the isles of Elishah was that which covered thee.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The inhabitants of Zidon and Arvad were thy mariners: thy wise &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;, O Tyrus, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; were in thee, were thy pilots.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The ancients of Gebal and the wise &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; thereof were in thee thy calkers: all the ships of the sea with their mariners were in thee to occupy thy merchandise.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">They of Persia and of Lud and of Phut were in thine army, thy men of war: they hanged the shield and helmet in thee; they set forth thy comeliness.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The men of Arvad with thine army &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; upon thy walls round about, and the Gammadims were in thy towers: they hanged their shields upon thy walls round about; they have made thy beauty perfect.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Tarshish &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; thy merchant by reason of the multitude of all &lt;i&gt;kind of&lt;/i&gt; riches; with silver, iron, tin, and lead, they traded in thy fairs.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Javan, Tubal, and Meshech, they &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thy merchants: they traded the persons of men and vessels of brass in thy market.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">They of the house of Togarmah traded in thy fairs with horses and horsemen and mules.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The men of Dedan &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thy merchants; many isles &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; the merchandise of thine hand: they brought thee &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a present horns of ivory and ebony.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Syria &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; thy merchant by reason of the multitude of the wares of thy making: they occupied in thy fairs with emeralds, purple, and broidered work, and fine linen, and coral, and agate.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Judah, and the land of Israel, they &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thy merchants: they traded in thy market wheat of Minnith, and Pannag, and honey, and oil, and balm.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Damascus &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; thy merchant in the multitude of the wares of thy making, for the multitude of all riches; in the wine of Helbon, and white wool.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Dan also and Javan going to and fro occupied in thy fairs: bright iron, cassia, and calamus, were in thy market.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Dedan &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; thy merchant in precious clothes for chariots.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Arabia, and all the princes of Kedar, they occupied with thee in lambs, and rams, and goats: in these &lt;i&gt;were they&lt;/i&gt; thy merchants.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The merchants of Sheba and Raamah, they &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thy merchants: they occupied in thy fairs with chief of all spices, and with all precious stones, and gold.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Haran, and Canneh, and Eden, the merchants of Sheba, Asshur, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Chilmad, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thy merchants.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">These &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; thy merchants in all sorts &lt;i&gt;of things&lt;/i&gt;, in blue clothes, and broidered work, and in chests of rich apparel, bound with cords, and made of cedar, among thy merchandise.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The ships of Tarshish did sing of thee in thy market: and thou wast replenished, and made very glorious in the midst of the seas.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">Thy rowers have brought thee into great waters: the east wind hath broken thee in the midst of the seas.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Thy riches, and thy fairs, thy merchandise, thy mariners, and thy pilots, thy calkers, and the occupiers of thy merchandise, and all thy men of war, that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in thee, and in all thy company which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the midst of thee, shall fall into the midst of the seas in the day of thy ruin.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The suburbs shall shake at the sound of the cry of thy pilots.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And all that handle the oar, the mariners, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; all the pilots of the sea, shall come down from their ships, they shall stand upon the land;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And shall cause their voice to be heard against thee, and shall cry bitterly, and shall cast up dust upon their heads, they shall wallow themselves in the ashes:</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And they shall make themselves utterly bald for thee, and gird them with sackcloth, and they shall weep for thee with bitterness of heart &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; bitter wailing.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And in their wailing they shall take up a lamentation for thee, and lament over thee, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;, What &lt;i&gt;city is&lt;/i&gt; like Tyrus, like the destroyed in the midst of the sea?</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">When thy wares went forth out of the seas, thou filledst many people; thou didst enrich the kings of the earth with the multitude of thy riches and of thy merchandise.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">In the time &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; thou shalt be broken by the seas in the depths of the waters thy merchandise and all thy company in the midst of thee shall fall.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">All the inhabitants of the isles shall be astonished at thee, and their kings shall be sore afraid, they shall be troubled in &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; countenance.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">The merchants among the people shall hiss at thee; thou shalt be a terror, and never &lt;i&gt;shalt be&lt;/i&gt; any more.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>