<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="29" verseCount="21" nextChapter="ezekiel_30.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 30" prevChapter="ezekiel_28.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 28" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In the tenth year, in the tenth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;month&lt;/span&gt;, in the twelfth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the month, the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Son of man, set thy face against Pharaoh king of Egypt, and prophesy against him, and against all Egypt:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Speak, and say, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; against thee, Pharaoh king of Egypt, the great dragon that lieth in the midst of his rivers, which hath said, My river &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine own, and I have made &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; for myself.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But I will put hooks in thy jaws, and I will cause the fish of thy rivers to stick unto thy scales, and I will bring thee up out of the midst of thy rivers, and all the fish of thy rivers shall stick unto thy scales.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And I will leave thee &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thrown&lt;/span&gt; into the wilderness, thee and all the fish of thy rivers: thou shalt fall upon the open fields; thou shalt not be brought together, nor gathered: I have given thee for meat to the beasts of the field and to the fowls of the heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And all the inhabitants of Egypt shall know that I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, because they have been a staff of reed to the house of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">When they took hold of thee by thy hand, thou didst break, and rend all their shoulder: and when they leaned upon thee, thou brakest, and madest all their loins to be at a stand.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I will bring a sword upon thee, and cut off man and beast out of thee.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the land of Egypt shall be desolate and waste; and they shall know that I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: because he hath said, The river &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine, and I have made &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Behold, therefore I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; against thee, and against thy rivers, and I will make the land of Egypt utterly waste &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; desolate, from the tower of Syene even unto the border of Ethiopia.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">No foot of man shall pass through it, nor foot of beast shall pass through it, neither shall it be inhabited forty years.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I will make the land of Egypt desolate in the midst of the countries &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; desolate, and her cities among the cities &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; laid waste shall be desolate forty years: and I will scatter the Egyptians among the nations, and will disperse them through the countries.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Yet thus saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; At the end of forty years will I gather the Egyptians from the people whither they were scattered:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And I will bring again the captivity of Egypt, and will cause them to return &lt;span class="extra"&gt;into&lt;/span&gt; the land of Pathros, into the land of their habitation; and they shall be there a base kingdom.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">It shall be the basest of the kingdoms; neither shall it exalt itself any more above the nations: for I will diminish them, that they shall no more rule over the nations.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And it shall be no more the confidence of the house of Israel, which bringeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; iniquity to remembrance, when they shall look after them: but they shall know that I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And it came to pass in the seven and twentieth year, in the first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;month&lt;/span&gt;, in the first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the month, the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Son of man, Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon caused his army to serve a great service against Tyrus: every head &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; made bald, and every shoulder &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; peeled: yet had he no wages, nor his army, for Tyrus, for the service that he had served against it:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I will give the land of Egypt unto Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon; and he shall take her multitude, and take her spoil, and take her prey; and it shall be the wages for his army.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">I have given him the land of Egypt &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; his labour wherewith he served against it, because they wrought for me, saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">In that day will I cause the horn of the house of Israel to bud forth, and I will give thee the opening of the mouth in the midst of them; and they shall know that I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>