<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="23" verseCount="49" nextChapter="ezekiel_24.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 24" prevChapter="ezekiel_22.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 22" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came again unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Son of man, there were two women, the daughters of one mother:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they committed whoredoms in Egypt; they committed whoredoms in their youth: there were their breasts pressed, and there they bruised the teats of their virginity.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the names of them &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; Aholah the elder, and Aholibah her sister: and they were mine, and they bare sons and daughters. Thus &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; their names; Samaria &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Aholah, and Jerusalem Aholibah.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Aholah played the harlot when she was mine; and she doted on her lovers, on the Assyrians &lt;span class='extra'&gt;her&lt;/span&gt; neighbours,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Which were&lt;/span&gt; clothed with blue, captains and rulers, all of them desirable young men, horsemen riding upon horses.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thus she committed her whoredoms with them, with all them &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that were&lt;/span&gt; the chosen men of Assyria, and with all on whom she doted: with all their idols she defiled herself.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Neither left she her whoredoms &lt;span class='extra'&gt;brought&lt;/span&gt; from Egypt: for in her youth they lay with her, and they bruised the breasts of her virginity, and poured their whoredom upon her.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Wherefore I have delivered her into the hand of her lovers, into the hand of the Assyrians, upon whom she doted.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">These discovered her nakedness: they took her sons and her daughters, and slew her with the sword: and she became famous among women; for they had executed judgment upon her.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And when her sister Aholibah saw &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;, she was more corrupt in her inordinate love than she, and in her whoredoms more than her sister in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;her&lt;/span&gt; whoredoms.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">She doted upon the Assyrians &lt;span class='extra'&gt;her&lt;/span&gt; neighbours, captains and rulers clothed most gorgeously, horsemen riding upon horses, all of them desirable young men.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then I saw that she was defiled, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;took&lt;/span&gt; both one way,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; she increased her whoredoms: for when she saw men pourtrayed upon the wall, the images of the Chaldeans pourtrayed with vermilion,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Girded with girdles upon their loins, exceeding in dyed attire upon their heads, all of them princes to look to, after the manner of the Babylonians of Chaldea, the land of their nativity:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And as soon as she saw them with her eyes, she doted upon them, and sent messengers unto them into Chaldea.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the Babylonians came to her into the bed of love, and they defiled her with their whoredom, and she was polluted with them, and her mind was alienated from them.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">So she discovered her whoredoms, and discovered her nakedness: then my mind was alienated from her, like as my mind was alienated from her sister.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Yet she multiplied her whoredoms, in calling to remembrance the days of her youth, wherein she had played the harlot in the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For she doted upon their paramours, whose flesh &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is as&lt;/span&gt; the flesh of asses, and whose issue &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is like&lt;/span&gt; the issue of horses.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Thus thou calledst to remembrance the lewdness of thy youth, in bruising thy teats by the Egyptians for the paps of thy youth.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">Therefore, O Aholibah, thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I will raise up thy lovers against thee, from whom thy mind is alienated, and I will bring them against thee on every side;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The Babylonians, and all the Chaldeans, Pekod, and Shoa, and Koa, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; all the Assyrians with them: all of them desirable young men, captains and rulers, great lords and renowned, all of them riding upon horses.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they shall come against thee with chariots, wagons, and wheels, and with an assembly of people, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; shall set against thee buckler and shield and helmet round about: and I will set judgment before them, and they shall judge thee according to their judgments.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And I will set my jealousy against thee, and they shall deal furiously with thee: they shall take away thy nose and thine ears; and thy remnant shall fall by the sword: they shall take thy sons and thy daughters; and thy residue shall be devoured by the fire.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">They shall also strip thee out of thy clothes, and take away thy fair jewels.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Thus will I make thy lewdness to cease from thee, and thy whoredom &lt;span class='extra'&gt;brought&lt;/span&gt; from the land of Egypt: so that thou shalt not lift up thine eyes unto them, nor remember Egypt any more.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">For thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I will deliver thee into the hand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of them&lt;/span&gt; whom thou hatest, into the hand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of them&lt;/span&gt; from whom thy mind is alienated:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And they shall deal with thee hatefully, and shall take away all thy labour, and shall leave thee naked and bare: and the nakedness of thy whoredoms shall be discovered, both thy lewdness and thy whoredoms.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">I will do these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; unto thee, because thou hast gone a whoring after the heathen, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; because thou art polluted with their idols.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Thou hast walked in the way of thy sister; therefore will I give her cup into thine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Thou shalt drink of thy sister's cup deep and large: thou shalt be laughed to scorn and had in derision; it containeth much.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Thou shalt be filled with drunkenness and sorrow, with the cup of astonishment and desolation, with the cup of thy sister Samaria.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Thou shalt even drink it and suck &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; out, and thou shalt break the sherds thereof, and pluck off thine own breasts: for I have spoken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Because thou hast forgotten me, and cast me behind thy back, therefore bear thou also thy lewdness and thy whoredoms.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said moreover unto me; Son of man, wilt thou judge Aholah and Aholibah? yea, declare unto them their abominations;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">That they have committed adultery, and blood &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in their hands, and with their idols have they committed adultery, and have also caused their sons, whom they bare unto me, to pass for them through &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the fire&lt;/span&gt;, to devour &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">Moreover this they have done unto me: they have defiled my sanctuary in the same day, and have profaned my sabbaths.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">For when they had slain their children to their idols, then they came the same day into my sanctuary to profane it; and, lo, thus have they done in the midst of mine house.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And furthermore, that ye have sent for men to come from far, unto whom a messenger &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; sent; and, lo, they came: for whom thou didst wash thyself, paintedst thy eyes, and deckedst thyself with ornaments,</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And satest upon a stately bed, and a table prepared before it, whereupon thou hast set mine incense and mine oil.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And a voice of a multitude being at ease &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; with her: and with the men of the common sort &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; brought Sabeans from the wilderness, which put bracelets upon their hands, and beautiful crowns upon their heads.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Then said I unto &lt;span class='extra'&gt;her that was&lt;/span&gt; old in adulteries, Will they now commit whoredoms with her, and she &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with them&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">Yet they went in unto her, as they go in unto a woman that playeth the harlot: so went they in unto Aholah and unto Aholibah, the lewd women.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45" newPara="true">And the righteous men, they shall judge them after the manner of adulteresses, and after the manner of women that shed blood; because they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; adulteresses, and blood &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in their hands.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">For thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; I will bring up a company upon them, and will give them to be removed and spoiled.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">And the company shall stone them with stones, and dispatch them with their swords; they shall slay their sons and their daughters, and burn up their houses with fire.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">Thus will I cause lewdness to cease out of the land, that all women may be taught not to do after your lewdness.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And they shall recompense your lewdness upon you, and ye shall bear the sins of your idols: and ye shall know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>