<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="31" nextChapter="ezekiel_23.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 23" prevChapter="ezekiel_21.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 21" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Now, thou son of man, wilt thou judge, wilt thou judge the bloody city? yea, thou shalt shew her all her abominations.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Then say thou, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, The city sheddeth blood in the midst of it, that her time may come, and maketh idols against herself to defile herself.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thou art become guilty in thy blood that thou hast shed; and hast defiled thyself in thine idols which thou hast made; and thou hast caused thy days to draw near, and art come &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; unto thy years: therefore have I made thee a reproach unto the heathen, and a mocking to all countries.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Those that be&lt;/span&gt; near, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;those that be&lt;/span&gt; far from thee, shall mock thee, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which art&lt;/span&gt; infamous &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; much vexed.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Behold, the princes of Israel, every one were in thee to their power to shed blood.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">In thee have they set light by father and mother: in the midst of thee have they dealt by oppression with the stranger: in thee have they vexed the fatherless and the widow.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Thou hast despised mine holy things, and hast profaned my sabbaths.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">In thee are men that carry tales to shed blood: and in thee they eat upon the mountains: in the midst of thee they commit lewdness.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">In thee have they discovered their fathers' nakedness: in thee have they humbled her that was set apart for pollution.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And one hath committed abomination with his neighbour's wife; and another hath lewdly defiled his daughter in law; and another in thee hath humbled his sister, his father's daughter.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">In thee have they taken gifts to shed blood; thou hast taken usury and increase, and thou hast greedily gained of thy neighbours by extortion, and hast forgotten me, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Behold, therefore I have smitten mine hand at thy dishonest gain which thou hast made, and at thy blood which hath been in the midst of thee.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Can thine heart endure, or can thine hands be strong, in the days that I shall deal with thee? I the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have spoken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and will do &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And I will scatter thee among the heathen, and disperse thee in the countries, and will consume thy filthiness out of thee.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And thou shalt take thine inheritance in thyself in the sight of the heathen, and thou shalt know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Son of man, the house of Israel is to me become dross: all they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; brass, and tin, and iron, and lead, in the midst of the furnace; they are &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the dross of silver.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Because ye are all become dross, behold, therefore I will gather you into the midst of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; they gather silver, and brass, and iron, and lead, and tin, into the midst of the furnace, to blow the fire upon it, to melt &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;; so will I gather &lt;span class='extra'&gt;you&lt;/span&gt; in mine anger and in my fury, and I will leave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;you there&lt;/span&gt;, and melt you.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Yea, I will gather you, and blow upon you in the fire of my wrath, and ye shall be melted in the midst thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">As silver is melted in the midst of the furnace, so shall ye be melted in the midst thereof; and ye shall know that I the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have poured out my fury upon you.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Son of man, say unto her, Thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; the land that is not cleansed, nor rained upon in the day of indignation.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;There is&lt;/span&gt; a conspiracy of her prophets in the midst thereof, like a roaring lion ravening the prey; they have devoured souls; they have taken the treasure and precious things; they have made her many widows in the midst thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Her priests have violated my law, and have profaned mine holy things: they have put no difference between the holy and profane, neither have they shewed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;difference&lt;/span&gt; between the unclean and the clean, and have hid their eyes from my sabbaths, and I am profaned among them.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Her princes in the midst thereof &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; like wolves ravening the prey, to shed blood, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to destroy souls, to get dishonest gain.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And her prophets have daubed them with untempered &lt;span class='extra'&gt;morter&lt;/span&gt;, seeing vanity, and divining lies unto them, saying, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, when the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath not spoken.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">The people of the land have used oppression, and exercised robbery, and have vexed the poor and needy: yea, they have oppressed the stranger wrongfully.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And I sought for a man among them, that should make up the hedge, and stand in the gap before me for the land, that I should not destroy it: but I found none.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Therefore have I poured out mine indignation upon them; I have consumed them with the fire of my wrath: their own way have I recompensed upon their heads, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>