<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="21" verseCount="32" nextChapter="ezekiel_22.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 22" prevChapter="ezekiel_20.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 20" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Son of man, set thy face toward Jerusalem, and drop &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thy word&lt;/span&gt; toward the holy places, and prophesy against the land of Israel,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And say to the land of Israel, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; against thee, and will draw forth my sword out of his sheath, and will cut off from thee the righteous and the wicked.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Seeing then that I will cut off from thee the righteous and the wicked, therefore shall my sword go forth out of his sheath against all flesh from the south to the north:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">That all flesh may know that I the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have drawn forth my sword out of his sheath: it shall not return any more.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Sigh therefore, thou son of man, with the breaking of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; loins; and with bitterness sigh before their eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And it shall be, when they say unto thee, Wherefore sighest thou? that thou shalt answer, For the tidings; because it cometh: and every heart shall melt, and all hands shall be feeble, and every spirit shall faint, and all knees shall be weak &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; water: behold, it cometh, and shall be brought to pass, saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Again the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Son of man, prophesy, and say, Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; Say, A sword, a sword is sharpened, and also furbished:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">It is sharpened to make a sore slaughter; it is furbished that it may glitter: should we then make mirth? it contemneth the rod of my son, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; every tree.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he hath given it to be furbished, that it may be handled: this sword is sharpened, and it is furbished, to give it into the hand of the slayer.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Cry and howl, son of man: for it shall be upon my people, it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; upon all the princes of Israel: terrors by reason of the sword shall be upon my people: smite therefore upon &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; thigh.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Because &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; a trial, and what if &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the sword&lt;/span&gt; contemn even the rod? it shall be no &lt;span class="extra"&gt;more&lt;/span&gt;, saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou therefore, son of man, prophesy, and smite &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thine&lt;/span&gt; hands together, and let the sword be doubled the third time, the sword of the slain: it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the sword of the great &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men that are&lt;/span&gt; slain, which entereth into their privy chambers.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I have set the point of the sword against all their gates, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; heart may faint, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; ruins be multiplied: ah! &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; made bright, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; wrapped up for the slaughter.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Go thee one way or other, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;either&lt;/span&gt; on the right hand, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; on the left, whithersoever thy face &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; set.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">I will also smite mine hands together, and I will cause my fury to rest: I the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have said &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">The word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me again, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Also, thou son of man, appoint thee two ways, that the sword of the king of Babylon may come: both twain shall come forth out of one land: and choose thou a place, choose &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; at the head of the way to the city.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Appoint a way, that the sword may come to Rabbath of the Ammonites, and to Judah in Jerusalem the defenced.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For the king of Babylon stood at the parting of the way, at the head of the two ways, to use divination: he made &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; arrows bright, he consulted with images, he looked in the liver.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">At his right hand was the divination for Jerusalem, to appoint captains, to open the mouth in the slaughter, to lift up the voice with shouting, to appoint &lt;span class="extra"&gt;battering&lt;/span&gt; rams against the gates, to cast a mount, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to build a fort.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And it shall be unto them as a false divination in their sight, to them that have sworn oaths: but he will call to remembrance the iniquity, that they may be taken.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Because ye have made your iniquity to be remembered, in that your transgressions are discovered, so that in all your doings your sins do appear; because, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;I say&lt;/span&gt;, that ye are come to remembrance, ye shall be taken with the hand.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And thou, profane wicked prince of Israel, whose day is come, when iniquity &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall have&lt;/span&gt; an end,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Remove the diadem, and take off the crown: this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the same: exalt &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him that is&lt;/span&gt; low, and abase &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him that is&lt;/span&gt; high.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">I will overturn, overturn, overturn, it: and it shall be no &lt;span class="extra"&gt;more&lt;/span&gt;, until he come whose right it is; and I will give it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">And thou, son of man, prophesy and say, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; concerning the Ammonites, and concerning their reproach; even say thou, The sword, the sword &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; drawn: for the slaughter &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; furbished, to consume because of the glittering:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Whiles they see vanity unto thee, whiles they divine a lie unto thee, to bring thee upon the necks of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them that are&lt;/span&gt; slain, of the wicked, whose day is come, when their iniquity &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall have&lt;/span&gt; an end.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Shall I cause &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to return into his sheath? I will judge thee in the place where thou wast created, in the land of thy nativity.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And I will pour out mine indignation upon thee, I will blow against thee in the fire of my wrath, and deliver thee into the hand of brutish men, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; skilful to destroy.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Thou shalt be for fuel to the fire; thy blood shall be in the midst of the land; thou shalt be no &lt;span class="extra"&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; remembered: for I the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have spoken &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>