<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="25" verseCount="17" nextChapter="ezekiel_26.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 26" prevChapter="ezekiel_24.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 24" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came again unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Son of man, set thy face against the Ammonites, and prophesy against them;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And say unto the Ammonites, Hear the word of the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Because thou saidst, Aha, against my sanctuary, when it was profaned; and against the land of Israel, when it was desolate; and against the house of Judah, when they went into captivity;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Behold, therefore I will deliver thee to the men of the east for a possession, and they shall set their palaces in thee, and make their dwellings in thee: they shall eat thy fruit, and they shall drink thy milk.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And I will make Rabbah a stable for camels, and the Ammonites a couchingplace for flocks: and ye shall know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Because thou hast clapped &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thine&lt;/span&gt; hands, and stamped with the feet, and rejoiced in heart with all thy despite against the land of Israel;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Behold, therefore I will stretch out mine hand upon thee, and will deliver thee for a spoil to the heathen; and I will cut thee off from the people, and I will cause thee to perish out of the countries: I will destroy thee; and thou shalt know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Because that Moab and Seir do say, Behold, the house of Judah &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; like unto all the heathen;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Therefore, behold, I will open the side of Moab from the cities, from his cities &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which are&lt;/span&gt; on his frontiers, the glory of the country, Beth-jeshimoth, Baal-meon, and Kiriathaim,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Unto the men of the east with the Ammonites, and will give them in possession, that the Ammonites may not be remembered among the nations.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I will execute judgments upon Moab; and they shall know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Because that Edom hath dealt against the house of Judah by taking vengeance, and hath greatly offended, and revenged himself upon them;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; I will also stretch out mine hand upon Edom, and will cut off man and beast from it; and I will make it desolate from Teman; and they of Dedan shall fall by the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And I will lay my vengeance upon Edom by the hand of my people Israel: and they shall do in Edom according to mine anger and according to my fury; and they shall know my vengeance, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Because the Philistines have dealt by revenge, and have taken vengeance with a despiteful heart, to destroy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; for the old hatred;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I will stretch out mine hand upon the Philistines, and I will cut off the Cherethims, and destroy the remnant of the sea coast.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And I will execute great vengeance upon them with furious rebukes; and they shall know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, when I shall lay my vengeance upon them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>