<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="23" nextChapter="ezekiel_15.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 15" prevChapter="ezekiel_13.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 13" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then came certain of the elders of Israel unto me, and sat before me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Son of man, these men have set up their idols in their heart, and put the stumblingblock of their iniquity before their face: should I be enquired of at all by them?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Therefore speak unto them, and say unto them, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Every man of the house of Israel that setteth up his idols in his heart, and putteth the stumblingblock of his iniquity before his face, and cometh to the prophet; I the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will answer him that cometh according to the multitude of his idols;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">That I may take the house of Israel in their own heart, because they are all estranged from me through their idols.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Therefore say unto the house of Israel, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Repent, and turn &lt;span class='extra'&gt;yourselves&lt;/span&gt; from your idols; and turn away your faces from all your abominations.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For every one of the house of Israel, or of the stranger that sojourneth in Israel, which separateth himself from me, and setteth up his idols in his heart, and putteth the stumblingblock of his iniquity before his face, and cometh to a prophet to enquire of him concerning me; I the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will answer him by myself:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I will set my face against that man, and will make him a sign and a proverb, and I will cut him off from the midst of my people; and ye shall know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And if the prophet be deceived when he hath spoken a thing, I the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have deceived that prophet, and I will stretch out my hand upon him, and will destroy him from the midst of my people Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they shall bear the punishment of their iniquity: the punishment of the prophet shall be even as the punishment of him that seeketh &lt;span class='extra'&gt;unto him&lt;/span&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">That the house of Israel may go no more astray from me, neither be polluted any more with all their transgressions; but that they may be my people, and I may be their God, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">The word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came again to me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Son of man, when the land sinneth against me by trespassing grievously, then will I stretch out mine hand upon it, and will break the staff of the bread thereof, and will send famine upon it, and will cut off man and beast from it:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Though these three men, Noah, Daniel, and Job, were in it, they should deliver &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; their own souls by their righteousness, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">If I cause noisome beasts to pass through the land, and they spoil it, so that it be desolate, that no man may pass through because of the beasts:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Though&lt;/span&gt; these three men &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in it, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; I live, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, they shall deliver neither sons nor daughters; they only shall be delivered, but the land shall be desolate.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Or &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; I bring a sword upon that land, and say, Sword, go through the land; so that I cut off man and beast from it:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Though these three men &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in it, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; I live, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, they shall deliver neither sons nor daughters, but they only shall be delivered themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">Or &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; I send a pestilence into that land, and pour out my fury upon it in blood, to cut off from it man and beast:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Though Noah, Daniel, and Job, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in it, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; I live, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, they shall deliver neither son nor daughter; they shall &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; deliver their own souls by their righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; How much more when I send my four sore judgments upon Jerusalem, the sword, and the famine, and the noisome beast, and the pestilence, to cut off from it man and beast?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">Yet, behold, therein shall be left a remnant that shall be brought forth, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;both&lt;/span&gt; sons and daughters: behold, they shall come forth unto you, and ye shall see their way and their doings: and ye shall be comforted concerning the evil that I have brought upon Jerusalem, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; concerning all that I have brought upon it.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And they shall comfort you, when ye see their ways and their doings: and ye shall know that I have not done without cause all that I have done in it, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>