<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="35" verseCount="15" nextChapter="ezekiel_36.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 36" prevChapter="ezekiel_34.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 34" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Son of man, set thy face against mount Seir, and prophesy against it,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And say unto it, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, O mount Seir, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; against thee, and I will stretch out mine hand against thee, and I will make thee most desolate.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I will lay thy cities waste, and thou shalt be desolate, and thou shalt know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Because thou hast had a perpetual hatred, and hast shed &lt;i&gt;the blood of&lt;/i&gt; the children of Israel by the force of the sword in the time of their calamity, in the time &lt;i&gt;that their&lt;/i&gt; iniquity &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; an end:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Therefore, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; I live, saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, I will prepare thee unto blood, and blood shall pursue thee: sith thou hast not hated blood, even blood shall pursue thee.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thus will I make mount Seir most desolate, and cut off from it him that passeth out and him that returneth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I will fill his mountains with his slain &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;: in thy hills, and in thy valleys, and in all thy rivers, shall they fall that are slain with the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I will make thee perpetual desolations, and thy cities shall not return: and ye shall know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Because thou hast said, These two nations and these two countries shall be mine, and we will possess it; whereas the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was there:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Therefore, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; I live, saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, I will even do according to thine anger, and according to thine envy which thou hast used out of thy hatred against them; and I will make myself known among them, when I have judged thee.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And thou shalt know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;and that&lt;/i&gt; I have heard all thy blasphemies which thou hast spoken against the mountains of Israel, saying, They are laid desolate, they are given us to consume.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thus with your mouth ye have boasted against me, and have multiplied your words against me: I have heard &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; When the whole earth rejoiceth, I will make thee desolate.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">As thou didst rejoice at the inheritance of the house of Israel, because it was desolate, so will I do unto thee: thou shalt be desolate, O mount Seir, and all Idumea, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; all of it: and they shall know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>