<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="34" verseCount="31" nextChapter="ezekiel_35.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 35" prevChapter="ezekiel_33.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 33" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Son of man, prophesy against the shepherds of Israel, prophesy, and say unto them, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; unto the shepherds; Woe &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; to the shepherds of Israel that do feed themselves! should not the shepherds feed the flocks?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Ye eat the fat, and ye clothe you with the wool, ye kill them that are fed: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; ye feed not the flock.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The diseased have ye not strengthened, neither have ye healed that which was sick, neither have ye bound up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which was&lt;/span&gt; broken, neither have ye brought again that which was driven away, neither have ye sought that which was lost; but with force and with cruelty have ye ruled them.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they were scattered, because &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no shepherd: and they became meat to all the beasts of the field, when they were scattered.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">My sheep wandered through all the mountains, and upon every high hill: yea, my flock was scattered upon all the face of the earth, and none did search or seek &lt;span class='extra'&gt;after them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Therefore, ye shepherds, hear the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; I live, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, surely because my flock became a prey, and my flock became meat to every beast of the field, because &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; no shepherd, neither did my shepherds search for my flock, but the shepherds fed themselves, and fed not my flock;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Therefore, O ye shepherds, hear the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; against the shepherds; and I will require my flock at their hand, and cause them to cease from feeding the flock; neither shall the shepherds feed themselves any more; for I will deliver my flock from their mouth, that they may not be meat for them.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">For thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; I, will both search my sheep, and seek them out.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">As a shepherd seeketh out his flock in the day that he is among his sheep &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; scattered; so will I seek out my sheep, and will deliver them out of all places where they have been scattered in the cloudy and dark day.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And I will bring them out from the people, and gather them from the countries, and will bring them to their own land, and feed them upon the mountains of Israel by the rivers, and in all the inhabited places of the country.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I will feed them in a good pasture, and upon the high mountains of Israel shall their fold be: there shall they lie in a good fold, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; a fat pasture shall they feed upon the mountains of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I will feed my flock, and I will cause them to lie down, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I will seek that which was lost, and bring again that which was driven away, and will bind up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which was&lt;/span&gt; broken, and will strengthen that which was sick: but I will destroy the fat and the strong; I will feed them with judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; you, O my flock, thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I judge between cattle and cattle, between the rams and the he goats.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Seemeth it&lt;/span&gt; a small thing unto you to have eaten up the good pasture, but ye must tread down with your feet the residue of your pastures? and to have drunk of the deep waters, but ye must foul the residue with your feet?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as for&lt;/span&gt; my flock, they eat that which ye have trodden with your feet; and they drink that which ye have fouled with your feet.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; unto them; Behold, I, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; I, will judge between the fat cattle and between the lean cattle.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Because ye have thrust with side and with shoulder, and pushed all the diseased with your horns, till ye have scattered them abroad;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Therefore will I save my flock, and they shall no more be a prey; and I will judge between cattle and cattle.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And I will set up one shepherd over them, and he shall feed them, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; my servant David; he shall feed them, and he shall be their shepherd.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And I the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will be their God, and my servant David a prince among them; I the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have spoken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And I will make with them a covenant of peace, and will cause the evil beasts to cease out of the land: and they shall dwell safely in the wilderness, and sleep in the woods.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And I will make them and the places round about my hill a blessing; and I will cause the shower to come down in his season; there shall be showers of blessing.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And the tree of the field shall yield her fruit, and the earth shall yield her increase, and they shall be safe in their land, and shall know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, when I have broken the bands of their yoke, and delivered them out of the hand of those that served themselves of them.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they shall no more be a prey to the heathen, neither shall the beast of the land devour them; but they shall dwell safely, and none shall make &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; afraid.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And I will raise up for them a plant of renown, and they shall be no more consumed with hunger in the land, neither bear the shame of the heathen any more.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Thus shall they know that I the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; with them, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; they, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the house of Israel, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; my people, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And ye my flock, the flock of my pasture, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; men, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; your God, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>