<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="37" verseCount="28" nextChapter="ezekiel_38.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 38" prevChapter="ezekiel_36.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 36" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The hand of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was upon me, and carried me out in the spirit of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and set me down in the midst of the valley which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; full of bones,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And caused me to pass by them round about: and, behold, &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; very many in the open valley; and, lo, &lt;i&gt;they were&lt;/i&gt; very dry.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he said unto me, Son of man, can these bones live? And I answered, O Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, thou knowest.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Again he said unto me, Prophesy upon these bones, and say unto them, O ye dry bones, hear the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; unto these bones; Behold, I will cause breath to enter into you, and ye shall live:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I will lay sinews upon you, and will bring up flesh upon you, and cover you with skin, and put breath in you, and ye shall live; and ye shall know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">So I prophesied as I was commanded: and as I prophesied, there was a noise, and behold a shaking, and the bones came together, bone to his bone.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And when I beheld, lo, the sinews and the flesh came up upon them, and the skin covered them above: but &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; no breath in them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then said he unto me, Prophesy unto the wind, prophesy, son of man, and say to the wind, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Come from the four winds, O breath, and breathe upon these slain, that they may live.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">So I prophesied as he commanded me, and the breath came into them, and they lived, and stood up upon their feet, an exceeding great army.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Then he said unto me, Son of man, these bones are the whole house of Israel: behold, they say, Our bones are dried, and our hope is lost: we are cut off for our parts.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore prophesy and say unto them, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, O my people, I will open your graves, and cause you to come up out of your graves, and bring you into the land of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And ye shall know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, when I have opened your graves, O my people, and brought you up out of your graves,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And shall put my spirit in you, and ye shall live, and I shall place you in your own land: then shall ye know that I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have spoken &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and performed &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">The word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came again unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Moreover, thou son of man, take thee one stick, and write upon it, For Judah, and for the children of Israel his companions: then take another stick, and write upon it, For Joseph, the stick of Ephraim, and &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; all the house of Israel his companions:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And join them one to another into one stick; and they shall become one in thine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And when the children of thy people shall speak unto thee, saying, Wilt thou not shew us what thou &lt;i&gt;meanest&lt;/i&gt; by these?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Say unto them, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I will take the stick of Joseph, which &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the hand of Ephraim, and the tribes of Israel his fellows, and will put them with him, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; with the stick of Judah, and make them one stick, and they shall be one in mine hand.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And the sticks whereon thou writest shall be in thine hand before their eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And say unto them, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I will take the children of Israel from among the heathen, whither they be gone, and will gather them on every side, and bring them into their own land:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And I will make them one nation in the land upon the mountains of Israel; and one king shall be king to them all: and they shall be no more two nations, neither shall they be divided into two kingdoms any more at all:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Neither shall they defile themselves any more with their idols, nor with their detestable things, nor with any of their transgressions: but I will save them out of all their dwellingplaces, wherein they have sinned, and will cleanse them: so shall they be my people, and I will be their God.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And David my servant &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; king over them; and they all shall have one shepherd: they shall also walk in my judgments, and observe my statutes, and do them.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they shall dwell in the land that I have given unto Jacob my servant, wherein your fathers have dwelt; and they shall dwell therein, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; they, and their children, and their children's children for ever: and my servant David &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; their prince for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Moreover I will make a covenant of peace with them; it shall be an everlasting covenant with them: and I will place them, and multiply them, and will set my sanctuary in the midst of them for evermore.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">My tabernacle also shall be with them: yea, I will be their God, and they shall be my people.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the heathen shall know that I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; do sanctify Israel, when my sanctuary shall be in the midst of them for evermore.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>