<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="24" verseCount="27" nextChapter="ezekiel_25.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 25" prevChapter="ezekiel_23.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 23" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Again in the ninth year, in the tenth month, in the tenth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the month, the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Son of man, write thee the name of the day, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of this same day: the king of Babylon set himself against Jerusalem this same day.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And utter a parable unto the rebellious house, and say unto them, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Set on a pot, set &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on, and also pour water into it:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Gather the pieces thereof into it, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; every good piece, the thigh, and the shoulder; fill &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; with the choice bones.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Take the choice of the flock, and burn also the bones under it, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; make it boil well, and let them seethe the bones of it therein.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Wherefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Woe to the bloody city, to the pot whose scum &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; therein, and whose scum is not gone out of it! bring it out piece by piece; let no lot fall upon it.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For her blood is in the midst of her; she set it upon the top of a rock; she poured it not upon the ground, to cover it with dust;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">That it might cause fury to come up to take vengeance; I have set her blood upon the top of a rock, that it should not be covered.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Woe to the bloody city! I will even make the pile for fire great.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Heap on wood, kindle the fire, consume the flesh, and spice it well, and let the bones be burned.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then set it empty upon the coals thereof, that the brass of it may be hot, and may burn, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the filthiness of it may be molten in it, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the scum of it may be consumed.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">She hath wearied &lt;span class='extra'&gt;herself&lt;/span&gt; with lies, and her great scum went not forth out of her: her scum &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; in the fire.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">In thy filthiness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; lewdness: because I have purged thee, and thou wast not purged, thou shalt not be purged from thy filthiness any more, till I have caused my fury to rest upon thee.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have spoken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;: it shall come to pass, and I will do &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;; I will not go back, neither will I spare, neither will I repent; according to thy ways, and according to thy doings, shall they judge thee, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Also the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Son of man, behold, I take away from thee the desire of thine eyes with a stroke: yet neither shalt thou mourn nor weep, neither shall thy tears run down.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Forbear to cry, make no mourning for the dead, bind the tire of thine head upon thee, and put on thy shoes upon thy feet, and cover not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; lips, and eat not the bread of men.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">So I spake unto the people in the morning: and at even my wife died; and I did in the morning as I was commanded.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And the people said unto me, Wilt thou not tell us what these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things are&lt;/span&gt; to us, that thou doest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Then I answered them, The word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Speak unto the house of Israel, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I will profane my sanctuary, the excellency of your strength, the desire of your eyes, and that which your soul pitieth; and your sons and your daughters whom ye have left shall fall by the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And ye shall do as I have done: ye shall not cover &lt;span class='extra'&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; lips, nor eat the bread of men.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And your tires &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; upon your heads, and your shoes upon your feet: ye shall not mourn nor weep; but ye shall pine away for your iniquities, and mourn one toward another.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Thus Ezekiel is unto you a sign: according to all that he hath done shall ye do: and when this cometh, ye shall know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Also, thou son of man, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall it&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in the day when I take from them their strength, the joy of their glory, the desire of their eyes, and that whereupon they set their minds, their sons and their daughters,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;That&lt;/span&gt; he that escapeth in that day shall come unto thee, to cause &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt; to hear &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thine&lt;/span&gt; ears?</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">In that day shall thy mouth be opened to him which is escaped, and thou shalt speak, and be no more dumb: and thou shalt be a sign unto them; and they shall know that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>