<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="10" nextChapter="ezekiel_3.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 3" prevChapter="ezekiel_1.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 1" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he said unto me, Son of man, stand upon thy feet, and I will speak unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the spirit entered into me when he spake unto me, and set me upon my feet, that I heard him that spake unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he said unto me, Son of man, I send thee to the children of Israel, to a rebellious nation that hath rebelled against me: they and their fathers have transgressed against me, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; unto this very day.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For &lt;i&gt;they are&lt;/i&gt; impudent children and stiffhearted. I do send thee unto them; and thou shalt say unto them, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they, whether they will hear, or whether they will forbear, (for they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; a rebellious house,) yet shall know that there hath been a prophet among them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And thou, son of man, be not afraid of them, neither be afraid of their words, though briers and thorns &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; with thee, and thou dost dwell among scorpions: be not afraid of their words, nor be dismayed at their looks, though they &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; a rebellious house.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And thou shalt speak my words unto them, whether they will hear, or whether they will forbear: for they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; most rebellious.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But thou, son of man, hear what I say unto thee; Be not thou rebellious like that rebellious house: open thy mouth, and eat that I give thee.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And when I looked, behold, an hand &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; sent unto me; and, lo, a roll of a book &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; therein;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he spread it before me; and it &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; written within and without: and &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; written therein lamentations, and mourning, and woe.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>