<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="40" verseCount="49" nextChapter="ezekiel_41.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 41" prevChapter="ezekiel_39.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 39" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In the five and twentieth year of our captivity, in the beginning of the year, in the tenth &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the month, in the fourteenth year after that the city was smitten, in the selfsame day the hand of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; was upon me, and brought me thither.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">In the visions of God brought he me into the land of Israel, and set me upon a very high mountain, by which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; as the frame of a city on the south.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he brought me thither, and, behold, &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; a man, whose appearance &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; like the appearance of brass, with a line of flax in his hand, and a measuring reed; and he stood in the gate.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the man said unto me, Son of man, behold with thine eyes, and hear with thine ears, and set thine heart upon all that I shall shew thee; for to the intent that I might shew &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; unto thee &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; thou brought hither: declare all that thou seest to the house of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And behold a wall on the outside of the house round about, and in the man's hand a measuring reed of six cubits &lt;i&gt;long&lt;/i&gt; by the cubit and an hand breadth: so he measured the breadth of the building, one reed; and the height, one reed.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Then came he unto the gate which looketh toward the east, and went up the stairs thereof, and measured the threshold of the gate, &lt;i&gt;which was&lt;/i&gt; one reed broad; and the other threshold &lt;i&gt;of the gate, which was&lt;/i&gt; one reed broad.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And &lt;i&gt;every&lt;/i&gt; little chamber &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; one reed long, and one reed broad; and between the little chambers &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; five cubits; and the threshold of the gate by the porch of the gate within &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; one reed.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He measured also the porch of the gate within, one reed.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then measured he the porch of the gate, eight cubits; and the posts thereof, two cubits; and the porch of the gate &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; inward.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the little chambers of the gate eastward &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; three on this side, and three on that side; they three &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; of one measure: and the posts had one measure on this side and on that side.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he measured the breadth of the entry of the gate, ten cubits; &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the length of the gate, thirteen cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The space also before the little chambers &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; one cubit &lt;i&gt;on this side&lt;/i&gt;, and the space &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; one cubit on that side: and the little chambers &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; six cubits on this side, and six cubits on that side.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">He measured then the gate from the roof of &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; little chamber to the roof of another: the breadth &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; five and twenty cubits, door against door.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">He made also posts of threescore cubits, even unto the post of the court round about the gate.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And from the face of the gate of the entrance unto the face of the porch of the inner gate &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; fifty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; narrow windows to the little chambers, and to their posts within the gate round about, and likewise to the arches: and windows &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; round about inward: and upon &lt;i&gt;each&lt;/i&gt; post &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; palm trees.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then brought he me into the outward court, and, lo, &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; chambers, and a pavement made for the court round about: thirty chambers &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; upon the pavement.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the pavement by the side of the gates over against the length of the gates &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the lower pavement.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Then he measured the breadth from the forefront of the lower gate unto the forefront of the inner court without, an hundred cubits eastward and northward.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And the gate of the outward court that looked toward the north, he measured the length thereof, and the breadth thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the little chambers thereof &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; three on this side and three on that side; and the posts thereof and the arches thereof were after the measure of the first gate: the length thereof &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; fifty cubits, and the breadth five and twenty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And their windows, and their arches, and their palm trees, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; after the measure of the gate that looketh toward the east; and they went up unto it by seven steps; and the arches thereof &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; before them.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the gate of the inner court &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; over against the gate toward the north, and toward the east; and he measured from gate to gate an hundred cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">After that he brought me toward the south, and behold a gate toward the south: and he measured the posts thereof and the arches thereof according to these measures.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; windows in it and in the arches thereof round about, like those windows: the length &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; fifty cubits, and the breadth five and twenty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; seven steps to go up to it, and the arches thereof &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; before them: and it had palm trees, one on this side, and another on that side, upon the posts thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And &lt;i&gt;there was&lt;/i&gt; a gate in the inner court toward the south: and he measured from gate to gate toward the south an hundred cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he brought me to the inner court by the south gate: and he measured the south gate according to these measures;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And the little chambers thereof, and the posts thereof, and the arches thereof, according to these measures: and &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; windows in it and in the arches thereof round about: &lt;i&gt;it was&lt;/i&gt; fifty cubits long, and five and twenty cubits broad.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the arches round about &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; five and twenty cubits long, and five cubits broad.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And the arches thereof &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; toward the utter court; and palm trees &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; upon the posts thereof: and the going up to it &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; eight steps.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">And he brought me into the inner court toward the east: and he measured the gate according to these measures.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And the little chambers thereof, and the posts thereof, and the arches thereof, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; according to these measures: and &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; windows therein and in the arches thereof round about: &lt;i&gt;it was&lt;/i&gt; fifty cubits long, and five and twenty cubits broad.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And the arches thereof &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; toward the outward court; and palm trees &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; upon the posts thereof, on this side, and on that side: and the going up to it &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; eight steps.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35" newPara="true">And he brought me to the north gate, and measured &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; according to these measures;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">The little chambers thereof, the posts thereof, and the arches thereof, and the windows to it round about: the length &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; fifty cubits, and the breadth five and twenty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And the posts thereof &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; toward the utter court; and palm trees &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; upon the posts thereof, on this side, and on that side: and the going up to it &lt;i&gt;had&lt;/i&gt; eight steps.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And the chambers and the entries thereof &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; by the posts of the gates, where they washed the burnt offering.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39" newPara="true">And in the porch of the gate &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; two tables on this side, and two tables on that side, to slay thereon the burnt offering and the sin offering and the trespass offering.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And at the side without, as one goeth up to the entry of the north gate, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; two tables; and on the other side, which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; at the porch of the gate, &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; two tables.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Four tables &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; on this side, and four tables on that side, by the side of the gate; eight tables, whereupon they slew &lt;i&gt;their sacrifices&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And the four tables &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; of hewn stone for the burnt offering, of a cubit and an half long, and a cubit and an half broad, and one cubit high: whereupon also they laid the instruments wherewith they slew the burnt offering and the sacrifice.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And within &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; hooks, an hand broad, fastened round about: and upon the tables &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the flesh of the offering.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44" newPara="true">And without the inner gate &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; the chambers of the singers in the inner court, which &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; at the side of the north gate; and their prospect &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; toward the south: one at the side of the east gate &lt;i&gt;having&lt;/i&gt; the prospect toward the north.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And he said unto me, This chamber, whose prospect &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; toward the south, &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; for the priests, the keepers of the charge of the house.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And the chamber whose prospect &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; toward the north &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; for the priests, the keepers of the charge of the altar: these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the sons of Zadok among the sons of Levi, which come near to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to minister unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">So he measured the court, an hundred cubits long, and an hundred cubits broad, foursquare; and the altar &lt;i&gt;that was&lt;/i&gt; before the house.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48" newPara="true">And he brought me to the porch of the house, and measured &lt;i&gt;each&lt;/i&gt; post of the porch, five cubits on this side, and five cubits on that side: and the breadth of the gate &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; three cubits on this side, and three cubits on that side.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">The length of the porch &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; twenty cubits, and the breadth eleven cubits; and &lt;i&gt;he brought me&lt;/i&gt; by the steps whereby they went up to it: and &lt;i&gt;there were&lt;/i&gt; pillars by the posts, one on this side, and another on that side.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>