<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="32" nextChapter="ezekiel_19.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 19" prevChapter="ezekiel_17.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 17" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me again, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">What mean ye, that ye use this proverb concerning the land of Israel, saying, The fathers have eaten sour grapes, and the children's teeth are set on edge?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; I live, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, ye shall not have &lt;span class='extra'&gt;occasion&lt;/span&gt; any more to use this proverb in Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Behold, all souls are mine; as the soul of the father, so also the soul of the son is mine: the soul that sinneth, it shall die.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">But if a man be just, and do that which is lawful and right,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;And&lt;/span&gt; hath not eaten upon the mountains, neither hath lifted up his eyes to the idols of the house of Israel, neither hath defiled his neighbour's wife, neither hath come near to a menstruous woman,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And hath not oppressed any, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; hath restored to the debtor his pledge, hath spoiled none by violence, hath given his bread to the hungry, and hath covered the naked with a garment;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; hath not given forth upon usury, neither hath taken any increase, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; hath withdrawn his hand from iniquity, hath executed true judgment between man and man,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Hath walked in my statutes, and hath kept my judgments, to deal truly; he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; just, he shall surely live, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">If he beget a son &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; a robber, a shedder of blood, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; doeth the like to &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; one of these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And that doeth not any of those &lt;span class='extra'&gt;duties&lt;/span&gt;, but even hath eaten upon the mountains, and defiled his neighbour's wife,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Hath oppressed the poor and needy, hath spoiled by violence, hath not restored the pledge, and hath lifted up his eyes to the idols, hath committed abomination,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Hath given forth upon usury, and hath taken increase: shall he then live? he shall not live: he hath done all these abominations; he shall surely die; his blood shall be upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Now, lo, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; he beget a son, that seeth all his father's sins which he hath done, and considereth, and doeth not such like,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;That&lt;/span&gt; hath not eaten upon the mountains, neither hath lifted up his eyes to the idols of the house of Israel, hath not defiled his neighbour's wife,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Neither hath oppressed any, hath not withholden the pledge, neither hath spoiled by violence, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; hath given his bread to the hungry, and hath covered the naked with a garment,</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;That&lt;/span&gt; hath taken off his hand from the poor, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; hath not received usury nor increase, hath executed my judgments, hath walked in my statutes; he shall not die for the iniquity of his father, he shall surely live.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;As for&lt;/span&gt; his father, because he cruelly oppressed, spoiled his brother by violence, and did &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not good among his people, lo, even he shall die in his iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">Yet say ye, Why? doth not the son bear the iniquity of the father? When the son hath done that which is lawful and right, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; hath kept all my statutes, and hath done them, he shall surely live.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The soul that sinneth, it shall die. The son shall not bear the iniquity of the father, neither shall the father bear the iniquity of the son: the righteousness of the righteous shall be upon him, and the wickedness of the wicked shall be upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But if the wicked will turn from all his sins that he hath committed, and keep all my statutes, and do that which is lawful and right, he shall surely live, he shall not die.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">All his transgressions that he hath committed, they shall not be mentioned unto him: in his righteousness that he hath done he shall live.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Have I any pleasure at all that the wicked should die? saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; not that he should return from his ways, and live?</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">But when the righteous turneth away from his righteousness, and committeth iniquity, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; doeth according to all the abominations that the wicked &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; doeth, shall he live? All his righteousness that he hath done shall not be mentioned: in his trespass that he hath trespassed, and in his sin that he hath sinned, in them shall he die.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">Yet ye say, The way of the Lord is not equal. Hear now, O house of Israel; Is not my way equal? are not your ways unequal?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">When a righteous &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; turneth away from his righteousness, and committeth iniquity, and dieth in them; for his iniquity that he hath done shall he die.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Again, when the wicked &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; turneth away from his wickedness that he hath committed, and doeth that which is lawful and right, he shall save his soul alive.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Because he considereth, and turneth away from all his transgressions that he hath committed, he shall surely live, he shall not die.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Yet saith the house of Israel, The way of the Lord is not equal. O house of Israel, are not my ways equal? are not your ways unequal?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Therefore I will judge you, O house of Israel, every one according to his ways, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;. Repent, and turn &lt;span class='extra'&gt;yourselves&lt;/span&gt; from all your transgressions; so iniquity shall not be your ruin.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">Cast away from you all your transgressions, whereby ye have transgressed; and make you a new heart and a new spirit: for why will ye die, O house of Israel?</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">For I have no pleasure in the death of him that dieth, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;: wherefore turn &lt;span class='extra'&gt;yourselves&lt;/span&gt;, and live ye.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>