<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="45" verseCount="25" nextChapter="ezekiel_46.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 46" prevChapter="ezekiel_44.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 44" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover, when ye shall divide by lot the land for inheritance, ye shall offer an oblation unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, an holy portion of the land: the length &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the length of five and twenty thousand &lt;i&gt;reeds&lt;/i&gt;, and the breadth &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; ten thousand. This &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; holy in all the borders thereof round about.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Of this there shall be for the sanctuary five hundred &lt;i&gt;in length&lt;/i&gt;, with five hundred &lt;i&gt;in breadth&lt;/i&gt;, square round about; and fifty cubits round about for the suburbs thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And of this measure shalt thou measure the length of five and twenty thousand, and the breadth of ten thousand: and in it shall be the sanctuary &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the most holy &lt;i&gt;place&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The holy &lt;i&gt;portion&lt;/i&gt; of the land shall be for the priests the ministers of the sanctuary, which shall come near to minister unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and it shall be a place for their houses, and an holy place for the sanctuary.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the five and twenty thousand of length, and the ten thousand of breadth, shall also the Levites, the ministers of the house, have for themselves, for a possession for twenty chambers.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And ye shall appoint the possession of the city five thousand broad, and five and twenty thousand long, over against the oblation of the holy &lt;i&gt;portion&lt;/i&gt;: it shall be for the whole house of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;portion shall be&lt;/i&gt; for the prince on the one side and on the other side of the oblation of the holy &lt;i&gt;portion&lt;/i&gt;, and of the possession of the city, before the oblation of the holy &lt;i&gt;portion&lt;/i&gt;, and before the possession of the city, from the west side westward, and from the east side eastward: and the length &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; over against one of the portions, from the west border unto the east border.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">In the land shall be his possession in Israel: and my princes shall no more oppress my people; and &lt;i&gt;the rest of&lt;/i&gt; the land shall they give to the house of Israel according to their tribes.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Let it suffice you, O princes of Israel: remove violence and spoil, and execute judgment and justice, take away your exactions from my people, saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Ye shall have just balances, and a just ephah, and a just bath.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The ephah and the bath shall be of one measure, that the bath may contain the tenth part of an homer, and the ephah the tenth part of an homer: the measure thereof shall be after the homer.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the shekel &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; twenty gerahs: twenty shekels, five and twenty shekels, fifteen shekels, shall be your maneh.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the oblation that ye shall offer; the sixth part of an ephah of an homer of wheat, and ye shall give the sixth part of an ephah of an homer of barley:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Concerning the ordinance of oil, the bath of oil, &lt;i&gt;ye shall offer&lt;/i&gt; the tenth part of a bath out of the cor, &lt;i&gt;which is&lt;/i&gt; an homer of ten baths; for ten baths &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; an homer:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And one lamb out of the flock, out of two hundred, out of the fat pastures of Israel; for a meat offering, and for a burnt offering, and for peace offerings, to make reconciliation for them, saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">All the people of the land shall give this oblation for the prince in Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And it shall be the prince's part &lt;i&gt;to give&lt;/i&gt; burnt offerings, and meat offerings, and drink offerings, in the feasts, and in the new moons, and in the sabbaths, in all solemnities of the house of Israel: he shall prepare the sin offering, and the meat offering, and the burnt offering, and the peace offerings, to make reconciliation for the house of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; In the first &lt;i&gt;month&lt;/i&gt;, in the first &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the month, thou shalt take a young bullock without blemish, and cleanse the sanctuary:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the priest shall take of the blood of the sin offering, and put &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; upon the posts of the house, and upon the four corners of the settle of the altar, and upon the posts of the gate of the inner court.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And so thou shalt do the seventh &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the month for every one that erreth, and for &lt;i&gt;him that is&lt;/i&gt; simple: so shall ye reconcile the house.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">In the first &lt;i&gt;month&lt;/i&gt;, in the fourteenth day of the month, ye shall have the passover, a feast of seven days; unleavened bread shall be eaten.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And upon that day shall the prince prepare for himself and for all the people of the land a bullock &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a sin offering.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And seven days of the feast he shall prepare a burnt offering to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, seven bullocks and seven rams without blemish daily the seven days; and a kid of the goats daily &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; a sin offering.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And he shall prepare a meat offering of an ephah for a bullock, and an ephah for a ram, and an hin of oil for an ephah.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">In the seventh &lt;i&gt;month&lt;/i&gt;, in the fifteenth day of the month, shall he do the like in the feast of the seven days, according to the sin offering, according to the burnt offering, and according to the meat offering, and according to the oil.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>