<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="17" nextChapter="ezekiel_6.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 6" prevChapter="ezekiel_4.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 4" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And thou, son of man, take thee a sharp knife, take thee a barber's razor, and cause &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to pass upon thine head and upon thy beard: then take thee balances to weigh, and divide the &lt;i&gt;hair&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thou shalt burn with fire a third part in the midst of the city, when the days of the siege are fulfilled: and thou shalt take a third part, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; smite about it with a knife: and a third part thou shalt scatter in the wind; and I will draw out a sword after them.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou shalt also take thereof a few in number, and bind them in thy skirts.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Then take of them again, and cast them into the midst of the fire, and burn them in the fire; &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; thereof shall a fire come forth into all the house of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Jerusalem: I have set it in the midst of the nations and countries &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; round about her.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And she hath changed my judgments into wickedness more than the nations, and my statutes more than the countries that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; round about her: for they have refused my judgments and my statutes, they have not walked in them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Because ye multiplied more than the nations that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; round about you, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; have not walked in my statutes, neither have kept my judgments, neither have done according to the judgments of the nations that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; round about you;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I, even I, &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; against thee, and will execute judgments in the midst of thee in the sight of the nations.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And I will do in thee that which I have not done, and whereunto I will not do any more the like, because of all thine abominations.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Therefore the fathers shall eat the sons in the midst of thee, and the sons shall eat their fathers; and I will execute judgments in thee, and the whole remnant of thee will I scatter into all the winds.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Wherefore, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; I live, saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Surely, because thou hast defiled my sanctuary with all thy detestable things, and with all thine abominations, therefore will I also diminish &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt;; neither shall mine eye spare, neither will I have any pity.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">A third part of thee shall die with the pestilence, and with famine shall they be consumed in the midst of thee: and a third part shall fall by the sword round about thee; and I will scatter a third part into all the winds, and I will draw out a sword after them.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thus shall mine anger be accomplished, and I will cause my fury to rest upon them, and I will be comforted: and they shall know that I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have spoken &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; in my zeal, when I have accomplished my fury in them.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Moreover I will make thee waste, and a reproach among the nations that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; round about thee, in the sight of all that pass by.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So it shall be a reproach and a taunt, an instruction and an astonishment unto the nations that &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; round about thee, when I shall execute judgments in thee in anger and in fury and in furious rebukes. I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have spoken &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">When I shall send upon them the evil arrows of famine, which shall be for &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; destruction, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; which I will send to destroy you: and I will increase the famine upon you, and will break your staff of bread:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">So will I send upon you famine and evil beasts, and they shall bereave thee; and pestilence and blood shall pass through thee; and I will bring the sword upon thee. I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have spoken &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>