<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="43" verseCount="27" nextChapter="ezekiel_44.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 44" prevChapter="ezekiel_42.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 42" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Afterward he brought me to the gate, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the gate that looketh toward the east:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And, behold, the glory of the God of Israel came from the way of the east: and his voice &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; like a noise of many waters: and the earth shined with his glory.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it was&lt;/span&gt; according to the appearance of the vision which I saw, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; according to the vision that I saw when I came to destroy the city: and the visions &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; like the vision that I saw by the river Chebar; and I fell upon my face.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the glory of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came into the house by the way of the gate whose prospect &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; toward the east.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">So the spirit took me up, and brought me into the inner court; and, behold, the glory of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; filled the house.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; speaking unto me out of the house; and the man stood by me.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And he said unto me, Son of man, the place of my throne, and the place of the soles of my feet, where I will dwell in the midst of the children of Israel for ever, and my holy name, shall the house of Israel no more defile, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;neither&lt;/span&gt; they, nor their kings, by their whoredom, nor by the carcases of their kings in their high places.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">In their setting of their threshold by my thresholds, and their post by my posts, and the wall between me and them, they have even defiled my holy name by their abominations that they have committed: wherefore I have consumed them in mine anger.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Now let them put away their whoredom, and the carcases of their kings, far from me, and I will dwell in the midst of them for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Thou son of man, shew the house to the house of Israel, that they may be ashamed of their iniquities: and let them measure the pattern.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And if they be ashamed of all that they have done, shew them the form of the house, and the fashion thereof, and the goings out thereof, and the comings in thereof, and all the forms thereof, and all the ordinances thereof, and all the forms thereof, and all the laws thereof: and write &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; in their sight, that they may keep the whole form thereof, and all the ordinances thereof, and do them.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law of the house; Upon the top of the mountain the whole limit thereof round about &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; most holy. Behold, this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law of the house.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the measures of the altar after the cubits: The cubit &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a cubit and an hand breadth; even the bottom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a cubit, and the breadth a cubit, and the border thereof by the edge thereof round about &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a span: and this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the higher place of the altar.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And from the bottom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;upon&lt;/span&gt; the ground &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to the lower settle &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; two cubits, and the breadth one cubit; and from the lesser settle &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to the greater settle &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; four cubits, and the breadth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; cubit.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So the altar &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; four cubits; and from the altar and upward &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; four horns.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the altar &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; twelve &lt;span class="extra"&gt;cubits&lt;/span&gt; long, twelve broad, square in the four squares thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the settle &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; fourteen &lt;span class="extra"&gt;cubits&lt;/span&gt; long and fourteen broad in the four squares thereof; and the border about it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; half a cubit; and the bottom thereof &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a cubit about; and his stairs shall look toward the east.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And he said unto me, Son of man, thus saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; These &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the ordinances of the altar in the day when they shall make it, to offer burnt offerings thereon, and to sprinkle blood thereon.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And thou shalt give to the priests the Levites that be of the seed of Zadok, which approach unto me, to minister unto me, saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, a young bullock for a sin offering.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And thou shalt take of the blood thereof, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on the four horns of it, and on the four corners of the settle, and upon the border round about: thus shalt thou cleanse and purge it.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Thou shalt take the bullock also of the sin offering, and he shall burn it in the appointed place of the house, without the sanctuary.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And on the second day thou shalt offer a kid of the goats without blemish for a sin offering; and they shall cleanse the altar, as they did cleanse &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; with the bullock.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">When thou hast made an end of cleansing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, thou shalt offer a young bullock without blemish, and a ram out of the flock without blemish.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And thou shalt offer them before the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and the priests shall cast salt upon them, and they shall offer them up &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a burnt offering unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Seven days shalt thou prepare every day a goat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; a sin offering: they shall also prepare a young bullock, and a ram out of the flock, without blemish.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Seven days shall they purge the altar and purify it; and they shall consecrate themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And when these days are expired, it shall be, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; upon the eighth day, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; forward, the priests shall make your burnt offerings upon the altar, and your peace offerings; and I will accept you, saith the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>