<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="30" verseCount="26" nextChapter="ezekiel_31.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 31" prevChapter="ezekiel_29.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 29" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came again unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Son of man, prophesy and say, Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Howl ye, Woe worth the day!</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For the day &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; near, even the day of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; near, a cloudy day; it shall be the time of the heathen.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the sword shall come upon Egypt, and great pain shall be in Ethiopia, when the slain shall fall in Egypt, and they shall take away her multitude, and her foundations shall be broken down.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Ethiopia, and Libya, and Lydia, and all the mingled people, and Chub, and the men of the land that is in league, shall fall with them by the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; They also that uphold Egypt shall fall; and the pride of her power shall come down: from the tower of Syene shall they fall in it by the sword, saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they shall be desolate in the midst of the countries &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; desolate, and her cities shall be in the midst of the cities &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; wasted.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And they shall know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, when I have set a fire in Egypt, and &lt;i&gt;when&lt;/i&gt; all her helpers shall be destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">In that day shall messengers go forth from me in ships to make the careless Ethiopians afraid, and great pain shall come upon them, as in the day of Egypt: for, lo, it cometh.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; I will also make the multitude of Egypt to cease by the hand of Nebuchadrezzar king of Babylon.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He and his people with him, the terrible of the nations, shall be brought to destroy the land: and they shall draw their swords against Egypt, and fill the land with the slain.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I will make the rivers dry, and sell the land into the hand of the wicked: and I will make the land waste, and all that is therein, by the hand of strangers: I the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; have spoken &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; I will also destroy the idols, and I will cause &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; images to cease out of Noph; and there shall be no more a prince of the land of Egypt: and I will put a fear in the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And I will make Pathros desolate, and will set fire in Zoan, and will execute judgments in No.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And I will pour my fury upon Sin, the strength of Egypt; and I will cut off the multitude of No.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And I will set fire in Egypt: Sin shall have great pain, and No shall be rent asunder, and Noph &lt;i&gt;shall have&lt;/i&gt; distresses daily.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The young men of Aven and of Pi-beseth shall fall by the sword: and these &lt;i&gt;cities&lt;/i&gt; shall go into captivity.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">At Tehaphnehes also the day shall be darkened, when I shall break there the yokes of Egypt: and the pomp of her strength shall cease in her: as for her, a cloud shall cover her, and her daughters shall go into captivity.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thus will I execute judgments in Egypt: and they shall know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And it came to pass in the eleventh year, in the first &lt;i&gt;month&lt;/i&gt;, in the seventh &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the month, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Son of man, I have broken the arm of Pharaoh king of Egypt; and, lo, it shall not be bound up to be healed, to put a roller to bind it, to make it strong to hold the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; Behold, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; against Pharaoh king of Egypt, and will break his arms, the strong, and that which was broken; and I will cause the sword to fall out of his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And I will scatter the Egyptians among the nations, and will disperse them through the countries.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And I will strengthen the arms of the king of Babylon, and put my sword in his hand: but I will break Pharaoh's arms, and he shall groan before him with the groanings of a deadly wounded &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">But I will strengthen the arms of the king of Babylon, and the arms of Pharaoh shall fall down; and they shall know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, when I shall put my sword into the hand of the king of Babylon, and he shall stretch it out upon the land of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And I will scatter the Egyptians among the nations, and disperse them among the countries; and they shall know that I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>