<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="26" name="Ezekiel" bookPage="ezekiel.html" title="Ezekiel" chapterCount="48" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="daniel_1.html" nextTitle="Daniel" prevBook="lamentations_1.html" prevTitle="Lamentations">
    <chapter number="42" verseCount="20" nextChapter="ezekiel_43.html" nextTitle="Ezekiel 43" prevChapter="ezekiel_41.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel 41" chapterPage="ezekiel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then he brought me forth into the utter court, the way toward the north: and he brought me into the chamber that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; over against the separate place, and which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; before the building toward the north.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Before the length of an hundred cubits &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the north door, and the breadth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; fifty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Over against the twenty &lt;span class='extra'&gt;cubits&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; for the inner court, and over against the pavement which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; for the utter court, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; gallery against gallery in three &lt;span class='extra'&gt;stories&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And before the chambers &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; a walk of ten cubits breadth inward, a way of one cubit; and their doors toward the north.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Now the upper chambers &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; shorter: for the galleries were higher than these, than the lower, and than the middlemost of the building.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in three &lt;span class='extra'&gt;stories&lt;/span&gt;, but had not pillars as the pillars of the courts: therefore &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the building&lt;/span&gt; was straitened more than the lowest and the middlemost from the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the wall that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; without over against the chambers, toward the utter court on the forepart of the chambers, the length thereof &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; fifty cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For the length of the chambers that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the utter court &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; fifty cubits: and, lo, before the temple &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; an hundred cubits.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And from under these chambers &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the entry on the east side, as one goeth into them from the utter court.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The chambers &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the thickness of the wall of the court toward the east, over against the separate place, and over against the building.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the way before them &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; like the appearance of the chambers which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; toward the north, as long as they, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; as broad as they: and all their goings out &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; both according to their fashions, and according to their doors.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And according to the doors of the chambers that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; toward the south &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; a door in the head of the way, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the way directly before the wall toward the east, as one entereth into them.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Then said he unto me, The north chambers &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the south chambers, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; before the separate place, they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; holy chambers, where the priests that approach unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall eat the most holy things: there shall they lay the most holy things, and the meat offering, and the sin offering, and the trespass offering; for the place &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; holy.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">When the priests enter therein, then shall they not go out of the holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt; into the utter court, but there they shall lay their garments wherein they minister; for they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; holy; and shall put on other garments, and shall approach to &lt;span class='extra'&gt;those things&lt;/span&gt; which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; for the people.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Now when he had made an end of measuring the inner house, he brought me forth toward the gate whose prospect &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; toward the east, and measured it round about.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He measured the east side with the measuring reed, five hundred reeds, with the measuring reed round about.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He measured the north side, five hundred reeds, with the measuring reed round about.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He measured the south side, five hundred reeds, with the measuring reed.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">He turned about to the west side, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; measured five hundred reeds with the measuring reed.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He measured it by the four sides: it had a wall round about, five hundred &lt;span class='extra'&gt;reeds&lt;/span&gt; long, and five hundred broad, to make a separation between the sanctuary and the profane place.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>