<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="27" name="Daniel" bookPage="daniel.html" title="Daniel" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="hosea_1.html" nextTitle="Hosea" prevBook="ezekiel_1.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="13" nextChapter="hosea_1.html" nextTitle="Hosea 1" prevChapter="daniel_11.html" prevTitle="Daniel 11" chapterPage="daniel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And at that time shall Michael stand up, the great prince which standeth for the children of thy people: and there shall be a time of trouble, such as never was since there was a nation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to that same time: and at that time thy people shall be delivered, every one that shall be found written in the book.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And many of them that sleep in the dust of the earth shall awake, some to everlasting life, and some to shame &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; everlasting contempt.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they that be wise shall shine as the brightness of the firmament; and they that turn many to righteousness as the stars for ever and ever.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But thou, O Daniel, shut up the words, and seal the book, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to the time of the end: many shall run to and fro, and knowledge shall be increased.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Then I Daniel looked, and, behold, there stood other two, the one on this side of the bank of the river, and the other on that side of the bank of the river.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; said to the man clothed in linen, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; upon the waters of the river, How long &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall it be to&lt;/span&gt; the end of these wonders?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And I heard the man clothed in linen, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; upon the waters of the river, when he held up his right hand and his left hand unto heaven, and sware by him that liveth for ever that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it shall be&lt;/span&gt; for a time, times, and an half; and when he shall have accomplished to scatter the power of the holy people, all these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; shall be finished.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I heard, but I understood not: then said I, O my Lord, what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the end of these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he said, Go thy way, Daniel: for the words &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; closed up and sealed till the time of the end.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Many shall be purified, and made white, and tried; but the wicked shall do wickedly: and none of the wicked shall understand; but the wise shall understand.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And from the time &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the daily &lt;span class='extra'&gt;sacrifice&lt;/span&gt; shall be taken away, and the abomination that maketh desolate set up, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; a thousand two hundred and ninety days.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he that waiteth, and cometh to the thousand three hundred and five and thirty days.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But go thou thy way till the end &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt;: for thou shalt rest, and stand in thy lot at the end of the days.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>