<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="27" name="Daniel" bookPage="daniel.html" title="Daniel" chapterCount="12" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="hosea_1.html" nextTitle="Hosea" prevBook="ezekiel_1.html" prevTitle="Ezekiel">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="27" nextChapter="daniel_9.html" nextTitle="Daniel 9" prevChapter="daniel_7.html" prevTitle="Daniel 7" chapterPage="daniel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In the third year of the reign of king Belshazzar a vision appeared unto me, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even unto&lt;/span&gt; me Daniel, after that which appeared unto me at the first.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And I saw in a vision; and it came to pass, when I saw, that I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; at Shushan &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the palace, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the province of Elam; and I saw in a vision, and I was by the river of Ulai.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Then I lifted up mine eyes, and saw, and, behold, there stood before the river a ram which had &lt;span class='extra'&gt;two&lt;/span&gt; horns: and the &lt;span class='extra'&gt;two&lt;/span&gt; horns &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; high; but one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; higher than the other, and the higher came up last.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I saw the ram pushing westward, and northward, and southward; so that no beasts might stand before him, neither &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was there any&lt;/span&gt; that could deliver out of his hand; but he did according to his will, and became great.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And as I was considering, behold, an he goat came from the west on the face of the whole earth, and touched not the ground: and the goat &lt;span class='extra'&gt;had&lt;/span&gt; a notable horn between his eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he came to the ram that had &lt;span class='extra'&gt;two&lt;/span&gt; horns, which I had seen standing before the river, and ran unto him in the fury of his power.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And I saw him come close unto the ram, and he was moved with choler against him, and smote the ram, and brake his two horns: and there was no power in the ram to stand before him, but he cast him down to the ground, and stamped upon him: and there was none that could deliver the ram out of his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Therefore the he goat waxed very great: and when he was strong, the great horn was broken; and for it came up four notable ones toward the four winds of heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And out of one of them came forth a little horn, which waxed exceeding great, toward the south, and toward the east, and toward the pleasant &lt;span class='extra'&gt;land&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And it waxed great, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to the host of heaven; and it cast down &lt;span class='extra'&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of the host and of the stars to the ground, and stamped upon them.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Yea, he magnified &lt;span class='extra'&gt;himself&lt;/span&gt; even to the prince of the host, and by him the daily &lt;span class='extra'&gt;sacrifice&lt;/span&gt; was taken away, and the place of his sanctuary was cast down.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And an host was given &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; against the daily &lt;span class='extra'&gt;sacrifice&lt;/span&gt; by reason of transgression, and it cast down the truth to the ground; and it practised, and prospered.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Then I heard one saint speaking, and another saint said unto that certain &lt;span class='extra'&gt;saint&lt;/span&gt; which spake, How long &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the vision &lt;span class='extra'&gt;concerning&lt;/span&gt; the daily &lt;span class='extra'&gt;sacrifice&lt;/span&gt;, and the transgression of desolation, to give both the sanctuary and the host to be trodden under foot?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he said unto me, Unto two thousand and three hundred days; then shall the sanctuary be cleansed.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when I, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; I Daniel, had seen the vision, and sought for the meaning, then, behold, there stood before me as the appearance of a man.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And I heard a man's voice between &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the banks of&lt;/span&gt; Ulai, which called, and said, Gabriel, make this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; to understand the vision.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">So he came near where I stood: and when he came, I was afraid, and fell upon my face: but he said unto me, Understand, O son of man: for at the time of the end &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; the vision.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Now as he was speaking with me, I was in a deep sleep on my face toward the ground: but he touched me, and set me upright.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he said, Behold, I will make thee know what shall be in the last end of the indignation: for at the time appointed the end &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The ram which thou sawest having &lt;span class='extra'&gt;two&lt;/span&gt; horns &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the kings of Media and Persia.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the rough goat &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the king of Grecia: and the great horn that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; between his eyes &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the first king.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Now that being broken, whereas four stood up for it, four kingdoms shall stand up out of the nation, but not in his power.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And in the latter time of their kingdom, when the transgressors are come to the full, a king of fierce countenance, and understanding dark sentences, shall stand up.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And his power shall be mighty, but not by his own power: and he shall destroy wonderfully, and shall prosper, and practise, and shall destroy the mighty and the holy people.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And through his policy also he shall cause craft to prosper in his hand; and he shall magnify &lt;span class='extra'&gt;himself&lt;/span&gt; in his heart, and by peace shall destroy many: he shall also stand up against the Prince of princes; but he shall be broken without hand.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And the vision of the evening and the morning which was told &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; true: wherefore shut thou up the vision; for it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; for many days.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And I Daniel fainted, and was sick &lt;span class='extra'&gt;certain&lt;/span&gt; days; afterward I rose up, and did the king's business; and I was astonished at the vision, but none understood &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>