<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="28" name="Hosea" bookPage="hosea.html" title="Hosea" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joel_1.html" nextTitle="Joel" prevBook="daniel_1.html" prevTitle="Daniel">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="14" nextChapter="hosea_13.html" nextTitle="Hosea 13" prevChapter="hosea_11.html" prevTitle="Hosea 11" chapterPage="hosea_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Ephraim feedeth on wind, and followeth after the east wind: he daily increaseth lies and desolation; and they do make a covenant with the Assyrians, and oil is carried into Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath also a controversy with Judah, and will punish Jacob according to his ways; according to his doings will he recompense him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">He took his brother by the heel in the womb, and by his strength he had power with God:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Yea, he had power over the angel, and prevailed: he wept, and made supplication unto him: he found him &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; Beth-el, and there he spake with us;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Even the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God of hosts; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; his memorial.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Therefore turn thou to thy God: keep mercy and judgment, and wait on thy God continually.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">&lt;i&gt;He is&lt;/i&gt; a merchant, the balances of deceit &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in his hand: he loveth to oppress.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Ephraim said, Yet I am become rich, I have found me out substance: &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; all my labours they shall find none iniquity in me that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; sin.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And I &lt;i&gt;that am&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God from the land of Egypt will yet make thee to dwell in tabernacles, as in the days of the solemn feast.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I have also spoken by the prophets, and I have multiplied visions, and used similitudes, by the ministry of the prophets.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;i&gt;Is there&lt;/i&gt; iniquity &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; Gilead? surely they are vanity: they sacrifice bullocks in Gilgal; yea, their altars &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; as heaps in the furrows of the fields.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Jacob fled into the country of Syria, and Israel served for a wife, and for a wife he kept &lt;i&gt;sheep&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And by a prophet the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; brought Israel out of Egypt, and by a prophet was he preserved.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Ephraim provoked &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; to anger most bitterly: therefore shall he leave his blood upon him, and his reproach shall his Lord return unto him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>