<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="28" name="Hosea" bookPage="hosea.html" title="Hosea" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joel_1.html" nextTitle="Joel" prevBook="daniel_1.html" prevTitle="Daniel">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="15" nextChapter="hosea_6.html" nextTitle="Hosea 6" prevChapter="hosea_4.html" prevTitle="Hosea 4" chapterPage="hosea_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hear ye this, O priests; and hearken, ye house of Israel; and give ye ear, O house of the king; for judgment &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; toward you, because ye have been a snare on Mizpah, and a net spread upon Tabor.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the revolters are profound to make slaughter, though I &lt;i&gt;have been&lt;/i&gt; a rebuker of them all.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I know Ephraim, and Israel is not hid from me: for now, O Ephraim, thou committest whoredom, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Israel is defiled.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They will not frame their doings to turn unto their God: for the spirit of whoredoms &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the midst of them, and they have not known the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the pride of Israel doth testify to his face: therefore shall Israel and Ephraim fall in their iniquity; Judah also shall fall with them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">They shall go with their flocks and with their herds to seek the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; but they shall not find &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;; he hath withdrawn himself from them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">They have dealt treacherously against the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for they have begotten strange children: now shall a month devour them with their portions.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Blow ye the cornet in Gibeah, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the trumpet in Ramah: cry aloud &lt;i&gt;at&lt;/i&gt; Beth-aven, after thee, O Benjamin.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Ephraim shall be desolate in the day of rebuke: among the tribes of Israel have I made known that which shall surely be.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The princes of Judah were like them that remove the bound: &lt;i&gt;therefore&lt;/i&gt; I will pour out my wrath upon them like water.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Ephraim &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; oppressed &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; broken in judgment, because he willingly walked after the commandment.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; I &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; unto Ephraim as a moth, and to the house of Judah as rottenness.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">When Ephraim saw his sickness, and Judah &lt;i&gt;saw&lt;/i&gt; his wound, then went Ephraim to the Assyrian, and sent to king Jareb: yet could he not heal you, nor cure you of your wound.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For I &lt;i&gt;will be&lt;/i&gt; unto Ephraim as a lion, and as a young lion to the house of Judah: I, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; I, will tear and go away; I will take away, and none shall rescue &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">I will go &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; return to my place, till they acknowledge their offence, and seek my face: in their affliction they will seek me early.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>