<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="28" name="Hosea" bookPage="hosea.html" title="Hosea" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joel_1.html" nextTitle="Joel" prevBook="daniel_1.html" prevTitle="Daniel">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="14" nextChapter="hosea_9.html" nextTitle="Hosea 9" prevChapter="hosea_7.html" prevTitle="Hosea 7" chapterPage="hosea_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt; the trumpet to thy mouth. &lt;span class="extra"&gt;He shall come&lt;/span&gt; as an eagle against the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, because they have transgressed my covenant, and trespassed against my law.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Israel shall cry unto me, My God, we know thee.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Israel hath cast off &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the thing that is&lt;/span&gt; good: the enemy shall pursue him.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They have set up kings, but not by me: they have made princes, and I knew &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; not: of their silver and their gold have they made them idols, that they may be cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Thy calf, O Samaria, hath cast &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt; off; mine anger is kindled against them: how long &lt;span class="extra"&gt;will it be&lt;/span&gt; ere they attain to innocency?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For from Israel &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; it also: the workman made it; therefore it &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not God: but the calf of Samaria shall be broken in pieces.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For they have sown the wind, and they shall reap the whirlwind: it hath no stalk: the bud shall yield no meal: if so be it yield, the strangers shall swallow it up.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Israel is swallowed up: now shall they be among the Gentiles as a vessel wherein &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; no pleasure.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For they are gone up to Assyria, a wild ass alone by himself: Ephraim hath hired lovers.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Yea, though they have hired among the nations, now will I gather them, and they shall sorrow a little for the burden of the king of princes.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Because Ephraim hath made many altars to sin, altars shall be unto him to sin.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I have written to him the great things of my law, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; they were counted as a strange thing.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">They sacrifice flesh &lt;span class="extra"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the sacrifices of mine offerings, and eat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it; but&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; accepteth them not; now will he remember their iniquity, and visit their sins: they shall return to Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For Israel hath forgotten his Maker, and buildeth temples; and Judah hath multiplied fenced cities: but I will send a fire upon his cities, and it shall devour the palaces thereof.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>