<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="28" name="Hosea" bookPage="hosea.html" title="Hosea" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joel_1.html" nextTitle="Joel" prevBook="daniel_1.html" prevTitle="Daniel">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="19" nextChapter="hosea_5.html" nextTitle="Hosea 5" prevChapter="hosea_3.html" prevTitle="Hosea 3" chapterPage="hosea_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hear the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, ye children of Israel: for the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath a controversy with the inhabitants of the land, because &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no truth, nor mercy, nor knowledge of God in the land.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">By swearing, and lying, and killing, and stealing, and committing adultery, they break out, and blood toucheth blood.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Therefore shall the land mourn, and every one that dwelleth therein shall languish, with the beasts of the field, and with the fowls of heaven; yea, the fishes of the sea also shall be taken away.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Yet let no man strive, nor reprove another: for thy people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; as they that strive with the priest.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Therefore shalt thou fall in the day, and the prophet also shall fall with thee in the night, and I will destroy thy mother.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">My people are destroyed for lack of knowledge: because thou hast rejected knowledge, I will also reject thee, that thou shalt be no priest to me: seeing thou hast forgotten the law of thy God, I will also forget thy children.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">As they were increased, so they sinned against me: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;therefore&lt;/span&gt; will I change their glory into shame.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">They eat up the sin of my people, and they set their heart on their iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And there shall be, like people, like priest: and I will punish them for their ways, and reward them their doings.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For they shall eat, and not have enough: they shall commit whoredom, and shall not increase: because they have left off to take heed to the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Whoredom and wine and new wine take away the heart.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">My people ask counsel at their stocks, and their staff declareth unto them: for the spirit of whoredoms hath caused &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; to err, and they have gone a whoring from under their God.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">They sacrifice upon the tops of the mountains, and burn incense upon the hills, under oaks and poplars and elms, because the shadow thereof &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; good: therefore your daughters shall commit whoredom, and your spouses shall commit adultery.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I will not punish your daughters when they commit whoredom, nor your spouses when they commit adultery: for themselves are separated with whores, and they sacrifice with harlots: therefore the people &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; doth not understand shall fall.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Though thou, Israel, play the harlot, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yet&lt;/span&gt; let not Judah offend; and come not ye unto Gilgal, neither go ye up to Beth-aven, nor swear, The &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; liveth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For Israel slideth back as a backsliding heifer: now the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will feed them as a lamb in a large place.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Ephraim &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; joined to idols: let him alone.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Their drink is sour: they have committed whoredom continually: her rulers &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; shame do love, Give ye.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The wind hath bound her up in her wings, and they shall be ashamed because of their sacrifices.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>