<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="28" name="Hosea" bookPage="hosea.html" title="Hosea" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joel_1.html" nextTitle="Joel" prevBook="daniel_1.html" prevTitle="Daniel">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="16" nextChapter="hosea_8.html" nextTitle="Hosea 8" prevChapter="hosea_6.html" prevTitle="Hosea 6" chapterPage="hosea_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">When I would have healed Israel, then the iniquity of Ephraim was discovered, and the wickedness of Samaria: for they commit falsehood; and the thief cometh in, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the troop of robbers spoileth without.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And they consider not in their hearts &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I remember all their wickedness: now their own doings have beset them about; they are before my face.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">They make the king glad with their wickedness, and the princes with their lies.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; all adulterers, as an oven heated by the baker, &lt;i&gt;who&lt;/i&gt; ceaseth from raising after he hath kneaded the dough, until it be leavened.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">In the day of our king the princes have made &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; sick with bottles of wine; he stretched out his hand with scorners.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For they have made ready their heart like an oven, whiles they lie in wait: their baker sleepeth all the night; in the morning it burneth as a flaming fire.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">They are all hot as an oven, and have devoured their judges; all their kings are fallen: &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none among them that calleth unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Ephraim, he hath mixed himself among the people; Ephraim is a cake not turned.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Strangers have devoured his strength, and he knoweth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not: yea, gray hairs are here and there upon him, yet he knoweth not.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the pride of Israel testifieth to his face: and they do not return to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God, nor seek him for all this.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Ephraim also is like a silly dove without heart: they call to Egypt, they go to Assyria.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">When they shall go, I will spread my net upon them; I will bring them down as the fowls of the heaven; I will chastise them, as their congregation hath heard.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Woe unto them! for they have fled from me: destruction unto them! because they have transgressed against me: though I have redeemed them, yet they have spoken lies against me.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they have not cried unto me with their heart, when they howled upon their beds: they assemble themselves for corn and wine, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; they rebel against me.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Though I have bound &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; strengthened their arms, yet do they imagine mischief against me.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">They return, &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; not to the most High: they are like a deceitful bow: their princes shall fall by the sword for the rage of their tongue: this &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; their derision in the land of Egypt.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>