<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="28" name="Hosea" bookPage="hosea.html" title="Hosea" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joel_1.html" nextTitle="Joel" prevBook="daniel_1.html" prevTitle="Daniel">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="9" nextChapter="joel_1.html" nextTitle="Joel 1" prevChapter="hosea_13.html" prevTitle="Hosea 13" chapterPage="hosea_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">O Israel, return unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God; for thou hast fallen by thine iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Take with you words, and turn to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: say unto him, Take away all iniquity, and receive &lt;span class='extra'&gt;us&lt;/span&gt; graciously: so will we render the calves of our lips.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Asshur shall not save us; we will not ride upon horses: neither will we say any more to the work of our hands, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Ye are&lt;/span&gt; our gods: for in thee the fatherless findeth mercy.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">I will heal their backsliding, I will love them freely: for mine anger is turned away from him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I will be as the dew unto Israel: he shall grow as the lily, and cast forth his roots as Lebanon.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">His branches shall spread, and his beauty shall be as the olive tree, and his smell as Lebanon.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">They that dwell under his shadow shall return; they shall revive &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the corn, and grow as the vine: the scent thereof &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; as the wine of Lebanon.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Ephraim &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall say&lt;/span&gt;, What have I to do any more with idols? I have heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, and observed him: I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; like a green fir tree. From me is thy fruit found.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; wise, and he shall understand these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;? prudent, and he shall know them? for the ways of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; right, and the just shall walk in them: but the transgressors shall fall therein.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>