<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="28" name="Hosea" bookPage="hosea.html" title="Hosea" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joel_1.html" nextTitle="Joel" prevBook="daniel_1.html" prevTitle="Daniel">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="11" nextChapter="hosea_2.html" nextTitle="Hosea 2" prevChapter="daniel_12.html" prevTitle="Daniel 12" chapterPage="hosea_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that came unto Hosea, the son of Beeri, in the days of Uzziah, Jotham, Ahaz, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Hezekiah, kings of Judah, and in the days of Jeroboam the son of Joash, king of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The beginning of the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; by Hosea. And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said to Hosea, Go, take unto thee a wife of whoredoms and children of whoredoms: for the land hath committed great whoredom, &lt;i&gt;departing&lt;/i&gt; from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">So he went and took Gomer the daughter of Diblaim; which conceived, and bare him a son.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto him, Call his name Jezreel; for yet a little &lt;i&gt;while&lt;/i&gt;, and I will avenge the blood of Jezreel upon the house of Jehu, and will cause to cease the kingdom of the house of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And it shall come to pass at that day, that I will break the bow of Israel in the valley of Jezreel.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And she conceived again, and bare a daughter. And &lt;i&gt;God&lt;/i&gt; said unto him, Call her name Lo-ruhamah: for I will no more have mercy upon the house of Israel; but I will utterly take them away.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But I will have mercy upon the house of Judah, and will save them by the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God, and will not save them by bow, nor by sword, nor by battle, by horses, nor by horsemen.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Now when she had weaned Lo-ruhamah, she conceived, and bare a son.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then said &lt;i&gt;God&lt;/i&gt;, Call his name Lo-ammi: for ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; not my people, and I will not be your &lt;i&gt;God&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Yet the number of the children of Israel shall be as the sand of the sea, which cannot be measured nor numbered; and it shall come to pass, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; in the place where it was said unto them, Ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; not my people, &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt; it shall be said unto them, &lt;i&gt;Ye are&lt;/i&gt; the sons of the living God.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then shall the children of Judah and the children of Israel be gathered together, and appoint themselves one head, and they shall come up out of the land: for great &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the day of Jezreel.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>