<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="28" name="Hosea" bookPage="hosea.html" title="Hosea" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joel_1.html" nextTitle="Joel" prevBook="daniel_1.html" prevTitle="Daniel">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="17" nextChapter="hosea_10.html" nextTitle="Hosea 10" prevChapter="hosea_8.html" prevTitle="Hosea 8" chapterPage="hosea_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Rejoice not, O Israel, for joy, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;other&lt;/span&gt; people: for thou hast gone a whoring from thy God, thou hast loved a reward upon every cornfloor.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The floor and the winepress shall not feed them, and the new wine shall fail in her.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">They shall not dwell in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s land; but Ephraim shall return to Egypt, and they shall eat unclean &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; in Assyria.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They shall not offer wine &lt;span class='extra'&gt;offerings&lt;/span&gt; to the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, neither shall they be pleasing unto him: their sacrifices &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; unto them as the bread of mourners; all that eat thereof shall be polluted: for their bread for their soul shall not come into the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">What will ye do in the solemn day, and in the day of the feast of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For, lo, they are gone because of destruction: Egypt shall gather them up, Memphis shall bury them: the pleasant &lt;span class='extra'&gt;places&lt;/span&gt; for their silver, nettles shall possess them: thorns &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; in their tabernacles.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The days of visitation are come, the days of recompence are come; Israel shall know &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;: the prophet &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a fool, the spiritual man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mad, for the multitude of thine iniquity, and the great hatred.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The watchman of Ephraim &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; with my God: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; the prophet &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a snare of a fowler in all his ways, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; hatred in the house of his God.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">They have deeply corrupted &lt;span class='extra'&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt;, as in the days of Gibeah: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;therefore&lt;/span&gt; he will remember their iniquity, he will visit their sins.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I found Israel like grapes in the wilderness; I saw your fathers as the firstripe in the fig tree at her first time: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; they went to Baal-peor, and separated themselves unto &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shame; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; abominations were according as they loved.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;As for&lt;/span&gt; Ephraim, their glory shall fly away like a bird, from the birth, and from the womb, and from the conception.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Though they bring up their children, yet will I bereave them, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that there shall&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; a man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;left&lt;/span&gt;: yea, woe also to them when I depart from them!</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Ephraim, as I saw Tyrus, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; planted in a pleasant place: but Ephraim shall bring forth his children to the murderer.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Give them, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: what wilt thou give? give them a miscarrying womb and dry breasts.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">All their wickedness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in Gilgal: for there I hated them: for the wickedness of their doings I will drive them out of mine house, I will love them no more: all their princes &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; revolters.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Ephraim is smitten, their root is dried up, they shall bear no fruit: yea, though they bring forth, yet will I slay &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the beloved &lt;span class='extra'&gt;fruit&lt;/span&gt; of their womb.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">My God will cast them away, because they did not hearken unto him: and they shall be wanderers among the nations.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>