<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="28" name="Hosea" bookPage="hosea.html" title="Hosea" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="joel_1.html" nextTitle="Joel" prevBook="daniel_1.html" prevTitle="Daniel">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="12" nextChapter="hosea_12.html" nextTitle="Hosea 12" prevChapter="hosea_10.html" prevTitle="Hosea 10" chapterPage="hosea_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">When Israel &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a child, then I loved him, and called my son out of Egypt.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;i&gt;As&lt;/i&gt; they called them, so they went from them: they sacrificed unto Baalim, and burned incense to graven images.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I taught Ephraim also to go, taking them by their arms; but they knew not that I healed them.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I drew them with cords of a man, with bands of love: and I was to them as they that take off the yoke on their jaws, and I laid meat unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">He shall not return into the land of Egypt, but the Assyrian shall be his king, because they refused to return.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the sword shall abide on his cities, and shall consume his branches, and devour &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;, because of their own counsels.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And my people are bent to backsliding from me: though they called them to the most High, none at all would exalt &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">How shall I give thee up, Ephraim? &lt;i&gt;how&lt;/i&gt; shall I deliver thee, Israel? how shall I make thee as Admah? &lt;i&gt;how&lt;/i&gt; shall I set thee as Zeboim? mine heart is turned within me, my repentings are kindled together.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I will not execute the fierceness of mine anger, I will not return to destroy Ephraim: for I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; God, and not man; the Holy One in the midst of thee: and I will not enter into the city.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">They shall walk after the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: he shall roar like a lion: when he shall roar, then the children shall tremble from the west.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">They shall tremble as a bird out of Egypt, and as a dove out of the land of Assyria: and I will place them in their houses, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Ephraim compasseth me about with lies, and the house of Israel with deceit: but Judah yet ruleth with God, and is faithful with the saints.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>