<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="29" name="Joel" bookPage="joel.html" title="Joel" chapterCount="3" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="amos_1.html" nextTitle="Amos" prevBook="hosea_1.html" prevTitle="Hosea">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="20" nextChapter="joel_2.html" nextTitle="Joel 2" prevChapter="hosea_14.html" prevTitle="Hosea 14" chapterPage="joel_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that came to Joel the son of Pethuel.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Hear this, ye old men, and give ear, all ye inhabitants of the land. Hath this been in your days, or even in the days of your fathers?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Tell ye your children of it, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; your children &lt;span class="extra"&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt; their children, and their children another generation.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">That which the palmerworm hath left hath the locust eaten; and that which the locust hath left hath the cankerworm eaten; and that which the cankerworm hath left hath the caterpiller eaten.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Awake, ye drunkards, and weep; and howl, all ye drinkers of wine, because of the new wine; for it is cut off from your mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For a nation is come up upon my land, strong, and without number, whose teeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the teeth of a lion, and he hath the cheek teeth of a great lion.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He hath laid my vine waste, and barked my fig tree: he hath made it clean bare, and cast &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; away; the branches thereof are made white.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Lament like a virgin girded with sackcloth for the husband of her youth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">The meat offering and the drink offering is cut off from the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; the priests, the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s ministers, mourn.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The field is wasted, the land mourneth; for the corn is wasted: the new wine is dried up, the oil languisheth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Be ye ashamed, O ye husbandmen; howl, O ye vinedressers, for the wheat and for the barley; because the harvest of the field is perished.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The vine is dried up, and the fig tree languisheth; the pomegranate tree, the palm tree also, and the apple tree, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all the trees of the field, are withered: because joy is withered away from the sons of men.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Gird yourselves, and lament, ye priests: howl, ye ministers of the altar: come, lie all night in sackcloth, ye ministers of my God: for the meat offering and the drink offering is withholden from the house of your God.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Sanctify ye a fast, call a solemn assembly, gather the elders &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; all the inhabitants of the land &lt;span class="extra"&gt;into&lt;/span&gt; the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; your God, and cry unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Alas for the day! for the day of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; at hand, and as a destruction from the Almighty shall it come.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Is not the meat cut off before our eyes, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yea&lt;/span&gt;, joy and gladness from the house of our God?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The seed is rotten under their clods, the garners are laid desolate, the barns are broken down; for the corn is withered.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">How do the beasts groan! the herds of cattle are perplexed, because they have no pasture; yea, the flocks of sheep are made desolate.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to thee will I cry: for the fire hath devoured the pastures of the wilderness, and the flame hath burned all the trees of the field.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The beasts of the field cry also unto thee: for the rivers of waters are dried up, and the fire hath devoured the pastures of the wilderness.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>