<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="30" name="Amos" bookPage="amos.html" title="Amos" chapterCount="9" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="obadiah_1.html" nextTitle="Obadiah" prevBook="joel_1.html" prevTitle="Joel">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="17" nextChapter="amos_8.html" nextTitle="Amos 8" prevChapter="amos_6.html" prevTitle="Amos 6" chapterPage="amos_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Thus hath the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; shewed unto me; and, behold, he formed grasshoppers in the beginning of the shooting up of the latter growth; and, lo, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it was&lt;/span&gt; the latter growth after the king's mowings.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And it came to pass, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; when they had made an end of eating the grass of the land, then I said, O Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, forgive, I beseech thee: by whom shall Jacob arise? for he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; small.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; repented for this: It shall not be, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Thus hath the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; shewed unto me: and, behold, the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; called to contend by fire, and it devoured the great deep, and did eat up a part.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then said I, O Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, cease, I beseech thee: by whom shall Jacob arise? for he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; small.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; repented for this: This also shall not be, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Thus he shewed me: and, behold, the Lord stood upon a wall &lt;span class='extra'&gt;made&lt;/span&gt; by a plumbline, with a plumbline in his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, Amos, what seest thou? And I said, A plumbline. Then said the Lord, Behold, I will set a plumbline in the midst of my people Israel: I will not again pass by them any more:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the high places of Isaac shall be desolate, and the sanctuaries of Israel shall be laid waste; and I will rise against the house of Jeroboam with the sword.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Then Amaziah the priest of Beth-el sent to Jeroboam king of Israel, saying, Amos hath conspired against thee in the midst of the house of Israel: the land is not able to bear all his words.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For thus Amos saith, Jeroboam shall die by the sword, and Israel shall surely be led away captive out of their own land.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Also Amaziah said unto Amos, O thou seer, go, flee thee away into the land of Judah, and there eat bread, and prophesy there:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But prophesy not again any more at Beth-el: for it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the king's chapel, and it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the king's court.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Then answered Amos, and said to Amaziah, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; no prophet, neither &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; I a prophet's son; but I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; an herdman, and a gatherer of sycomore fruit:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; took me as I followed the flock, and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, Go, prophesy unto my people Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Now therefore hear thou the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: Thou sayest, Prophesy not against Israel, and drop not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thy word&lt;/span&gt; against the house of Isaac.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; Thy wife shall be an harlot in the city, and thy sons and thy daughters shall fall by the sword, and thy land shall be divided by line; and thou shalt die in a polluted land: and Israel shall surely go into captivity forth of his land.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>