<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="30" name="Amos" bookPage="amos.html" title="Amos" chapterCount="9" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="obadiah_1.html" nextTitle="Obadiah" prevBook="joel_1.html" prevTitle="Joel">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="16" nextChapter="amos_3.html" nextTitle="Amos 3" prevChapter="amos_1.html" prevTitle="Amos 1" chapterPage="amos_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; For three transgressions of Moab, and for four, I will not turn away &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the punishment&lt;/span&gt; thereof; because he burned the bones of the king of Edom into lime:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">But I will send a fire upon Moab, and it shall devour the palaces of Kerioth: and Moab shall die with tumult, with shouting, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; with the sound of the trumpet:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I will cut off the judge from the midst thereof, and will slay all the princes thereof with him, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; For three transgressions of Judah, and for four, I will not turn away &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the punishment&lt;/span&gt; thereof; because they have despised the law of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and have not kept his commandments, and their lies caused them to err, after the which their fathers have walked:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But I will send a fire upon Judah, and it shall devour the palaces of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; For three transgressions of Israel, and for four, I will not turn away &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the punishment&lt;/span&gt; thereof; because they sold the righteous for silver, and the poor for a pair of shoes;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">That pant after the dust of the earth on the head of the poor, and turn aside the way of the meek: and a man and his father will go in unto the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;same&lt;/span&gt; maid, to profane my holy name:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And they lay &lt;span class="extra"&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt; down upon clothes laid to pledge by every altar, and they drink the wine of the condemned &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the house of their god.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Yet destroyed I the Amorite before them, whose height &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; like the height of the cedars, and he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; strong as the oaks; yet I destroyed his fruit from above, and his roots from beneath.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Also I brought you up from the land of Egypt, and led you forty years through the wilderness, to possess the land of the Amorite.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I raised up of your sons for prophets, and of your young men for Nazarites. &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Is it&lt;/span&gt; not even thus, O ye children of Israel? saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But ye gave the Nazarites wine to drink; and commanded the prophets, saying, Prophesy not.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Behold, I am pressed under you, as a cart is pressed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; full of sheaves.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Therefore the flight shall perish from the swift, and the strong shall not strengthen his force, neither shall the mighty deliver himself:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Neither shall he stand that handleth the bow; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he that is&lt;/span&gt; swift of foot shall not deliver &lt;span class="extra"&gt;himself&lt;/span&gt;: neither shall he that rideth the horse deliver himself.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he that is&lt;/span&gt; courageous among the mighty shall flee away naked in that day, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>