<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="30" name="Amos" bookPage="amos.html" title="Amos" chapterCount="9" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="obadiah_1.html" nextTitle="Obadiah" prevBook="joel_1.html" prevTitle="Joel">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="13" nextChapter="amos_5.html" nextTitle="Amos 5" prevChapter="amos_3.html" prevTitle="Amos 3" chapterPage="amos_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hear this word, ye kine of Bashan, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in the mountain of Samaria, which oppress the poor, which crush the needy, which say to their masters, Bring, and let us drink.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; hath sworn by his holiness, that, lo, the days shall come upon you, that he will take you away with hooks, and your posterity with fishhooks.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And ye shall go out at the breaches, every &lt;span class='extra'&gt;cow at that which is&lt;/span&gt; before her; and ye shall cast &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; into the palace, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Come to Beth-el, and transgress; at Gilgal multiply transgression; and bring your sacrifices every morning, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; your tithes after three years:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And offer a sacrifice of thanksgiving with leaven, and proclaim &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; publish the free offerings: for this liketh you, O ye children of Israel, saith the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">And I also have given you cleanness of teeth in all your cities, and want of bread in all your places: yet have ye not returned unto me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And also I have withholden the rain from you, when &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there were&lt;/span&gt; yet three months to the harvest: and I caused it to rain upon one city, and caused it not to rain upon another city: one piece was rained upon, and the piece whereupon it rained not withered.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">So two &lt;span class='extra'&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; three cities wandered unto one city, to drink water; but they were not satisfied: yet have ye not returned unto me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I have smitten you with blasting and mildew: when your gardens and your vineyards and your fig trees and your olive trees increased, the palmerworm devoured &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;: yet have ye not returned unto me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I have sent among you the pestilence after the manner of Egypt: your young men have I slain with the sword, and have taken away your horses; and I have made the stink of your camps to come up unto your nostrils: yet have ye not returned unto me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">I have overthrown &lt;span class='extra'&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of you, as God overthrew Sodom and Gomorrah, and ye were as a firebrand plucked out of the burning: yet have ye not returned unto me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore thus will I do unto thee, O Israel: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; because I will do this unto thee, prepare to meet thy God, O Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For, lo, he that formeth the mountains, and createth the wind, and declareth unto man what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his thought, that maketh the morning darkness, and treadeth upon the high places of the earth, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, The God of hosts, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his name.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>