<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="30" name="Amos" bookPage="amos.html" title="Amos" chapterCount="9" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="obadiah_1.html" nextTitle="Obadiah" prevBook="joel_1.html" prevTitle="Joel">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="15" nextChapter="amos_4.html" nextTitle="Amos 4" prevChapter="amos_2.html" prevTitle="Amos 2" chapterPage="amos_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Hear this word that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken against you, O children of Israel, against the whole family which I brought up from the land of Egypt, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">You only have I known of all the families of the earth: therefore I will punish you for all your iniquities.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Can two walk together, except they be agreed?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Will a lion roar in the forest, when he hath no prey? will a young lion cry out of his den, if he have taken nothing?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Can a bird fall in a snare upon the earth, where no gin &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; for him? shall &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; take up a snare from the earth, and have taken nothing at all?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Shall a trumpet be blown in the city, and the people not be afraid? shall there be evil in a city, and the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath not done &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Surely the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; will do nothing, but he revealeth his secret unto his servants the prophets.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The lion hath roared, who will not fear? the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; hath spoken, who can but prophesy?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Publish in the palaces at Ashdod, and in the palaces in the land of Egypt, and say, Assemble yourselves upon the mountains of Samaria, and behold the great tumults in the midst thereof, and the oppressed in the midst thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For they know not to do right, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, who store up violence and robbery in their palaces.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Therefore thus saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;; An adversary &lt;i&gt;there shall be&lt;/i&gt; even round about the land; and he shall bring down thy strength from thee, and thy palaces shall be spoiled.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; As the shepherd taketh out of the mouth of the lion two legs, or a piece of an ear; so shall the children of Israel be taken out that dwell in Samaria in the corner of a bed, and in Damascus &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; a couch.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Hear ye, and testify in the house of Jacob, saith the Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;, the God of hosts,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">That in the day that I shall visit the transgressions of Israel upon him I will also visit the altars of Beth-el: and the horns of the altar shall be cut off, and fall to the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And I will smite the winter house with the summer house; and the houses of ivory shall perish, and the great houses shall have an end, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>