<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="30" name="Amos" bookPage="amos.html" title="Amos" chapterCount="9" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="obadiah_1.html" nextTitle="Obadiah" prevBook="joel_1.html" prevTitle="Joel">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="14" nextChapter="amos_7.html" nextTitle="Amos 7" prevChapter="amos_5.html" prevTitle="Amos 5" chapterPage="amos_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Woe to them &lt;i&gt;that are&lt;/i&gt; at ease in Zion, and trust in the mountain of Samaria, &lt;i&gt;which are&lt;/i&gt; named chief of the nations, to whom the house of Israel came!</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Pass ye unto Calneh, and see; and from thence go ye to Hamath the great: then go down to Gath of the Philistines: &lt;i&gt;be they&lt;/i&gt; better than these kingdoms? or their border greater than your border?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Ye that put far away the evil day, and cause the seat of violence to come near;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">That lie upon beds of ivory, and stretch themselves upon their couches, and eat the lambs out of the flock, and the calves out of the midst of the stall;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">That chant to the sound of the viol, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; invent to themselves instruments of musick, like David;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">That drink wine in bowls, and anoint themselves with the chief ointments: but they are not grieved for the affliction of Joseph.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Therefore now shall they go captive with the first that go captive, and the banquet of them that stretched themselves shall be removed.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The Lord &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; hath sworn by himself, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; the God of hosts, I abhor the excellency of Jacob, and hate his palaces: therefore will I deliver up the city with all that is therein.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And it shall come to pass, if there remain ten men in one house, that they shall die.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And a man's uncle shall take him up, and he that burneth him, to bring out the bones out of the house, and shall say unto him that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; by the sides of the house, &lt;i&gt;Is there&lt;/i&gt; yet &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; with thee? and he shall say, No. Then shall he say, Hold thy tongue: for we may not make mention of the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For, behold, the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; commandeth, and he will smite the great house with breaches, and the little house with clefts.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Shall horses run upon the rock? will &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; plow &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt; with oxen? for ye have turned judgment into gall, and the fruit of righteousness into hemlock:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Ye which rejoice in a thing of nought, which say, Have we not taken to us horns by our own strength?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But, behold, I will raise up against you a nation, O house of Israel, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; the God of hosts; and they shall afflict you from the entering in of Hemath unto the river of the wilderness.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>