<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="32" name="Jonah" bookPage="jonah.html" title="Jonah" chapterCount="4" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="micah_1.html" nextTitle="Micah" prevBook="obadiah_1.html" prevTitle="Obadiah">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="11" nextChapter="micah_1.html" nextTitle="Micah 1" prevChapter="jonah_3.html" prevTitle="Jonah 3" chapterPage="jonah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">But it displeased Jonah exceedingly, and he was very angry.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he prayed unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and said, I pray thee, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; not this my saying, when I was yet in my country? Therefore I fled before unto Tarshish: for I knew that thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; a gracious God, and merciful, slow to anger, and of great kindness, and repentest thee of the evil.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Therefore now, O &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, take, I beseech thee, my life from me; for &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; better for me to die than to live.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Then said the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Doest thou well to be angry?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">So Jonah went out of the city, and sat on the east side of the city, and there made him a booth, and sat under it in the shadow, till he might see what would become of the city.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God prepared a gourd, and made &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to come up over Jonah, that it might be a shadow over his head, to deliver him from his grief. So Jonah was exceeding glad of the gourd.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But God prepared a worm when the morning rose the next day, and it smote the gourd that it withered.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And it came to pass, when the sun did arise, that God prepared a vehement east wind; and the sun beat upon the head of Jonah, that he fainted, and wished in himself to die, and said, &lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; better for me to die than to live.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And God said to Jonah, Doest thou well to be angry for the gourd? And he said, I do well to be angry, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; unto death.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then said the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, Thou hast had pity on the gourd, for the which thou hast not laboured, neither madest it grow; which came up in a night, and perished in a night:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And should not I spare Nineveh, that great city, wherein are more than sixscore thousand persons that cannot discern between their right hand and their left hand; and &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; much cattle?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>