<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="32" name="Jonah" bookPage="jonah.html" title="Jonah" chapterCount="4" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="micah_1.html" nextTitle="Micah" prevBook="obadiah_1.html" prevTitle="Obadiah">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="10" nextChapter="jonah_3.html" nextTitle="Jonah 3" prevChapter="jonah_1.html" prevTitle="Jonah 1" chapterPage="jonah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then Jonah prayed unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God out of the fish's belly,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And said, I cried by reason of mine affliction unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and he heard me; out of the belly of hell cried I, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; thou heardest my voice.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For thou hadst cast me into the deep, in the midst of the seas; and the floods compassed me about: all thy billows and thy waves passed over me.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Then I said, I am cast out of thy sight; yet I will look again toward thy holy temple.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The waters compassed me about, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to the soul: the depth closed me round about, the weeds were wrapped about my head.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I went down to the bottoms of the mountains; the earth with her bars &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; about me for ever: yet hast thou brought up my life from corruption, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">When my soul fainted within me I remembered the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and my prayer came in unto thee, into thine holy temple.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">They that observe lying vanities forsake their own mercy.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But I will sacrifice unto thee with the voice of thanksgiving; I will pay &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; that I have vowed. Salvation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake unto the fish, and it vomited out Jonah upon the dry &lt;span class='extra'&gt;land&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>