<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="32" name="Jonah" bookPage="jonah.html" title="Jonah" chapterCount="4" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="micah_1.html" nextTitle="Micah" prevBook="obadiah_1.html" prevTitle="Obadiah">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="17" nextChapter="jonah_2.html" nextTitle="Jonah 2" prevChapter="obadiah_1.html" prevTitle="Obadiah 1" chapterPage="jonah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto Jonah the son of Amittai, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Arise, go to Nineveh, that great city, and cry against it; for their wickedness is come up before me.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But Jonah rose up to flee unto Tarshish from the presence of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and went down to Joppa; and he found a ship going to Tarshish: so he paid the fare thereof, and went down into it, to go with them unto Tarshish from the presence of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">But the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; sent out a great wind into the sea, and there was a mighty tempest in the sea, so that the ship was like to be broken.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then the mariners were afraid, and cried every man unto his god, and cast forth the wares that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the ship into the sea, to lighten &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; of them. But Jonah was gone down into the sides of the ship; and he lay, and was fast asleep.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">So the shipmaster came to him, and said unto him, What meanest thou, O sleeper? arise, call upon thy God, if so be that God will think upon us, that we perish not.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they said every one to his fellow, Come, and let us cast lots, that we may know for whose cause this evil &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon us. So they cast lots, and the lot fell upon Jonah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then said they unto him, Tell us, we pray thee, for whose cause this evil &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon us; What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thine occupation? and whence comest thou? what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy country? and of what people &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; thou?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he said unto them, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; an Hebrew; and I fear the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, the God of heaven, which hath made the sea and the dry &lt;span class='extra'&gt;land&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then were the men exceedingly afraid, and said unto him, Why hast thou done this? For the men knew that he fled from the presence of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, because he had told them.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Then said they unto him, What shall we do unto thee, that the sea may be calm unto us? for the sea wrought, and was tempestuous.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he said unto them, Take me up, and cast me forth into the sea; so shall the sea be calm unto you: for I know that for my sake this great tempest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; upon you.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Nevertheless the men rowed hard to bring &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to the land; but they could not: for the sea wrought, and was tempestuous against them.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Wherefore they cried unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and said, We beseech thee, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, we beseech thee, let us not perish for this man's life, and lay not upon us innocent blood: for thou, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, hast done as it pleased thee.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So they took up Jonah, and cast him forth into the sea: and the sea ceased from her raging.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Then the men feared the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; exceedingly, and offered a sacrifice unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and made vows.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Now the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; had prepared a great fish to swallow up Jonah. And Jonah was in the belly of the fish three days and three nights.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>