<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="32" name="Jonah" bookPage="jonah.html" title="Jonah" chapterCount="4" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="micah_1.html" nextTitle="Micah" prevBook="obadiah_1.html" prevTitle="Obadiah">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="10" nextChapter="jonah_4.html" nextTitle="Jonah 4" prevChapter="jonah_2.html" prevTitle="Jonah 2" chapterPage="jonah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto Jonah the second time, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Arise, go unto Nineveh, that great city, and preach unto it the preaching that I bid thee.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">So Jonah arose, and went unto Nineveh, according to the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. Now Nineveh was an exceeding great city of three days' journey.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Jonah began to enter into the city a day's journey, and he cried, and said, Yet forty days, and Nineveh shall be overthrown.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">So the people of Nineveh believed God, and proclaimed a fast, and put on sackcloth, from the greatest of them even to the least of them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For word came unto the king of Nineveh, and he arose from his throne, and he laid his robe from him, and covered &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; with sackcloth, and sat in ashes.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he caused &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to be proclaimed and published through Nineveh by the decree of the king and his nobles, saying, Let neither man nor beast, herd nor flock, taste any thing: let them not feed, nor drink water:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But let man and beast be covered with sackcloth, and cry mightily unto God: yea, let them turn every one from his evil way, and from the violence that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in their hands.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Who can tell &lt;span class='extra'&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; God will turn and repent, and turn away from his fierce anger, that we perish not?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And God saw their works, that they turned from their evil way; and God repented of the evil, that he had said that he would do unto them; and he did &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; not.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>