<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="33" name="Micah" bookPage="micah.html" title="Micah" chapterCount="7" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="nahum_1.html" nextTitle="Nahum" prevBook="jonah_1.html" prevTitle="Jonah">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="12" nextChapter="micah_4.html" nextTitle="Micah 4" prevChapter="micah_2.html" prevTitle="Micah 2" chapterPage="micah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And I said, Hear, I pray you, O heads of Jacob, and ye princes of the house of Israel; &lt;i&gt;Is it&lt;/i&gt; not for you to know judgment?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Who hate the good, and love the evil; who pluck off their skin from off them, and their flesh from off their bones;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Who also eat the flesh of my people, and flay their skin from off them; and they break their bones, and chop them in pieces, as for the pot, and as flesh within the caldron.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Then shall they cry unto the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, but he will not hear them: he will even hide his face from them at that time, as they have behaved themselves ill in their doings.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; concerning the prophets that make my people err, that bite with their teeth, and cry, Peace; and he that putteth not into their mouths, they even prepare war against him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Therefore night &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; unto you, that ye shall not have a vision; and it shall be dark unto you, that ye shall not divine; and the sun shall go down over the prophets, and the day shall be dark over them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then shall the seers be ashamed, and the diviners confounded: yea, they shall all cover their lips; for &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no answer of God.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">But truly I am full of power by the spirit of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and of judgment, and of might, to declare unto Jacob his transgression, and to Israel his sin.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Hear this, I pray you, ye heads of the house of Jacob, and princes of the house of Israel, that abhor judgment, and pervert all equity.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">They build up Zion with blood, and Jerusalem with iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The heads thereof judge for reward, and the priests thereof teach for hire, and the prophets thereof divine for money: yet will they lean upon the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and say, &lt;i&gt;Is&lt;/i&gt; not the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; among us? none evil can come upon us.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore shall Zion for your sake be plowed &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; a field, and Jerusalem shall become heaps, and the mountain of the house as the high places of the forest.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>