<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="33" name="Micah" bookPage="micah.html" title="Micah" chapterCount="7" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="nahum_1.html" nextTitle="Nahum" prevBook="jonah_1.html" prevTitle="Jonah">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="20" nextChapter="nahum_1.html" nextTitle="Nahum 1" prevChapter="micah_6.html" prevTitle="Micah 6" chapterPage="micah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Woe is me! for I am as when they have gathered the summer fruits, as the grapegleanings of the vintage: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; no cluster to eat: my soul desired the firstripe fruit.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The good &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; is perished out of the earth: and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none upright among men: they all lie in wait for blood; they hunt every man his brother with a net.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">That they may do evil with both hands earnestly, the prince asketh, and the judge &lt;span class='extra'&gt;asketh&lt;/span&gt; for a reward; and the great &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt;, he uttereth his mischievous desire: so they wrap it up.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The best of them &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; as a brier: the most upright &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is sharper&lt;/span&gt; than a thorn hedge: the day of thy watchmen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; thy visitation cometh; now shall be their perplexity.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Trust ye not in a friend, put ye not confidence in a guide: keep the doors of thy mouth from her that lieth in thy bosom.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For the son dishonoureth the father, the daughter riseth up against her mother, the daughter in law against her mother in law; a man's enemies &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the men of his own house.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Therefore I will look unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; I will wait for the God of my salvation: my God will hear me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Rejoice not against me, O mine enemy: when I fall, I shall arise; when I sit in darkness, the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a light unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I will bear the indignation of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, because I have sinned against him, until he plead my cause, and execute judgment for me: he will bring me forth to the light, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; I shall behold his righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then &lt;span class='extra'&gt;she that is&lt;/span&gt; mine enemy shall see &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and shame shall cover her which said unto me, Where is the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God? mine eyes shall behold her: now shall she be trodden down as the mire of the streets.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;In&lt;/span&gt; the day that thy walls are to be built, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; that day shall the decree be far removed.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;In&lt;/span&gt; that day &lt;span class='extra'&gt;also&lt;/span&gt; he shall come even to thee from Assyria, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the fortified cities, and from the fortress even to the river, and from sea to sea, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; mountain to mountain.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Notwithstanding the land shall be desolate because of them that dwell therein, for the fruit of their doings.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Feed thy people with thy rod, the flock of thine heritage, which dwell solitarily &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the wood, in the midst of Carmel: let them feed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; Bashan and Gilead, as in the days of old.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">According to the days of thy coming out of the land of Egypt will I shew unto him marvellous &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">The nations shall see and be confounded at all their might: they shall lay &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; hand upon &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; mouth, their ears shall be deaf.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">They shall lick the dust like a serpent, they shall move out of their holes like worms of the earth: they shall be afraid of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God, and shall fear because of thee.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a God like unto thee, that pardoneth iniquity, and passeth by the transgression of the remnant of his heritage? he retaineth not his anger for ever, because he delighteth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; mercy.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">He will turn again, he will have compassion upon us; he will subdue our iniquities; and thou wilt cast all their sins into the depths of the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Thou wilt perform the truth to Jacob, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the mercy to Abraham, which thou hast sworn unto our fathers from the days of old.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>