<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="33" name="Micah" bookPage="micah.html" title="Micah" chapterCount="7" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="nahum_1.html" nextTitle="Nahum" prevBook="jonah_1.html" prevTitle="Jonah">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="15" nextChapter="micah_6.html" nextTitle="Micah 6" prevChapter="micah_4.html" prevTitle="Micah 4" chapterPage="micah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now gather thyself in troops, O daughter of troops: he hath laid siege against us: they shall smite the judge of Israel with a rod upon the cheek.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">But thou, Beth-lehem Ephratah, &lt;i&gt;though&lt;/i&gt; thou be little among the thousands of Judah, &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; out of thee shall he come forth unto me &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; to be ruler in Israel; whose goings forth &lt;i&gt;have been&lt;/i&gt; from of old, from everlasting.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Therefore will he give them up, until the time &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; she which travaileth hath brought forth: then the remnant of his brethren shall return unto the children of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">And he shall stand and feed in the strength of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, in the majesty of the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; his God; and they shall abide: for now shall he be great unto the ends of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And this &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; shall be the peace, when the Assyrian shall come into our land: and when he shall tread in our palaces, then shall we raise against him seven shepherds, and eight principal men.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And they shall waste the land of Assyria with the sword, and the land of Nimrod in the entrances thereof: thus shall he deliver &lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt; from the Assyrian, when he cometh into our land, and when he treadeth within our borders.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the remnant of Jacob shall be in the midst of many people as a dew from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as the showers upon the grass, that tarrieth not for man, nor waiteth for the sons of men.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And the remnant of Jacob shall be among the Gentiles in the midst of many people as a lion among the beasts of the forest, as a young lion among the flocks of sheep: who, if he go through, both treadeth down, and teareth in pieces, and none can deliver.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thine hand shall be lifted up upon thine adversaries, and all thine enemies shall be cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And it shall come to pass in that day, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, that I will cut off thy horses out of the midst of thee, and I will destroy thy chariots:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I will cut off the cities of thy land, and throw down all thy strong holds:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I will cut off witchcrafts out of thine hand; and thou shalt have no &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; soothsayers:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thy graven images also will I cut off, and thy standing images out of the midst of thee; and thou shalt no more worship the work of thine hands.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And I will pluck up thy groves out of the midst of thee: so will I destroy thy cities.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And I will execute vengeance in anger and fury upon the heathen, such as they have not heard.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>