<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="33" name="Micah" bookPage="micah.html" title="Micah" chapterCount="7" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="nahum_1.html" nextTitle="Nahum" prevBook="jonah_1.html" prevTitle="Jonah">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="16" nextChapter="micah_2.html" nextTitle="Micah 2" prevChapter="jonah_4.html" prevTitle="Jonah 4" chapterPage="micah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that came to Micah the Morasthite in the days of Jotham, Ahaz, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Hezekiah, kings of Judah, which he saw concerning Samaria and Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Hear, all ye people; hearken, O earth, and all that therein is: and let the Lord &lt;span class="nog"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; be witness against you, the Lord from his holy temple.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For, behold, the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; cometh forth out of his place, and will come down, and tread upon the high places of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And the mountains shall be molten under him, and the valleys shall be cleft, as wax before the fire, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; as the waters &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; poured down a steep place.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For the transgression of Jacob &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; all this, and for the sins of the house of Israel. What &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the transgression of Jacob? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt; not Samaria? and what &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the high places of Judah? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are they&lt;/span&gt; not Jerusalem?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Therefore I will make Samaria as an heap of the field, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; as plantings of a vineyard: and I will pour down the stones thereof into the valley, and I will discover the foundations thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And all the graven images thereof shall be beaten to pieces, and all the hires thereof shall be burned with the fire, and all the idols thereof will I lay desolate: for she gathered &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; of the hire of an harlot, and they shall return to the hire of an harlot.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Therefore I will wail and howl, I will go stripped and naked: I will make a wailing like the dragons, and mourning as the owls.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For her wound &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; incurable; for it is come unto Judah; he is come unto the gate of my people, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Declare ye &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; not at Gath, weep ye not at all: in the house of Aphrah roll thyself in the dust.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Pass ye away, thou inhabitant of Saphir, having thy shame naked: the inhabitant of Zaanan came not forth in the mourning of Beth-ezel; he shall receive of you his standing.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For the inhabitant of Maroth waited carefully for good: but evil came down from the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto the gate of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">O thou inhabitant of Lachish, bind the chariot to the swift beast: she &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the beginning of the sin to the daughter of Zion: for the transgressions of Israel were found in thee.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Therefore shalt thou give presents to Moresheth-gath: the houses of Achzib &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a lie to the kings of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Yet will I bring an heir unto thee, O inhabitant of Mareshah: he shall come unto Adullam the glory of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Make thee bald, and poll thee for thy delicate children; enlarge thy baldness as the eagle; for they are gone into captivity from thee.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>