<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="33" name="Micah" bookPage="micah.html" title="Micah" chapterCount="7" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="nahum_1.html" nextTitle="Nahum" prevBook="jonah_1.html" prevTitle="Jonah">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="13" nextChapter="micah_5.html" nextTitle="Micah 5" prevChapter="micah_3.html" prevTitle="Micah 3" chapterPage="micah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">But in the last days it shall come to pass, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the mountain of the house of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall be established in the top of the mountains, and it shall be exalted above the hills; and people shall flow unto it.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And many nations shall come, and say, Come, and let us go up to the mountain of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and to the house of the God of Jacob; and he will teach us of his ways, and we will walk in his paths: for the law shall go forth of Zion, and the word of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; from Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And he shall judge among many people, and rebuke strong nations afar off; and they shall beat their swords into plowshares, and their spears into pruninghooks: nation shall not lift up a sword against nation, neither shall they learn war any more.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But they shall sit every man under his vine and under his fig tree; and none shall make &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; afraid: for the mouth of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts hath spoken &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For all people will walk every one in the name of his god, and we will walk in the name of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; our God for ever and ever.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">In that day, saith the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, will I assemble her that halteth, and I will gather her that is driven out, and her that I have afflicted;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And I will make her that halted a remnant, and her that was cast far off a strong nation: and the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall reign over them in mount Zion from henceforth, even for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And thou, O tower of the flock, the strong hold of the daughter of Zion, unto thee shall it come, even the first dominion; the kingdom shall come to the daughter of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Now why dost thou cry out aloud? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; no king in thee? is thy counsellor perished? for pangs have taken thee as a woman in travail.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Be in pain, and labour to bring forth, O daughter of Zion, like a woman in travail: for now shalt thou go forth out of the city, and thou shalt dwell in the field, and thou shalt go &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; to Babylon; there shalt thou be delivered; there the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall redeem thee from the hand of thine enemies.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Now also many nations are gathered against thee, that say, Let her be defiled, and let our eye look upon Zion.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But they know not the thoughts of the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, neither understand they his counsel: for he shall gather them as the sheaves into the floor.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Arise and thresh, O daughter of Zion: for I will make thine horn iron, and I will make thy hoofs brass: and thou shalt beat in pieces many people: and I will consecrate their gain unto the &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and their substance unto the Lord of the whole earth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>