<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="34" name="Nahum" bookPage="nahum.html" title="Nahum" chapterCount="3" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="habakkuk_1.html" nextTitle="Habakkuk" prevBook="micah_1.html" prevTitle="Micah">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="19" nextChapter="habakkuk_1.html" nextTitle="Habakkuk 1" prevChapter="nahum_2.html" prevTitle="Nahum 2" chapterPage="nahum_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Woe to the bloody city! it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; all full of lies &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; robbery; the prey departeth not;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The noise of a whip, and the noise of the rattling of the wheels, and of the pransing horses, and of the jumping chariots.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The horseman lifteth up both the bright sword and the glittering spear: and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; a multitude of slain, and a great number of carcases; and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none end of &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; corpses; they stumble upon their corpses:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Because of the multitude of the whoredoms of the wellfavoured harlot, the mistress of witchcrafts, that selleth nations through her whoredoms, and families through her witchcrafts.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Behold, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; against thee, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; and I will discover thy skirts upon thy face, and I will shew the nations thy nakedness, and the kingdoms thy shame.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I will cast abominable filth upon thee, and make thee vile, and will set thee as a gazingstock.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And it shall come to pass, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; all they that look upon thee shall flee from thee, and say, Nineveh is laid waste: who will bemoan her? whence shall I seek comforters for thee?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Art thou better than populous No, that was situate among the rivers, &lt;i&gt;that had&lt;/i&gt; the waters round about it, whose rampart &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the sea, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; her wall &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; from the sea?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Ethiopia and Egypt &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; her strength, and &lt;i&gt;it was&lt;/i&gt; infinite; Put and Lubim were thy helpers.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Yet &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; she carried away, she went into captivity: her young children also were dashed in pieces at the top of all the streets: and they cast lots for her honourable men, and all her great men were bound in chains.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Thou also shalt be drunken: thou shalt be hid, thou also shalt seek strength because of the enemy.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">All thy strong holds &lt;i&gt;shall be like&lt;/i&gt; fig trees with the firstripe figs: if they be shaken, they shall even fall into the mouth of the eater.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Behold, thy people in the midst of thee &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; women: the gates of thy land shall be set wide open unto thine enemies: the fire shall devour thy bars.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Draw thee waters for the siege, fortify thy strong holds: go into clay, and tread the morter, make strong the brickkiln.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">There shall the fire devour thee; the sword shall cut thee off, it shall eat thee up like the cankerworm: make thyself many as the cankerworm, make thyself many as the locusts.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thou hast multiplied thy merchants above the stars of heaven: the cankerworm spoileth, and flieth away.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Thy crowned &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; as the locusts, and thy captains as the great grasshoppers, which camp in the hedges in the cold day, &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; when the sun ariseth they flee away, and their place is not known where they &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Thy shepherds slumber, O king of Assyria: thy nobles shall dwell &lt;i&gt;in the dust&lt;/i&gt;: thy people is scattered upon the mountains, and no man gathereth &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;i&gt;There is&lt;/i&gt; no healing of thy bruise; thy wound is grievous: all that hear the bruit of thee shall clap the hands over thee: for upon whom hath not thy wickedness passed continually?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>