<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="34" name="Nahum" bookPage="nahum.html" title="Nahum" chapterCount="3" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="habakkuk_1.html" nextTitle="Habakkuk" prevBook="micah_1.html" prevTitle="Micah">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="13" nextChapter="nahum_3.html" nextTitle="Nahum 3" prevChapter="nahum_1.html" prevTitle="Nahum 1" chapterPage="nahum_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">He that dasheth in pieces is come up before thy face: keep the munition, watch the way, make &lt;i&gt;thy&lt;/i&gt; loins strong, fortify &lt;i&gt;thy&lt;/i&gt; power mightily.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath turned away the excellency of Jacob, as the excellency of Israel: for the emptiers have emptied them out, and marred their vine branches.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The shield of his mighty men is made red, the valiant men &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; in scarlet: the chariots &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; with flaming torches in the day of his preparation, and the fir trees shall be terribly shaken.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">The chariots shall rage in the streets, they shall justle one against another in the broad ways: they shall seem like torches, they shall run like the lightnings.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">He shall recount his worthies: they shall stumble in their walk; they shall make haste to the wall thereof, and the defence shall be prepared.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The gates of the rivers shall be opened, and the palace shall be dissolved.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Huzzab shall be led away captive, she shall be brought up, and her maids shall lead &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; as with the voice of doves, tabering upon their breasts.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But Nineveh &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; of old like a pool of water: yet they shall flee away. Stand, stand, &lt;i&gt;shall they cry&lt;/i&gt;; but none shall look back.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Take ye the spoil of silver, take the spoil of gold: for &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; none end of the store &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; glory out of all the pleasant furniture.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">She is empty, and void, and waste: and the heart melteth, and the knees smite together, and much pain &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in all loins, and the faces of them all gather blackness.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Where &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the dwelling of the lions, and the feedingplace of the young lions, where the lion, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the old lion, walked, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the lion's whelp, and none made &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; afraid?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The lion did tear in pieces enough for his whelps, and strangled for his lionesses, and filled his holes with prey, and his dens with ravin.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Behold, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; against thee, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, and I will burn her chariots in the smoke, and the sword shall devour thy young lions: and I will cut off thy prey from the earth, and the voice of thy messengers shall no more be heard.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>