<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="35" name="Habakkuk" bookPage="habakkuk.html" title="Habakkuk" chapterCount="3" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="zephaniah_1.html" nextTitle="Zephaniah" prevBook="nahum_1.html" prevTitle="Nahum">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="17" nextChapter="habakkuk_2.html" nextTitle="Habakkuk 2" prevChapter="nahum_3.html" prevTitle="Nahum 3" chapterPage="habakkuk_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The burden which Habakkuk the prophet did see.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, how long shall I cry, and thou wilt not hear! &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; cry out unto thee &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; violence, and thou wilt not save!</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Why dost thou shew me iniquity, and cause &lt;span class="extra"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; to behold grievance? for spoiling and violence &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; before me: and there are &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; raise up strife and contention.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Therefore the law is slacked, and judgment doth never go forth: for the wicked doth compass about the righteous; therefore wrong judgment proceedeth.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Behold ye among the heathen, and regard, and wonder marvellously: for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; will work a work in your days, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; ye will not believe, though it be told &lt;span class="extra"&gt;you&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For, lo, I raise up the Chaldeans, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; bitter and hasty nation, which shall march through the breadth of the land, to possess the dwellingplaces &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; not theirs.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">They &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; terrible and dreadful: their judgment and their dignity shall proceed of themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Their horses also are swifter than the leopards, and are more fierce than the evening wolves: and their horsemen shall spread themselves, and their horsemen shall come from far; they shall fly as the eagle &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; hasteth to eat.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">They shall come all for violence: their faces shall sup up &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the east wind, and they shall gather the captivity as the sand.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they shall scoff at the kings, and the princes shall be a scorn unto them: they shall deride every strong hold; for they shall heap dust, and take it.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then shall &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; mind change, and he shall pass over, and offend, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;imputing&lt;/span&gt; this his power unto his god.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Art&lt;/span&gt; thou not from everlasting, O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God, mine Holy One? we shall not die. O &lt;span class="nog"&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, thou hast ordained them for judgment; and, O mighty God, thou hast established them for correction.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Thou art&lt;/span&gt; of purer eyes than to behold evil, and canst not look on iniquity: wherefore lookest thou upon them that deal treacherously, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; holdest thy tongue when the wicked devoureth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the man that is&lt;/span&gt; more righteous than he?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And makest men as the fishes of the sea, as the creeping things, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that have&lt;/span&gt; no ruler over them?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">They take up all of them with the angle, they catch them in their net, and gather them in their drag: therefore they rejoice and are glad.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Therefore they sacrifice unto their net, and burn incense unto their drag; because by them their portion &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; fat, and their meat plenteous.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Shall they therefore empty their net, and not spare continually to slay the nations?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>
