<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="35" name="Habakkuk" bookPage="habakkuk.html" title="Habakkuk" chapterCount="3" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="zephaniah_1.html" nextTitle="Zephaniah" prevBook="nahum_1.html" prevTitle="Nahum">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="20" nextChapter="habakkuk_3.html" nextTitle="Habakkuk 3" prevChapter="habakkuk_1.html" prevTitle="Habakkuk 1" chapterPage="habakkuk_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I will stand upon my watch, and set me upon the tower, and will watch to see what he will say unto me, and what I shall answer when I am reproved.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; answered me, and said, Write the vision, and make &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; plain upon tables, that he may run that readeth it.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For the vision &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; yet for an appointed time, but at the end it shall speak, and not lie: though it tarry, wait for it; because it will surely come, it will not tarry.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Behold, his soul &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; is lifted up is not upright in him: but the just shall live by his faith.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">Yea also, because he transgresseth by wine, &lt;i&gt;he is&lt;/i&gt; a proud man, neither keepeth at home, who enlargeth his desire as hell, and &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; as death, and cannot be satisfied, but gathereth unto him all nations, and heapeth unto him all people:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Shall not all these take up a parable against him, and a taunting proverb against him, and say, Woe to him that increaseth &lt;i&gt;that which is&lt;/i&gt; not his! how long? and to him that ladeth himself with thick clay!</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Shall they not rise up suddenly that shall bite thee, and awake that shall vex thee, and thou shalt be for booties unto them?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Because thou hast spoiled many nations, all the remnant of the people shall spoil thee; because of men's blood, and &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; the violence of the land, of the city, and of all that dwell therein.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Woe to him that coveteth an evil covetousness to his house, that he may set his nest on high, that he may be delivered from the power of evil!</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Thou hast consulted shame to thy house by cutting off many people, and hast sinned &lt;i&gt;against&lt;/i&gt; thy soul.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For the stone shall cry out of the wall, and the beam out of the timber shall answer it.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Woe to him that buildeth a town with blood, and stablisheth a city by iniquity!</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Behold, &lt;i&gt;is it&lt;/i&gt; not of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts that the people shall labour in the very fire, and the people shall weary themselves for very vanity?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For the earth shall be filled with the knowledge of the glory of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as the waters cover the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">Woe unto him that giveth his neighbour drink, that puttest thy bottle to &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, and makest &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; drunken also, that thou mayest look on their nakedness!</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Thou art filled with shame for glory: drink thou also, and let thy foreskin be uncovered: the cup of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s right hand shall be turned unto thee, and shameful spewing &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; on thy glory.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For the violence of Lebanon shall cover thee, and the spoil of beasts, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; made them afraid, because of men's blood, and for the violence of the land, of the city, and of all that dwell therein.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">What profiteth the graven image that the maker thereof hath graven it; the molten image, and a teacher of lies, that the maker of his work trusteth therein, to make dumb idols?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Woe unto him that saith to the wood, Awake; to the dumb stone, Arise, it shall teach! Behold, it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; laid over with gold and silver, and &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no breath at all in the midst of it.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in his holy temple: let all the earth keep silence before him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>
