<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="35" name="Habakkuk" bookPage="habakkuk.html" title="Habakkuk" chapterCount="3" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="zephaniah_1.html" nextTitle="Zephaniah" prevBook="nahum_1.html" prevTitle="Nahum">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="19" nextChapter="zephaniah_1.html" nextTitle="Zephaniah 1" prevChapter="habakkuk_2.html" prevTitle="Habakkuk 2" chapterPage="habakkuk_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">A prayer of Habakkuk the prophet upon Shigionoth.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I have heard thy speech, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; was afraid: O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, revive thy work in the midst of the years, in the midst of the years make known; in wrath remember mercy.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">God came from Teman, and the Holy One from mount Paran. Selah. His glory covered the heavens, and the earth was full of his praise.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; brightness was as the light; he had horns &lt;span class='extra'&gt;coming&lt;/span&gt; out of his hand: and there &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the hiding of his power.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Before him went the pestilence, and burning coals went forth at his feet.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He stood, and measured the earth: he beheld, and drove asunder the nations; and the everlasting mountains were scattered, the perpetual hills did bow: his ways &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; everlasting.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">I saw the tents of Cushan in affliction: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the curtains of the land of Midian did tremble.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Was the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; displeased against the rivers? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; thine anger against the rivers? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; thy wrath against the sea, that thou didst ride upon thine horses &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; thy chariots of salvation?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thy bow was made quite naked, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;according&lt;/span&gt; to the oaths of the tribes, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even thy&lt;/span&gt; word. Selah. Thou didst cleave the earth with rivers.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The mountains saw thee, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; they trembled: the overflowing of the water passed by: the deep uttered his voice, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; lifted up his hands on high.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The sun &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; moon stood still in their habitation: at the light of thine arrows they went, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; at the shining of thy glittering spear.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Thou didst march through the land in indignation, thou didst thresh the heathen in anger.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Thou wentest forth for the salvation of thy people, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; for salvation with thine anointed; thou woundedst the head out of the house of the wicked, by discovering the foundation unto the neck. Selah.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Thou didst strike through with his staves the head of his villages: they came out as a whirlwind to scatter me: their rejoicing &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; as to devour the poor secretly.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Thou didst walk through the sea with thine horses, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;through&lt;/span&gt; the heap of great waters.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">When I heard, my belly trembled; my lips quivered at the voice: rottenness entered into my bones, and I trembled in myself, that I might rest in the day of trouble: when he cometh up unto the people, he will invade them with his troops.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">Although the fig tree shall not blossom, neither &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall&lt;/span&gt; fruit &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; in the vines; the labour of the olive shall fail, and the fields shall yield no meat; the flock shall be cut off from the fold, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there shall be&lt;/span&gt; no herd in the stalls:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Yet I will rejoice in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I will joy in the God of my salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my strength, and he will make my feet like hinds' &lt;span class='extra'&gt;feet&lt;/span&gt;, and he will make me to walk upon mine high places. To the chief singer on my stringed instruments.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>
