<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="36" name="Zephaniah" bookPage="zephaniah.html" title="Zephaniah" chapterCount="3" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="haggai_1.html" nextTitle="Haggai" prevBook="habakkuk_1.html" prevTitle="Habakkuk">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="20" nextChapter="haggai_1.html" nextTitle="Haggai 1" prevChapter="zephaniah_2.html" prevTitle="Zephaniah 2" chapterPage="zephaniah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Woe to her that is filthy and polluted, to the oppressing city!</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">She obeyed not the voice; she received not correction; she trusted not in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; she drew not near to her God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Her princes within her &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; roaring lions; her judges &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; evening wolves; they gnaw not the bones till the morrow.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Her prophets &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; light &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; treacherous persons: her priests have polluted the sanctuary, they have done violence to the law.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">The just &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the midst thereof; he will not do iniquity: every morning doth he bring his judgment to light, he faileth not; but the unjust knoweth no shame.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I have cut off the nations: their towers are desolate; I made their streets waste, that none passeth by: their cities are destroyed, so that there is no man, that there is none inhabitant.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">I said, Surely thou wilt fear me, thou wilt receive instruction; so their dwelling should not be cut off, howsoever I punished them: but they rose early, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; corrupted all their doings.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Therefore wait ye upon me, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, until the day that I rise up to the prey: for my determination &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; to gather the nations, that I may assemble the kingdoms, to pour upon them mine indignation, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; all my fierce anger: for all the earth shall be devoured with the fire of my jealousy.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For then will I turn to the people a pure language, that they may all call upon the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, to serve him with one consent.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">From beyond the rivers of Ethiopia my suppliants, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the daughter of my dispersed, shall bring mine offering.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">In that day shalt thou not be ashamed for all thy doings, wherein thou hast transgressed against me: for then I will take away out of the midst of thee them that rejoice in thy pride, and thou shalt no more be haughty because of my holy mountain.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I will also leave in the midst of thee an afflicted and poor people, and they shall trust in the name of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The remnant of Israel shall not do iniquity, nor speak lies; neither shall a deceitful tongue be found in their mouth: for they shall feed and lie down, and none shall make &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; afraid.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Sing, O daughter of Zion; shout, O Israel; be glad and rejoice with all the heart, O daughter of Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath taken away thy judgments, he hath cast out thine enemy: the king of Israel, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; in the midst of thee: thou shalt not see evil any more.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">In that day it shall be said to Jerusalem, Fear thou not: &lt;i&gt;and to&lt;/i&gt; Zion, Let not thine hands be slack.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; thy God in the midst of thee &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; mighty; he will save, he will rejoice over thee with joy; he will rest in his love, he will joy over thee with singing.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">I will gather &lt;i&gt;them that are&lt;/i&gt; sorrowful for the solemn assembly, &lt;i&gt;who&lt;/i&gt; are of thee, &lt;i&gt;to whom&lt;/i&gt; the reproach of it &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; a burden.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Behold, at that time I will undo all that afflict thee: and I will save her that halteth, and gather her that was driven out; and I will get them praise and fame in every land where they have been put to shame.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">At that time will I bring you &lt;i&gt;again&lt;/i&gt;, even in the time that I gather you: for I will make you a name and a praise among all people of the earth, when I turn back your captivity before your eyes, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>
