<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="36" name="Zephaniah" bookPage="zephaniah.html" title="Zephaniah" chapterCount="3" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="haggai_1.html" nextTitle="Haggai" prevBook="habakkuk_1.html" prevTitle="Habakkuk">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="18" nextChapter="zephaniah_2.html" nextTitle="Zephaniah 2" prevChapter="habakkuk_3.html" prevTitle="Habakkuk 3" chapterPage="zephaniah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; which came unto Zephaniah the son of Cushi, the son of Gedaliah, the son of Amariah, the son of Hizkiah, in the days of Josiah the son of Amon, king of Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I will utterly consume all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; from off the land, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I will consume man and beast; I will consume the fowls of the heaven, and the fishes of the sea, and the stumblingblocks with the wicked; and I will cut off man from off the land, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I will also stretch out mine hand upon Judah, and upon all the inhabitants of Jerusalem; and I will cut off the remnant of Baal from this place, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the name of the Chemarims with the priests;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And them that worship the host of heaven upon the housetops; and them that worship &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; that swear by the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and that swear by Malcham;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And them that are turned back from the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;those&lt;/span&gt; that have not sought the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, nor enquired for him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Hold thy peace at the presence of the Lord &lt;span class='nog'&gt;God&lt;/span&gt;: for the day of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; at hand: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath prepared a sacrifice, he hath bid his guests.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And it shall come to pass in the day of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s sacrifice, that I will punish the princes, and the king's children, and all such as are clothed with strange apparel.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">In the same day also will I punish all those that leap on the threshold, which fill their masters' houses with violence and deceit.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And it shall come to pass in that day, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that there shall be&lt;/span&gt; the noise of a cry from the fish gate, and an howling from the second, and a great crashing from the hills.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Howl, ye inhabitants of Maktesh, for all the merchant people are cut down; all they that bear silver are cut off.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And it shall come to pass at that time, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; I will search Jerusalem with candles, and punish the men that are settled on their lees: that say in their heart, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will not do good, neither will he do evil.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Therefore their goods shall become a booty, and their houses a desolation: they shall also build houses, but not inhabit &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;; and they shall plant vineyards, but not drink the wine thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The great day of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; near, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; near, and hasteth greatly, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the voice of the day of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: the mighty man shall cry there bitterly.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">That day &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a day of wrath, a day of trouble and distress, a day of wasteness and desolation, a day of darkness and gloominess, a day of clouds and thick darkness,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">A day of the trumpet and alarm against the fenced cities, and against the high towers.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And I will bring distress upon men, that they shall walk like blind men, because they have sinned against the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: and their blood shall be poured out as dust, and their flesh as the dung.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Neither their silver nor their gold shall be able to deliver them in the day of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s wrath; but the whole land shall be devoured by the fire of his jealousy: for he shall make even a speedy riddance of all them that dwell in the land.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>
