<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="36" name="Zephaniah" bookPage="zephaniah.html" title="Zephaniah" chapterCount="3" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="haggai_1.html" nextTitle="Haggai" prevBook="habakkuk_1.html" prevTitle="Habakkuk">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="15" nextChapter="zephaniah_3.html" nextTitle="Zephaniah 3" prevChapter="zephaniah_1.html" prevTitle="Zephaniah 1" chapterPage="zephaniah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Gather yourselves together, yea, gather together, O nation not desired;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Before the decree bring forth, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;before&lt;/span&gt; the day pass as the chaff, before the fierce anger of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; come upon you, before the day of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s anger come upon you.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Seek ye the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, all ye meek of the earth, which have wrought his judgment; seek righteousness, seek meekness: it may be ye shall be hid in the day of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s anger.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">For Gaza shall be forsaken, and Ashkelon a desolation: they shall drive out Ashdod at the noon day, and Ekron shall be rooted up.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Woe unto the inhabitants of the sea coast, the nation of the Cherethites! the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; against you; O Canaan, the land of the Philistines, I will even destroy thee, that there shall be no inhabitant.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the sea coast shall be dwellings &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; cottages for shepherds, and folds for flocks.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the coast shall be for the remnant of the house of Judah; they shall feed thereupon: in the houses of Ashkelon shall they lie down in the evening: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God shall visit them, and turn away their captivity.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">I have heard the reproach of Moab, and the revilings of the children of Ammon, whereby they have reproached my people, and magnified &lt;span class='extra'&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt; against their border.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Therefore &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; I live, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, the God of Israel, Surely Moab shall be as Sodom, and the children of Ammon as Gomorrah, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the breeding of nettles, and saltpits, and a perpetual desolation: the residue of my people shall spoil them, and the remnant of my people shall possess them.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">This shall they have for their pride, because they have reproached and magnified &lt;span class='extra'&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt; against the people of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;will be&lt;/span&gt; terrible unto them: for he will famish all the gods of the earth; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; shall worship him, every one from his place, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all the isles of the heathen.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Ye Ethiopians also, ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; slain by my sword.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he will stretch out his hand against the north, and destroy Assyria; and will make Nineveh a desolation, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; dry like a wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And flocks shall lie down in the midst of her, all the beasts of the nations: both the cormorant and the bittern shall lodge in the upper lintels of it; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; voice shall sing in the windows; desolation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; in the thresholds: for he shall uncover the cedar work.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the rejoicing city that dwelt carelessly, that said in her heart, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none beside me: how is she become a desolation, a place for beasts to lie down in! every one that passeth by her shall hiss, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; wag his hand.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>
