<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="37" name="Haggai" bookPage="haggai.html" title="Haggai" chapterCount="2" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="zechariah_1.html" nextTitle="Zechariah" prevBook="zephaniah_1.html" prevTitle="Zephaniah">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="15" nextChapter="haggai_2.html" nextTitle="Haggai 2" prevChapter="zephaniah_3.html" prevTitle="Zephaniah 3" chapterPage="haggai_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In the second year of Darius the king, in the sixth month, in the first day of the month, came the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; by Haggai the prophet unto Zerubbabel the son of Shealtiel, governor of Judah, and to Joshua the son of Josedech, the high priest, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thus speaketh the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, saying, This people say, The time is not come, the time that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s house should be built.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Then came the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; by Haggai the prophet, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;i&gt;Is it&lt;/i&gt; time for you, O ye, to dwell in your cieled houses, and this house &lt;i&gt;lie&lt;/i&gt; waste?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Now therefore thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; Consider your ways.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Ye have sown much, and bring in little; ye eat, but ye have not enough; ye drink, but ye are not filled with drink; ye clothe you, but there is none warm; and he that earneth wages earneth wages &lt;i&gt;to put it&lt;/i&gt; into a bag with holes.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; Consider your ways.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Go up to the mountain, and bring wood, and build the house; and I will take pleasure in it, and I will be glorified, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Ye looked for much, and, lo, &lt;i&gt;it came&lt;/i&gt; to little; and when ye brought &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; home, I did blow upon it. Why? saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts. Because of mine house that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; waste, and ye run every man unto his own house.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Therefore the heaven over you is stayed from dew, and the earth is stayed &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; her fruit.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I called for a drought upon the land, and upon the mountains, and upon the corn, and upon the new wine, and upon the oil, and upon &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; which the ground bringeth forth, and upon men, and upon cattle, and upon all the labour of the hands.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Then Zerubbabel the son of Shealtiel, and Joshua the son of Josedech, the high priest, with all the remnant of the people, obeyed the voice of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God, and the words of Haggai the prophet, as the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God had sent him, and the people did fear before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then spake Haggai the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s messenger in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;'s message unto the people, saying, I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; with you, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; stirred up the spirit of Zerubbabel the son of Shealtiel, governor of Judah, and the spirit of Joshua the son of Josedech, the high priest, and the spirit of all the remnant of the people; and they came and did work in the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, their God,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">In the four and twentieth day of the sixth month, in the second year of Darius the king.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>
