<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="38" name="Zechariah" bookPage="zechariah.html" title="Zechariah" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="malachi_1.html" nextTitle="Malachi" prevBook="haggai_1.html" prevTitle="Haggai">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="17" nextChapter="zechariah_12.html" nextTitle="Zechariah 12" prevChapter="zechariah_10.html" prevTitle="Zechariah 10" chapterPage="zechariah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Open thy doors, O Lebanon, that the fire may devour thy cedars.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Howl, fir tree; for the cedar is fallen; because the mighty are spoiled: howl, O ye oaks of Bashan; for the forest of the vintage is come down.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;There is&lt;/span&gt; a voice of the howling of the shepherds; for their glory is spoiled: a voice of the roaring of young lions; for the pride of Jordan is spoiled.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; my God; Feed the flock of the slaughter;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Whose possessors slay them, and hold themselves not guilty: and they that sell them say, Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; for I am rich: and their own shepherds pity them not.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For I will no more pity the inhabitants of the land, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: but, lo, I will deliver the men every one into his neighbour's hand, and into the hand of his king: and they shall smite the land, and out of their hand I will not deliver &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And I will feed the flock of slaughter, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; you, O poor of the flock. And I took unto me two staves; the one I called Beauty, and the other I called Bands; and I fed the flock.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Three shepherds also I cut off in one month; and my soul lothed them, and their soul also abhorred me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then said I, I will not feed you: that that dieth, let it die; and that that is to be cut off, let it be cut off; and let the rest eat every one the flesh of another.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And I took my staff, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; Beauty, and cut it asunder, that I might break my covenant which I had made with all the people.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And it was broken in that day: and so the poor of the flock that waited upon me knew that it &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I said unto them, If ye think good, give &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; my price; and if not, forbear. So they weighed for my price thirty &lt;span class='extra'&gt;pieces&lt;/span&gt; of silver.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, Cast it unto the potter: a goodly price that I was prised at of them. And I took the thirty &lt;span class='extra'&gt;pieces&lt;/span&gt; of silver, and cast them to the potter in the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then I cut asunder mine other staff, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; Bands, that I might break the brotherhood between Judah and Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto me, Take unto thee yet the instruments of a foolish shepherd.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For, lo, I will raise up a shepherd in the land, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which&lt;/span&gt; shall not visit those that be cut off, neither shall seek the young one, nor heal that that is broken, nor feed that that standeth still: but he shall eat the flesh of the fat, and tear their claws in pieces.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Woe to the idol shepherd that leaveth the flock! the sword &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; upon his arm, and upon his right eye: his arm shall be clean dried up, and his right eye shall be utterly darkened.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>