<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="38" name="Zechariah" bookPage="zechariah.html" title="Zechariah" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="malachi_1.html" nextTitle="Malachi" prevBook="haggai_1.html" prevTitle="Haggai">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="14" nextChapter="zechariah_13.html" nextTitle="Zechariah 13" prevChapter="zechariah_11.html" prevTitle="Zechariah 11" chapterPage="zechariah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The burden of the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; for Israel, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, which stretcheth forth the heavens, and layeth the foundation of the earth, and formeth the spirit of man within him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Behold, I will make Jerusalem a cup of trembling unto all the people round about, when they shall be in the siege both against Judah &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; against Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And in that day will I make Jerusalem a burdensome stone for all people: all that burden themselves with it shall be cut in pieces, though all the people of the earth be gathered together against it.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">In that day, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I will smite every horse with astonishment, and his rider with madness: and I will open mine eyes upon the house of Judah, and will smite every horse of the people with blindness.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the governors of Judah shall say in their heart, The inhabitants of Jerusalem &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; my strength in the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts their God.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">In that day will I make the governors of Judah like an hearth of fire among the wood, and like a torch of fire in a sheaf; and they shall devour all the people round about, on the right hand and on the left: and Jerusalem shall be inhabited again in her own place, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; in Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; also shall save the tents of Judah first, that the glory of the house of David and the glory of the inhabitants of Jerusalem do not magnify &lt;i&gt;themselves&lt;/i&gt; against Judah.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">In that day shall the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; defend the inhabitants of Jerusalem; and he that is feeble among them at that day shall be as David; and the house of David &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; as God, as the angel of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; before them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And it shall come to pass in that day, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I will seek to destroy all the nations that come against Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And I will pour upon the house of David, and upon the inhabitants of Jerusalem, the spirit of grace and of supplications: and they shall look upon me whom they have pierced, and they shall mourn for him, as one mourneth for &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; only &lt;i&gt;son&lt;/i&gt;, and shall be in bitterness for him, as one that is in bitterness for &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; firstborn.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">In that day shall there be a great mourning in Jerusalem, as the mourning of Hadadrimmon in the valley of Megiddon.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the land shall mourn, every family apart; the family of the house of David apart, and their wives apart; the family of the house of Nathan apart, and their wives apart;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The family of the house of Levi apart, and their wives apart; the family of Shimei apart, and their wives apart;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">All the families that remain, every family apart, and their wives apart.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>