<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="38" name="Zechariah" bookPage="zechariah.html" title="Zechariah" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="malachi_1.html" nextTitle="Malachi" prevBook="haggai_1.html" prevTitle="Haggai">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="14" nextChapter="zechariah_8.html" nextTitle="Zechariah 8" prevChapter="zechariah_6.html" prevTitle="Zechariah 6" chapterPage="zechariah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass in the fourth year of king Darius, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto Zechariah in the fourth &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the ninth month, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; in Chisleu;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">When they had sent unto the house of God Sherezer and Regem-melech, and their men, to pray before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;i&gt;And&lt;/i&gt; to speak unto the priests which &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; in the house of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, and to the prophets, saying, Should I weep in the fifth month, separating myself, as I have done these so many years?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4" newPara="true">Then came the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Speak unto all the people of the land, and to the priests, saying, When ye fasted and mourned in the fifth and seventh &lt;i&gt;month&lt;/i&gt;, even those seventy years, did ye at all fast unto me, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to me?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And when ye did eat, and when ye did drink, did not ye eat &lt;i&gt;for yourselves&lt;/i&gt;, and drink &lt;i&gt;for yourselves&lt;/i&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;i&gt;Should ye&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;hear&lt;/i&gt; the words which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath cried by the former prophets, when Jerusalem was inhabited and in prosperity, and the cities thereof round about her, when &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; inhabited the south and the plain?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">And the word of the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; came unto Zechariah, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thus speaketh the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, saying, Execute true judgment, and shew mercy and compassions every man to his brother:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And oppress not the widow, nor the fatherless, the stranger, nor the poor; and let none of you imagine evil against his brother in your heart.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But they refused to hearken, and pulled away the shoulder, and stopped their ears, that they should not hear.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Yea, they made their hearts &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; an adamant stone, lest they should hear the law, and the words which the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts hath sent in his spirit by the former prophets: therefore came a great wrath from the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Therefore it is come to pass, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; as he cried, and they would not hear; so they cried, and I would not hear, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But I scattered them with a whirlwind among all the nations whom they knew not. Thus the land was desolate after them, that no man passed through nor returned: for they laid the pleasant land desolate.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>