<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="38" name="Zechariah" bookPage="zechariah.html" title="Zechariah" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="malachi_1.html" nextTitle="Malachi" prevBook="haggai_1.html" prevTitle="Haggai">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="10" nextChapter="zechariah_4.html" nextTitle="Zechariah 4" prevChapter="zechariah_2.html" prevTitle="Zechariah 2" chapterPage="zechariah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he shewed me Joshua the high priest standing before the angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and Satan standing at his right hand to resist him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto Satan, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; rebuke thee, O Satan; even the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that hath chosen Jerusalem rebuke thee: &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not this a brand plucked out of the fire?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Now Joshua was clothed with filthy garments, and stood before the angel.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he answered and spake unto those that stood before him, saying, Take away the filthy garments from him. And unto him he said, Behold, I have caused thine iniquity to pass from thee, and I will clothe thee with change of raiment.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And I said, Let them set a fair mitre upon his head. So they set a fair mitre upon his head, and clothed him with garments. And the angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; stood by.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; protested unto Joshua, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; If thou wilt walk in my ways, and if thou wilt keep my charge, then thou shalt also judge my house, and shalt also keep my courts, and I will give thee places to walk among these that stand by.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Hear now, O Joshua the high priest, thou, and thy fellows that sit before thee: for they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; men wondered at: for, behold, I will bring forth my servant the BRANCH.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For behold the stone that I have laid before Joshua; upon one stone &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; seven eyes: behold, I will engrave the graving thereof, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, and I will remove the iniquity of that land in one day.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">In that day, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, shall ye call every man his neighbour under the vine and under the fig tree.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>