<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="38" name="Zechariah" bookPage="zechariah.html" title="Zechariah" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="malachi_1.html" nextTitle="Malachi" prevBook="haggai_1.html" prevTitle="Haggai">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="12" nextChapter="zechariah_11.html" nextTitle="Zechariah 11" prevChapter="zechariah_9.html" prevTitle="Zechariah 9" chapterPage="zechariah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Ask ye of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; rain in the time of the latter rain; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall make bright clouds, and give them showers of rain, to every one grass in the field.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For the idols have spoken vanity, and the diviners have seen a lie, and have told false dreams; they comfort in vain: therefore they went their way as a flock, they were troubled, because &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; no shepherd.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Mine anger was kindled against the shepherds, and I punished the goats: for the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts hath visited his flock the house of Judah, and hath made them as his goodly horse in the battle.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Out of him came forth the corner, out of him the nail, out of him the battle bow, out of him every oppressor together.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And they shall be as mighty &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;, which tread down &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their enemies&lt;/span&gt; in the mire of the streets in the battle: and they shall fight, because the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with them, and the riders on horses shall be confounded.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I will strengthen the house of Judah, and I will save the house of Joseph, and I will bring them again to place them; for I have mercy upon them: and they shall be as though I had not cast them off: for I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; their God, and will hear them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they of&lt;/span&gt; Ephraim shall be like a mighty &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt;, and their heart shall rejoice as through wine: yea, their children shall see &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and be glad; their heart shall rejoice in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I will hiss for them, and gather them; for I have redeemed them: and they shall increase as they have increased.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And I will sow them among the people: and they shall remember me in far countries; and they shall live with their children, and turn again.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I will bring them again also out of the land of Egypt, and gather them out of Assyria; and I will bring them into the land of Gilead and Lebanon; and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;place&lt;/span&gt; shall not be found for them.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he shall pass through the sea with affliction, and shall smite the waves in the sea, and all the deeps of the river shall dry up: and the pride of Assyria shall be brought down, and the sceptre of Egypt shall depart away.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I will strengthen them in the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; and they shall walk up and down in his name, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>