<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="38" name="Zechariah" bookPage="zechariah.html" title="Zechariah" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="malachi_1.html" nextTitle="Malachi" prevBook="haggai_1.html" prevTitle="Haggai">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="23" nextChapter="zechariah_9.html" nextTitle="Zechariah 9" prevChapter="zechariah_7.html" prevTitle="Zechariah 7" chapterPage="zechariah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Again the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts came &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to me&lt;/span&gt;, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; I was jealous for Zion with great jealousy, and I was jealous for her with great fury.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; I am returned unto Zion, and will dwell in the midst of Jerusalem: and Jerusalem shall be called a city of truth; and the mountain of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts the holy mountain.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; There shall yet old men and old women dwell in the streets of Jerusalem, and every man with his staff in his hand for very age.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the streets of the city shall be full of boys and girls playing in the streets thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; If it be marvellous in the eyes of the remnant of this people in these days, should it also be marvellous in mine eyes? saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; Behold, I will save my people from the east country, and from the west country;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I will bring them, and they shall dwell in the midst of Jerusalem: and they shall be my people, and I will be their God, in truth and in righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; Let your hands be strong, ye that hear in these days these words by the mouth of the prophets, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the day &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the foundation of the house of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts was laid, that the temple might be built.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For before these days there was no hire for man, nor any hire for beast; neither &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was there any&lt;/span&gt; peace to him that went out or came in because of the affliction: for I set all men every one against his neighbour.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But now I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;will&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; unto the residue of this people as in the former days, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For the seed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; prosperous; the vine shall give her fruit, and the ground shall give her increase, and the heavens shall give their dew; and I will cause the remnant of this people to possess all these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And it shall come to pass, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; as ye were a curse among the heathen, O house of Judah, and house of Israel; so will I save you, and ye shall be a blessing: fear not, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; let your hands be strong.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; As I thought to punish you, when your fathers provoked me to wrath, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, and I repented not:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So again have I thought in these days to do well unto Jerusalem and to the house of Judah: fear ye not.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the things that ye shall do; Speak ye every man the truth to his neighbour; execute the judgment of truth and peace in your gates:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And let none of you imagine evil in your hearts against his neighbour; and love no false oath: for all these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are things&lt;/span&gt; that I hate, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts came unto me, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; The fast of the fourth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;month&lt;/span&gt;, and the fast of the fifth, and the fast of the seventh, and the fast of the tenth, shall be to the house of Judah joy and gladness, and cheerful feasts; therefore love the truth and peace.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;It shall&lt;/span&gt; yet &lt;span class='extra'&gt;come to pass&lt;/span&gt;, that there shall come people, and the inhabitants of many cities:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the inhabitants of one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;city&lt;/span&gt; shall go to another, saying, Let us go speedily to pray before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and to seek the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts: I will go also.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Yea, many people and strong nations shall come to seek the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts in Jerusalem, and to pray before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; In those days &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it shall come to pass&lt;/span&gt;, that ten men shall take hold out of all languages of the nations, even shall take hold of the skirt of him that is a Jew, saying, We will go with you: for we have heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with you.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>