<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="38" name="Zechariah" bookPage="zechariah.html" title="Zechariah" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="malachi_1.html" nextTitle="Malachi" prevBook="haggai_1.html" prevTitle="Haggai">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="21" nextChapter="zechariah_2.html" nextTitle="Zechariah 2" prevChapter="haggai_2.html" prevTitle="Haggai 2" chapterPage="zechariah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In the eighth month, in the second year of Darius, came the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto Zechariah, the son of Berechiah, the son of Iddo the prophet, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath been sore displeased with your fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Therefore say thou unto them, Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; Turn ye unto me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, and I will turn unto you, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Be ye not as your fathers, unto whom the former prophets have cried, saying, Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; Turn ye now from your evil ways, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; your evil doings: but they did not hear, nor hearken unto me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Your fathers, where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they? and the prophets, do they live for ever?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But my words and my statutes, which I commanded my servants the prophets, did they not take hold of your fathers? and they returned and said, Like as the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts thought to do unto us, according to our ways, and according to our doings, so hath he dealt with us.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Upon the four and twentieth day of the eleventh month, which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the month Sebat, in the second year of Darius, came the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; unto Zechariah, the son of Berechiah, the son of Iddo the prophet, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I saw by night, and behold a man riding upon a red horse, and he stood among the myrtle trees that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; in the bottom; and behind him &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were there&lt;/span&gt; red horses, speckled, and white.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then said I, O my lord, what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; these? And the angel that talked with me said unto me, I will shew thee what these &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the man that stood among the myrtle trees answered and said, These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are they&lt;/span&gt; whom the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath sent to walk to and fro through the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And they answered the angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; that stood among the myrtle trees, and said, We have walked to and fro through the earth, and, behold, all the earth sitteth still, and is at rest.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Then the angel of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; answered and said, O &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, how long wilt thou not have mercy on Jerusalem and on the cities of Judah, against which thou hast had indignation these threescore and ten years?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; answered the angel that talked with me &lt;span class='extra'&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; good words &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; comfortable words.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">So the angel that communed with me said unto me, Cry thou, saying, Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; I am jealous for Jerusalem and for Zion with a great jealousy.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And I am very sore displeased with the heathen &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; at ease: for I was but a little displeased, and they helped forward the affliction.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Therefore thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;; I am returned to Jerusalem with mercies: my house shall be built in it, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, and a line shall be stretched forth upon Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Cry yet, saying, Thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; My cities through prosperity shall yet be spread abroad; and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall yet comfort Zion, and shall yet choose Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Then lifted I up mine eyes, and saw, and behold four horns.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And I said unto the angel that talked with me, What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; these? And he answered me, These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the horns which have scattered Judah, Israel, and Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shewed me four carpenters.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then said I, What come these to do? And he spake, saying, These &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the horns which have scattered Judah, so that no man did lift up his head: but these are come to fray them, to cast out the horns of the Gentiles, which lifted up &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; horn over the land of Judah to scatter it.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>