<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="38" name="Zechariah" bookPage="zechariah.html" title="Zechariah" chapterCount="14" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="malachi_1.html" nextTitle="Malachi" prevBook="haggai_1.html" prevTitle="Haggai">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="13" nextChapter="zechariah_3.html" nextTitle="Zechariah 3" prevChapter="zechariah_1.html" prevTitle="Zechariah 1" chapterPage="zechariah_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I lifted up mine eyes again, and looked, and behold a man with a measuring line in his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then said I, Whither goest thou? And he said unto me, To measure Jerusalem, to see what &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the breadth thereof, and what &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the length thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And, behold, the angel that talked with me went forth, and another angel went out to meet him,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And said unto him, Run, speak to this young man, saying, Jerusalem shall be inhabited &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; towns without walls for the multitude of men and cattle therein:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For I, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, will be unto her a wall of fire round about, and will be the glory in the midst of her.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Ho, ho, &lt;i&gt;come forth&lt;/i&gt;, and flee from the land of the north, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for I have spread you abroad as the four winds of the heaven, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Deliver thyself, O Zion, that dwellest &lt;i&gt;with&lt;/i&gt; the daughter of Babylon.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For thus saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; After the glory hath he sent me unto the nations which spoiled you: for he that toucheth you toucheth the apple of his eye.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For, behold, I will shake mine hand upon them, and they shall be a spoil to their servants: and ye shall know that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts hath sent me.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">Sing and rejoice, O daughter of Zion: for, lo, I come, and I will dwell in the midst of thee, saith the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And many nations shall be joined to the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; in that day, and shall be my people: and I will dwell in the midst of thee, and thou shalt know that the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts hath sent me unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; shall inherit Judah his portion in the holy land, and shall choose Jerusalem again.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Be silent, O all flesh, before the &lt;span style='font-variant: small-caps;'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: for he is raised up out of his holy habitation.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>