<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="39" name="Malachi" bookPage="malachi.html" title="Malachi" chapterCount="4" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="matthew_1.html" nextTitle="Matthew" prevBook="zechariah_1.html" prevTitle="Zechariah">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="18" nextChapter="malachi_4.html" nextTitle="Malachi 4" prevChapter="malachi_2.html" prevTitle="Malachi 2" chapterPage="malachi_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Behold, I will send my messenger, and he shall prepare the way before me: and the Lord, whom ye seek, shall suddenly come to his temple, even the messenger of the covenant, whom ye delight in: behold, he shall come, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">But who may abide the day of his coming? and who shall stand when he appeareth? for he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; like a refiner's fire, and like fullers' soap:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he shall sit &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; a refiner and purifier of silver: and he shall purify the sons of Levi, and purge them as gold and silver, that they may offer unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; an offering in righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Then shall the offering of Judah and Jerusalem be pleasant unto the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, as in the days of old, and as in former years.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And I will come near to you to judgment; and I will be a swift witness against the sorcerers, and against the adulterers, and against false swearers, and against those that oppress the hireling in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; wages, the widow, and the fatherless, and that turn aside the stranger &lt;span class='extra'&gt;from his right&lt;/span&gt;, and fear not me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, I change not; therefore ye sons of Jacob are not consumed.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Even from the days of your fathers ye are gone away from mine ordinances, and have not kept &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;. Return unto me, and I will return unto you, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts. But ye said, Wherein shall we return?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">Will a man rob God? Yet ye have robbed me. But ye say, Wherein have we robbed thee? In tithes and offerings.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; cursed with a curse: for ye have robbed me, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; this whole nation.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Bring ye all the tithes into the storehouse, that there may be meat in mine house, and prove me now herewith, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, if I will not open you the windows of heaven, and pour you out a blessing, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there shall&lt;/span&gt; not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be room&lt;/span&gt; enough &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to receive it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I will rebuke the devourer for your sakes, and he shall not destroy the fruits of your ground; neither shall your vine cast her fruit before the time in the field, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And all nations shall call you blessed: for ye shall be a delightsome land, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Your words have been stout against me, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. Yet ye say, What have we spoken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so much&lt;/span&gt; against thee?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Ye have said, It &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vain to serve God: and what profit &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt; that we have kept his ordinance, and that we have walked mournfully before the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And now we call the proud happy; yea, they that work wickedness are set up; yea, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they that&lt;/span&gt; tempt God are even delivered.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Then they that feared the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; spake often one to another: and the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hearkened, and heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and a book of remembrance was written before him for them that feared the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;, and that thought upon his name.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And they shall be mine, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, in that day when I make up my jewels; and I will spare them, as a man spareth his own son that serveth him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Then shall ye return, and discern between the righteous and the wicked, between him that serveth God and him that serveth him not.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>