<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="39" name="Malachi" bookPage="malachi.html" title="Malachi" chapterCount="4" testament="old" nt="false" ot="true" nextBook="matthew_1.html" nextTitle="Matthew" prevBook="zechariah_1.html" prevTitle="Zechariah">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="14" nextChapter="malachi_2.html" nextTitle="Malachi 2" prevChapter="zechariah_14.html" prevTitle="Zechariah 14" chapterPage="malachi_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The burden of the word of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; to Israel by Malachi.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I have loved you, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;. Yet ye say, Wherein hast thou loved us? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Was&lt;/span&gt; not Esau Jacob's brother? saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;: yet I loved Jacob,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I hated Esau, and laid his mountains and his heritage waste for the dragons of the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Whereas Edom saith, We are impoverished, but we will return and build the desolate places; thus saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, They shall build, but I will throw down; and they shall call them, The border of wickedness, and, The people against whom the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; hath indignation for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And your eyes shall see, and ye shall say, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; will be magnified from the border of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">A son honoureth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; father, and a servant his master: if then I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; a father, where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine honour? and if I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; a master, where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my fear? saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts unto you, O priests, that despise my name. And ye say, Wherein have we despised thy name?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Ye offer polluted bread upon mine altar; and ye say, Wherein have we polluted thee? In that ye say, The table of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; contemptible.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And if ye offer the blind for sacrifice, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt; not evil? and if ye offer the lame and sick, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt; not evil? offer it now unto thy governor; will he be pleased with thee, or accept thy person? saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And now, I pray you, beseech God that he will be gracious unto us: this hath been by your means: will he regard your persons? saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Who &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; even among you that would shut the doors &lt;span class='extra'&gt;for nought&lt;/span&gt;? neither do ye kindle &lt;span class='extra'&gt;fire&lt;/span&gt; on mine altar for nought. I have no pleasure in you, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, neither will I accept an offering at your hand.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For from the rising of the sun even unto the going down of the same my name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; great among the Gentiles; and in every place incense &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; offered unto my name, and a pure offering: for my name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; great among the heathen, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">But ye have profaned it, in that ye say, The table of the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; polluted; and the fruit thereof, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; his meat, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; contemptible.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Ye said also, Behold, what a weariness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt;! and ye have snuffed at it, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts; and ye brought &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that which was&lt;/span&gt; torn, and the lame, and the sick; thus ye brought an offering: should I accept this of your hand? saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But cursed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the deceiver, which hath in his flock a male, and voweth, and sacrificeth unto the Lord a corrupt thing: for I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; a great King, saith the &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; of hosts, and my name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; dreadful among the heathen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>