<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="27" verseCount="66" nextChapter="matthew_28.html" nextTitle="Matthew 28" prevChapter="matthew_26.html" prevTitle="Matthew 26" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">When the morning was come, all the chief priests and elders of the people took counsel against Jesus to put him to death:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And when they had bound him, they led &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; away, and delivered him to Pontius Pilate the governor.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Then Judas, which had betrayed him, when he saw that he was condemned, repented himself, and brought again the thirty pieces of silver to the chief priests and elders,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Saying, I have sinned in that I have betrayed the innocent blood. And they said, What &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is that&lt;/span&gt; to us? see thou &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to that&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he cast down the pieces of silver in the temple, and departed, and went and hanged himself.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the chief priests took the silver pieces, and said, It is not lawful for to put them into the treasury, because it is the price of blood.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they took counsel, and bought with them the potter's field, to bury strangers in.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Wherefore that field was called, The field of blood, unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then was fulfilled that which was spoken by Jeremy the prophet, saying, And they took the thirty pieces of silver, the price of him that was valued, whom they of the children of Israel did value;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And gave them for the potter's field, as the Lord appointed me.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And Jesus stood before the governor: and the governor asked him, saying, Art thou the King of the Jews? And Jesus said unto him, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Thou sayest.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And when he was accused of the chief priests and elders, he answered nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then said Pilate unto him, Hearest thou not how many things they witness against thee?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he answered him to never a word; insomuch that the governor marvelled greatly.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Now at &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; feast the governor was wont to release unto the people a prisoner, whom they would.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And they had then a notable prisoner, called Barabbas.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Therefore when they were gathered together, Pilate said unto them, Whom will ye that I release unto you? Barabbas, or Jesus which is called Christ?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For he knew that for envy they had delivered him.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">When he was set down on the judgment seat, his wife sent unto him, saying, Have thou nothing to do with that just man: for I have suffered many things this day in a dream because of him.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But the chief priests and elders persuaded the multitude that they should ask Barabbas, and destroy Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The governor answered and said unto them, Whether of the twain will ye that I release unto you? They said, Barabbas.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Pilate saith unto them, What shall I do then with Jesus which is called Christ? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;They&lt;/span&gt; all say unto him, Let him be crucified.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the governor said, Why, what evil hath he done? But they cried out the more, saying, Let him be crucified.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">When Pilate saw that he could prevail nothing, but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; rather a tumult was made, he took water, and washed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; hands before the multitude, saying, I am innocent of the blood of this just person: see ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then answered all the people, and said, His blood &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; on us, and on our children.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">Then released he Barabbas unto them: and when he had scourged Jesus, he delivered &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; to be crucified.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Then the soldiers of the governor took Jesus into the common hall, and gathered unto him the whole band &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of soldiers&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they stripped him, and put on him a scarlet robe.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29" newPara="true">And when they had platted a crown of thorns, they put &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon his head, and a reed in his right hand: and they bowed the knee before him, and mocked him, saying, Hail, King of the Jews!</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And they spit upon him, and took the reed, and smote him on the head.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And after that they had mocked him, they took the robe off from him, and put his own raiment on him, and led him away to crucify &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And as they came out, they found a man of Cyrene, Simon by name: him they compelled to bear his cross.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And when they were come unto a place called Golgotha, that is to say, a place of a skull,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">They gave him vinegar to drink mingled with gall: and when he had tasted &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thereof&lt;/span&gt;, he would not drink.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And they crucified him, and parted his garments, casting lots: that it might be fulfilled which was spoken by the prophet, They parted my garments among them, and upon my vesture did they cast lots.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And sitting down they watched him there;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And set up over his head his accusation written, THIS IS JESUS THE KING OF THE JEWS.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">Then were there two thieves crucified with him, one on the right hand, and another on the left.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39" newPara="true">And they that passed by reviled him, wagging their heads,</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And saying, Thou that destroyest the temple, and buildest &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; in three days, save thyself. If thou be the Son of God, come down from the cross.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Likewise also the chief priests mocking &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, with the scribes and elders, said,</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">He saved others; himself he cannot save. If he be the King of Israel, let him now come down from the cross, and we will believe him.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">He trusted in God; let him deliver him now, if he will have him: for he said, I am the Son of God.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">The thieves also, which were crucified with him, cast the same in his teeth.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">Now from the sixth hour there was darkness over all the land unto the ninth hour.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And about the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, saying, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Eli, Eli, lama sabachthani?&lt;/span&gt; that is to say, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;My God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">Some of them that stood there, when they heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt;, said, This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; calleth for Elias.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">And straightway one of them ran, and took a spunge, and filled &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; with vinegar, and put &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on a reed, and gave him to drink.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">The rest said, Let be, let us see whether Elias will come to save him.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50" newPara="true">Jesus, when he had cried again with a loud voice, yielded up the ghost.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And, behold, the veil of the temple was rent in twain from the top to the bottom; and the earth did quake, and the rocks rent;</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">And the graves were opened; and many bodies of the saints which slept arose,</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">And came out of the graves after his resurrection, and went into the holy city, and appeared unto many.</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">Now when the centurion, and they that were with him, watching Jesus, saw the earthquake, and those things that were done, they feared greatly, saying, Truly this was the Son of God.</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">And many women were there beholding afar off, which followed Jesus from Galilee, ministering unto him:</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">Among which was Mary Magdalene, and Mary the mother of James and Joses, and the mother of Zebedee's children.</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">When the even was come, there came a rich man of Arimathaea, named Joseph, who also himself was Jesus' disciple:</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">He went to Pilate, and begged the body of Jesus. Then Pilate commanded the body to be delivered.</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">And when Joseph had taken the body, he wrapped it in a clean linen cloth,</verse>
      <verse number="60" id="v60">And laid it in his own new tomb, which he had hewn out in the rock: and he rolled a great stone to the door of the sepulchre, and departed.</verse>
      <verse number="61" id="v61">And there was Mary Magdalene, and the other Mary, sitting over against the sepulchre.</verse>
      <verse number="62" id="v62" newPara="true">Now the next day, that followed the day of the preparation, the chief priests and Pharisees came together unto Pilate,</verse>
      <verse number="63" id="v63">Saying, Sir, we remember that that deceiver said, while he was yet alive, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;After three days I will rise again.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="64" id="v64">Command therefore that the sepulchre be made sure until the third day, lest his disciples come by night, and steal him away, and say unto the people, He is risen from the dead: so the last error shall be worse than the first.</verse>
      <verse number="65" id="v65">Pilate said unto them, Ye have a watch: go your way, make &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; as sure as ye can.</verse>
      <verse number="66" id="v66">So they went, and made the sepulchre sure, sealing the stone, and setting a watch.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>