<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="39" nextChapter="matthew_16.html" nextTitle="Matthew 16" prevChapter="matthew_14.html" prevTitle="Matthew 14" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then came to Jesus scribes and Pharisees, which were of Jerusalem, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Why do thy disciples transgress the tradition of the elders? for they wash not their hands when they eat bread.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But he answered and said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Why do ye also transgress the commandment of God by your tradition?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;woc&gt;For God commanded, saying, Honour thy father and mother: and, He that curseth father or mother, let him die the death.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;woc&gt;But ye say, Whosoever shall say to &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; father or &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; mother, &lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; a gift, by whatsoever thou mightest be profited by me;&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;woc&gt;And honour not his father or his mother, &lt;i&gt;he shall be free&lt;/i&gt;. Thus have ye made the commandment of God of none effect by your tradition.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;woc&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ye&lt;/i&gt; hypocrites, well did Esaias prophesy of you, saying,&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;woc&gt;This people draweth nigh unto me with their mouth, and honoureth me with &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; lips; but their heart is far from me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;woc&gt;But in vain they do worship me, teaching &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; doctrines the commandments of men.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And he called the multitude, and said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Hear, and understand:&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;woc&gt;Not that which goeth into the mouth defileth a man; but that which cometh out of the mouth, this defileth a man.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Then came his disciples, and said unto him, Knowest thou that the Pharisees were offended, after they heard this saying?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But he answered and said, &lt;woc&gt;Every plant, which my heavenly Father hath not planted, shall be rooted up.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;woc&gt;Let them alone: they be blind leaders of the blind. And if the blind lead the blind, both shall fall into the ditch.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Then answered Peter and said unto him, Declare unto us this parable.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Jesus said, &lt;woc&gt;Are ye also yet without understanding?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;woc&gt;Do not ye yet understand, that whatsoever entereth in at the mouth goeth into the belly, and is cast out into the draught?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;woc&gt;But those things which proceed out of the mouth come forth from the heart; and they defile the man.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;woc&gt;For out of the heart proceed evil thoughts, murders, adulteries, fornications, thefts, false witness, blasphemies:&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;woc&gt;These are &lt;i&gt;the things&lt;/i&gt; which defile a man: but to eat with unwashen hands defileth not a man.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">Then Jesus went thence, and departed into the coasts of Tyre and Sidon.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And, behold, a woman of Canaan came out of the same coasts, and cried unto him, saying, Have mercy on me, O Lord, &lt;i&gt;thou&lt;/i&gt; Son of David; my daughter is grievously vexed with a devil.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But he answered her not a word. And his disciples came and besought him, saying, Send her away; for she crieth after us.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But he answered and said, &lt;woc&gt;I am not sent but unto the lost sheep of the house of Israel.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then came she and worshipped him, saying, Lord, help me.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">But he answered and said, &lt;woc&gt;It is not meet to take the children's bread, and to cast &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to dogs.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And she said, Truth, Lord: yet the dogs eat of the crumbs which fall from their masters' table.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Then Jesus answered and said unto her, &lt;woc&gt;O woman, great &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy faith: be it unto thee even as thou wilt.&lt;/woc&gt; And her daughter was made whole from that very hour.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Jesus departed from thence, and came nigh unto the sea of Galilee; and went up into a mountain, and sat down there.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And great multitudes came unto him, having with them &lt;i&gt;those that were&lt;/i&gt; lame, blind, dumb, maimed, and many others, and cast them down at Jesus' feet; and he healed them:</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Insomuch that the multitude wondered, when they saw the dumb to speak, the maimed to be whole, the lame to walk, and the blind to see: and they glorified the God of Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">Then Jesus called his disciples &lt;i&gt;unto him&lt;/i&gt;, and said, &lt;woc&gt;I have compassion on the multitude, because they continue with me now three days, and have nothing to eat: and I will not send them away fasting, lest they faint in the way.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And his disciples say unto him, Whence should we have so much bread in the wilderness, as to fill so great a multitude?</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And Jesus saith unto them, &lt;woc&gt;How many loaves have ye?&lt;/woc&gt; And they said, Seven, and a few little fishes.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And he commanded the multitude to sit down on the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And he took the seven loaves and the fishes, and gave thanks, and brake &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;, and gave to his disciples, and the disciples to the multitude.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And they did all eat, and were filled: and they took up of the broken &lt;i&gt;meat&lt;/i&gt; that was left seven baskets full.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And they that did eat were four thousand men, beside women and children.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And he sent away the multitude, and took ship, and came into the coasts of Magdala.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>