<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="25" verseCount="46" nextChapter="matthew_26.html" nextTitle="Matthew 26" prevChapter="matthew_24.html" prevTitle="Matthew 24" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then shall the kingdom of heaven be likened unto ten virgins, which took their lamps, and went forth to meet the bridegroom.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And five of them were wise, and five &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; foolish.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;They that &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; foolish took their lamps, and took no oil with them:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But the wise took oil in their vessels with their lamps.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;While the bridegroom tarried, they all slumbered and slept.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And at midnight there was a cry made, Behold, the bridegroom cometh; go ye out to meet him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then all those virgins arose, and trimmed their lamps.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And the foolish said unto the wise, Give us of your oil; for our lamps are gone out.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But the wise answered, saying, &lt;i&gt;Not so&lt;/i&gt;; lest there be not enough for us and you: but go ye rather to them that sell, and buy for yourselves.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And while they went to buy, the bridegroom came; and they that were ready went in with him to the marriage: and the door was shut.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Afterward came also the other virgins, saying, Lord, Lord, open to us.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But he answered and said, Verily I say unto you, I know you not.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Watch therefore, for ye know neither the day nor the hour wherein the Son of man cometh.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For &lt;i&gt;the kingdom of heaven is&lt;/i&gt; as a man travelling into a far country, &lt;i&gt;who&lt;/i&gt; called his own servants, and delivered unto them his goods.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And unto one he gave five talents, to another two, and to another one; to every man according to his several ability; and straightway took his journey.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then he that had received the five talents went and traded with the same, and made &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; other five talents.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And likewise he that &lt;i&gt;had received&lt;/i&gt; two, he also gained other two.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But he that had received one went and digged in the earth, and hid his lord's money.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;After a long time the lord of those servants cometh, and reckoneth with them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And so he that had received five talents came and brought other five talents, saying, Lord, thou deliveredst unto me five talents: behold, I have gained beside them five talents more.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;His lord said unto him, Well done, &lt;i&gt;thou&lt;/i&gt; good and faithful servant: thou hast been faithful over a few things, I will make thee ruler over many things: enter thou into the joy of thy lord.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;He also that had received two talents came and said, Lord, thou deliveredst unto me two talents: behold, I have gained two other talents beside them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;His lord said unto him, Well done, good and faithful servant; thou hast been faithful over a few things, I will make thee ruler over many things: enter thou into the joy of thy lord.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then he which had received the one talent came and said, Lord, I knew thee that thou art an hard man, reaping where thou hast not sown, and gathering where thou hast not strawed:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And I was afraid, and went and hid thy talent in the earth: lo, &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt; thou hast &lt;i&gt;that is&lt;/i&gt; thine.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;His lord answered and said unto him, &lt;i&gt;Thou&lt;/i&gt; wicked and slothful servant, thou knewest that I reap where I sowed not, and gather where I have not strawed:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thou oughtest therefore to have put my money to the exchangers, and &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; at my coming I should have received mine own with usury.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take therefore the talent from him, and give &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; unto him which hath ten talents.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For unto every one that hath shall be given, and he shall have abundance: but from him that hath not shall be taken away even that which he hath.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And cast ye the unprofitable servant into outer darkness: there shall be weeping and gnashing of teeth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;When the Son of man shall come in his glory, and all the holy angels with him, then shall he sit upon the throne of his glory:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And before him shall be gathered all nations: and he shall separate them one from another, as a shepherd divideth &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; sheep from the goats:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he shall set the sheep on his right hand, but the goats on the left.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then shall the King say unto them on his right hand, Come, ye blessed of my Father, inherit the kingdom prepared for you from the foundation of the world:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I was an hungred, and ye gave me meat: I was thirsty, and ye gave me drink: I was a stranger, and ye took me in:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Naked, and ye clothed me: I was sick, and ye visited me: I was in prison, and ye came unto me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then shall the righteous answer him, saying, Lord, when saw we thee an hungred, and fed &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt;? or thirsty, and gave &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt; drink?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;When saw we thee a stranger, and took &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt; in? or naked, and clothed &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt;?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Or when saw we thee sick, or in prison, and came unto thee?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And the King shall answer and say unto them, Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye have done &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; unto one of the least of these my brethren, ye have done &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; unto me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then shall he say also unto them on the left hand, Depart from me, ye cursed, into everlasting fire, prepared for the devil and his angels:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I was an hungred, and ye gave me no meat: I was thirsty, and ye gave me no drink:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I was a stranger, and ye took me not in: naked, and ye clothed me not: sick, and in prison, and ye visited me not.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then shall they also answer him, saying, Lord, when saw we thee an hungred, or athirst, or a stranger, or naked, or sick, or in prison, and did not minister unto thee?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then shall he answer them, saying, Verily I say unto you, Inasmuch as ye did &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not to one of the least of these, ye did &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not to me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And these shall go away into everlasting punishment: but the righteous into life eternal.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>