<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="28" nextChapter="matthew_17.html" nextTitle="Matthew 17" prevChapter="matthew_15.html" prevTitle="Matthew 15" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The Pharisees also with the Sadducees came, and tempting desired him that he would shew them a sign from heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">He answered and said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;When it is evening, ye say, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;It will be&lt;/span&gt; fair weather: for the sky is red.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And in the morning, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;It will be&lt;/span&gt; foul weather to day: for the sky is red and lowring. O &lt;span class='extra'&gt;ye&lt;/span&gt; hypocrites, ye can discern the face of the sky; but can ye not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;discern&lt;/span&gt; the signs of the times?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;A wicked and adulterous generation seeketh after a sign; and there shall no sign be given unto it, but the sign of the prophet Jonas.&lt;/span&gt; And he left them, and departed.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And when his disciples were come to the other side, they had forgotten to take bread.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6" newPara="true">Then Jesus said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Take heed and beware of the leaven of the Pharisees and of the Sadducees.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they reasoned among themselves, saying, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; because we have taken no bread.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Which&lt;/span&gt; when Jesus perceived, he said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;O ye of little faith, why reason ye among yourselves, because ye have brought no bread?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Do ye not yet understand, neither remember the five loaves of the five thousand, and how many baskets ye took up?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Neither the seven loaves of the four thousand, and how many baskets ye took up?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;How is it that ye do not understand that I spake &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; not to you concerning bread, that ye should beware of the leaven of the Pharisees and of the Sadducees?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Then understood they how that he bade &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; not beware of the leaven of bread, but of the doctrine of the Pharisees and of the Sadducees.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">When Jesus came into the coasts of Caesarea Philippi, he asked his disciples, saying, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Whom do men say that I the Son of man am?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they said, Some &lt;span class='extra'&gt;say that thou art&lt;/span&gt; John the Baptist: some, Elias; and others, Jeremias, or one of the prophets.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">He saith unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;But whom say ye that I am?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Simon Peter answered and said, Thou art the Christ, the Son of the living God.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Jesus answered and said unto him, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Blessed art thou, Simon Bar-jona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; unto thee, but my Father which is in heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And I say also unto thee, That thou art Peter, and upon this rock I will build my church; and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And I will give unto thee the keys of the kingdom of heaven: and whatsoever thou shalt bind on earth shall be bound in heaven: and whatsoever thou shalt loose on earth shall be loosed in heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Then charged he his disciples that they should tell no man that he was Jesus the Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">From that time forth began Jesus to shew unto his disciples, how that he must go unto Jerusalem, and suffer many things of the elders and chief priests and scribes, and be killed, and be raised again the third day.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then Peter took him, and began to rebuke him, saying, Be it far from thee, Lord: this shall not be unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But he turned, and said unto Peter, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Get thee behind me, Satan: thou art an offence unto me: for thou savourest not the things that be of God, but those that be of men.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">Then said Jesus unto his disciples, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;If any &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; will come after me, let him deny himself, and take up his cross, and follow me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;For whosoever will save his life shall lose it: and whosoever will lose his life for my sake shall find it.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;For the Son of man shall come in the glory of his Father with his angels; and then he shall reward every man according to his works.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Verily I say unto you, There be some standing here, which shall not taste of death, till they see the Son of man coming in his kingdom.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>