<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="34" nextChapter="matthew_21.html" nextTitle="Matthew 21" prevChapter="matthew_19.html" prevTitle="Matthew 19" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For the kingdom of heaven is like unto a man &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt; an householder, which went out early in the morning to hire labourers into his vineyard.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when he had agreed with the labourers for a penny a day, he sent them into his vineyard.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he went out about the third hour, and saw others standing idle in the marketplace,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And said unto them; Go ye also into the vineyard, and whatsoever is right I will give you. And they went their way.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Again he went out about the sixth and ninth hour, and did likewise.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And about the eleventh hour he went out, and found others standing idle, and saith unto them, Why stand ye here all the day idle?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;They say unto him, Because no man hath hired us. He saith unto them, Go ye also into the vineyard; and whatsoever is right, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shall ye receive.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;So when even was come, the lord of the vineyard saith unto his steward, Call the labourers, and give them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; hire, beginning from the last unto the first.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when they came that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were hired&lt;/span&gt; about the eleventh hour, they received every man a penny.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But when the first came, they supposed that they should have received more; and they likewise received every man a penny.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when they had received &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, they murmured against the goodman of the house,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Saying, These last have wrought &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; one hour, and thou hast made them equal unto us, which have borne the burden and heat of the day.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But he answered one of them, and said, Friend, I do thee no wrong: didst not thou agree with me for a penny?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; thine &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;, and go thy way: I will give unto this last, even as unto thee.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Is it not lawful for me to do what I will with mine own? Is thine eye evil, because I am good?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;So the last shall be first, and the first last: for many be called, but few chosen.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And Jesus going up to Jerusalem took the twelve disciples apart in the way, and said unto them,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold, we go up to Jerusalem; and the Son of man shall be betrayed unto the chief priests and unto the scribes, and they shall condemn him to death,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And shall deliver him to the Gentiles to mock, and to scourge, and to crucify &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;: and the third day he shall rise again.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">Then came to him the mother of Zebedee's children with her sons, worshipping &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, and desiring a certain thing of him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he said unto her, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;What wilt thou?&lt;/span&gt; She saith unto him, Grant that these my two sons may sit, the one on thy right hand, and the other on the left, in thy kingdom.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But Jesus answered and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye know not what ye ask. Are ye able to drink of the cup that I shall drink of, and to be baptized with the baptism that I am baptized with?&lt;/span&gt; They say unto him, We are able.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye shall drink indeed of my cup, and be baptized with the baptism that I am baptized with: but to sit on my right hand, and on my left, is not mine to give, but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it shall be given to them&lt;/span&gt; for whom it is prepared of my Father.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And when the ten heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, they were moved with indignation against the two brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">But Jesus called them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;unto him&lt;/span&gt;, and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye know that the princes of the Gentiles exercise dominion over them, and they that are great exercise authority upon them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But it shall not be so among you: but whosoever will be great among you, let him be your minister;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And whosoever will be chief among you, let him be your servant:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Even as the Son of man came not to be ministered unto, but to minister, and to give his life a ransom for many.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And as they departed from Jericho, a great multitude followed him.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">And, behold, two blind men sitting by the way side, when they heard that Jesus passed by, cried out, saying, Have mercy on us, O Lord, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thou&lt;/span&gt; Son of David.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And the multitude rebuked them, because they should hold their peace: but they cried the more, saying, Have mercy on us, O Lord, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thou&lt;/span&gt; Son of David.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And Jesus stood still, and called them, and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;What will ye that I shall do unto you?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">They say unto him, Lord, that our eyes may be opened.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">So Jesus had compassion &lt;span class="extra"&gt;on them&lt;/span&gt;, and touched their eyes: and immediately their eyes received sight, and they followed him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>