<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="28" verseCount="20" nextChapter="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark 1" prevChapter="matthew_27.html" prevTitle="Matthew 27" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In the end of the sabbath, as it began to dawn toward the first &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the week, came Mary Magdalene and the other Mary to see the sepulchre.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And, behold, there was a great earthquake: for the angel of the Lord descended from heaven, and came and rolled back the stone from the door, and sat upon it.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">His countenance was like lightning, and his raiment white as snow:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And for fear of him the keepers did shake, and became as dead &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And the angel answered and said unto the women, Fear not ye: for I know that ye seek Jesus, which was crucified.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He is not here: for he is risen, as he said. Come, see the place where the Lord lay.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And go quickly, and tell his disciples that he is risen from the dead; and, behold, he goeth before you into Galilee; there shall ye see him: lo, I have told you.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And they departed quickly from the sepulchre with fear and great joy; and did run to bring his disciples word.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And as they went to tell his disciples, behold, Jesus met them, saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;All hail.&lt;/span&gt; And they came and held him by the feet, and worshipped him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then said Jesus unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Be not afraid: go tell my brethren that they go into Galilee, and there shall they see me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">Now when they were going, behold, some of the watch came into the city, and shewed unto the chief priests all the things that were done.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And when they were assembled with the elders, and had taken counsel, they gave large money unto the soldiers,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Saying, Say ye, His disciples came by night, and stole him &lt;i&gt;away&lt;/i&gt; while we slept.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And if this come to the governor's ears, we will persuade him, and secure you.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So they took the money, and did as they were taught: and this saying is commonly reported among the Jews until this day.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">Then the eleven disciples went away into Galilee, into a mountain where Jesus had appointed them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And when they saw him, they worshipped him: but some doubted.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Jesus came and spake unto them, saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;All power is given unto me in heaven and in earth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Go ye therefore, and teach all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Teaching them to observe all things whatsoever I have commanded you: and, lo, I am with you alway, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; unto the end of the world.&lt;/span&gt; Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>