<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="36" nextChapter="matthew_15.html" nextTitle="Matthew 15" prevChapter="matthew_13.html" prevTitle="Matthew 13" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">At that time Herod the tetrarch heard of the fame of Jesus,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And said unto his servants, This is John the Baptist; he is risen from the dead; and therefore mighty works do shew forth themselves in him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">For Herod had laid hold on John, and bound him, and put &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; in prison for Herodias' sake, his brother Philip's wife.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For John said unto him, It is not lawful for thee to have her.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And when he would have put him to death, he feared the multitude, because they counted him as a prophet.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But when Herod's birthday was kept, the daughter of Herodias danced before them, and pleased Herod.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Whereupon he promised with an oath to give her whatsoever she would ask.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And she, being before instructed of her mother, said, Give me here John Baptist's head in a charger.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the king was sorry: nevertheless for the oath's sake, and them which sat with him at meat, he commanded &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to be given &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he sent, and beheaded John in the prison.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And his head was brought in a charger, and given to the damsel: and she brought &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; to her mother.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And his disciples came, and took up the body, and buried it, and went and told Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">When Jesus heard &lt;i&gt;of it&lt;/i&gt;, he departed thence by ship into a desert place apart: and when the people had heard &lt;i&gt;thereof&lt;/i&gt;, they followed him on foot out of the cities.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Jesus went forth, and saw a great multitude, and was moved with compassion toward them, and he healed their sick.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And when it was evening, his disciples came to him, saying, This is a desert place, and the time is now past; send the multitude away, that they may go into the villages, and buy themselves victuals.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But Jesus said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;They need not depart; give ye them to eat.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And they say unto him, We have here but five loaves, and two fishes.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He said, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Bring them hither to me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he commanded the multitude to sit down on the grass, and took the five loaves, and the two fishes, and looking up to heaven, he blessed, and brake, and gave the loaves to &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; disciples, and the disciples to the multitude.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And they did all eat, and were filled: and they took up of the fragments that remained twelve baskets full.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they that had eaten were about five thousand men, beside women and children.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And straightway Jesus constrained his disciples to get into a ship, and to go before him unto the other side, while he sent the multitudes away.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And when he had sent the multitudes away, he went up into a mountain apart to pray: and when the evening was come, he was there alone.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But the ship was now in the midst of the sea, tossed with waves: for the wind was contrary.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And in the fourth watch of the night Jesus went unto them, walking on the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And when the disciples saw him walking on the sea, they were troubled, saying, It is a spirit; and they cried out for fear.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">But straightway Jesus spake unto them, saying, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Be of good cheer; it is I; be not afraid.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Peter answered him and said, Lord, if it be thou, bid me come unto thee on the water.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And he said, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Come.&lt;/span&gt; And when Peter was come down out of the ship, he walked on the water, to go to Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">But when he saw the wind boisterous, he was afraid; and beginning to sink, he cried, saying, Lord, save me.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And immediately Jesus stretched forth &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; hand, and caught him, and said unto him, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;O thou of little faith, wherefore didst thou doubt?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And when they were come into the ship, the wind ceased.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Then they that were in the ship came and worshipped him, saying, Of a truth thou art the Son of God.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">And when they were gone over, they came into the land of Gennesaret.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And when the men of that place had knowledge of him, they sent out into all that country round about, and brought unto him all that were diseased;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And besought him that they might only touch the hem of his garment: and as many as touched were made perfectly whole.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>