<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="25" nextChapter="matthew_5.html" nextTitle="Matthew 5" prevChapter="matthew_3.html" prevTitle="Matthew 3" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then was Jesus led up of the Spirit into the wilderness to be tempted of the devil.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And when he had fasted forty days and forty nights, he was afterward an hungred.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And when the tempter came to him, he said, If thou be the Son of God, command that these stones be made bread.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But he answered and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;It is written, Man shall not live by bread alone, but by every word that proceedeth out of the mouth of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then the devil taketh him up into the holy city, and setteth him on a pinnacle of the temple,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And saith unto him, If thou be the Son of God, cast thyself down: for it is written, He shall give his angels charge concerning thee: and in &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; hands they shall bear thee up, lest at any time thou dash thy foot against a stone.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Jesus said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;It is written again, Thou shalt not tempt the Lord thy God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Again, the devil taketh him up into an exceeding high mountain, and sheweth him all the kingdoms of the world, and the glory of them;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And saith unto him, All these things will I give thee, if thou wilt fall down and worship me.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then saith Jesus unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Get thee hence, Satan: for it is written, Thou shalt worship the Lord thy God, and him only shalt thou serve.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then the devil leaveth him, and, behold, angels came and ministered unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Now when Jesus had heard that John was cast into prison, he departed into Galilee;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And leaving Nazareth, he came and dwelt in Capernaum, which is upon the sea coast, in the borders of Zabulon and Nephthalim:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">That it might be fulfilled which was spoken by Esaias the prophet, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The land of Zabulon, and the land of Nephthalim, &lt;i&gt;by&lt;/i&gt; the way of the sea, beyond Jordan, Galilee of the Gentiles;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The people which sat in darkness saw great light; and to them which sat in the region and shadow of death light is sprung up.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">From that time Jesus began to preach, and to say, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Repent: for the kingdom of heaven is at hand.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And Jesus, walking by the sea of Galilee, saw two brethren, Simon called Peter, and Andrew his brother, casting a net into the sea: for they were fishers.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Follow me, and I will make you fishers of men.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And they straightway left &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; nets, and followed him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And going on from thence, he saw other two brethren, James &lt;i&gt;the son&lt;/i&gt; of Zebedee, and John his brother, in a ship with Zebedee their father, mending their nets; and he called them.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And they immediately left the ship and their father, and followed him.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And Jesus went about all Galilee, teaching in their synagogues, and preaching the gospel of the kingdom, and healing all manner of sickness and all manner of disease among the people.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And his fame went throughout all Syria: and they brought unto him all sick people that were taken with divers diseases and torments, and those which were possessed with devils, and those which were lunatick, and those that had the palsy; and he healed them.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And there followed him great multitudes of people from Galilee, and &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; Decapolis, and &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; Jerusalem, and &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; Judaea, and &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; beyond Jordan.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>