<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="19" verseCount="30" nextChapter="matthew_20.html" nextTitle="Matthew 20" prevChapter="matthew_18.html" prevTitle="Matthew 18" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; when Jesus had finished these sayings, he departed from Galilee, and came into the coasts of Judaea beyond Jordan;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And great multitudes followed him; and he healed them there.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">The Pharisees also came unto him, tempting him, and saying unto him, Is it lawful for a man to put away his wife for every cause?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he answered and said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Have ye not read, that he which made &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; at the beginning made them male and female,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And said, For this cause shall a man leave father and mother, and shall cleave to his wife: and they twain shall be one flesh?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Wherefore they are no more twain, but one flesh. What therefore God hath joined together, let not man put asunder.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">They say unto him, Why did Moses then command to give a writing of divorcement, and to put her away?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Moses because of the hardness of your hearts suffered you to put away your wives: but from the beginning it was not so.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And I say unto you, Whosoever shall put away his wife, except &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it be&lt;/span&gt; for fornication, and shall marry another, committeth adultery: and whoso marrieth her which is put away doth commit adultery.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">His disciples say unto him, If the case of the man be so with &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; wife, it is not good to marry.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;All &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; cannot receive this saying, save &lt;span class="extra"&gt;they&lt;/span&gt; to whom it is given.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For there are some eunuchs, which were so born from &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; mother's womb: and there are some eunuchs, which were made eunuchs of men: and there be eunuchs, which have made themselves eunuchs for the kingdom of heaven's sake. He that is able to receive &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, let him receive &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Then were there brought unto him little children, that he should put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; hands on them, and pray: and the disciples rebuked them.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But Jesus said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Suffer little children, and forbid them not, to come unto me: for of such is the kingdom of heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he laid &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; hands on them, and departed thence.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And, behold, one came and said unto him, Good Master, what good thing shall I do, that I may have eternal life?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Why callest thou me good? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none good but one, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt;, God: but if thou wilt enter into life, keep the commandments.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">He saith unto him, Which? Jesus said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thou shalt do no murder, Thou shalt not commit adultery, Thou shalt not steal, Thou shalt not bear false witness,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Honour thy father and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thy&lt;/span&gt; mother: and, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The young man saith unto him, All these things have I kept from my youth up: what lack I yet?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Jesus said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;If thou wilt be perfect, go &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; sell that thou hast, and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven: and come &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; follow me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But when the young man heard that saying, he went away sorrowful: for he had great possessions.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">Then said Jesus unto his disciples, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto you, That a rich man shall hardly enter into the kingdom of heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And again I say unto you, It is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle, than for a rich man to enter into the kingdom of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">When his disciples heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, they were exceedingly amazed, saying, Who then can be saved?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">But Jesus beheld &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, and said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;With men this is impossible; but with God all things are possible.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">Then answered Peter and said unto him, Behold, we have forsaken all, and followed thee; what shall we have therefore?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Jesus said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto you, That ye which have followed me, in the regeneration when the Son of man shall sit in the throne of his glory, ye also shall sit upon twelve thrones, judging the twelve tribes of Israel.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And every one that hath forsaken houses, or brethren, or sisters, or father, or mother, or wife, or children, or lands, for my name's sake, shall receive an hundredfold, and shall inherit everlasting life.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But many &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; first shall be last; and the last &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; first.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>