<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="34" nextChapter="matthew_9.html" nextTitle="Matthew 9" prevChapter="matthew_7.html" prevTitle="Matthew 7" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">When he was come down from the mountain, great multitudes followed him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And, behold, there came a leper and worshipped him, saying, Lord, if thou wilt, thou canst make me clean.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Jesus put forth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; hand, and touched him, saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;I will; be thou clean.&lt;/span&gt; And immediately his leprosy was cleansed.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Jesus saith unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;See thou tell no man; but go thy way, shew thyself to the priest, and offer the gift that Moses commanded, for a testimony unto them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And when Jesus was entered into Capernaum, there came unto him a centurion, beseeching him,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And saying, Lord, my servant lieth at home sick of the palsy, grievously tormented.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And Jesus saith unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;I will come and heal him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">The centurion answered and said, Lord, I am not worthy that thou shouldest come under my roof: but speak the word only, and my servant shall be healed.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For I am a man under authority, having soldiers under me: and I say to this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt;, Go, and he goeth; and to another, Come, and he cometh; and to my servant, Do this, and he doeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">When Jesus heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, he marvelled, and said to them that followed, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto you, I have not found so great faith, no, not in Israel.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And I say unto you, That many shall come from the east and west, and shall sit down with Abraham, and Isaac, and Jacob, in the kingdom of heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But the children of the kingdom shall be cast out into outer darkness: there shall be weeping and gnashing of teeth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And Jesus said unto the centurion, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Go thy way; and as thou hast believed, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; be it done unto thee.&lt;/span&gt; And his servant was healed in the selfsame hour.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">And when Jesus was come into Peter's house, he saw his wife's mother laid, and sick of a fever.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he touched her hand, and the fever left her: and she arose, and ministered unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">When the even was come, they brought unto him many that were possessed with devils: and he cast out the spirits with &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; word, and healed all that were sick:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">That it might be fulfilled which was spoken by Esaias the prophet, saying, Himself took our infirmities, and bare &lt;span class="extra"&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; sicknesses.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Now when Jesus saw great multitudes about him, he gave commandment to depart unto the other side.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And a certain scribe came, and said unto him, Master, I will follow thee whithersoever thou goest.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And Jesus saith unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;The foxes have holes, and the birds of the air &lt;span class="extra"&gt;have&lt;/span&gt; nests; but the Son of man hath not where to lay &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; head.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And another of his disciples said unto him, Lord, suffer me first to go and bury my father.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But Jesus said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Follow me; and let the dead bury their dead.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And when he was entered into a ship, his disciples followed him.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And, behold, there arose a great tempest in the sea, insomuch that the ship was covered with the waves: but he was asleep.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And his disciples came to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, and awoke him, saying, Lord, save us: we perish.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And he saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Why are ye fearful, O ye of little faith?&lt;/span&gt; Then he arose, and rebuked the winds and the sea; and there was a great calm.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">But the men marvelled, saying, What manner of man is this, that even the winds and the sea obey him!</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">And when he was come to the other side into the country of the Gergesenes, there met him two possessed with devils, coming out of the tombs, exceeding fierce, so that no man might pass by that way.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And, behold, they cried out, saying, What have we to do with thee, Jesus, thou Son of God? art thou come hither to torment us before the time?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And there was a good way off from them an herd of many swine feeding.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">So the devils besought him, saying, If thou cast us out, suffer us to go away into the herd of swine.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Go.&lt;/span&gt; And when they were come out, they went into the herd of swine: and, behold, the whole herd of swine ran violently down a steep place into the sea, and perished in the waters.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And they that kept them fled, and went their ways into the city, and told every thing, and what was befallen to the possessed of the devils.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And, behold, the whole city came out to meet Jesus: and when they saw him, they besought &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; that he would depart out of their coasts.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>