<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="34" nextChapter="matthew_7.html" nextTitle="Matthew 7" prevChapter="matthew_5.html" prevTitle="Matthew 5" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take heed that ye do not your alms before men, to be seen of them: otherwise ye have no reward of your Father which is in heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Therefore when thou doest &lt;i&gt;thine&lt;/i&gt; alms, do not sound a trumpet before thee, as the hypocrites do in the synagogues and in the streets, that they may have glory of men. Verily I say unto you, They have their reward.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But when thou doest alms, let not thy left hand know what thy right hand doeth:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;That thine alms may be in secret: and thy Father which seeth in secret himself shall reward thee openly.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when thou prayest, thou shalt not be as the hypocrites &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt;: for they love to pray standing in the synagogues and in the corners of the streets, that they may be seen of men. Verily I say unto you, They have their reward.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But thou, when thou prayest, enter into thy closet, and when thou hast shut thy door, pray to thy Father which is in secret; and thy Father which seeth in secret shall reward thee openly.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But when ye pray, use not vain repetitions, as the heathen &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt;: for they think that they shall be heard for their much speaking.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Be not ye therefore like unto them: for your Father knoweth what things ye have need of, before ye ask him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;After this manner therefore pray ye: Our Father which art in heaven, Hallowed be thy name.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done in earth, as &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; in heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And forgive us our debts, as we forgive our debtors.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil: For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, for ever. Amen.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For if ye forgive men their trespasses, your heavenly Father will also forgive you:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But if ye forgive not men their trespasses, neither will your Father forgive your trespasses.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Moreover when ye fast, be not, as the hypocrites, of a sad countenance: for they disfigure their faces, that they may appear unto men to fast. Verily I say unto you, They have their reward.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But thou, when thou fastest, anoint thine head, and wash thy face;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;That thou appear not unto men to fast, but unto thy Father which is in secret: and thy Father, which seeth in secret, shall reward thee openly.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Lay not up for yourselves treasures upon earth, where moth and rust doth corrupt, and where thieves break through and steal:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But lay up for yourselves treasures in heaven, where neither moth nor rust doth corrupt, and where thieves do not break through nor steal:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For where your treasure is, there will your heart be also.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;The light of the body is the eye: if therefore thine eye be single, thy whole body shall be full of light.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But if thine eye be evil, thy whole body shall be full of darkness. If therefore the light that is in thee be darkness, how great &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; that darkness!&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;No man can serve two masters: for either he will hate the one, and love the other; or else he will hold to the one, and despise the other. Ye cannot serve God and mammon.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Therefore I say unto you, Take no thought for your life, what ye shall eat, or what ye shall drink; nor yet for your body, what ye shall put on. Is not the life more than meat, and the body than raiment?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold the fowls of the air: for they sow not, neither do they reap, nor gather into barns; yet your heavenly Father feedeth them. Are ye not much better than they?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Which of you by taking thought can add one cubit unto his stature?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And why take ye thought for raiment? Consider the lilies of the field, how they grow; they toil not, neither do they spin:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And yet I say unto you, That even Solomon in all his glory was not arrayed like one of these.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Wherefore, if God so clothe the grass of the field, which to day is, and to morrow is cast into the oven, &lt;i&gt;shall he&lt;/i&gt; not much more &lt;i&gt;clothe&lt;/i&gt; you, O ye of little faith?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Therefore take no thought, saying, What shall we eat? or, What shall we drink? or, Wherewithal shall we be clothed?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;(For after all these things do the Gentiles seek:) for your heavenly Father knoweth that ye have need of all these things.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But seek ye first the kingdom of God, and his righteousness; and all these things shall be added unto you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take therefore no thought for the morrow: for the morrow shall take thought for the things of itself. Sufficient unto the day &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the evil thereof.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>