<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="40" name="Matthew" bookPage="matthew.html" title="Matthew" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="mark_1.html" nextTitle="Mark" prevBook="malachi_1.html" prevTitle="Malachi">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="38" nextChapter="matthew_10.html" nextTitle="Matthew 10" prevChapter="matthew_8.html" prevTitle="Matthew 8" chapterPage="matthew_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he entered into a ship, and passed over, and came into his own city.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And, behold, they brought to him a man sick of the palsy, lying on a bed: and Jesus seeing their faith said unto the sick of the palsy; &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Son, be of good cheer; thy sins be forgiven thee.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And, behold, certain of the scribes said within themselves, This &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; blasphemeth.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Jesus knowing their thoughts said, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Wherefore think ye evil in your hearts?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;For whether is easier, to say, &lt;i&gt;Thy&lt;/i&gt; sins be forgiven thee; or to say, Arise, and walk?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But that ye may know that the Son of man hath power on earth to forgive sins,&lt;/span&gt; (then saith he to the sick of the palsy,) &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Arise, take up thy bed, and go unto thine house.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And he arose, and departed to his house.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But when the multitudes saw &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, they marvelled, and glorified God, which had given such power unto men.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">And as Jesus passed forth from thence, he saw a man, named Matthew, sitting at the receipt of custom: and he saith unto him, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Follow me.&lt;/span&gt; And he arose, and followed him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And it came to pass, as Jesus sat at meat in the house, behold, many publicans and sinners came and sat down with him and his disciples.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And when the Pharisees saw &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, they said unto his disciples, Why eateth your Master with publicans and sinners?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But when Jesus heard &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt;, he said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;They that be whole need not a physician, but they that are sick.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But go ye and learn what &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; meaneth, I will have mercy, and not sacrifice: for I am not come to call the righteous, but sinners to repentance.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Then came to him the disciples of John, saying, Why do we and the Pharisees fast oft, but thy disciples fast not?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And Jesus said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Can the children of the bridechamber mourn, as long as the bridegroom is with them? but the days will come, when the bridegroom shall be taken from them, and then shall they fast.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;No man putteth a piece of new cloth unto an old garment, for that which is put in to fill it up taketh from the garment, and the rent is made worse.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Neither do men put new wine into old bottles: else the bottles break, and the wine runneth out, and the bottles perish: but they put new wine into new bottles, and both are preserved.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">While he spake these things unto them, behold, there came a certain ruler, and worshipped him, saying, My daughter is even now dead: but come and lay thy hand upon her, and she shall live.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Jesus arose, and followed him, and &lt;i&gt;so did&lt;/i&gt; his disciples.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20" newPara="true">And, behold, a woman, which was diseased with an issue of blood twelve years, came behind &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, and touched the hem of his garment:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For she said within herself, If I may but touch his garment, I shall be whole.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But Jesus turned him about, and when he saw her, he said, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Daughter, be of good comfort; thy faith hath made thee whole.&lt;/span&gt; And the woman was made whole from that hour.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And when Jesus came into the ruler's house, and saw the minstrels and the people making a noise,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">He said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Give place: for the maid is not dead, but sleepeth.&lt;/span&gt; And they laughed him to scorn.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">But when the people were put forth, he went in, and took her by the hand, and the maid arose.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And the fame hereof went abroad into all that land.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And when Jesus departed thence, two blind men followed him, crying, and saying, &lt;i&gt;Thou&lt;/i&gt; Son of David, have mercy on us.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And when he was come into the house, the blind men came to him: and Jesus saith unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Believe ye that I am able to do this?&lt;/span&gt; They said unto him, Yea, Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Then touched he their eyes, saying, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;According to your faith be it unto you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And their eyes were opened; and Jesus straitly charged them, saying, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;See &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; no man know &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">But they, when they were departed, spread abroad his fame in all that country.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">As they went out, behold, they brought to him a dumb man possessed with a devil.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And when the devil was cast out, the dumb spake: and the multitudes marvelled, saying, It was never so seen in Israel.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">But the Pharisees said, He casteth out devils through the prince of the devils.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And Jesus went about all the cities and villages, teaching in their synagogues, and preaching the gospel of the kingdom, and healing every sickness and every disease among the people.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">But when he saw the multitudes, he was moved with compassion on them, because they fainted, and were scattered abroad, as sheep having no shepherd.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Then saith he unto his disciples, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;The harvest truly &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; plenteous, but the labourers &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; few;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Pray ye therefore the Lord of the harvest, that he will send forth labourers into his harvest.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>