<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="41" name="Mark" bookPage="mark.html" title="Mark" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="luke_1.html" nextTitle="Luke" prevBook="matthew_1.html" prevTitle="Matthew">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="43" nextChapter="mark_6.html" nextTitle="Mark 6" prevChapter="mark_4.html" prevTitle="Mark 4" chapterPage="mark_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And they came over unto the other side of the sea, into the country of the Gadarenes.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And when he was come out of the ship, immediately there met him out of the tombs a man with an unclean spirit,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Who had &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; dwelling among the tombs; and no man could bind him, no, not with chains:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Because that he had been often bound with fetters and chains, and the chains had been plucked asunder by him, and the fetters broken in pieces: neither could any &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; tame him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And always, night and day, he was in the mountains, and in the tombs, crying, and cutting himself with stones.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But when he saw Jesus afar off, he ran and worshipped him,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And cried with a loud voice, and said, What have I to do with thee, Jesus, &lt;i&gt;thou&lt;/i&gt; Son of the most high God? I adjure thee by God, that thou torment me not.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For he said unto him, &lt;woc&gt;Come out of the man, &lt;i&gt;thou&lt;/i&gt; unclean spirit.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he asked him, &lt;woc&gt;What &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thy name?&lt;/woc&gt; And he answered, saying, My name &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Legion: for we are many.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he besought him much that he would not send them away out of the country.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Now there was there nigh unto the mountains a great herd of swine feeding.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And all the devils besought him, saying, Send us into the swine, that we may enter into them.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And forthwith Jesus gave them leave. And the unclean spirits went out, and entered into the swine: and the herd ran violently down a steep place into the sea, (they were about two thousand;) and were choked in the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they that fed the swine fled, and told &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; in the city, and in the country. And they went out to see what it was that was done.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And they come to Jesus, and see him that was possessed with the devil, and had the legion, sitting, and clothed, and in his right mind: and they were afraid.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And they that saw &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; told them how it befell to him that was possessed with the devil, and &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; concerning the swine.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And they began to pray him to depart out of their coasts.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And when he was come into the ship, he that had been possessed with the devil prayed him that he might be with him.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Howbeit Jesus suffered him not, but saith unto him, &lt;woc&gt;Go home to thy friends, and tell them how great things the Lord hath done for thee, and hath had compassion on thee.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And he departed, and began to publish in Decapolis how great things Jesus had done for him: and all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; did marvel.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And when Jesus was passed over again by ship unto the other side, much people gathered unto him: and he was nigh unto the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And, behold, there cometh one of the rulers of the synagogue, Jairus by name; and when he saw him, he fell at his feet,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And besought him greatly, saying, My little daughter lieth at the point of death: &lt;i&gt;I pray thee&lt;/i&gt;, come and lay thy hands on her, that she may be healed; and she shall live.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And &lt;i&gt;Jesus&lt;/i&gt; went with him; and much people followed him, and thronged him.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And a certain woman, which had an issue of blood twelve years,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And had suffered many things of many physicians, and had spent all that she had, and was nothing bettered, but rather grew worse,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">When she had heard of Jesus, came in the press behind, and touched his garment.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">For she said, If I may touch but his clothes, I shall be whole.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And straightway the fountain of her blood was dried up; and she felt in &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; body that she was healed of that plague.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Jesus, immediately knowing in himself that virtue had gone out of him, turned him about in the press, and said, &lt;woc&gt;Who touched my clothes?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And his disciples said unto him, Thou seest the multitude thronging thee, and sayest thou, &lt;woc&gt;Who touched me?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And he looked round about to see her that had done this thing.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">But the woman fearing and trembling, knowing what was done in her, came and fell down before him, and told him all the truth.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And he said unto her, &lt;woc&gt;Daughter, thy faith hath made thee whole; go in peace, and be whole of thy plague.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">While he yet spake, there came from the ruler of the synagogue's &lt;i&gt;house certain&lt;/i&gt; which said, Thy daughter is dead: why troublest thou the Master any further?</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">As soon as Jesus heard the word that was spoken, he saith unto the ruler of the synagogue, &lt;woc&gt;Be not afraid, only believe.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And he suffered no man to follow him, save Peter, and James, and John the brother of James.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And he cometh to the house of the ruler of the synagogue, and seeth the tumult, and them that wept and wailed greatly.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And when he was come in, he saith unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Why make ye this ado, and weep? the damsel is not dead, but sleepeth.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And they laughed him to scorn. But when he had put them all out, he taketh the father and the mother of the damsel, and them that were with him, and entereth in where the damsel was lying.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And he took the damsel by the hand, and said unto her, &lt;woc&gt;Talitha cumi;&lt;/woc&gt; which is, being interpreted, &lt;woc&gt;Damsel,&lt;/woc&gt; I say unto thee, &lt;woc&gt;arise.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And straightway the damsel arose, and walked; for she was &lt;i&gt;of the age&lt;/i&gt; of twelve years. And they were astonished with a great astonishment.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And he charged them straitly that no man should know it; and commanded that something should be given her to eat.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>