<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="41" name="Mark" bookPage="mark.html" title="Mark" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="luke_1.html" nextTitle="Luke" prevBook="matthew_1.html" prevTitle="Matthew">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="35" nextChapter="mark_4.html" nextTitle="Mark 4" prevChapter="mark_2.html" prevTitle="Mark 2" chapterPage="mark_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he entered again into the synagogue; and there was a man there which had a withered hand.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And they watched him, whether he would heal him on the sabbath day; that they might accuse him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he saith unto the man which had the withered hand, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Stand forth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he saith unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Is it lawful to do good on the sabbath days, or to do evil? to save life, or to kill?&lt;/span&gt; But they held their peace.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And when he had looked round about on them with anger, being grieved for the hardness of their hearts, he saith unto the man, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Stretch forth thine hand.&lt;/span&gt; And he stretched &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; out: and his hand was restored whole as the other.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the Pharisees went forth, and straightway took counsel with the Herodians against him, how they might destroy him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But Jesus withdrew himself with his disciples to the sea: and a great multitude from Galilee followed him, and from Judaea,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And from Jerusalem, and from Idumaea, and &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; beyond Jordan; and they about Tyre and Sidon, a great multitude, when they had heard what great things he did, came unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he spake to his disciples, that a small ship should wait on him because of the multitude, lest they should throng him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For he had healed many; insomuch that they pressed upon him for to touch him, as many as had plagues.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And unclean spirits, when they saw him, fell down before him, and cried, saying, Thou art the Son of God.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he straitly charged them that they should not make him known.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he goeth up into a mountain, and calleth &lt;i&gt;unto him&lt;/i&gt; whom he would: and they came unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he ordained twelve, that they should be with him, and that he might send them forth to preach,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And to have power to heal sicknesses, and to cast out devils:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And Simon he surnamed Peter;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And James the &lt;i&gt;son&lt;/i&gt; of Zebedee, and John the brother of James; and he surnamed them Boanerges, which is, The sons of thunder:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Andrew, and Philip, and Bartholomew, and Matthew, and Thomas, and James the &lt;i&gt;son&lt;/i&gt; of Alphaeus, and Thaddaeus, and Simon the Canaanite,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And Judas Iscariot, which also betrayed him: and they went into an house.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the multitude cometh together again, so that they could not so much as eat bread.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And when his friends heard &lt;i&gt;of it&lt;/i&gt;, they went out to lay hold on him: for they said, He is beside himself.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And the scribes which came down from Jerusalem said, He hath Beelzebub, and by the prince of the devils casteth he out devils.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he called them &lt;i&gt;unto him&lt;/i&gt;, and said unto them in parables, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;How can Satan cast out Satan?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And if a kingdom be divided against itself, that kingdom cannot stand.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And if a house be divided against itself, that house cannot stand.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And if Satan rise up against himself, and be divided, he cannot stand, but hath an end.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;No man can enter into a strong man's house, and spoil his goods, except he will first bind the strong man; and then he will spoil his house.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Verily I say unto you, All sins shall be forgiven unto the sons of men, and blasphemies wherewith soever they shall blaspheme:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But he that shall blaspheme against the Holy Ghost hath never forgiveness, but is in danger of eternal damnation:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Because they said, He hath an unclean spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">There came then his brethren and his mother, and, standing without, sent unto him, calling him.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And the multitude sat about him, and they said unto him, Behold, thy mother and thy brethren without seek for thee.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And he answered them, saying, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Who is my mother, or my brethren?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And he looked round about on them which sat about him, and said, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Behold my mother and my brethren!&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;For whosoever shall do the will of God, the same is my brother, and my sister, and mother.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>