<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="41" name="Mark" bookPage="mark.html" title="Mark" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="luke_1.html" nextTitle="Luke" prevBook="matthew_1.html" prevTitle="Matthew">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="45" nextChapter="mark_2.html" nextTitle="Mark 2" prevChapter="matthew_28.html" prevTitle="Matthew 28" chapterPage="mark_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The beginning of the gospel of Jesus Christ, the Son of God;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">As it is written in the prophets, Behold, I send my messenger before thy face, which shall prepare thy way before thee.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The voice of one crying in the wilderness, Prepare ye the way of the Lord, make his paths straight.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">John did baptize in the wilderness, and preach the baptism of repentance for the remission of sins.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And there went out unto him all the land of Judaea, and they of Jerusalem, and were all baptized of him in the river of Jordan, confessing their sins.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And John was clothed with camel's hair, and with a girdle of a skin about his loins; and he did eat locusts and wild honey;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And preached, saying, There cometh one mightier than I after me, the latchet of whose shoes I am not worthy to stoop down and unloose.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I indeed have baptized you with water: but he shall baptize you with the Holy Ghost.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And it came to pass in those days, that Jesus came from Nazareth of Galilee, and was baptized of John in Jordan.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And straightway coming up out of the water, he saw the heavens opened, and the Spirit like a dove descending upon him:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And there came a voice from heaven, &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt;, Thou art my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And immediately the Spirit driveth him into the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he was there in the wilderness forty days, tempted of Satan; and was with the wild beasts; and the angels ministered unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Now after that John was put in prison, Jesus came into Galilee, preaching the gospel of the kingdom of God,</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And saying, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand: repent ye, and believe the gospel.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Now as he walked by the sea of Galilee, he saw Simon and Andrew his brother casting a net into the sea: for they were fishers.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Jesus said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Come ye after me, and I will make you to become fishers of men.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And straightway they forsook their nets, and followed him.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And when he had gone a little further thence, he saw James the &lt;i&gt;son&lt;/i&gt; of Zebedee, and John his brother, who also were in the ship mending their nets.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And straightway he called them: and they left their father Zebedee in the ship with the hired servants, and went after him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they went into Capernaum; and straightway on the sabbath day he entered into the synagogue, and taught.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And they were astonished at his doctrine: for he taught them as one that had authority, and not as the scribes.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And there was in their synagogue a man with an unclean spirit; and he cried out,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Saying, Let &lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt; alone; what have we to do with thee, thou Jesus of Nazareth? art thou come to destroy us? I know thee who thou art, the Holy One of God.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And Jesus rebuked him, saying, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Hold thy peace, and come out of him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And when the unclean spirit had torn him, and cried with a loud voice, he came out of him.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And they were all amazed, insomuch that they questioned among themselves, saying, What thing is this? what new doctrine &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; this? for with authority commandeth he even the unclean spirits, and they do obey him.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And immediately his fame spread abroad throughout all the region round about Galilee.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And forthwith, when they were come out of the synagogue, they entered into the house of Simon and Andrew, with James and John.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">But Simon's wife's mother lay sick of a fever, and anon they tell him of her.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And he came and took her by the hand, and lifted her up; and immediately the fever left her, and she ministered unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And at even, when the sun did set, they brought unto him all that were diseased, and them that were possessed with devils.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And all the city was gathered together at the door.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And he healed many that were sick of divers diseases, and cast out many devils; and suffered not the devils to speak, because they knew him.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And in the morning, rising up a great while before day, he went out, and departed into a solitary place, and there prayed.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And Simon and they that were with him followed after him.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And when they had found him, they said unto him, All &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; seek for thee.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And he said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Let us go into the next towns, that I may preach there also: for therefore came I forth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And he preached in their synagogues throughout all Galilee, and cast out devils.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And there came a leper to him, beseeching him, and kneeling down to him, and saying unto him, If thou wilt, thou canst make me clean.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And Jesus, moved with compassion, put forth &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; hand, and touched him, and saith unto him, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;I will; be thou clean.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And as soon as he had spoken, immediately the leprosy departed from him, and he was cleansed.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And he straitly charged him, and forthwith sent him away;</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And saith unto him, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;See thou say nothing to any man: but go thy way, shew thyself to the priest, and offer for thy cleansing those things which Moses commanded, for a testimony unto them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">But he went out, and began to publish &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; much, and to blaze abroad the matter, insomuch that Jesus could no more openly enter into the city, but was without in desert places: and they came to him from every quarter.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>