<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="41" name="Mark" bookPage="mark.html" title="Mark" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="luke_1.html" nextTitle="Luke" prevBook="matthew_1.html" prevTitle="Matthew">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="52" nextChapter="mark_11.html" nextTitle="Mark 11" prevChapter="mark_9.html" prevTitle="Mark 9" chapterPage="mark_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he arose from thence, and cometh into the coasts of Judaea by the farther side of Jordan: and the people resort unto him again; and, as he was wont, he taught them again.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2" newPara="true">And the Pharisees came to him, and asked him, Is it lawful for a man to put away &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; wife? tempting him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he answered and said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;What did Moses command you?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they said, Moses suffered to write a bill of divorcement, and to put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;her&lt;/span&gt; away.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Jesus answered and said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;For the hardness of your heart he wrote you this precept.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But from the beginning of the creation God made them male and female.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For this cause shall a man leave his father and mother, and cleave to his wife;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And they twain shall be one flesh: so then they are no more twain, but one flesh.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;What therefore God hath joined together, let not man put asunder.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And in the house his disciples asked him again of the same &lt;span class="extra"&gt;matter&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Whosoever shall put away his wife, and marry another, committeth adultery against her.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And if a woman shall put away her husband, and be married to another, she committeth adultery.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And they brought young children to him, that he should touch them: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; disciples rebuked those that brought &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But when Jesus saw &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, he was much displeased, and said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Suffer the little children to come unto me, and forbid them not: for of such is the kingdom of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto you, Whosoever shall not receive the kingdom of God as a little child, he shall not enter therein.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he took them up in his arms, put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; hands upon them, and blessed them.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">And when he was gone forth into the way, there came one running, and kneeled to him, and asked him, Good Master, what shall I do that I may inherit eternal life?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Jesus said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Why callest thou me good? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none good but one, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt;, God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thou knowest the commandments, Do not commit adultery, Do not kill, Do not steal, Do not bear false witness, Defraud not, Honour thy father and mother.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And he answered and said unto him, Master, all these have I observed from my youth.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then Jesus beholding him loved him, and said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;One thing thou lackest: go thy way, sell whatsoever thou hast, and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven: and come, take up the cross, and follow me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And he was sad at that saying, and went away grieved: for he had great possessions.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And Jesus looked round about, and saith unto his disciples, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;How hardly shall they that have riches enter into the kingdom of God!&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the disciples were astonished at his words. But Jesus answereth again, and saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Children, how hard is it for them that trust in riches to enter into the kingdom of God!&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;It is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle, than for a rich man to enter into the kingdom of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And they were astonished out of measure, saying among themselves, Who then can be saved?</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Jesus looking upon them saith, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;With men &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; impossible, but not with God: for with God all things are possible.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">Then Peter began to say unto him, Lo, we have left all, and have followed thee.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Jesus answered and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto you, There is no man that hath left house, or brethren, or sisters, or father, or mother, or wife, or children, or lands, for my sake, and the gospel's,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But he shall receive an hundredfold now in this time, houses, and brethren, and sisters, and mothers, and children, and lands, with persecutions; and in the world to come eternal life.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But many &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that are&lt;/span&gt; first shall be last; and the last first.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">And they were in the way going up to Jerusalem; and Jesus went before them: and they were amazed; and as they followed, they were afraid. And he took again the twelve, and began to tell them what things should happen unto him,</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Saying&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold, we go up to Jerusalem; and the Son of man shall be delivered unto the chief priests, and unto the scribes; and they shall condemn him to death, and shall deliver him to the Gentiles:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And they shall mock him, and shall scourge him, and shall spit upon him, and shall kill him: and the third day he shall rise again.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35" newPara="true">And James and John, the sons of Zebedee, come unto him, saying, Master, we would that thou shouldest do for us whatsoever we shall desire.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;What would ye that I should do for you?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">They said unto him, Grant unto us that we may sit, one on thy right hand, and the other on thy left hand, in thy glory.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">But Jesus said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye know not what ye ask: can ye drink of the cup that I drink of? and be baptized with the baptism that I am baptized with?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And they said unto him, We can. And Jesus said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye shall indeed drink of the cup that I drink of; and with the baptism that I am baptized withal shall ye be baptized:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But to sit on my right hand and on my left hand is not mine to give; but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it shall be given to them&lt;/span&gt; for whom it is prepared.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And when the ten heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, they began to be much displeased with James and John.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">But Jesus called them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to him&lt;/span&gt;, and saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye know that they which are accounted to rule over the Gentiles exercise lordship over them; and their great ones exercise authority upon them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But so shall it not be among you: but whosoever will be great among you, shall be your minister:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And whosoever of you will be the chiefest, shall be servant of all.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For even the Son of man came not to be ministered unto, but to minister, and to give his life a ransom for many.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46" newPara="true">And they came to Jericho: and as he went out of Jericho with his disciples and a great number of people, blind Bartimaeus, the son of Timaeus, sat by the highway side begging.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">And when he heard that it was Jesus of Nazareth, he began to cry out, and say, Jesus, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thou&lt;/span&gt; Son of David, have mercy on me.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">And many charged him that he should hold his peace: but he cried the more a great deal, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Thou&lt;/span&gt; Son of David, have mercy on me.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And Jesus stood still, and commanded him to be called. And they call the blind man, saying unto him, Be of good comfort, rise; he calleth thee.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">And he, casting away his garment, rose, and came to Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And Jesus answered and said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;What wilt thou that I should do unto thee?&lt;/span&gt; The blind man said unto him, Lord, that I might receive my sight.</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">And Jesus said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Go thy way; thy faith hath made thee whole.&lt;/span&gt; And immediately he received his sight, and followed Jesus in the way.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>