<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="41" name="Mark" bookPage="mark.html" title="Mark" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="luke_1.html" nextTitle="Luke" prevBook="matthew_1.html" prevTitle="Matthew">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="72" nextChapter="mark_15.html" nextTitle="Mark 15" prevChapter="mark_13.html" prevTitle="Mark 13" chapterPage="mark_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">After two days was &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the feast of&lt;/span&gt; the passover, and of unleavened bread: and the chief priests and the scribes sought how they might take him by craft, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; to death.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">But they said, Not on the feast &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt;, lest there be an uproar of the people.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And being in Bethany in the house of Simon the leper, as he sat at meat, there came a woman having an alabaster box of ointment of spikenard very precious; and she brake the box, and poured &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on his head.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And there were some that had indignation within themselves, and said, Why was this waste of the ointment made?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For it might have been sold for more than three hundred pence, and have been given to the poor. And they murmured against her.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Jesus said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Let her alone; why trouble ye her? she hath wrought a good work on me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For ye have the poor with you always, and whensoever ye will ye may do them good: but me ye have not always.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;She hath done what she could: she is come aforehand to anoint my body to the burying.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto you, Wheresoever this gospel shall be preached throughout the whole world, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; also that she hath done shall be spoken of for a memorial of her.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">And Judas Iscariot, one of the twelve, went unto the chief priests, to betray him unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And when they heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, they were glad, and promised to give him money. And he sought how he might conveniently betray him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And the first day of unleavened bread, when they killed the passover, his disciples said unto him, Where wilt thou that we go and prepare that thou mayest eat the passover?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he sendeth forth two of his disciples, and saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Go ye into the city, and there shall meet you a man bearing a pitcher of water: follow him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And wheresoever he shall go in, say ye to the goodman of the house, The Master saith, Where is the guestchamber, where I shall eat the passover with my disciples?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he will shew you a large upper room furnished &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; prepared: there make ready for us.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And his disciples went forth, and came into the city, and found as he had said unto them: and they made ready the passover.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And in the evening he cometh with the twelve.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And as they sat and did eat, Jesus said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto you, One of you which eateth with me shall betray me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And they began to be sorrowful, and to say unto him one by one, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; it I? and another &lt;span class="extra"&gt;said, Is&lt;/span&gt; it I?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And he answered and said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;&lt;span class="extra"&gt;It is&lt;/span&gt; one of the twelve, that dippeth with me in the dish.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;The Son of man indeed goeth, as it is written of him: but woe to that man by whom the Son of man is betrayed! good were it for that man if he had never been born.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And as they did eat, Jesus took bread, and blessed, and brake &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and gave to them, and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take, eat: this is my body.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he took the cup, and when he had given thanks, he gave &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to them: and they all drank of it.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;This is my blood of the new testament, which is shed for many.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto you, I will drink no more of the fruit of the vine, until that day that I drink it new in the kingdom of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And when they had sung an hymn, they went out into the mount of Olives.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And Jesus saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;All ye shall be offended because of me this night: for it is written, I will smite the shepherd, and the sheep shall be scattered.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But after that I am risen, I will go before you into Galilee.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">But Peter said unto him, Although all shall be offended, yet &lt;span class="extra"&gt;will&lt;/span&gt; not I.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Jesus saith unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto thee, That this day, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; in this night, before the cock crow twice, thou shalt deny me thrice.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">But he spake the more vehemently, If I should die with thee, I will not deny thee in any wise. Likewise also said they all.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And they came to a place which was named Gethsemane: and he saith to his disciples, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Sit ye here, while I shall pray.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And he taketh with him Peter and James and John, and began to be sore amazed, and to be very heavy;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;My soul is exceeding sorrowful unto death: tarry ye here, and watch.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And he went forward a little, and fell on the ground, and prayed that, if it were possible, the hour might pass from him.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And he said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Abba, Father, all things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; possible unto thee; take away this cup from me: nevertheless not what I will, but what thou wilt.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And he cometh, and findeth them sleeping, and saith unto Peter, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Simon, sleepest thou? couldest not thou watch one hour?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Watch ye and pray, lest ye enter into temptation. The spirit truly &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; ready, but the flesh &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; weak.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And again he went away, and prayed, and spake the same words.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And when he returned, he found them asleep again, (for their eyes were heavy,) neither wist they what to answer him.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And he cometh the third time, and saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Sleep on now, and take &lt;span class="extra"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; rest: it is enough, the hour is come; behold, the Son of man is betrayed into the hands of sinners.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Rise up, let us go; lo, he that betrayeth me is at hand.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43" newPara="true">And immediately, while he yet spake, cometh Judas, one of the twelve, and with him a great multitude with swords and staves, from the chief priests and the scribes and the elders.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And he that betrayed him had given them a token, saying, Whomsoever I shall kiss, that same is he; take him, and lead &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; away safely.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And as soon as he was come, he goeth straightway to him, and saith, Master, master; and kissed him.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46" newPara="true">And they laid their hands on him, and took him.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">And one of them that stood by drew a sword, and smote a servant of the high priest, and cut off his ear.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">And Jesus answered and said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Are ye come out, as against a thief, with swords and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; staves to take me?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I was daily with you in the temple teaching, and ye took me not: but the scriptures must be fulfilled.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">And they all forsook him, and fled.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And there followed him a certain young man, having a linen cloth cast about &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; naked &lt;span class="extra"&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;; and the young men laid hold on him:</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">And he left the linen cloth, and fled from them naked.</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53" newPara="true">And they led Jesus away to the high priest: and with him were assembled all the chief priests and the elders and the scribes.</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">And Peter followed him afar off, even into the palace of the high priest: and he sat with the servants, and warmed himself at the fire.</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">And the chief priests and all the council sought for witness against Jesus to put him to death; and found none.</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">For many bare false witness against him, but their witness agreed not together.</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">And there arose certain, and bare false witness against him, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">We heard him say, I will destroy this temple that is made with hands, and within three days I will build another made without hands.</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">But neither so did their witness agree together.</verse>
      <verse number="60" id="v60">And the high priest stood up in the midst, and asked Jesus, saying, Answerest thou nothing? what &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is it which&lt;/span&gt; these witness against thee?</verse>
      <verse number="61" id="v61">But he held his peace, and answered nothing. Again the high priest asked him, and said unto him, Art thou the Christ, the Son of the Blessed?</verse>
      <verse number="62" id="v62">And Jesus said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;I am: and ye shall see the Son of man sitting on the right hand of power, and coming in the clouds of heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="63" id="v63">Then the high priest rent his clothes, and saith, What need we any further witnesses?</verse>
      <verse number="64" id="v64">Ye have heard the blasphemy: what think ye? And they all condemned him to be guilty of death.</verse>
      <verse number="65" id="v65">And some began to spit on him, and to cover his face, and to buffet him, and to say unto him, Prophesy: and the servants did strike him with the palms of their hands.</verse>
      <verse number="66" id="v66" newPara="true">And as Peter was beneath in the palace, there cometh one of the maids of the high priest:</verse>
      <verse number="67" id="v67">And when she saw Peter warming himself, she looked upon him, and said, And thou also wast with Jesus of Nazareth.</verse>
      <verse number="68" id="v68">But he denied, saying, I know not, neither understand I what thou sayest. And he went out into the porch; and the cock crew.</verse>
      <verse number="69" id="v69">And a maid saw him again, and began to say to them that stood by, This is &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; of them.</verse>
      <verse number="70" id="v70">And he denied it again. And a little after, they that stood by said again to Peter, Surely thou art &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; of them: for thou art a Galilaean, and thy speech agreeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thereto&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="71" id="v71">But he began to curse and to swear, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;saying&lt;/span&gt;, I know not this man of whom ye speak.</verse>
      <verse number="72" id="v72">And the second time the cock crew. And Peter called to mind the word that Jesus said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Before the cock crow twice, thou shalt deny me thrice.&lt;/span&gt; And when he thought thereon, he wept.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>