<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="41" name="Mark" bookPage="mark.html" title="Mark" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="luke_1.html" nextTitle="Luke" prevBook="matthew_1.html" prevTitle="Matthew">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="37" nextChapter="mark_14.html" nextTitle="Mark 14" prevChapter="mark_12.html" prevTitle="Mark 12" chapterPage="mark_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And as he went out of the temple, one of his disciples saith unto him, Master, see what manner of stones and what buildings &lt;i&gt;are here&lt;/i&gt;!</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Jesus answering said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Seest thou these great buildings? there shall not be left one stone upon another, that shall not be thrown down.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And as he sat upon the mount of Olives over against the temple, Peter and James and John and Andrew asked him privately,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Tell us, when shall these things be? and what &lt;i&gt;shall be&lt;/i&gt; the sign when all these things shall be fulfilled?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Jesus answering them began to say, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take heed lest any &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; deceive you:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For many shall come in my name, saying, I am &lt;i&gt;Christ&lt;/i&gt;; and shall deceive many.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when ye shall hear of wars and rumours of wars, be ye not troubled: for &lt;i&gt;such things&lt;/i&gt; must needs be; but the end &lt;i&gt;shall&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; yet.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For nation shall rise against nation, and kingdom against kingdom: and there shall be earthquakes in divers places, and there shall be famines and troubles: these &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the beginnings of sorrows.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But take heed to yourselves: for they shall deliver you up to councils; and in the synagogues ye shall be beaten: and ye shall be brought before rulers and kings for my sake, for a testimony against them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And the gospel must first be published among all nations.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But when they shall lead &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;, and deliver you up, take no thought beforehand what ye shall speak, neither do ye premeditate: but whatsoever shall be given you in that hour, that speak ye: for it is not ye that speak, but the Holy Ghost.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Now the brother shall betray the brother to death, and the father the son; and children shall rise up against &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; parents, and shall cause them to be put to death.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And ye shall be hated of all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; for my name's sake: but he that shall endure unto the end, the same shall be saved.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But when ye shall see the abomination of desolation, spoken of by Daniel the prophet, standing where it ought not,&lt;/span&gt; (let him that readeth understand,) &lt;span class="woc"&gt;then let them that be in Judaea flee to the mountains:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And let him that is on the housetop not go down into the house, neither enter &lt;i&gt;therein&lt;/i&gt;, to take any thing out of his house:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And let him that is in the field not turn back again for to take up his garment.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But woe to them that are with child, and to them that give suck in those days!&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And pray ye that your flight be not in the winter.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; those days shall be affliction, such as was not from the beginning of the creation which God created unto this time, neither shall be.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And except that the Lord had shortened those days, no flesh should be saved: but for the elect's sake, whom he hath chosen, he hath shortened the days.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And then if any man shall say to you, Lo, here &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Christ; or, lo, &lt;i&gt;he is&lt;/i&gt; there; believe &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; not:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For false Christs and false prophets shall rise, and shall shew signs and wonders, to seduce, if &lt;i&gt;it were&lt;/i&gt; possible, even the elect.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But take ye heed: behold, I have foretold you all things.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But in those days, after that tribulation, the sun shall be darkened, and the moon shall not give her light,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And the stars of heaven shall fall, and the powers that are in heaven shall be shaken.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And then shall they see the Son of man coming in the clouds with great power and glory.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And then shall he send his angels, and shall gather together his elect from the four winds, from the uttermost part of the earth to the uttermost part of heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Now learn a parable of the fig tree; When her branch is yet tender, and putteth forth leaves, ye know that summer is near:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;So ye in like manner, when ye shall see these things come to pass, know that it is nigh, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; at the doors.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto you, that this generation shall not pass, till all these things be done.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Heaven and earth shall pass away: but my words shall not pass away.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But of that day and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; hour knoweth no man, no, not the angels which are in heaven, neither the Son, but the Father.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take ye heed, watch and pray: for ye know not when the time is.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;&lt;i&gt;For the Son of man is&lt;/i&gt; as a man taking a far journey, who left his house, and gave authority to his servants, and to every man his work, and commanded the porter to watch.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Watch ye therefore: for ye know not when the master of the house cometh, at even, or at midnight, or at the cockcrowing, or in the morning:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Lest coming suddenly he find you sleeping.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And what I say unto you I say unto all, Watch.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>