<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="41" name="Mark" bookPage="mark.html" title="Mark" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="luke_1.html" nextTitle="Luke" prevBook="matthew_1.html" prevTitle="Matthew">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="47" nextChapter="mark_16.html" nextTitle="Mark 16" prevChapter="mark_14.html" prevTitle="Mark 14" chapterPage="mark_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And straightway in the morning the chief priests held a consultation with the elders and scribes and the whole council, and bound Jesus, and carried &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; away, and delivered &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; to Pilate.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And Pilate asked him, Art thou the King of the Jews? And he answering said unto him, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Thou sayest &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the chief priests accused him of many things: but he answered nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And Pilate asked him again, saying, Answerest thou nothing? behold how many things they witness against thee.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But Jesus yet answered nothing; so that Pilate marvelled.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Now at &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; feast he released unto them one prisoner, whomsoever they desired.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And there was &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; named Barabbas, &lt;i&gt;which lay&lt;/i&gt; bound with them that had made insurrection with him, who had committed murder in the insurrection.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the multitude crying aloud began to desire &lt;i&gt;him to do&lt;/i&gt; as he had ever done unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But Pilate answered them, saying, Will ye that I release unto you the King of the Jews?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For he knew that the chief priests had delivered him for envy.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But the chief priests moved the people, that he should rather release Barabbas unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Pilate answered and said again unto them, What will ye then that I shall do &lt;i&gt;unto him&lt;/i&gt; whom ye call the King of the Jews?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And they cried out again, Crucify him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Then Pilate said unto them, Why, what evil hath he done? And they cried out the more exceedingly, Crucify him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; Pilate, willing to content the people, released Barabbas unto them, and delivered Jesus, when he had scourged &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, to be crucified.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the soldiers led him away into the hall, called Praetorium; and they call together the whole band.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And they clothed him with purple, and platted a crown of thorns, and put it about his &lt;i&gt;head&lt;/i&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And began to salute him, Hail, King of the Jews!</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And they smote him on the head with a reed, and did spit upon him, and bowing &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; knees worshipped him.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And when they had mocked him, they took off the purple from him, and put his own clothes on him, and led him out to crucify him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they compel one Simon a Cyrenian, who passed by, coming out of the country, the father of Alexander and Rufus, to bear his cross.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And they bring him unto the place Golgotha, which is, being interpreted, The place of a skull.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And they gave him to drink wine mingled with myrrh: but he received &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And when they had crucified him, they parted his garments, casting lots upon them, what every man should take.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And it was the third hour, and they crucified him.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And the superscription of his accusation was written over, THE KING OF THE JEWS.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And with him they crucify two thieves; the one on his right hand, and the other on his left.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the scripture was fulfilled, which saith, And he was numbered with the transgressors.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And they that passed by railed on him, wagging their heads, and saying, Ah, thou that destroyest the temple, and buildest &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; in three days,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Save thyself, and come down from the cross.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Likewise also the chief priests mocking said among themselves with the scribes, He saved others; himself he cannot save.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Let Christ the King of Israel descend now from the cross, that we may see and believe. And they that were crucified with him reviled him.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And when the sixth hour was come, there was darkness over the whole land until the ninth hour.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And at the ninth hour Jesus cried with a loud voice, saying, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Eloi, Eloi, lama sabachthani?&lt;/span&gt; which is, being interpreted, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;My God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And some of them that stood by, when they heard &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, said, Behold, he calleth Elias.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And one ran and filled a spunge full of vinegar, and put &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; on a reed, and gave him to drink, saying, Let alone; let us see whether Elias will come to take him down.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And Jesus cried with a loud voice, and gave up the ghost.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And the veil of the temple was rent in twain from the top to the bottom.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39" newPara="true">And when the centurion, which stood over against him, saw that he so cried out, and gave up the ghost, he said, Truly this man was the Son of God.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">There were also women looking on afar off: among whom was Mary Magdalene, and Mary the mother of James the less and of Joses, and Salome;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">(Who also, when he was in Galilee, followed him, and ministered unto him;) and many other women which came up with him unto Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42" newPara="true">And now when the even was come, because it was the preparation, that is, the day before the sabbath,</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Joseph of Arimathaea, an honourable counsellor, which also waited for the kingdom of God, came, and went in boldly unto Pilate, and craved the body of Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And Pilate marvelled if he were already dead: and calling &lt;i&gt;unto him&lt;/i&gt; the centurion, he asked him whether he had been any while dead.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And when he knew &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; of the centurion, he gave the body to Joseph.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And he bought fine linen, and took him down, and wrapped him in the linen, and laid him in a sepulchre which was hewn out of a rock, and rolled a stone unto the door of the sepulchre.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">And Mary Magdalene and Mary &lt;i&gt;the mother&lt;/i&gt; of Joses beheld where he was laid.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>