<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="41" name="Mark" bookPage="mark.html" title="Mark" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="luke_1.html" nextTitle="Luke" prevBook="matthew_1.html" prevTitle="Matthew">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="44" nextChapter="mark_13.html" nextTitle="Mark 13" prevChapter="mark_11.html" prevTitle="Mark 11" chapterPage="mark_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he began to speak unto them by parables. &lt;span class='woc'&gt;A &lt;span class='extra'&gt;certain&lt;/span&gt; man planted a vineyard, and set an hedge about &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, and digged &lt;span class='extra'&gt;a place for&lt;/span&gt; the winefat, and built a tower, and let it out to husbandmen, and went into a far country.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And at the season he sent to the husbandmen a servant, that he might receive from the husbandmen of the fruit of the vineyard.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And they caught &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, and beat him, and sent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; away empty.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And again he sent unto them another servant; and at him they cast stones, and wounded &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; in the head, and sent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; away shamefully handled.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And again he sent another; and him they killed, and many others; beating some, and killing some.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Having yet therefore one son, his wellbeloved, he sent him also last unto them, saying, They will reverence my son.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;But those husbandmen said among themselves, This is the heir; come, let us kill him, and the inheritance shall be ours.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And they took him, and killed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, and cast &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; out of the vineyard.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;What shall therefore the lord of the vineyard do? he will come and destroy the husbandmen, and will give the vineyard unto others.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And have ye not read this scripture; The stone which the builders rejected is become the head of the corner:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;This was the Lord's doing, and it is marvellous in our eyes?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And they sought to lay hold on him, but feared the people: for they knew that he had spoken the parable against them: and they left him, and went their way.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And they send unto him certain of the Pharisees and of the Herodians, to catch him in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; words.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And when they were come, they say unto him, Master, we know that thou art true, and carest for no man: for thou regardest not the person of men, but teachest the way of God in truth: Is it lawful to give tribute to Caesar, or not?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Shall we give, or shall we not give? But he, knowing their hypocrisy, said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Why tempt ye me? bring me a penny, that I may see &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And they brought &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;. And he saith unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Whose &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this image and superscription?&lt;/span&gt; And they said unto him, Caesar's.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And Jesus answering said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Render to Caesar the things that are Caesar's, and to God the things that are God's.&lt;/span&gt; And they marvelled at him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Then come unto him the Sadducees, which say there is no resurrection; and they asked him, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Master, Moses wrote unto us, If a man's brother die, and leave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; wife &lt;span class='extra'&gt;behind him&lt;/span&gt;, and leave no children, that his brother should take his wife, and raise up seed unto his brother.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Now there were seven brethren: and the first took a wife, and dying left no seed.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the second took her, and died, neither left he any seed: and the third likewise.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And the seven had her, and left no seed: last of all the woman died also.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">In the resurrection therefore, when they shall rise, whose wife shall she be of them? for the seven had her to wife.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And Jesus answering said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Do ye not therefore err, because ye know not the scriptures, neither the power of God?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;For when they shall rise from the dead, they neither marry, nor are given in marriage; but are as the angels which are in heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And as touching the dead, that they rise: have ye not read in the book of Moses, how in the bush God spake unto him, saying, I &lt;span class='extra'&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; the God of Abraham, and the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;He is not the God of the dead, but the God of the living: ye therefore do greatly err.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">And one of the scribes came, and having heard them reasoning together, and perceiving that he had answered them well, asked him, Which is the first commandment of all?</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Jesus answered him, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;The first of all the commandments &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;, Hear, O Israel; The Lord our God is one Lord:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind, and with all thy strength: this &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the first commandment.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And the second &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; like, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;namely&lt;/span&gt; this, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself. There is none other commandment greater than these.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And the scribe said unto him, Well, Master, thou hast said the truth: for there is one God; and there is none other but he:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And to love him with all the heart, and with all the understanding, and with all the soul, and with all the strength, and to love &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; neighbour as himself, is more than all whole burnt offerings and sacrifices.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And when Jesus saw that he answered discreetly, he said unto him, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Thou art not far from the kingdom of God.&lt;/span&gt; And no man after that durst ask him &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any question&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35" newPara="true">And Jesus answered and said, while he taught in the temple, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;How say the scribes that Christ is the Son of David?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;For David himself said by the Holy Ghost, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said to my Lord, Sit thou on my right hand, till I make thine enemies thy footstool.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;David therefore himself calleth him Lord; and whence is he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; his son?&lt;/span&gt; And the common people heard him gladly.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38" newPara="true">And he said unto them in his doctrine, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Beware of the scribes, which love to go in long clothing, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;love&lt;/span&gt; salutations in the marketplaces,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And the chief seats in the synagogues, and the uppermost rooms at feasts:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Which devour widows' houses, and for a pretence make long prayers: these shall receive greater damnation.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41" newPara="true">And Jesus sat over against the treasury, and beheld how the people cast money into the treasury: and many that were rich cast in much.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And there came a certain poor widow, and she threw in two mites, which make a farthing.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And he called &lt;span class='extra'&gt;unto him&lt;/span&gt; his disciples, and saith unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Verily I say unto you, That this poor widow hath cast more in, than all they which have cast into the treasury:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;For all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they&lt;/span&gt; did cast in of their abundance; but she of her want did cast in all that she had, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; all her living.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>