<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="35" nextChapter="luke_15.html" nextTitle="Luke 15" prevChapter="luke_13.html" prevTitle="Luke 13" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, as he went into the house of one of the chief Pharisees to eat bread on the sabbath day, that they watched him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And, behold, there was a certain man before him which had the dropsy.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And Jesus answering spake unto the lawyers and Pharisees, saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Is it lawful to heal on the sabbath day?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they held their peace. And he took &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, and healed him, and let him go;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And answered them, saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Which of you shall have an ass or an ox fallen into a pit, and will not straightway pull him out on the sabbath day?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And they could not answer him again to these things.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And he put forth a parable to those which were bidden, when he marked how they chose out the chief rooms; saying unto them,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;When thou art bidden of any &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; to a wedding, sit not down in the highest room; lest a more honourable man than thou be bidden of him;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he that bade thee and him come and say to thee, Give this man place; and thou begin with shame to take the lowest room.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But when thou art bidden, go and sit down in the lowest room; that when he that bade thee cometh, he may say unto thee, Friend, go up higher: then shalt thou have worship in the presence of them that sit at meat with thee.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For whosoever exalteth himself shall be abased; and he that humbleth himself shall be exalted.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Then said he also to him that bade him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;When thou makest a dinner or a supper, call not thy friends, nor thy brethren, neither thy kinsmen, nor &lt;i&gt;thy&lt;/i&gt; rich neighbours; lest they also bid thee again, and a recompence be made thee.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But when thou makest a feast, call the poor, the maimed, the lame, the blind:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And thou shalt be blessed; for they cannot recompense thee: for thou shalt be recompensed at the resurrection of the just.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">And when one of them that sat at meat with him heard these things, he said unto him, Blessed &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he that shall eat bread in the kingdom of God.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Then said he unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;A certain man made a great supper, and bade many:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And sent his servant at supper time to say to them that were bidden, Come; for all things are now ready.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And they all with one &lt;i&gt;consent&lt;/i&gt; began to make excuse. The first said unto him, I have bought a piece of ground, and I must needs go and see it: I pray thee have me excused.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And another said, I have bought five yoke of oxen, and I go to prove them: I pray thee have me excused.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And another said, I have married a wife, and therefore I cannot come.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;So that servant came, and shewed his lord these things. Then the master of the house being angry said to his servant, Go out quickly into the streets and lanes of the city, and bring in hither the poor, and the maimed, and the halt, and the blind.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And the servant said, Lord, it is done as thou hast commanded, and yet there is room.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And the lord said unto the servant, Go out into the highways and hedges, and compel &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; to come in, that my house may be filled.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I say unto you, That none of those men which were bidden shall taste of my supper.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">And there went great multitudes with him: and he turned, and said unto them,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;If any &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; come to me, and hate not his father, and mother, and wife, and children, and brethren, and sisters, yea, and his own life also, he cannot be my disciple.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And whosoever doth not bear his cross, and come after me, cannot be my disciple.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For which of you, intending to build a tower, sitteth not down first, and counteth the cost, whether he have &lt;i&gt;sufficient&lt;/i&gt; to finish &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Lest haply, after he hath laid the foundation, and is not able to finish &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, all that behold &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; begin to mock him,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Saying, This man began to build, and was not able to finish.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Or what king, going to make war against another king, sitteth not down first, and consulteth whether he be able with ten thousand to meet him that cometh against him with twenty thousand?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Or else, while the other is yet a great way off, he sendeth an ambassage, and desireth conditions of peace.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;So likewise, whosoever he be of you that forsaketh not all that he hath, he cannot be my disciple.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Salt &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; good: but if the salt have lost his savour, wherewith shall it be seasoned?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;It is neither fit for the land, nor yet for the dunghill; &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; men cast it out. He that hath ears to hear, let him hear.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>