<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="39" nextChapter="luke_6.html" nextTitle="Luke 6" prevChapter="luke_4.html" prevTitle="Luke 4" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, that, as the people pressed upon him to hear the word of God, he stood by the lake of Gennesaret,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And saw two ships standing by the lake: but the fishermen were gone out of them, and were washing &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; nets.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he entered into one of the ships, which was Simon's, and prayed him that he would thrust out a little from the land. And he sat down, and taught the people out of the ship.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Now when he had left speaking, he said unto Simon, &lt;woc&gt;Launch out into the deep, and let down your nets for a draught.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Simon answering said unto him, Master, we have toiled all the night, and have taken nothing: nevertheless at thy word I will let down the net.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And when they had this done, they inclosed a great multitude of fishes: and their net brake.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they beckoned unto &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; partners, which were in the other ship, that they should come and help them. And they came, and filled both the ships, so that they began to sink.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">When Simon Peter saw &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, he fell down at Jesus' knees, saying, Depart from me; for I am a sinful man, O Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For he was astonished, and all that were with him, at the draught of the fishes which they had taken:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And so &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; also James, and John, the sons of Zebedee, which were partners with Simon. And Jesus said unto Simon, &lt;woc&gt;Fear not; from henceforth thou shalt catch men.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And when they had brought their ships to land, they forsook all, and followed him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And it came to pass, when he was in a certain city, behold a man full of leprosy: who seeing Jesus fell on &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; face, and besought him, saying, Lord, if thou wilt, thou canst make me clean.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he put forth &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; hand, and touched him, saying, &lt;woc&gt;I will: be thou clean.&lt;/woc&gt; And immediately the leprosy departed from him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he charged him to tell no man: &lt;woc&gt;but go, and shew thyself to the priest, and offer for thy cleansing, according as Moses commanded, for a testimony unto them.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But so much the more went there a fame abroad of him: and great multitudes came together to hear, and to be healed by him of their infirmities.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">And he withdrew himself into the wilderness, and prayed.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And it came to pass on a certain day, as he was teaching, that there were Pharisees and doctors of the law sitting by, which were come out of every town of Galilee, and Judaea, and Jerusalem: and the power of the Lord was &lt;i&gt;present&lt;/i&gt; to heal them.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And, behold, men brought in a bed a man which was taken with a palsy: and they sought &lt;i&gt;means&lt;/i&gt; to bring him in, and to lay &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; before him.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And when they could not find by what &lt;i&gt;way&lt;/i&gt; they might bring him in because of the multitude, they went upon the housetop, and let him down through the tiling with &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; couch into the midst before Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And when he saw their faith, he said unto him, &lt;woc&gt;Man, thy sins are forgiven thee.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the scribes and the Pharisees began to reason, saying, Who is this which speaketh blasphemies? Who can forgive sins, but God alone?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But when Jesus perceived their thoughts, he answering said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;What reason ye in your hearts?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;woc&gt;Whether is easier, to say, Thy sins be forgiven thee; or to say, Rise up and walk?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;woc&gt;But that ye may know that the Son of man hath power upon earth to forgive sins,&lt;/woc&gt; (he said unto the sick of the palsy,) &lt;woc&gt;I say unto thee, Arise, and take up thy couch, and go into thine house.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And immediately he rose up before them, and took up that whereon he lay, and departed to his own house, glorifying God.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And they were all amazed, and they glorified God, and were filled with fear, saying, We have seen strange things to day.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">And after these things he went forth, and saw a publican, named Levi, sitting at the receipt of custom: and he said unto him, &lt;woc&gt;Follow me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he left all, rose up, and followed him.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Levi made him a great feast in his own house: and there was a great company of publicans and of others that sat down with them.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">But their scribes and Pharisees murmured against his disciples, saying, Why do ye eat and drink with publicans and sinners?</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And Jesus answering said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;They that are whole need not a physician; but they that are sick.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;woc&gt;I came not to call the righteous, but sinners to repentance.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">And they said unto him, Why do the disciples of John fast often, and make prayers, and likewise &lt;i&gt;the disciples&lt;/i&gt; of the Pharisees; but thine eat and drink?</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And he said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Can ye make the children of the bridechamber fast, while the bridegroom is with them?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;woc&gt;But the days will come, when the bridegroom shall be taken away from them, and then shall they fast in those days.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">And he spake also a parable unto them; &lt;woc&gt;No man putteth a piece of a new garment upon an old; if otherwise, then both the new maketh a rent, and the piece that was &lt;i&gt;taken&lt;/i&gt; out of the new agreeth not with the old.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">&lt;woc&gt;And no man putteth new wine into old bottles; else the new wine will burst the bottles, and be spilled, and the bottles shall perish.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;woc&gt;But new wine must be put into new bottles; and both are preserved.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">&lt;woc&gt;No man also having drunk old &lt;i&gt;wine&lt;/i&gt; straightway desireth new: for he saith, The old is better.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>