<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="21" verseCount="38" nextChapter="luke_22.html" nextTitle="Luke 22" prevChapter="luke_20.html" prevTitle="Luke 20" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he looked up, and saw the rich men casting their gifts into the treasury.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And he saw also a certain poor widow casting in thither two mites.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Of a truth I say unto you, that this poor widow hath cast in more than they all:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For all these have of their abundance cast in unto the offerings of God: but she of her penury hath cast in all the living that she had.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And as some spake of the temple, how it was adorned with goodly stones and gifts, he said,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As for&lt;/i&gt; these things which ye behold, the days will come, in the which there shall not be left one stone upon another, that shall not be thrown down.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they asked him, saying, Master, but when shall these things be? and what sign &lt;i&gt;will there be&lt;/i&gt; when these things shall come to pass?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take heed that ye be not deceived: for many shall come in my name, saying, I am &lt;i&gt;Christ&lt;/i&gt;; and the time draweth near: go ye not therefore after them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But when ye shall hear of wars and commotions, be not terrified: for these things must first come to pass; but the end &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not by and by.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then said he unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Nation shall rise against nation, and kingdom against kingdom:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And great earthquakes shall be in divers places, and famines, and pestilences; and fearful sights and great signs shall there be from heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But before all these, they shall lay their hands on you, and persecute &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;, delivering &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; up to the synagogues, and into prisons, being brought before kings and rulers for my name's sake.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And it shall turn to you for a testimony.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Settle &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; therefore in your hearts, not to meditate before what ye shall answer:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I will give you a mouth and wisdom, which all your adversaries shall not be able to gainsay nor resist.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And ye shall be betrayed both by parents, and brethren, and kinsfolks, and friends; and &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; of you shall they cause to be put to death.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And ye shall be hated of all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; for my name's sake.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But there shall not an hair of your head perish.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;In your patience possess ye your souls.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when ye shall see Jerusalem compassed with armies, then know that the desolation thereof is nigh.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then let them which are in Judaea flee to the mountains; and let them which are in the midst of it depart out; and let not them that are in the countries enter thereinto.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For these be the days of vengeance, that all things which are written may be fulfilled.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But woe unto them that are with child, and to them that give suck, in those days! for there shall be great distress in the land, and wrath upon this people.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And they shall fall by the edge of the sword, and shall be led away captive into all nations: and Jerusalem shall be trodden down of the Gentiles, until the times of the Gentiles be fulfilled.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And there shall be signs in the sun, and in the moon, and in the stars; and upon the earth distress of nations, with perplexity; the sea and the waves roaring;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Men's hearts failing them for fear, and for looking after those things which are coming on the earth: for the powers of heaven shall be shaken.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And then shall they see the Son of man coming in a cloud with power and great glory.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when these things begin to come to pass, then look up, and lift up your heads; for your redemption draweth nigh.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And he spake to them a parable; &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold the fig tree, and all the trees;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;When they now shoot forth, ye see and know of your own selves that summer is now nigh at hand.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;So likewise ye, when ye see these things come to pass, know ye that the kingdom of God is nigh at hand.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily I say unto you, This generation shall not pass away, till all be fulfilled.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Heaven and earth shall pass away: but my words shall not pass away.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And take heed to yourselves, lest at any time your hearts be overcharged with surfeiting, and drunkenness, and cares of this life, and &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; that day come upon you unawares.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For as a snare shall it come on all them that dwell on the face of the whole earth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Watch ye therefore, and pray always, that ye may be accounted worthy to escape all these things that shall come to pass, and to stand before the Son of man.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And in the day time he was teaching in the temple; and at night he went out, and abode in the mount that is called &lt;i&gt;the mount&lt;/i&gt; of Olives.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And all the people came early in the morning to him in the temple, for to hear him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>