<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="71" nextChapter="luke_23.html" nextTitle="Luke 23" prevChapter="luke_21.html" prevTitle="Luke 21" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now the feast of unleavened bread drew nigh, which is called the Passover.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the chief priests and scribes sought how they might kill him; for they feared the people.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">Then entered Satan into Judas surnamed Iscariot, being of the number of the twelve.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he went his way, and communed with the chief priests and captains, how he might betray him unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they were glad, and covenanted to give him money.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he promised, and sought opportunity to betray him unto them in the absence of the multitude.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">Then came the day of unleavened bread, when the passover must be killed.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he sent Peter and John, saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Go and prepare us the passover, that we may eat.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And they said unto him, Where wilt thou that we prepare?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold, when ye are entered into the city, there shall a man meet you, bearing a pitcher of water; follow him into the house where he entereth in.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And ye shall say unto the goodman of the house, The Master saith unto thee, Where is the guestchamber, where I shall eat the passover with my disciples?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he shall shew you a large upper room furnished: there make ready.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And they went, and found as he had said unto them: and they made ready the passover.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And when the hour was come, he sat down, and the twelve apostles with him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;With desire I have desired to eat this passover with you before I suffer:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I say unto you, I will not any more eat thereof, until it be fulfilled in the kingdom of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he took the cup, and gave thanks, and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take this, and divide &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; among yourselves:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I say unto you, I will not drink of the fruit of the vine, until the kingdom of God shall come.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And he took bread, and gave thanks, and brake &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and gave unto them, saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;This is my body which is given for you: this do in remembrance of me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Likewise also the cup after supper, saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;This cup &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the new testament in my blood, which is shed for you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But, behold, the hand of him that betrayeth me &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; with me on the table.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And truly the Son of man goeth, as it was determined: but woe unto that man by whom he is betrayed!&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And they began to enquire among themselves, which of them it was that should do this thing.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And there was also a strife among them, which of them should be accounted the greatest.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;The kings of the Gentiles exercise lordship over them; and they that exercise authority upon them are called benefactors.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But ye &lt;i&gt;shall&lt;/i&gt; not &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; so: but he that is greatest among you, let him be as the younger; and he that is chief, as he that doth serve.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For whether &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; greater, he that sitteth at meat, or he that serveth? &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not he that sitteth at meat? but I am among you as he that serveth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye are they which have continued with me in my temptations.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And I appoint unto you a kingdom, as my Father hath appointed unto me;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;That ye may eat and drink at my table in my kingdom, and sit on thrones judging the twelve tribes of Israel.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And the Lord said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Simon, Simon, behold, Satan hath desired &lt;i&gt;to have&lt;/i&gt; you, that he may sift &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; as wheat:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But I have prayed for thee, that thy faith fail not: and when thou art converted, strengthen thy brethren.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And he said unto him, Lord, I am ready to go with thee, both into prison, and to death.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And he said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;I tell thee, Peter, the cock shall not crow this day, before that thou shalt thrice deny that thou knowest me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;When I sent you without purse, and scrip, and shoes, lacked ye any thing?&lt;/span&gt; And they said, Nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Then said he unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;But now, he that hath a purse, let him take &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and likewise &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; scrip: and he that hath no sword, let him sell his garment, and buy one.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I say unto you, that this that is written must yet be accomplished in me, And he was reckoned among the transgressors: for the things concerning me have an end.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And they said, Lord, behold, here &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; two swords. And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;It is enough.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39" newPara="true">And he came out, and went, as he was wont, to the mount of Olives; and his disciples also followed him.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And when he was at the place, he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Pray that ye enter not into temptation.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And he was withdrawn from them about a stone's cast, and kneeled down, and prayed,</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Father, if thou be willing, remove this cup from me: nevertheless not my will, but thine, be done.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And there appeared an angel unto him from heaven, strengthening him.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And being in an agony he prayed more earnestly: and his sweat was as it were great drops of blood falling down to the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And when he rose up from prayer, and was come to his disciples, he found them sleeping for sorrow,</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Why sleep ye? rise and pray, lest ye enter into temptation.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47" newPara="true">And while he yet spake, behold a multitude, and he that was called Judas, one of the twelve, went before them, and drew near unto Jesus to kiss him.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">But Jesus said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Judas, betrayest thou the Son of man with a kiss?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">When they which were about him saw what would follow, they said unto him, Lord, shall we smite with the sword?</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50" newPara="true">And one of them smote the servant of the high priest, and cut off his right ear.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And Jesus answered and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Suffer ye thus far.&lt;/span&gt; And he touched his ear, and healed him.</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">Then Jesus said unto the chief priests, and captains of the temple, and the elders, which were come to him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Be ye come out, as against a thief, with swords and staves?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;When I was daily with you in the temple, ye stretched forth no hands against me: but this is your hour, and the power of darkness.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54" newPara="true">Then took they him, and led &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, and brought him into the high priest's house. And Peter followed afar off.</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">And when they had kindled a fire in the midst of the hall, and were set down together, Peter sat down among them.</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">But a certain maid beheld him as he sat by the fire, and earnestly looked upon him, and said, This man was also with him.</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">And he denied him, saying, Woman, I know him not.</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">And after a little while another saw him, and said, Thou art also of them. And Peter said, Man, I am not.</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">And about the space of one hour after another confidently affirmed, saying, Of a truth this &lt;i&gt;fellow&lt;/i&gt; also was with him: for he is a Galilaean.</verse>
      <verse number="60" id="v60">And Peter said, Man, I know not what thou sayest. And immediately, while he yet spake, the cock crew.</verse>
      <verse number="61" id="v61">And the Lord turned, and looked upon Peter. And Peter remembered the word of the Lord, how he had said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Before the cock crow, thou shalt deny me thrice.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="62" id="v62">And Peter went out, and wept bitterly.</verse>
      <verse number="63" id="v63" newPara="true">And the men that held Jesus mocked him, and smote &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="64" id="v64">And when they had blindfolded him, they struck him on the face, and asked him, saying, Prophesy, who is it that smote thee?</verse>
      <verse number="65" id="v65">And many other things blasphemously spake they against him.</verse>
      <verse number="66" id="v66" newPara="true">And as soon as it was day, the elders of the people and the chief priests and the scribes came together, and led him into their council, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="67" id="v67">Art thou the Christ? tell us. And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;If I tell you, ye will not believe:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="68" id="v68">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And if I also ask &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;, ye will not answer me, nor let &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; go.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="69" id="v69">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Hereafter shall the Son of man sit on the right hand of the power of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="70" id="v70">Then said they all, Art thou then the Son of God? And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye say that I am.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="71" id="v71">And they said, What need we any further witness? for we ourselves have heard of his own mouth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>