<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="47" nextChapter="luke_21.html" nextTitle="Luke 21" prevChapter="luke_19.html" prevTitle="Luke 19" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And it came to pass, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; on one of those days, as he taught the people in the temple, and preached the gospel, the chief priests and the scribes came upon &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; with the elders,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And spake unto him, saying, Tell us, by what authority doest thou these things? or who is he that gave thee this authority?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And he answered and said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;I will also ask you one thing; and answer me:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;The baptism of John, was it from heaven, or of men?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And they reasoned with themselves, saying, If we shall say, From heaven; he will say, Why then believed ye him not?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But and if we say, Of men; all the people will stone us: for they be persuaded that John was a prophet.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they answered, that they could not tell whence &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it was&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Jesus said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Neither tell I you by what authority I do these things.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then began he to speak to the people this parable; &lt;span class='woc'&gt;A certain man planted a vineyard, and let it forth to husbandmen, and went into a far country for a long time.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And at the season he sent a servant to the husbandmen, that they should give him of the fruit of the vineyard: but the husbandmen beat him, and sent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; away empty.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And again he sent another servant: and they beat him also, and entreated &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; shamefully, and sent &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; away empty.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And again he sent a third: and they wounded him also, and cast &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; out.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Then said the lord of the vineyard, What shall I do? I will send my beloved son: it may be they will reverence &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; when they see him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;But when the husbandmen saw him, they reasoned among themselves, saying, This is the heir: come, let us kill him, that the inheritance may be ours.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;So they cast him out of the vineyard, and killed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;. What therefore shall the lord of the vineyard do unto them?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;He shall come and destroy these husbandmen, and shall give the vineyard to others.&lt;/span&gt; And when they heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, they said, God forbid.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he beheld them, and said, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;What is this then that is written, The stone which the builders rejected, the same is become the head of the corner?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Whosoever shall fall upon that stone shall be broken; but on whomsoever it shall fall, it will grind him to powder.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And the chief priests and the scribes the same hour sought to lay hands on him; and they feared the people: for they perceived that he had spoken this parable against them.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And they watched &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, and sent forth spies, which should feign themselves just men, that they might take hold of his words, that so they might deliver him unto the power and authority of the governor.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they asked him, saying, Master, we know that thou sayest and teachest rightly, neither acceptest thou the person &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of any&lt;/span&gt;, but teachest the way of God truly:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Is it lawful for us to give tribute unto Caesar, or no?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But he perceived their craftiness, and said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Why tempt ye me?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Shew me a penny. Whose image and superscription hath it?&lt;/span&gt; They answered and said, Caesar's.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And he said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Render therefore unto Caesar the things which be Caesar's, and unto God the things which be God's.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And they could not take hold of his words before the people: and they marvelled at his answer, and held their peace.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27" newPara="true">Then came to &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; certain of the Sadducees, which deny that there is any resurrection; and they asked him,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Saying, Master, Moses wrote unto us, If any man's brother die, having a wife, and he die without children, that his brother should take his wife, and raise up seed unto his brother.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">There were therefore seven brethren: and the first took a wife, and died without children.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the second took her to wife, and he died childless.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And the third took her; and in like manner the seven also: and they left no children, and died.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Last of all the woman died also.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Therefore in the resurrection whose wife of them is she? for seven had her to wife.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And Jesus answering said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;The children of this world marry, and are given in marriage:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;But they which shall be accounted worthy to obtain that world, and the resurrection from the dead, neither marry, nor are given in marriage:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Neither can they die any more: for they are equal unto the angels; and are the children of God, being the children of the resurrection.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Now that the dead are raised, even Moses shewed at the bush, when he calleth the Lord the God of Abraham, and the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;For he is not a God of the dead, but of the living: for all live unto him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39" newPara="true">Then certain of the scribes answering said, Master, thou hast well said.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And after that they durst not ask him any &lt;span class='extra'&gt;question at all&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And he said unto them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;How say they that Christ is David's son?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And David himself saith in the book of Psalms, The &lt;span class='nog'&gt;Lord&lt;/span&gt; said unto my Lord, Sit thou on my right hand,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Till I make thine enemies thy footstool.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;David therefore calleth him Lord, how is he then his son?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45" newPara="true">Then in the audience of all the people he said unto his disciples,</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Beware of the scribes, which desire to walk in long robes, and love greetings in the markets, and the highest seats in the synagogues, and the chief rooms at feasts;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Which devour widows' houses, and for a shew make long prayers: the same shall receive greater damnation.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>