<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="59" nextChapter="luke_13.html" nextTitle="Luke 13" prevChapter="luke_11.html" prevTitle="Luke 11" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">In the mean time, when there were gathered together an innumerable multitude of people, insomuch that they trode one upon another, he began to say unto his disciples first of all, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Beware ye of the leaven of the Pharisees, which is hypocrisy.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;For there is nothing covered, that shall not be revealed; neither hid, that shall not be known.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Therefore whatsoever ye have spoken in darkness shall be heard in the light; and that which ye have spoken in the ear in closets shall be proclaimed upon the housetops.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And I say unto you my friends, Be not afraid of them that kill the body, and after that have no more that they can do.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But I will forewarn you whom ye shall fear: Fear him, which after he hath killed hath power to cast into hell; yea, I say unto you, Fear him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Are not five sparrows sold for two farthings, and not one of them is forgotten before God?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But even the very hairs of your head are all numbered. Fear not therefore: ye are of more value than many sparrows.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Also I say unto you, Whosoever shall confess me before men, him shall the Son of man also confess before the angels of God:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But he that denieth me before men shall be denied before the angels of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And whosoever shall speak a word against the Son of man, it shall be forgiven him: but unto him that blasphemeth against the Holy Ghost it shall not be forgiven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And when they bring you unto the synagogues, and &lt;i&gt;unto&lt;/i&gt; magistrates, and powers, take ye no thought how or what thing ye shall answer, or what ye shall say:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;For the Holy Ghost shall teach you in the same hour what ye ought to say.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And one of the company said unto him, Master, speak to my brother, that he divide the inheritance with me.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he said unto him, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Man, who made me a judge or a divider over you?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Take heed, and beware of covetousness: for a man's life consisteth not in the abundance of the things which he possesseth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he spake a parable unto them, saying, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;The ground of a certain rich man brought forth plentifully:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And he thought within himself, saying, What shall I do, because I have no room where to bestow my fruits?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And he said, This will I do: I will pull down my barns, and build greater; and there will I bestow all my fruits and my goods.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And I will say to my soul, Soul, thou hast much goods laid up for many years; take thine ease, eat, drink, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; be merry.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But God said unto him, &lt;i&gt;Thou&lt;/i&gt; fool, this night thy soul shall be required of thee: then whose shall those things be, which thou hast provided?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;So &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he that layeth up treasure for himself, and is not rich toward God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And he said unto his disciples, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Therefore I say unto you, Take no thought for your life, what ye shall eat; neither for the body, what ye shall put on.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;The life is more than meat, and the body &lt;i&gt;is more&lt;/i&gt; than raiment.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Consider the ravens: for they neither sow nor reap; which neither have storehouse nor barn; and God feedeth them: how much more are ye better than the fowls?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And which of you with taking thought can add to his stature one cubit?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;If ye then be not able to do that thing which is least, why take ye thought for the rest?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Consider the lilies how they grow: they toil not, they spin not; and yet I say unto you, that Solomon in all his glory was not arrayed like one of these.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;If then God so clothe the grass, which is to day in the field, and to morrow is cast into the oven; how much more &lt;i&gt;will he clothe&lt;/i&gt; you, O ye of little faith?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And seek not ye what ye shall eat, or what ye shall drink, neither be ye of doubtful mind.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;For all these things do the nations of the world seek after: and your Father knoweth that ye have need of these things.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But rather seek ye the kingdom of God; and all these things shall be added unto you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Fear not, little flock; for it is your Father's good pleasure to give you the kingdom.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Sell that ye have, and give alms; provide yourselves bags which wax not old, a treasure in the heavens that faileth not, where no thief approacheth, neither moth corrupteth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;For where your treasure is, there will your heart be also.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Let your loins be girded about, and &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; lights burning;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And ye yourselves like unto men that wait for their lord, when he will return from the wedding; that when he cometh and knocketh, they may open unto him immediately.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Blessed &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; those servants, whom the lord when he cometh shall find watching: verily I say unto you, that he shall gird himself, and make them to sit down to meat, and will come forth and serve them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And if he shall come in the second watch, or come in the third watch, and find &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; so, blessed are those servants.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And this know, that if the goodman of the house had known what hour the thief would come, he would have watched, and not have suffered his house to be broken through.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Be ye therefore ready also: for the Son of man cometh at an hour when ye think not.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41" newPara="true">Then Peter said unto him, Lord, speakest thou this parable unto us, or even to all?</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And the Lord said, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Who then is that faithful and wise steward, whom &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; lord shall make ruler over his household, to give &lt;i&gt;them their&lt;/i&gt; portion of meat in due season?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Blessed &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; that servant, whom his lord when he cometh shall find so doing.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Of a truth I say unto you, that he will make him ruler over all that he hath.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But and if that servant say in his heart, My lord delayeth his coming; and shall begin to beat the menservants and maidens, and to eat and drink, and to be drunken;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;The lord of that servant will come in a day when he looketh not for &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, and at an hour when he is not aware, and will cut him in sunder, and will appoint him his portion with the unbelievers.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And that servant, which knew his lord's will, and prepared not &lt;i&gt;himself&lt;/i&gt;, neither did according to his will, shall be beaten with many &lt;i&gt;stripes&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But he that knew not, and did commit things worthy of stripes, shall be beaten with few &lt;i&gt;stripes&lt;/i&gt;. For unto whomsoever much is given, of him shall be much required: and to whom men have committed much, of him they will ask the more.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49" newPara="true">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;I am come to send fire on the earth; and what will I, if it be already kindled?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But I have a baptism to be baptized with; and how am I straitened till it be accomplished!&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Suppose ye that I am come to give peace on earth? I tell you, Nay; but rather division:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;For from henceforth there shall be five in one house divided, three against two, and two against three.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;The father shall be divided against the son, and the son against the father; the mother against the daughter, and the daughter against the mother; the mother in law against her daughter in law, and the daughter in law against her mother in law.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54" newPara="true">And he said also to the people, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;When ye see a cloud rise out of the west, straightway ye say, There cometh a shower; and so it is.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And when &lt;i&gt;ye see&lt;/i&gt; the south wind blow, ye say, There will be heat; and it cometh to pass.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ye&lt;/i&gt; hypocrites, ye can discern the face of the sky and of the earth; but how is it that ye do not discern this time?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Yea, and why even of yourselves judge ye not what is right?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58" newPara="true">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;When thou goest with thine adversary to the magistrate, &lt;i&gt;as thou art&lt;/i&gt; in the way, give diligence that thou mayest be delivered from him; lest he hale thee to the judge, and the judge deliver thee to the officer, and the officer cast thee into prison.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;I tell thee, thou shalt not depart thence, till thou hast paid the very last mite.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>