<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="31" nextChapter="luke_17.html" nextTitle="Luke 17" prevChapter="luke_15.html" prevTitle="Luke 15" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he said also unto his disciples, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;There was a certain rich man, which had a steward; and the same was accused unto him that he had wasted his goods.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he called him, and said unto him, How is it that I hear this of thee? give an account of thy stewardship; for thou mayest be no longer steward.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then the steward said within himself, What shall I do? for my lord taketh away from me the stewardship: I cannot dig; to beg I am ashamed.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I am resolved what to do, that, when I am put out of the stewardship, they may receive me into their houses.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;So he called every one of his lord's debtors &lt;i&gt;unto him&lt;/i&gt;, and said unto the first, How much owest thou unto my lord?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he said, An hundred measures of oil. And he said unto him, Take thy bill, and sit down quickly, and write fifty.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then said he to another, And how much owest thou? And he said, An hundred measures of wheat. And he said unto him, Take thy bill, and write fourscore.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And the lord commended the unjust steward, because he had done wisely: for the children of this world are in their generation wiser than the children of light.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And I say unto you, Make to yourselves friends of the mammon of unrighteousness; that, when ye fail, they may receive you into everlasting habitations.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;He that is faithful in that which is least is faithful also in much: and he that is unjust in the least is unjust also in much.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;If therefore ye have not been faithful in the unrighteous mammon, who will commit to your trust the true &lt;i&gt;riches&lt;/i&gt;?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And if ye have not been faithful in that which is another man's, who shall give you that which is your own?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;No servant can serve two masters: for either he will hate the one, and love the other; or else he will hold to the one, and despise the other. Ye cannot serve God and mammon.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the Pharisees also, who were covetous, heard all these things: and they derided him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye are they which justify yourselves before men; but God knoweth your hearts: for that which is highly esteemed among men is abomination in the sight of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;The law and the prophets &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; until John: since that time the kingdom of God is preached, and every man presseth into it.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And it is easier for heaven and earth to pass, than one tittle of the law to fail.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Whosoever putteth away his wife, and marrieth another, committeth adultery: and whosoever marrieth her that is put away from &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; husband committeth adultery.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;There was a certain rich man, which was clothed in purple and fine linen, and fared sumptuously every day:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And there was a certain beggar named Lazarus, which was laid at his gate, full of sores,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And desiring to be fed with the crumbs which fell from the rich man's table: moreover the dogs came and licked his sores.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And it came to pass, that the beggar died, and was carried by the angels into Abraham's bosom: the rich man also died, and was buried;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And in hell he lift up his eyes, being in torments, and seeth Abraham afar off, and Lazarus in his bosom.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he cried and said, Father Abraham, have mercy on me, and send Lazarus, that he may dip the tip of his finger in water, and cool my tongue; for I am tormented in this flame.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But Abraham said, Son, remember that thou in thy lifetime receivedst thy good things, and likewise Lazarus evil things: but now he is comforted, and thou art tormented.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And beside all this, between us and you there is a great gulf fixed: so that they which would pass from hence to you cannot; neither can they pass to us, that &lt;i&gt;would come&lt;/i&gt; from thence.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Then he said, I pray thee therefore, father, that thou wouldest send him to my father's house:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I have five brethren; that he may testify unto them, lest they also come into this place of torment.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Abraham saith unto him, They have Moses and the prophets; let them hear them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he said, Nay, father Abraham: but if one went unto them from the dead, they will repent.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he said unto him, If they hear not Moses and the prophets, neither will they be persuaded, though one rose from the dead.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>