<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="32" nextChapter="luke_16.html" nextTitle="Luke 16" prevChapter="luke_14.html" prevTitle="Luke 14" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then drew near unto him all the publicans and sinners for to hear him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the Pharisees and scribes murmured, saying, This man receiveth sinners, and eateth with them.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3" newPara="true">And he spake this parable unto them, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;What man of you, having an hundred sheep, if he lose one of them, doth not leave the ninety and nine in the wilderness, and go after that which is lost, until he find it?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when he hath found &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, he layeth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; on his shoulders, rejoicing.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when he cometh home, he calleth together &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; friends and neighbours, saying unto them, Rejoice with me; for I have found my sheep which was lost.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I say unto you, that likewise joy shall be in heaven over one sinner that repenteth, more than over ninety and nine just persons, which need no repentance.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Either what woman having ten pieces of silver, if she lose one piece, doth not light a candle, and sweep the house, and seek diligently till she find &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when she hath found &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, she calleth &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; friends and &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; neighbours together, saying, Rejoice with me; for I have found the piece which I had lost.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Likewise, I say unto you, there is joy in the presence of the angels of God over one sinner that repenteth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And he said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;A certain man had two sons:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And the younger of them said to &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; father, Father, give me the portion of goods that falleth &lt;i&gt;to me&lt;/i&gt;. And he divided unto them &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; living.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And not many days after the younger son gathered all together, and took his journey into a far country, and there wasted his substance with riotous living.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when he had spent all, there arose a mighty famine in that land; and he began to be in want.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he went and joined himself to a citizen of that country; and he sent him into his fields to feed swine. &lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he would fain have filled his belly with the husks that the swine did eat: and no man gave unto him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when he came to himself, he said, How many hired servants of my father's have bread enough and to spare, and I perish with hunger!&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I will arise and go to my father, and will say unto him, Father, I have sinned against heaven, and before thee,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And am no more worthy to be called thy son: make me as one of thy hired servants.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he arose, and came to his father. But when he was yet a great way off, his father saw him, and had compassion, and ran, and fell on his neck, and kissed him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And the son said unto him, Father, I have sinned against heaven, and in thy sight, and am no more worthy to be called thy son.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But the father said to his servants, Bring forth the best robe, and put &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; on him; and put a ring on his hand, and shoes on &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; feet:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And bring hither the fatted calf, and kill &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;; and let us eat, and be merry:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For this my son was dead, and is alive again; he was lost, and is found. And they began to be merry.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Now his elder son was in the field: and as he came and drew nigh to the house, he heard musick and dancing.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he called one of the servants, and asked what these things meant.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he said unto him, Thy brother is come; and thy father hath killed the fatted calf, because he hath received him safe and sound.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he was angry, and would not go in: therefore came his father out, and intreated him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he answering said to &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; father, Lo, these many years do I serve thee, neither transgressed I at any time thy commandment: and yet thou never gavest me a kid, that I might make merry with my friends:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But as soon as this thy son was come, which hath devoured thy living with harlots, thou hast killed for him the fatted calf.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And he said unto him, Son, thou art ever with me, and all that I have is thine.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;It was meet that we should make merry, and be glad: for this thy brother was dead, and is alive again; and was lost, and is found.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>