<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="80" nextChapter="luke_2.html" nextTitle="Luke 2" prevChapter="mark_16.html" prevTitle="Mark 16" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Forasmuch as many have taken in hand to set forth in order a declaration of those things which are most surely believed among us,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Even as they delivered them unto us, which from the beginning were eyewitnesses, and ministers of the word;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">It seemed good to me also, having had perfect understanding of all things from the very first, to write unto thee in order, most excellent Theophilus,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">That thou mightest know the certainty of those things, wherein thou hast been instructed.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">There was in the days of Herod, the king of Judaea, a certain priest named Zacharias, of the course of Abia: and his wife &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; of the daughters of Aaron, and her name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Elisabeth.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And they were both righteous before God, walking in all the commandments and ordinances of the Lord blameless.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And they had no child, because that Elisabeth was barren, and they both were &lt;span class='extra'&gt;now&lt;/span&gt; well stricken in years.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And it came to pass, that while he executed the priest's office before God in the order of his course,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">According to the custom of the priest's office, his lot was to burn incense when he went into the temple of the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And the whole multitude of the people were praying without at the time of incense.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And there appeared unto him an angel of the Lord standing on the right side of the altar of incense.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And when Zacharias saw &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, he was troubled, and fear fell upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But the angel said unto him, Fear not, Zacharias: for thy prayer is heard; and thy wife Elisabeth shall bear thee a son, and thou shalt call his name John.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And thou shalt have joy and gladness; and many shall rejoice at his birth.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For he shall be great in the sight of the Lord, and shall drink neither wine nor strong drink; and he shall be filled with the Holy Ghost, even from his mother's womb.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And many of the children of Israel shall he turn to the Lord their God.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he shall go before him in the spirit and power of Elias, to turn the hearts of the fathers to the children, and the disobedient to the wisdom of the just; to make ready a people prepared for the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And Zacharias said unto the angel, Whereby shall I know this? for I am an old man, and my wife well stricken in years.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the angel answering said unto him, I am Gabriel, that stand in the presence of God; and am sent to speak unto thee, and to shew thee these glad tidings.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And, behold, thou shalt be dumb, and not able to speak, until the day that these things shall be performed, because thou believest not my words, which shall be fulfilled in their season.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the people waited for Zacharias, and marvelled that he tarried so long in the temple.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And when he came out, he could not speak unto them: and they perceived that he had seen a vision in the temple: for he beckoned unto them, and remained speechless.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And it came to pass, that, as soon as the days of his ministration were accomplished, he departed to his own house.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And after those days his wife Elisabeth conceived, and hid herself five months, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Thus hath the Lord dealt with me in the days wherein he looked on &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt;, to take away my reproach among men.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And in the sixth month the angel Gabriel was sent from God unto a city of Galilee, named Nazareth,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">To a virgin espoused to a man whose name was Joseph, of the house of David; and the virgin's name &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; Mary.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the angel came in unto her, and said, Hail, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thou that art&lt;/span&gt; highly favoured, the Lord &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with thee: blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; thou among women.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And when she saw &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, she was troubled at his saying, and cast in her mind what manner of salutation this should be.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And the angel said unto her, Fear not, Mary: for thou hast found favour with God.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And, behold, thou shalt conceive in thy womb, and bring forth a son, and shalt call his name JESUS.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">He shall be great, and shall be called the Son of the Highest: and the Lord God shall give unto him the throne of his father David:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And he shall reign over the house of Jacob for ever; and of his kingdom there shall be no end.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Then said Mary unto the angel, How shall this be, seeing I know not a man?</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And the angel answered and said unto her, The Holy Ghost shall come upon thee, and the power of the Highest shall overshadow thee: therefore also that holy thing which shall be born of thee shall be called the Son of God.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And, behold, thy cousin Elisabeth, she hath also conceived a son in her old age: and this is the sixth month with her, who was called barren.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">For with God nothing shall be impossible.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And Mary said, Behold the handmaid of the Lord; be it unto me according to thy word. And the angel departed from her.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And Mary arose in those days, and went into the hill country with haste, into a city of Juda;</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And entered into the house of Zacharias, and saluted Elisabeth.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And it came to pass, that, when Elisabeth heard the salutation of Mary, the babe leaped in her womb; and Elisabeth was filled with the Holy Ghost:</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And she spake out with a loud voice, and said, Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;art&lt;/span&gt; thou among women, and blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the fruit of thy womb.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And whence &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; this to me, that the mother of my Lord should come to me?</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">For, lo, as soon as the voice of thy salutation sounded in mine ears, the babe leaped in my womb for joy.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; she that believed: for there shall be a performance of those things which were told her from the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And Mary said, My soul doth magnify the Lord,</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">And my spirit hath rejoiced in God my Saviour.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">For he hath regarded the low estate of his handmaiden: for, behold, from henceforth all generations shall call me blessed.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">For he that is mighty hath done to me great things; and holy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; his name.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">And his mercy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; on them that fear him from generation to generation.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">He hath shewed strength with his arm; he hath scattered the proud in the imagination of their hearts.</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">He hath put down the mighty from &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; seats, and exalted them of low degree.</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">He hath filled the hungry with good things; and the rich he hath sent empty away.</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">He hath holpen his servant Israel, in remembrance of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; mercy;</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">As he spake to our fathers, to Abraham, and to his seed for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">And Mary abode with her about three months, and returned to her own house.</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">Now Elisabeth's full time came that she should be delivered; and she brought forth a son.</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">And her neighbours and her cousins heard how the Lord had shewed great mercy upon her; and they rejoiced with her.</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">And it came to pass, that on the eighth day they came to circumcise the child; and they called him Zacharias, after the name of his father.</verse>
      <verse number="60" id="v60">And his mother answered and said, Not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;; but he shall be called John.</verse>
      <verse number="61" id="v61">And they said unto her, There is none of thy kindred that is called by this name.</verse>
      <verse number="62" id="v62">And they made signs to his father, how he would have him called.</verse>
      <verse number="63" id="v63">And he asked for a writing table, and wrote, saying, His name is John. And they marvelled all.</verse>
      <verse number="64" id="v64">And his mouth was opened immediately, and his tongue &lt;span class='extra'&gt;loosed&lt;/span&gt;, and he spake, and praised God.</verse>
      <verse number="65" id="v65">And fear came on all that dwelt round about them: and all these sayings were noised abroad throughout all the hill country of Judaea.</verse>
      <verse number="66" id="v66">And all they that heard &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; laid &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; up in their hearts, saying, What manner of child shall this be! And the hand of the Lord was with him.</verse>
      <verse number="67" id="v67">And his father Zacharias was filled with the Holy Ghost, and prophesied, saying,</verse>
      <verse number="68" id="v68">Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the Lord God of Israel; for he hath visited and redeemed his people,</verse>
      <verse number="69" id="v69">And hath raised up an horn of salvation for us in the house of his servant David;</verse>
      <verse number="70" id="v70">As he spake by the mouth of his holy prophets, which have been since the world began:</verse>
      <verse number="71" id="v71">That we should be saved from our enemies, and from the hand of all that hate us;</verse>
      <verse number="72" id="v72">To perform the mercy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;promised&lt;/span&gt; to our fathers, and to remember his holy covenant;</verse>
      <verse number="73" id="v73">The oath which he sware to our father Abraham,</verse>
      <verse number="74" id="v74">That he would grant unto us, that we being delivered out of the hand of our enemies might serve him without fear,</verse>
      <verse number="75" id="v75">In holiness and righteousness before him, all the days of our life.</verse>
      <verse number="76" id="v76">And thou, child, shalt be called the prophet of the Highest: for thou shalt go before the face of the Lord to prepare his ways;</verse>
      <verse number="77" id="v77">To give knowledge of salvation unto his people by the remission of their sins,</verse>
      <verse number="78" id="v78">Through the tender mercy of our God; whereby the dayspring from on high hath visited us,</verse>
      <verse number="79" id="v79">To give light to them that sit in darkness and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; the shadow of death, to guide our feet into the way of peace.</verse>
      <verse number="80" id="v80">And the child grew, and waxed strong in spirit, and was in the deserts till the day of his shewing unto Israel.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>