<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="24" verseCount="53" nextChapter="john_1.html" nextTitle="John 1" prevChapter="luke_23.html" prevTitle="Luke 23" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now upon the first &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the week, very early in the morning, they came unto the sepulchre, bringing the spices which they had prepared, and certain &lt;i&gt;others&lt;/i&gt; with them.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And they found the stone rolled away from the sepulchre.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they entered in, and found not the body of the Lord Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And it came to pass, as they were much perplexed thereabout, behold, two men stood by them in shining garments:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And as they were afraid, and bowed down &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; faces to the earth, they said unto them, Why seek ye the living among the dead?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He is not here, but is risen: remember how he spake unto you when he was yet in Galilee,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Saying, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;The Son of man must be delivered into the hands of sinful men, and be crucified, and the third day rise again.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And they remembered his words,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And returned from the sepulchre, and told all these things unto the eleven, and to all the rest.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">It was Mary Magdalene, and Joanna, and Mary &lt;i&gt;the mother&lt;/i&gt; of James, and other &lt;i&gt;women that were&lt;/i&gt; with them, which told these things unto the apostles.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And their words seemed to them as idle tales, and they believed them not.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Then arose Peter, and ran unto the sepulchre; and stooping down, he beheld the linen clothes laid by themselves, and departed, wondering in himself at that which was come to pass.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And, behold, two of them went that same day to a village called Emmaus, which was from Jerusalem &lt;i&gt;about&lt;/i&gt; threescore furlongs.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And they talked together of all these things which had happened.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And it came to pass, that, while they communed &lt;i&gt;together&lt;/i&gt; and reasoned, Jesus himself drew near, and went with them.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But their eyes were holden that they should not know him.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;What manner of communications &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; these that ye have one to another, as ye walk, and are sad?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the one of them, whose name was Cleopas, answering said unto him, Art thou only a stranger in Jerusalem, and hast not known the things which are come to pass there in these days?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;What things?&lt;/span&gt; And they said unto him, Concerning Jesus of Nazareth, which was a prophet mighty in deed and word before God and all the people:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And how the chief priests and our rulers delivered him to be condemned to death, and have crucified him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But we trusted that it had been he which should have redeemed Israel: and beside all this, to day is the third day since these things were done.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Yea, and certain women also of our company made us astonished, which were early at the sepulchre;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And when they found not his body, they came, saying, that they had also seen a vision of angels, which said that he was alive.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And certain of them which were with us went to the sepulchre, and found &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; even so as the women had said: but him they saw not.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then he said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;O fools, and slow of heart to believe all that the prophets have spoken:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Ought not Christ to have suffered these things, and to enter into his glory?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And beginning at Moses and all the prophets, he expounded unto them in all the scriptures the things concerning himself.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And they drew nigh unto the village, whither they went: and he made as though he would have gone further.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">But they constrained him, saying, Abide with us: for it is toward evening, and the day is far spent. And he went in to tarry with them.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And it came to pass, as he sat at meat with them, he took bread, and blessed &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and brake, and gave to them.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And their eyes were opened, and they knew him; and he vanished out of their sight.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And they said one to another, Did not our heart burn within us, while he talked with us by the way, and while he opened to us the scriptures?</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And they rose up the same hour, and returned to Jerusalem, and found the eleven gathered together, and them that were with them,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Saying, The Lord is risen indeed, and hath appeared to Simon.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And they told what things &lt;i&gt;were done&lt;/i&gt; in the way, and how he was known of them in breaking of bread.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">And as they thus spake, Jesus himself stood in the midst of them, and saith unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Peace &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; unto you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">But they were terrified and affrighted, and supposed that they had seen a spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And he said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Why are ye troubled? and why do thoughts arise in your hearts?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Behold my hands and my feet, that it is I myself: handle me, and see; for a spirit hath not flesh and bones, as ye see me have.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And when he had thus spoken, he shewed them &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; hands and &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; feet.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And while they yet believed not for joy, and wondered, he said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Have ye here any meat?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And they gave him a piece of a broiled fish, and of an honeycomb.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">And he took &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and did eat before them.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And he said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;These &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the words which I spake unto you, while I was yet with you, that all things must be fulfilled, which were written in the law of Moses, and &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the prophets, and &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the psalms, concerning me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">Then opened he their understanding, that they might understand the scriptures,</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">And said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Thus it is written, and thus it behoved Christ to suffer, and to rise from the dead the third day:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And that repentance and remission of sins should be preached in his name among all nations, beginning at Jerusalem.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And ye are witnesses of these things.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49" newPara="true">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And, behold, I send the promise of my Father upon you: but tarry ye in the city of Jerusalem, until ye be endued with power from on high.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50" newPara="true">And he led them out as far as to Bethany, and he lifted up his hands, and blessed them.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">And it came to pass, while he blessed them, he was parted from them, and carried up into heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">And they worshipped him, and returned to Jerusalem with great joy:</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">And were continually in the temple, praising and blessing God. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>