<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="42" name="Luke" bookPage="luke.html" title="Luke" chapterCount="24" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="john_1.html" nextTitle="John" prevBook="mark_1.html" prevTitle="Mark">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="50" nextChapter="luke_8.html" nextTitle="Luke 8" prevChapter="luke_6.html" prevTitle="Luke 6" chapterPage="luke_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now when he had ended all his sayings in the audience of the people, he entered into Capernaum.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And a certain centurion's servant, who was dear unto him, was sick, and ready to die.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And when he heard of Jesus, he sent unto him the elders of the Jews, beseeching him that he would come and heal his servant.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And when they came to Jesus, they besought him instantly, saying, That he was worthy for whom he should do this:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For he loveth our nation, and he hath built us a synagogue.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Then Jesus went with them. And when he was now not far from the house, the centurion sent friends to him, saying unto him, Lord, trouble not thyself: for I am not worthy that thou shouldest enter under my roof:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Wherefore neither thought I myself worthy to come unto thee: but say in a word, and my servant shall be healed.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For I also am a man set under authority, having under me soldiers, and I say unto one, Go, and he goeth; and to another, Come, and he cometh; and to my servant, Do this, and he doeth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">When Jesus heard these things, he marvelled at him, and turned him about, and said unto the people that followed him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;I say unto you, I have not found so great faith, no, not in Israel.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they that were sent, returning to the house, found the servant whole that had been sick.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">And it came to pass the day after, that he went into a city called Nain; and many of his disciples went with him, and much people.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Now when he came nigh to the gate of the city, behold, there was a dead man carried out, the only son of his mother, and she was a widow: and much people of the city was with her.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And when the Lord saw her, he had compassion on her, and said unto her, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Weep not.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he came and touched the bier: and they that bare &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; stood still. And he said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Young man, I say unto thee, Arise.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he that was dead sat up, and began to speak. And he delivered him to his mother.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And there came a fear on all: and they glorified God, saying, That a great prophet is risen up among us; and, That God hath visited his people.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And this rumour of him went forth throughout all Judaea, and throughout all the region round about.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the disciples of John shewed him of all these things.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And John calling &lt;i&gt;unto him&lt;/i&gt; two of his disciples sent &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; to Jesus, saying, Art thou he that should come? or look we for another?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">When the men were come unto him, they said, John Baptist hath sent us unto thee, saying, Art thou he that should come? or look we for another?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And in that same hour he cured many of &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; infirmities and plagues, and of evil spirits; and unto many &lt;i&gt;that were&lt;/i&gt; blind he gave sight.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then Jesus answering said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Go your way, and tell John what things ye have seen and heard; how that the blind see, the lame walk, the lepers are cleansed, the deaf hear, the dead are raised, to the poor the gospel is preached.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And blessed is &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, whosoever shall not be offended in me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And when the messengers of John were departed, he began to speak unto the people concerning John, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;What went ye out into the wilderness for to see? A reed shaken with the wind?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But what went ye out for to see? A man clothed in soft raiment? Behold, they which are gorgeously apparelled, and live delicately, are in kings' courts.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But what went ye out for to see? A prophet? Yea, I say unto you, and much more than a prophet.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;This is &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, of whom it is written, Behold, I send my messenger before thy face, which shall prepare thy way before thee.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I say unto you, Among those that are born of women there is not a greater prophet than John the Baptist: but he that is least in the kingdom of God is greater than he.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And all the people that heard &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, and the publicans, justified God, being baptized with the baptism of John.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">But the Pharisees and lawyers rejected the counsel of God against themselves, being not baptized of him.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And the Lord said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Whereunto then shall I liken the men of this generation? and to what are they like?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;They are like unto children sitting in the marketplace, and calling one to another, and saying, We have piped unto you, and ye have not danced; we have mourned to you, and ye have not wept.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For John the Baptist came neither eating bread nor drinking wine; and ye say, He hath a devil.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;The Son of man is come eating and drinking; and ye say, Behold a gluttonous man, and a winebibber, a friend of publicans and sinners!&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But wisdom is justified of all her children.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">And one of the Pharisees desired him that he would eat with him. And he went into the Pharisee's house, and sat down to meat.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And, behold, a woman in the city, which was a sinner, when she knew that &lt;i&gt;Jesus&lt;/i&gt; sat at meat in the Pharisee's house, brought an alabaster box of ointment,</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And stood at his feet behind &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; weeping, and began to wash his feet with tears, and did wipe &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; with the hairs of her head, and kissed his feet, and anointed &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; with the ointment.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Now when the Pharisee which had bidden him saw &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, he spake within himself, saying, This man, if he were a prophet, would have known who and what manner of woman &lt;i&gt;this is&lt;/i&gt; that toucheth him: for she is a sinner.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And Jesus answering said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Simon, I have somewhat to say unto thee.&lt;/span&gt; And he saith, Master, say on.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;There was a certain creditor which had two debtors: the one owed five hundred pence, and the other fifty.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And when they had nothing to pay, he frankly forgave them both. Tell me therefore, which of them will love him most?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">Simon answered and said, I suppose that &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, to whom he forgave most. And he said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thou hast rightly judged.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And he turned to the woman, and said unto Simon, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Seest thou this woman? I entered into thine house, thou gavest me no water for my feet: but she hath washed my feet with tears, and wiped &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; with the hairs of her head.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thou gavest me no kiss: but this woman since the time I came in hath not ceased to kiss my feet.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;My head with oil thou didst not anoint: but this woman hath anointed my feet with ointment.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Wherefore I say unto thee, Her sins, which are many, are forgiven; for she loved much: but to whom little is forgiven, &lt;i&gt;the same&lt;/i&gt; loveth little.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">And he said unto her, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thy sins are forgiven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And they that sat at meat with him began to say within themselves, Who is this that forgiveth sins also?</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">And he said to the woman, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thy faith hath saved thee; go in peace.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>