<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="59" nextChapter="john_9.html" nextTitle="John 9" prevChapter="john_7.html" prevTitle="John 7" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Jesus went unto the mount of Olives.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And early in the morning he came again into the temple, and all the people came unto him; and he sat down, and taught them.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the scribes and Pharisees brought unto him a woman taken in adultery; and when they had set her in the midst,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">They say unto him, Master, this woman was taken in adultery, in the very act.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Now Moses in the law commanded us, that such should be stoned: but what sayest thou?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">This they said, tempting him, that they might have to accuse him. But Jesus stooped down, and with &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; finger wrote on the ground, &lt;i&gt;as though he heard them not&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">So when they continued asking him, he lifted up himself, and said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;He that is without sin among you, let him first cast a stone at her.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And again he stooped down, and wrote on the ground.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And they which heard &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, being convicted by &lt;i&gt;their own&lt;/i&gt; conscience, went out one by one, beginning at the eldest, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; unto the last: and Jesus was left alone, and the woman standing in the midst.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">When Jesus had lifted up himself, and saw none but the woman, he said unto her, &lt;woc&gt;Woman, where are those thine accusers? hath no man condemned thee?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">She said, No man, Lord. And Jesus said unto her, &lt;woc&gt;Neither do I condemn thee: go, and sin no more.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">Then spake Jesus again unto them, saying, &lt;woc&gt;I am the light of the world: he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The Pharisees therefore said unto him, Thou bearest record of thyself; thy record is not true.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Jesus answered and said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Though I bear record of myself, &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; my record is true: for I know whence I came, and whither I go; but ye cannot tell whence I come, and whither I go.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;woc&gt;Ye judge after the flesh; I judge no man.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;woc&gt;And yet if I judge, my judgment is true: for I am not alone, but I and the Father that sent me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;woc&gt;It is also written in your law, that the testimony of two men is true.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;woc&gt;I am one that bear witness of myself, and the Father that sent me beareth witness of me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Then said they unto him, Where is thy Father? Jesus answered, &lt;woc&gt;Ye neither know me, nor my Father: if ye had known me, ye should have known my Father also.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">These words spake Jesus in the treasury, as he taught in the temple: and no man laid hands on him; for his hour was not yet come.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then said Jesus again unto them, &lt;woc&gt;I go my way, and ye shall seek me, and shall die in your sins: whither I go, ye cannot come.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then said the Jews, Will he kill himself? because he saith, Whither I go, ye cannot come.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And he said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Ye are from beneath; I am from above: ye are of this world; I am not of this world.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;woc&gt;I said therefore unto you, that ye shall die in your sins: for if ye believe not that I am &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, ye shall die in your sins.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then said they unto him, Who art thou? And Jesus saith unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Even &lt;i&gt;the same&lt;/i&gt; that I said unto you from the beginning.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;woc&gt;I have many things to say and to judge of you: but he that sent me is true; and I speak to the world those things which I have heard of him.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">They understood not that he spake to them of the Father.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Then said Jesus unto them, &lt;woc&gt;When ye have lifted up the Son of man, then shall ye know that I am &lt;i&gt;he&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I do nothing of myself; but as my Father hath taught me, I speak these things.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;woc&gt;And he that sent me is with me: the Father hath not left me alone; for I do always those things that please him.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">As he spake these words, many believed on him.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Then said Jesus to those Jews which believed on him, &lt;woc&gt;If ye continue in my word, &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; are ye my disciples indeed;&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;woc&gt;And ye shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33" newPara="true">They answered him, We be Abraham's seed, and were never in bondage to any man: how sayest thou, &lt;woc&gt;Ye shall be made free?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Jesus answered them, &lt;woc&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, Whosoever committeth sin is the servant of sin.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;woc&gt;And the servant abideth not in the house for ever: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; the Son abideth ever.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">&lt;woc&gt;If the Son therefore shall make you free, ye shall be free indeed.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">&lt;woc&gt;I know that ye are Abraham's seed; but ye seek to kill me, because my word hath no place in you.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;woc&gt;I speak that which I have seen with my Father: and ye do that which ye have seen with your father.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">They answered and said unto him, Abraham is our father. Jesus saith unto them, &lt;woc&gt;If ye were Abraham's children, ye would do the works of Abraham.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">&lt;woc&gt;But now ye seek to kill me, a man that hath told you the truth, which I have heard of God: this did not Abraham.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">&lt;woc&gt;Ye do the deeds of your father.&lt;/woc&gt; Then said they to him, We be not born of fornication; we have one Father, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; God.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Jesus said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;If God were your Father, ye would love me: for I proceeded forth and came from God; neither came I of myself, but he sent me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">&lt;woc&gt;Why do ye not understand my speech? &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; because ye cannot hear my word.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">&lt;woc&gt;Ye are of &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; father the devil, and the lusts of your father ye will do. He was a murderer from the beginning, and abode not in the truth, because there is no truth in him. When he speaketh a lie, he speaketh of his own: for he is a liar, and the father of it.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">&lt;woc&gt;And because I tell &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; the truth, ye believe me not.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">&lt;woc&gt;Which of you convinceth me of sin? And if I say the truth, why do ye not believe me?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">&lt;woc&gt;He that is of God heareth God's words: ye therefore hear &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; not, because ye are not of God.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">Then answered the Jews, and said unto him, Say we not well that thou art a Samaritan, and hast a devil?</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">Jesus answered, &lt;woc&gt;I have not a devil; but I honour my Father, and ye do dishonour me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">&lt;woc&gt;And I seek not mine own glory: there is one that seeketh and judgeth.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">&lt;woc&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, If a man keep my saying, he shall never see death.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">Then said the Jews unto him, Now we know that thou hast a devil. Abraham is dead, and the prophets; and thou sayest, &lt;woc&gt;If a man keep my saying, he shall never taste of death.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">Art thou greater than our father Abraham, which is dead? and the prophets are dead: whom makest thou thyself?</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">Jesus answered, &lt;woc&gt;If I honour myself, my honour is nothing: it is my Father that honoureth me; of whom ye say, that he is your God:&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">&lt;woc&gt;Yet ye have not known him; but I know him: and if I should say, I know him not, I shall be a liar like unto you: but I know him, and keep his saying.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">&lt;woc&gt;Your father Abraham rejoiced to see my day: and he saw &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and was glad.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">Then said the Jews unto him, Thou art not yet fifty years old, and hast thou seen Abraham?</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">Jesus said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, Before Abraham was, I am.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="59" id="v59">Then took they up stones to cast at him: but Jesus hid himself, and went out of the temple, going through the midst of them, and so passed by.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>