<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="20" verseCount="31" nextChapter="john_21.html" nextTitle="John 21" prevChapter="john_19.html" prevTitle="John 19" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the week cometh Mary Magdalene early, when it was yet dark, unto the sepulchre, and seeth the stone taken away from the sepulchre.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Then she runneth, and cometh to Simon Peter, and to the other disciple, whom Jesus loved, and saith unto them, They have taken away the Lord out of the sepulchre, and we know not where they have laid him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Peter therefore went forth, and that other disciple, and came to the sepulchre.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">So they ran both together: and the other disciple did outrun Peter, and came first to the sepulchre.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he stooping down, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and looking in&lt;/span&gt;, saw the linen clothes lying; yet went he not in.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Then cometh Simon Peter following him, and went into the sepulchre, and seeth the linen clothes lie,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the napkin, that was about his head, not lying with the linen clothes, but wrapped together in a place by itself.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then went in also that other disciple, which came first to the sepulchre, and he saw, and believed.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For as yet they knew not the scripture, that he must rise again from the dead.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then the disciples went away again unto their own home.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11" newPara="true">But Mary stood without at the sepulchre weeping: and as she wept, she stooped down, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and looked&lt;/span&gt; into the sepulchre,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And seeth two angels in white sitting, the one at the head, and the other at the feet, where the body of Jesus had lain.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And they say unto her, Woman, why weepest thou? She saith unto them, Because they have taken away my Lord, and I know not where they have laid him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And when she had thus said, she turned herself back, and saw Jesus standing, and knew not that it was Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Jesus saith unto her, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Woman, why weepest thou? whom seekest thou?&lt;/span&gt; She, supposing him to be the gardener, saith unto him, Sir, if thou have borne him hence, tell me where thou hast laid him, and I will take him away.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Jesus saith unto her, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Mary.&lt;/span&gt; She turned herself, and saith unto him, Rabboni; which is to say, Master.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Jesus saith unto her, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Touch me not; for I am not yet ascended to my Father: but go to my brethren, and say unto them, I ascend unto my Father, and your Father; and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; my God, and your God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Mary Magdalene came and told the disciples that she had seen the Lord, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; he had spoken these things unto her.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">Then the same day at evening, being the first &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; of the week, when the doors were shut where the disciples were assembled for fear of the Jews, came Jesus and stood in the midst, and saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Peace &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; unto you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And when he had so said, he shewed unto them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; hands and his side. Then were the disciples glad, when they saw the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then said Jesus to them again, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Peace &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; unto you: as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; Father hath sent me, even so send I you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And when he had said this, he breathed on &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, and saith unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Receive ye the Holy Ghost:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Whose soever sins ye remit, they are remitted unto them; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; whose soever &lt;span class="extra"&gt;sins&lt;/span&gt; ye retain, they are retained.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">But Thomas, one of the twelve, called Didymus, was not with them when Jesus came.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">The other disciples therefore said unto him, We have seen the Lord. But he said unto them, Except I shall see in his hands the print of the nails, and put my finger into the print of the nails, and thrust my hand into his side, I will not believe.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26" newPara="true">And after eight days again his disciples were within, and Thomas with them: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; came Jesus, the doors being shut, and stood in the midst, and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Peace &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; unto you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Then saith he to Thomas, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Reach hither thy finger, and behold my hands; and reach hither thy hand, and thrust &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; into my side: and be not faithless, but believing.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And Thomas answered and said unto him, My Lord and my God.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Jesus saith unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thomas, because thou hast seen me, thou hast believed: blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they that have not seen, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yet&lt;/span&gt; have believed.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30" newPara="true">And many other signs truly did Jesus in the presence of his disciples, which are not written in this book:</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">But these are written, that ye might believe that Jesus is the Christ, the Son of God; and that believing ye might have life through his name.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>