<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="38" nextChapter="john_14.html" nextTitle="John 14" prevChapter="john_12.html" prevTitle="John 12" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now before the feast of the passover, when Jesus knew that his hour was come that he should depart out of this world unto the Father, having loved his own which were in the world, he loved them unto the end.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And supper being ended, the devil having now put into the heart of Judas Iscariot, Simon's &lt;span class="extra"&gt;son&lt;/span&gt;, to betray him;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Jesus knowing that the Father had given all things into his hands, and that he was come from God, and went to God;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He riseth from supper, and laid aside his garments; and took a towel, and girded himself.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">After that he poureth water into a bason, and began to wash the disciples' feet, and to wipe &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; with the towel wherewith he was girded.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Then cometh he to Simon Peter: and Peter saith unto him, Lord, dost thou wash my feet?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Jesus answered and said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;What I do thou knowest not now; but thou shalt know hereafter.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Peter saith unto him, Thou shalt never wash my feet. Jesus answered him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;If I wash thee not, thou hast no part with me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Simon Peter saith unto him, Lord, not my feet only, but also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; hands and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; head.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Jesus saith to him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;He that is washed needeth not save to wash &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; feet, but is clean every whit: and ye are clean, but not all.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For he knew who should betray him; therefore said he, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye are not all clean.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">So after he had washed their feet, and had taken his garments, and was set down again, he said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Know ye what I have done to you?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye call me Master and Lord: and ye say well; for &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; I am.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;If I then, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; Lord and Master, have washed your feet; ye also ought to wash one another's feet.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I have given you an example, that ye should do as I have done to you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, The servant is not greater than his lord; neither he that is sent greater than he that sent him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;If ye know these things, happy are ye if ye do them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I speak not of you all: I know whom I have chosen: but that the scripture may be fulfilled, He that eateth bread with me hath lifted up his heel against me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Now I tell you before it come, that, when it is come to pass, ye may believe that I am &lt;span class="extra"&gt;he&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, He that receiveth whomsoever I send receiveth me; and he that receiveth me receiveth him that sent me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">When Jesus had thus said, he was troubled in spirit, and testified, and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, that one of you shall betray me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Then the disciples looked one on another, doubting of whom he spake.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Now there was leaning on Jesus' bosom one of his disciples, whom Jesus loved.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Simon Peter therefore beckoned to him, that he should ask who it should be of whom he spake.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">He then lying on Jesus' breast saith unto him, Lord, who is it?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Jesus answered, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;He it is, to whom I shall give a sop, when I have dipped &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; And when he had dipped the sop, he gave &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to Judas Iscariot, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the son&lt;/span&gt; of Simon.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And after the sop Satan entered into him. Then said Jesus unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;That thou doest, do quickly.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Now no man at the table knew for what intent he spake this unto him.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For some &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of them&lt;/span&gt; thought, because Judas had the bag, that Jesus had said unto him, Buy &lt;span class="extra"&gt;those things&lt;/span&gt; that we have need of against the feast; or, that he should give something to the poor.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">He then having received the sop went immediately out: and it was night.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">Therefore, when he was gone out, Jesus said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Now is the Son of man glorified, and God is glorified in him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;If God be glorified in him, God shall also glorify him in himself, and shall straightway glorify him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Little children, yet a little while I am with you. Ye shall seek me: and as I said unto the Jews, Whither I go, ye cannot come; so now I say to you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;A new commandment I give unto you, That ye love one another; as I have loved you, that ye also love one another.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;By this shall all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one to another.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">Simon Peter said unto him, Lord, whither goest thou? Jesus answered him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Whither I go, thou canst not follow me now; but thou shalt follow me afterwards.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Peter said unto him, Lord, why cannot I follow thee now? I will lay down my life for thy sake.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">Jesus answered him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Wilt thou lay down thy life for my sake? Verily, verily, I say unto thee, The cock shall not crow, till thou hast denied me thrice.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>