<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="19" verseCount="42" nextChapter="john_20.html" nextTitle="John 20" prevChapter="john_18.html" prevTitle="John 18" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then Pilate therefore took Jesus, and scourged &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the soldiers platted a crown of thorns, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on his head, and they put on him a purple robe,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And said, Hail, King of the Jews! and they smote him with their hands.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Pilate therefore went forth again, and saith unto them, Behold, I bring him forth to you, that ye may know that I find no fault in him.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then came Jesus forth, wearing the crown of thorns, and the purple robe. And &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Pilate&lt;/span&gt; saith unto them, Behold the man!</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">When the chief priests therefore and officers saw him, they cried out, saying, Crucify &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, crucify &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;. Pilate saith unto them, Take ye him, and crucify &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;: for I find no fault in him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The Jews answered him, We have a law, and by our law he ought to die, because he made himself the Son of God.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8" newPara="true">When Pilate therefore heard that saying, he was the more afraid;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And went again into the judgment hall, and saith unto Jesus, Whence art thou? But Jesus gave him no answer.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Then saith Pilate unto him, Speakest thou not unto me? knowest thou not that I have power to crucify thee, and have power to release thee?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Jesus answered, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thou couldest have no power &lt;span class="extra"&gt;at all&lt;/span&gt; against me, except it were given thee from above: therefore he that delivered me unto thee hath the greater sin.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And from thenceforth Pilate sought to release him: but the Jews cried out, saying, If thou let this man go, thou art not Caesar's friend: whosoever maketh himself a king speaketh against Caesar.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">When Pilate therefore heard that saying, he brought Jesus forth, and sat down in the judgment seat in a place that is called the Pavement, but in the Hebrew, Gabbatha.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And it was the preparation of the passover, and about the sixth hour: and he saith unto the Jews, Behold your King!</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But they cried out, Away with &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, away with &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, crucify him. Pilate saith unto them, Shall I crucify your King? The chief priests answered, We have no king but Caesar.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Then delivered he him therefore unto them to be crucified. And they took Jesus, and led &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; away.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he bearing his cross went forth into a place called &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the place&lt;/span&gt; of a skull, which is called in the Hebrew Golgotha:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Where they crucified him, and two other with him, on either side one, and Jesus in the midst.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">And Pilate wrote a title, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; on the cross. And the writing was, JESUS OF NAZARETH THE KING OF THE JEWS.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">This title then read many of the Jews: for the place where Jesus was crucified was nigh to the city: and it was written in Hebrew, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Greek, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; Latin.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then said the chief priests of the Jews to Pilate, Write not, The King of the Jews; but that he said, I am King of the Jews.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Pilate answered, What I have written I have written.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">Then the soldiers, when they had crucified Jesus, took his garments, and made four parts, to every soldier a part; and also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; coat: now the coat was without seam, woven from the top throughout.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">They said therefore among themselves, Let us not rend it, but cast lots for it, whose it shall be: that the scripture might be fulfilled, which saith, They parted my raiment among them, and for my vesture they did cast lots. These things therefore the soldiers did.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">Now there stood by the cross of Jesus his mother, and his mother's sister, Mary the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;wife&lt;/span&gt; of Cleophas, and Mary Magdalene.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">When Jesus therefore saw his mother, and the disciple standing by, whom he loved, he saith unto his mother, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Woman, behold thy son!&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Then saith he to the disciple, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold thy mother!&lt;/span&gt; And from that hour that disciple took her unto his own &lt;span class="extra"&gt;home&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28" newPara="true">After this, Jesus knowing that all things were now accomplished, that the scripture might be fulfilled, saith, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;I thirst.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Now there was set a vessel full of vinegar: and they filled a spunge with vinegar, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon hyssop, and put &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; to his mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">When Jesus therefore had received the vinegar, he said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;It is finished:&lt;/span&gt; and he bowed his head, and gave up the ghost.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The Jews therefore, because it was the preparation, that the bodies should not remain upon the cross on the sabbath day, (for that sabbath day was an high day,) besought Pilate that their legs might be broken, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; they might be taken away.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Then came the soldiers, and brake the legs of the first, and of the other which was crucified with him.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">But when they came to Jesus, and saw that he was dead already, they brake not his legs:</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">But one of the soldiers with a spear pierced his side, and forthwith came there out blood and water.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And he that saw &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; bare record, and his record is true: and he knoweth that he saith true, that ye might believe.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">For these things were done, that the scripture should be fulfilled, A bone of him shall not be broken.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And again another scripture saith, They shall look on him whom they pierced.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38" newPara="true">And after this Joseph of Arimathaea, being a disciple of Jesus, but secretly for fear of the Jews, besought Pilate that he might take away the body of Jesus: and Pilate gave &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; leave. He came therefore, and took the body of Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And there came also Nicodemus, which at the first came to Jesus by night, and brought a mixture of myrrh and aloes, about an hundred pound &lt;span class="extra"&gt;weight&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Then took they the body of Jesus, and wound it in linen clothes with the spices, as the manner of the Jews is to bury.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Now in the place where he was crucified there was a garden; and in the garden a new sepulchre, wherein was never man yet laid.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">There laid they Jesus therefore because of the Jews' preparation &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt;; for the sepulchre was nigh at hand.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>