<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="27" nextChapter="john_16.html" nextTitle="John 16" prevChapter="john_14.html" prevTitle="John 14" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;woc&gt;I am the true vine, and my Father is the husbandman.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;woc&gt;Every branch in me that beareth not fruit he taketh away: and every &lt;i&gt;branch&lt;/i&gt; that beareth fruit, he purgeth it, that it may bring forth more fruit.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;woc&gt;Now ye are clean through the word which I have spoken unto you.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;woc&gt;Abide in me, and I in you. As the branch cannot bear fruit of itself, except it abide in the vine; no more can ye, except ye abide in me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;woc&gt;I am the vine, ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the branches: He that abideth in me, and I in him, the same bringeth forth much fruit: for without me ye can do nothing.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;woc&gt;If a man abide not in me, he is cast forth as a branch, and is withered; and men gather them, and cast &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; into the fire, and they are burned.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;woc&gt;If ye abide in me, and my words abide in you, ye shall ask what ye will, and it shall be done unto you.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;woc&gt;Herein is my Father glorified, that ye bear much fruit; so shall ye be my disciples.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;woc&gt;As the Father hath loved me, so have I loved you: continue ye in my love.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;woc&gt;If ye keep my commandments, ye shall abide in my love; even as I have kept my Father's commandments, and abide in his love.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;woc&gt;These things have I spoken unto you, that my joy might remain in you, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; your joy might be full.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;woc&gt;This is my commandment, That ye love one another, as I have loved you.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;woc&gt;Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay down his life for his friends.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;woc&gt;Ye are my friends, if ye do whatsoever I command you.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;woc&gt;Henceforth I call you not servants; for the servant knoweth not what his lord doeth: but I have called you friends; for all things that I have heard of my Father I have made known unto you.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;woc&gt;Ye have not chosen me, but I have chosen you, and ordained you, that ye should go and bring forth fruit, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; your fruit should remain: that whatsoever ye shall ask of the Father in my name, he may give it you.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;woc&gt;These things I command you, that ye love one another.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;woc&gt;If the world hate you, ye know that it hated me before &lt;i&gt;it hated&lt;/i&gt; you.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;woc&gt;If ye were of the world, the world would love his own: but because ye are not of the world, but I have chosen you out of the world, therefore the world hateth you.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;woc&gt;Remember the word that I said unto you, The servant is not greater than his lord. If they have persecuted me, they will also persecute you; if they have kept my saying, they will keep yours also.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;woc&gt;But all these things will they do unto you for my name's sake, because they know not him that sent me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;woc&gt;If I had not come and spoken unto them, they had not had sin: but now they have no cloke for their sin.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;woc&gt;He that hateth me hateth my Father also.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;woc&gt;If I had not done among them the works which none other man did, they had not had sin: but now have they both seen and hated both me and my Father.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;woc&gt;But &lt;i&gt;this cometh to pass&lt;/i&gt;, that the word might be fulfilled that is written in their law, They hated me without a cause.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;woc&gt;But when the Comforter is come, whom I will send unto you from the Father, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the Spirit of truth, which proceedeth from the Father, he shall testify of me:&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;woc&gt;And ye also shall bear witness, because ye have been with me from the beginning.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>