<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="25" nextChapter="john_3.html" nextTitle="John 3" prevChapter="john_1.html" prevTitle="John 1" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And the third day there was a marriage in Cana of Galilee; and the mother of Jesus was there:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And both Jesus was called, and his disciples, to the marriage.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And when they wanted wine, the mother of Jesus saith unto him, They have no wine.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Jesus saith unto her, &lt;woc&gt;Woman, what have I to do with thee? mine hour is not yet come.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">His mother saith unto the servants, Whatsoever he saith unto you, do &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And there were set there six waterpots of stone, after the manner of the purifying of the Jews, containing two or three firkins apiece.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Jesus saith unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Fill the waterpots with water.&lt;/woc&gt; And they filled them up to the brim.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And he saith unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Draw out now, and bear unto the governor of the feast.&lt;/woc&gt; And they bare &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">When the ruler of the feast had tasted the water that was made wine, and knew not whence it was: (but the servants which drew the water knew;) the governor of the feast called the bridegroom,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And saith unto him, Every man at the beginning doth set forth good wine; and when men have well drunk, then that which is worse: &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; thou hast kept the good wine until now.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">This beginning of miracles did Jesus in Cana of Galilee, and manifested forth his glory; and his disciples believed on him.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">After this he went down to Capernaum, he, and his mother, and his brethren, and his disciples: and they continued there not many days.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">And the Jews' passover was at hand, and Jesus went up to Jerusalem,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And found in the temple those that sold oxen and sheep and doves, and the changers of money sitting:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And when he had made a scourge of small cords, he drove them all out of the temple, and the sheep, and the oxen; and poured out the changers' money, and overthrew the tables;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And said unto them that sold doves, &lt;woc&gt;Take these things hence; make not my Father's house an house of merchandise.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And his disciples remembered that it was written, The zeal of thine house hath eaten me up.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">Then answered the Jews and said unto him, What sign shewest thou unto us, seeing that thou doest these things?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Jesus answered and said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Destroy this temple, and in three days I will raise it up.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Then said the Jews, Forty and six years was this temple in building, and wilt thou rear it up in three days?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But he spake of the temple of his body.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">When therefore he was risen from the dead, his disciples remembered that he had said this unto them; and they believed the scripture, and the word which Jesus had said.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">Now when he was in Jerusalem at the passover, in the feast &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt;, many believed in his name, when they saw the miracles which he did.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But Jesus did not commit himself unto them, because he knew all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And needed not that any should testify of man: for he knew what was in man.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>