<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="42" nextChapter="john_11.html" nextTitle="John 11" prevChapter="john_9.html" prevTitle="John 9" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, He that entereth not by the door into the sheepfold, but climbeth up some other way, the same is a thief and a robber.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;But he that entereth in by the door is the shepherd of the sheep.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;To him the porter openeth; and the sheep hear his voice: and he calleth his own sheep by name, and leadeth them out.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And when he putteth forth his own sheep, he goeth before them, and the sheep follow him: for they know his voice.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And a stranger will they not follow, but will flee from him: for they know not the voice of strangers.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">This parable spake Jesus unto them: but they understood not what things they were which he spake unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Then said Jesus unto them again, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, I am the door of the sheep.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;All that ever came before me are thieves and robbers: but the sheep did not hear them.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;I am the door: by me if any man enter in, he shall be saved, and shall go in and out, and find pasture.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;The thief cometh not, but for to steal, and to kill, and to destroy: I am come that they might have life, and that they might have &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; more abundantly.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;I am the good shepherd: the good shepherd giveth his life for the sheep.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;But he that is an hireling, and not the shepherd, whose own the sheep are not, seeth the wolf coming, and leaveth the sheep, and fleeth: and the wolf catcheth them, and scattereth the sheep.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;The hireling fleeth, because he is an hireling, and careth not for the sheep.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;I am the good shepherd, and know my &lt;span class='extra'&gt;sheep&lt;/span&gt;, and am known of mine.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;As the Father knoweth me, even so know I the Father: and I lay down my life for the sheep.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And other sheep I have, which are not of this fold: them also I must bring, and they shall hear my voice; and there shall be one fold, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; one shepherd.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Therefore doth my Father love me, because I lay down my life, that I might take it again.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;No man taketh it from me, but I lay it down of myself. I have power to lay it down, and I have power to take it again. This commandment have I received of my Father.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">There was a division therefore again among the Jews for these sayings.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And many of them said, He hath a devil, and is mad; why hear ye him?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Others said, These are not the words of him that hath a devil. Can a devil open the eyes of the blind?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">And it was at Jerusalem the feast of the dedication, and it was winter.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And Jesus walked in the temple in Solomon's porch.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Then came the Jews round about him, and said unto him, How long dost thou make us to doubt? If thou be the Christ, tell us plainly.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Jesus answered them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;I told you, and ye believed not: the works that I do in my Father's name, they bear witness of me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;But ye believe not, because ye are not of my sheep, as I said unto you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;And I give unto them eternal life; and they shall never perish, neither shall any &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; pluck them out of my hand.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;My Father, which gave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; me, is greater than all; and no &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; is able to pluck &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; out of my Father's hand.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;I and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; Father are one.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Then the Jews took up stones again to stone him.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Jesus answered them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Many good works have I shewed you from my Father; for which of those works do ye stone me?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">The Jews answered him, saying, For a good work we stone thee not; but for blasphemy; and because that thou, being a man, makest thyself God.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Jesus answered them, &lt;span class='woc'&gt;Is it not written in your law, I said, Ye are gods?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;If he called them gods, unto whom the word of God came, and the scripture cannot be broken;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;Say ye of him, whom the Father hath sanctified, and sent into the world, Thou blasphemest; because I said, I am the Son of God?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;If I do not the works of my Father, believe me not.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;span class='woc'&gt;But if I do, though ye believe not me, believe the works: that ye may know, and believe, that the Father &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in me, and I in him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Therefore they sought again to take him: but he escaped out of their hand,</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And went away again beyond Jordan into the place where John at first baptized; and there he abode.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And many resorted unto him, and said, John did no miracle: but all things that John spake of this man were true.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And many believed on him there.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>