<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="21" verseCount="25" nextChapter="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts 1" prevChapter="john_20.html" prevTitle="John 20" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">After these things Jesus shewed himself again to the disciples at the sea of Tiberias; and on this wise shewed he &lt;i&gt;himself&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">There were together Simon Peter, and Thomas called Didymus, and Nathanael of Cana in Galilee, and the &lt;i&gt;sons&lt;/i&gt; of Zebedee, and two other of his disciples.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Simon Peter saith unto them, I go a fishing. They say unto him, We also go with thee. They went forth, and entered into a ship immediately; and that night they caught nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But when the morning was now come, Jesus stood on the shore: but the disciples knew not that it was Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then Jesus saith unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Children, have ye any meat?&lt;/woc&gt; They answered him, No.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he said unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Cast the net on the right side of the ship, and ye shall find.&lt;/woc&gt; They cast therefore, and now they were not able to draw it for the multitude of fishes.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Therefore that disciple whom Jesus loved saith unto Peter, It is the Lord. Now when Simon Peter heard that it was the Lord, he girt &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; fisher's coat &lt;i&gt;unto him&lt;/i&gt;, (for he was naked,) and did cast himself into the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And the other disciples came in a little ship; (for they were not far from land, but as it were two hundred cubits,) dragging the net with fishes.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">As soon then as they were come to land, they saw a fire of coals there, and fish laid thereon, and bread.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Jesus saith unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Bring of the fish which ye have now caught.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Simon Peter went up, and drew the net to land full of great fishes, an hundred and fifty and three: and for all there were so many, yet was not the net broken.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Jesus saith unto them, &lt;woc&gt;Come &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; dine.&lt;/woc&gt; And none of the disciples durst ask him, Who art thou? knowing that it was the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Jesus then cometh, and taketh bread, and giveth them, and fish likewise.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">This is now the third time that Jesus shewed himself to his disciples, after that he was risen from the dead.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15" newPara="true">So when they had dined, Jesus saith to Simon Peter, &lt;woc&gt;Simon, &lt;i&gt;son&lt;/i&gt; of Jonas, lovest thou me more than these?&lt;/woc&gt; He saith unto him, Yea, Lord; thou knowest that I love thee. He saith unto him, &lt;woc&gt;Feed my lambs.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">He saith to him again the second time, &lt;woc&gt;Simon, &lt;i&gt;son&lt;/i&gt; of Jonas, lovest thou me?&lt;/woc&gt; He saith unto him, Yea, Lord; thou knowest that I love thee. He saith unto him, &lt;woc&gt;Feed my sheep.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">He saith unto him the third time, &lt;woc&gt;Simon, &lt;i&gt;son&lt;/i&gt; of Jonas, lovest thou me?&lt;/woc&gt; Peter was grieved because he said unto him the third time, &lt;woc&gt;Lovest thou me?&lt;/woc&gt; And he said unto him, Lord, thou knowest all things; thou knowest that I love thee. Jesus saith unto him, &lt;woc&gt;Feed my sheep.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;woc&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto thee, When thou wast young, thou girdedst thyself, and walkedst whither thou wouldest: but when thou shalt be old, thou shalt stretch forth thy hands, and another shall gird thee, and carry &lt;i&gt;thee&lt;/i&gt; whither thou wouldest not.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">This spake he, signifying by what death he should glorify God. And when he had spoken this, he saith unto him, &lt;woc&gt;Follow me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Then Peter, turning about, seeth the disciple whom Jesus loved following; which also leaned on his breast at supper, and said, Lord, which is he that betrayeth thee?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Peter seeing him saith to Jesus, Lord, and what &lt;i&gt;shall&lt;/i&gt; this man &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Jesus saith unto him, &lt;woc&gt;If I will that he tarry till I come, what &lt;i&gt;is that&lt;/i&gt; to thee? follow thou me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Then went this saying abroad among the brethren, that that disciple should not die: yet Jesus said not unto him, He shall not die; but, &lt;woc&gt;If I will that he tarry till I come, what &lt;i&gt;is that&lt;/i&gt; to thee?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">This is the disciple which testifieth of these things, and wrote these things: and we know that his testimony is true.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And there are also many other things which Jesus did, the which, if they should be written every one, I suppose that even the world itself could not contain the books that should be written. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>