<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="47" nextChapter="john_6.html" nextTitle="John 6" prevChapter="john_4.html" prevTitle="John 4" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">After this there was a feast of the Jews; and Jesus went up to Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Now there is at Jerusalem by the sheep &lt;i&gt;market&lt;/i&gt; a pool, which is called in the Hebrew tongue Bethesda, having five porches.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">In these lay a great multitude of impotent folk, of blind, halt, withered, waiting for the moving of the water.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For an angel went down at a certain season into the pool, and troubled the water: whosoever then first after the troubling of the water stepped in was made whole of whatsoever disease he had.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And a certain man was there, which had an infirmity thirty and eight years.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">When Jesus saw him lie, and knew that he had been now a long time &lt;i&gt;in that case&lt;/i&gt;, he saith unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Wilt thou be made whole?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">The impotent man answered him, Sir, I have no man, when the water is troubled, to put me into the pool: but while I am coming, another steppeth down before me.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Jesus saith unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Rise, take up thy bed, and walk.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And immediately the man was made whole, and took up his bed, and walked: and on the same day was the sabbath.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">The Jews therefore said unto him that was cured, It is the sabbath day: it is not lawful for thee to carry &lt;i&gt;thy&lt;/i&gt; bed.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He answered them, He that made me whole, the same said unto me, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take up thy bed, and walk.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Then asked they him, What man is that which said unto thee, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Take up thy bed, and walk?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he that was healed wist not who it was: for Jesus had conveyed himself away, a multitude being in &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; place.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Afterward Jesus findeth him in the temple, and said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold, thou art made whole: sin no more, lest a worse thing come unto thee.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">The man departed, and told the Jews that it was Jesus, which had made him whole.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And therefore did the Jews persecute Jesus, and sought to slay him, because he had done these things on the sabbath day.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17" newPara="true">But Jesus answered them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;My Father worketh hitherto, and I work.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Therefore the Jews sought the more to kill him, because he not only had broken the sabbath, but said also that God was his Father, making himself equal with God.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Then answered Jesus and said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, The Son can do nothing of himself, but what he seeth the Father do: for what things soever he doeth, these also doeth the Son likewise.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For the Father loveth the Son, and sheweth him all things that himself doeth: and he will shew him greater works than these, that ye may marvel.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For as the Father raiseth up the dead, and quickeneth &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;; even so the Son quickeneth whom he will.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For the Father judgeth no man, but hath committed all judgment unto the Son:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;That all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; should honour the Son, even as they honour the Father. He that honoureth not the Son honoureth not the Father which hath sent him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, He that heareth my word, and believeth on him that sent me, hath everlasting life, and shall not come into condemnation; but is passed from death unto life.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, The hour is coming, and now is, when the dead shall hear the voice of the Son of God: and they that hear shall live.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For as the Father hath life in himself; so hath he given to the Son to have life in himself;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And hath given him authority to execute judgment also, because he is the Son of man.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Marvel not at this: for the hour is coming, in the which all that are in the graves shall hear his voice,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And shall come forth; they that have done good, unto the resurrection of life; and they that have done evil, unto the resurrection of damnation.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I can of mine own self do nothing: as I hear, I judge: and my judgment is just; because I seek not mine own will, but the will of the Father which hath sent me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;If I bear witness of myself, my witness is not true.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;There is another that beareth witness of me; and I know that the witness which he witnesseth of me is true.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye sent unto John, and he bare witness unto the truth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But I receive not testimony from man: but these things I say, that ye might be saved.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;He was a burning and a shining light: and ye were willing for a season to rejoice in his light.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But I have greater witness than &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; of John: for the works which the Father hath given me to finish, the same works that I do, bear witness of me, that the Father hath sent me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And the Father himself, which hath sent me, hath borne witness of me. Ye have neither heard his voice at any time, nor seen his shape.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And ye have not his word abiding in you: for whom he hath sent, him ye believe not.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Search the scriptures; for in them ye think ye have eternal life: and they are they which testify of me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And ye will not come to me, that ye might have life.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I receive not honour from men.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But I know you, that ye have not the love of God in you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I am come in my Father's name, and ye receive me not: if another shall come in his own name, him ye will receive.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;How can ye believe, which receive honour one of another, and seek not the honour that &lt;i&gt;cometh&lt;/i&gt; from God only?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Do not think that I will accuse you to the Father: there is &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; that accuseth you, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; Moses, in whom ye trust.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For had ye believed Moses, ye would have believed me: for he wrote of me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But if ye believe not his writings, how shall ye believe my words?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>