<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="33" nextChapter="john_17.html" nextTitle="John 17" prevChapter="john_15.html" prevTitle="John 15" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;These things have I spoken unto you, that ye should not be offended.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;They shall put you out of the synagogues: yea, the time cometh, that whosoever killeth you will think that he doeth God service.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And these things will they do unto you, because they have not known the Father, nor me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But these things have I told you, that when the time shall come, ye may remember that I told you of them. And these things I said not unto you at the beginning, because I was with you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But now I go my way to him that sent me; and none of you asketh me, Whither goest thou?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But because I have said these things unto you, sorrow hath filled your heart.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Nevertheless I tell you the truth; It is expedient for you that I go away: for if I go not away, the Comforter will not come unto you; but if I depart, I will send him unto you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And when he is come, he will reprove the world of sin, and of righteousness, and of judgment:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Of sin, because they believe not on me;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Of righteousness, because I go to my Father, and ye see me no more;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Of judgment, because the prince of this world is judged.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;I have yet many things to say unto you, but ye cannot bear them now.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Howbeit when he, the Spirit of truth, is come, he will guide you into all truth: for he shall not speak of himself; but whatsoever he shall hear, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; shall he speak: and he will shew you things to come.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;He shall glorify me: for he shall receive of mine, and shall shew &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; unto you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;All things that the Father hath are mine: therefore said I, that he shall take of mine, and shall shew &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; unto you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;A little while, and ye shall not see me: and again, a little while, and ye shall see me, because I go to the Father.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then said &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; of his disciples among themselves, What is this that he saith unto us, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;A little while, and ye shall not see me: and again, a little while, and ye shall see me: and, Because I go to the Father?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">They said therefore, What is this that he saith, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;A little while?&lt;/span&gt; we cannot tell what he saith.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Now Jesus knew that they were desirous to ask him, and said unto them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Do ye enquire among yourselves of that I said, A little while, and ye shall not see me: and again, a little while, and ye shall see me?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto you, That ye shall weep and lament, but the world shall rejoice: and ye shall be sorrowful, but your sorrow shall be turned into joy.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;A woman when she is in travail hath sorrow, because her hour is come: but as soon as she is delivered of the child, she remembereth no more the anguish, for joy that a man is born into the world.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And ye now therefore have sorrow: but I will see you again, and your heart shall rejoice, and your joy no man taketh from you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And in that day ye shall ask me nothing. Verily, verily, I say unto you, Whatsoever ye shall ask the Father in my name, he will give &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; you.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Hitherto have ye asked nothing in my name: ask, and ye shall receive, that your joy may be full.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;These things have I spoken unto you in proverbs: but the time cometh, when I shall no more speak unto you in proverbs, but I shall shew you plainly of the Father.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;At that day ye shall ask in my name: and I say not unto you, that I will pray the Father for you:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;For the Father himself loveth you, because ye have loved me, and have believed that I came out from God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;I came forth from the Father, and am come into the world: again, I leave the world, and go to the Father.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">His disciples said unto him, Lo, now speakest thou plainly, and speakest no proverb.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Now are we sure that thou knowest all things, and needest not that any man should ask thee: by this we believe that thou camest forth from God.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Jesus answered them, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Do ye now believe?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Behold, the hour cometh, yea, is now come, that ye shall be scattered, every man to his own, and shall leave me alone: and yet I am not alone, because the Father is with me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;These things I have spoken unto you, that in me ye might have peace. In the world ye shall have tribulation: but be of good cheer; I have overcome the world.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>