<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="36" nextChapter="john_4.html" nextTitle="John 4" prevChapter="john_2.html" prevTitle="John 2" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">There was a man of the Pharisees, named Nicodemus, a ruler of the Jews:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The same came to Jesus by night, and said unto him, Rabbi, we know that thou art a teacher come from God: for no man can do these miracles that thou doest, except God be with him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Jesus answered and said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto thee, Except a man be born again, he cannot see the kingdom of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Nicodemus saith unto him, How can a man be born when he is old? can he enter the second time into his mother's womb, and be born?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Jesus answered, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto thee, Except a man be born of water and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; the Spirit, he cannot enter into the kingdom of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;That which is born of the flesh is flesh; and that which is born of the Spirit is spirit.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Marvel not that I said unto thee, Ye must be born again.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;The wind bloweth where it listeth, and thou hearest the sound thereof, but canst not tell whence it cometh, and whither it goeth: so is every one that is born of the Spirit.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Nicodemus answered and said unto him, How can these things be?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Jesus answered and said unto him, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Art thou a master of Israel, and knowest not these things?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Verily, verily, I say unto thee, We speak that we do know, and testify that we have seen; and ye receive not our witness.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;If I have told you earthly things, and ye believe not, how shall ye believe, if I tell you &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; heavenly things?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And no man hath ascended up to heaven, but he that came down from heaven, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; the Son of man which is in heaven.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And as Moses lifted up the serpent in the wilderness, even so must the Son of man be lifted up:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;That whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have eternal life.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For God so loved the world, that he gave his only begotten Son, that whosoever believeth in him should not perish, but have everlasting life.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For God sent not his Son into the world to condemn the world; but that the world through him might be saved.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;He that believeth on him is not condemned: but he that believeth not is condemned already, because he hath not believed in the name of the only begotten Son of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And this is the condemnation, that light is come into the world, and men loved darkness rather than light, because their deeds were evil.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For every one that doeth evil hateth the light, neither cometh to the light, lest his deeds should be reproved.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But he that doeth truth cometh to the light, that his deeds may be made manifest, that they are wrought in God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22" newPara="true">After these things came Jesus and his disciples into the land of Judaea; and there he tarried with them, and baptized.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And John also was baptizing in Aenon near to Salim, because there was much water there: and they came, and were baptized.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For John was not yet cast into prison.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25" newPara="true">Then there arose a question between &lt;span class="extra"&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; of John's disciples and the Jews about purifying.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And they came unto John, and said unto him, Rabbi, he that was with thee beyond Jordan, to whom thou barest witness, behold, the same baptizeth, and all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; come to him.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">John answered and said, A man can receive nothing, except it be given him from heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Ye yourselves bear me witness, that I said, I am not the Christ, but that I am sent before him.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">He that hath the bride is the bridegroom: but the friend of the bridegroom, which standeth and heareth him, rejoiceth greatly because of the bridegroom's voice: this my joy therefore is fulfilled.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">He must increase, but I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;must&lt;/span&gt; decrease.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">He that cometh from above is above all: he that is of the earth is earthly, and speaketh of the earth: he that cometh from heaven is above all.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And what he hath seen and heard, that he testifieth; and no man receiveth his testimony.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">He that hath received his testimony hath set to his seal that God is true.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">For he whom God hath sent speaketh the words of God: for God giveth not the Spirit by measure &lt;span class="extra"&gt;unto him&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">The Father loveth the Son, and hath given all things into his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">He that believeth on the Son hath everlasting life: and he that believeth not the Son shall not see life; but the wrath of God abideth on him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>