<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="43" name="John" bookPage="john.html" title="John" chapterCount="21" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="acts_1.html" nextTitle="Acts" prevBook="luke_1.html" prevTitle="Luke">
    <chapter number="7" verseCount="53" nextChapter="john_8.html" nextTitle="John 8" prevChapter="john_6.html" prevTitle="John 6" chapterPage="john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">After these things Jesus walked in Galilee: for he would not walk in Jewry, because the Jews sought to kill him.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Now the Jews' feast of tabernacles was at hand.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">His brethren therefore said unto him, Depart hence, and go into Judaea, that thy disciples also may see the works that thou doest.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; no man &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; doeth any thing in secret, and he himself seeketh to be known openly. If thou do these things, shew thyself to the world.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For neither did his brethren believe in him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Then Jesus said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;My time is not yet come: but your time is alway ready.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;The world cannot hate you; but me it hateth, because I testify of it, that the works thereof are evil.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Go ye up unto this feast: I go not up yet unto this feast; for my time is not yet full come.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">When he had said these words unto them, he abode &lt;i&gt;still&lt;/i&gt; in Galilee.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10" newPara="true">But when his brethren were gone up, then went he also up unto the feast, not openly, but as it were in secret.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Then the Jews sought him at the feast, and said, Where is he?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And there was much murmuring among the people concerning him: for some said, He is a good man: others said, Nay; but he deceiveth the people.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Howbeit no man spake openly of him for fear of the Jews.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14" newPara="true">Now about the midst of the feast Jesus went up into the temple, and taught.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the Jews marvelled, saying, How knoweth this man letters, having never learned?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Jesus answered them, and said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;My doctrine is not mine, but his that sent me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;If any man will do his will, he shall know of the doctrine, whether it be of God, or &lt;i&gt;whether&lt;/i&gt; I speak of myself.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;He that speaketh of himself seeketh his own glory: but he that seeketh his glory that sent him, the same is true, and no unrighteousness is in him.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Did not Moses give you the law, and &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; none of you keepeth the law? Why go ye about to kill me?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The people answered and said, Thou hast a devil: who goeth about to kill thee?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Jesus answered and said unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;I have done one work, and ye all marvel.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Moses therefore gave unto you circumcision; (not because it is of Moses, but of the fathers;) and ye on the sabbath day circumcise a man.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;If a man on the sabbath day receive circumcision, that the law of Moses should not be broken; are ye angry at me, because I have made a man every whit whole on the sabbath day?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Judge not according to the appearance, but judge righteous judgment.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Then said some of them of Jerusalem, Is not this he, whom they seek to kill?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">But, lo, he speaketh boldly, and they say nothing unto him. Do the rulers know indeed that this is the very Christ?</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Howbeit we know this man whence he is: but when Christ cometh, no man knoweth whence he is.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Then cried Jesus in the temple as he taught, saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye both know me, and ye know whence I am: and I am not come of myself, but he that sent me is true, whom ye know not.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But I know him: for I am from him, and he hath sent me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Then they sought to take him: but no man laid hands on him, because his hour was not yet come.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And many of the people believed on him, and said, When Christ cometh, will he do more miracles than these which this &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt; hath done?</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32" newPara="true">The Pharisees heard that the people murmured such things concerning him; and the Pharisees and the chief priests sent officers to take him.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Then said Jesus unto them, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Yet a little while am I with you, and &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; I go unto him that sent me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye shall seek me, and shall not find &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt;: and where I am, &lt;i&gt;thither&lt;/i&gt; ye cannot come.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Then said the Jews among themselves, Whither will he go, that we shall not find him? will he go unto the dispersed among the Gentiles, and teach the Gentiles?</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">What &lt;i&gt;manner of&lt;/i&gt; saying is this that he said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Ye shall seek me, and shall not find &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt;: and where I am, &lt;i&gt;thither&lt;/i&gt; ye cannot come?&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">In the last day, that great &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the feast, Jesus stood and cried, saying, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;If any man thirst, let him come unto me, and drink.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;He that believeth on me, as the scripture hath said, out of his belly shall flow rivers of living water.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">(But this spake he of the Spirit, which they that believe on him should receive: for the Holy Ghost was not yet &lt;i&gt;given&lt;/i&gt;; because that Jesus was not yet glorified.)</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40" newPara="true">Many of the people therefore, when they heard this saying, said, Of a truth this is the Prophet.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Others said, This is the Christ. But some said, Shall Christ come out of Galilee?</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">Hath not the scripture said, That Christ cometh of the seed of David, and out of the town of Bethlehem, where David was?</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">So there was a division among the people because of him.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And some of them would have taken him; but no man laid hands on him.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45" newPara="true">Then came the officers to the chief priests and Pharisees; and they said unto them, Why have ye not brought him?</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">The officers answered, Never man spake like this man.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">Then answered them the Pharisees, Are ye also deceived?</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">Have any of the rulers or of the Pharisees believed on him?</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">But this people who knoweth not the law are cursed.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">Nicodemus saith unto them, (he that came to Jesus by night, being one of them,)</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">Doth our law judge &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; man, before it hear him, and know what he doeth?</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">They answered and said unto him, Art thou also of Galilee? Search, and look: for out of Galilee ariseth no prophet.</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">And every man went unto his own house.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>