<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="44" name="Acts" bookPage="acts.html" title="Acts" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="romans_1.html" nextTitle="Romans" prevBook="john_1.html" prevTitle="John">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="30" nextChapter="acts_23.html" nextTitle="Acts 23" prevChapter="acts_21.html" prevTitle="Acts 21" chapterPage="acts_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Men, brethren, and fathers, hear ye my defence &lt;i&gt;which I make&lt;/i&gt; now unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">(And when they heard that he spake in the Hebrew tongue to them, they kept the more silence: and he saith,)</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I am verily a man &lt;i&gt;which am&lt;/i&gt; a Jew, born in Tarsus, &lt;i&gt;a city&lt;/i&gt; in Cilicia, yet brought up in this city at the feet of Gamaliel, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; taught according to the perfect manner of the law of the fathers, and was zealous toward God, as ye all are this day.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And I persecuted this way unto the death, binding and delivering into prisons both men and women.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">As also the high priest doth bear me witness, and all the estate of the elders: from whom also I received letters unto the brethren, and went to Damascus, to bring them which were there bound unto Jerusalem, for to be punished.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And it came to pass, that, as I made my journey, and was come nigh unto Damascus about noon, suddenly there shone from heaven a great light round about me.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And I fell unto the ground, and heard a voice saying unto me, &lt;woc&gt;Saul, Saul, why persecutest thou me?&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I answered, Who art thou, Lord? And he said unto me, &lt;woc&gt;I am Jesus of Nazareth, whom thou persecutest.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And they that were with me saw indeed the light, and were afraid; but they heard not the voice of him that spake to me.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And I said, What shall I do, Lord? And the Lord said unto me, &lt;woc&gt;Arise, and go into Damascus; and there it shall be told thee of all things which are appointed for thee to do.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And when I could not see for the glory of that light, being led by the hand of them that were with me, I came into Damascus.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And one Ananias, a devout man according to the law, having a good report of all the Jews which dwelt &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Came unto me, and stood, and said unto me, Brother Saul, receive thy sight. And the same hour I looked up upon him.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And he said, The God of our fathers hath chosen thee, that thou shouldest know his will, and see that Just One, and shouldest hear the voice of his mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For thou shalt be his witness unto all men of what thou hast seen and heard.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And now why tarriest thou? arise, and be baptized, and wash away thy sins, calling on the name of the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And it came to pass, that, when I was come again to Jerusalem, even while I prayed in the temple, I was in a trance;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And saw him saying unto me, &lt;woc&gt;Make haste, and get thee quickly out of Jerusalem: for they will not receive thy testimony concerning me.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And I said, Lord, they know that I imprisoned and beat in every synagogue them that believed on thee:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And when the blood of thy martyr Stephen was shed, I also was standing by, and consenting unto his death, and kept the raiment of them that slew him.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And he said unto me, &lt;woc&gt;Depart: for I will send thee far hence unto the Gentiles.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And they gave him audience unto this word, and &lt;i&gt;then&lt;/i&gt; lifted up their voices, and said, Away with such a &lt;i&gt;fellow&lt;/i&gt; from the earth: for it is not fit that he should live.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And as they cried out, and cast off &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; clothes, and threw dust into the air,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">The chief captain commanded him to be brought into the castle, and bade that he should be examined by scourging; that he might know wherefore they cried so against him.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And as they bound him with thongs, Paul said unto the centurion that stood by, Is it lawful for you to scourge a man that is a Roman, and uncondemned?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">When the centurion heard &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt;, he went and told the chief captain, saying, Take heed what thou doest: for this man is a Roman.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Then the chief captain came, and said unto him, Tell me, art thou a Roman? He said, Yea.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And the chief captain answered, With a great sum obtained I this freedom. And Paul said, But I was &lt;i&gt;free&lt;/i&gt; born.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Then straightway they departed from him which should have examined him: and the chief captain also was afraid, after he knew that he was a Roman, and because he had bound him.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">On the morrow, because he would have known the certainty wherefore he was accused of the Jews, he loosed him from &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; bands, and commanded the chief priests and all their council to appear, and brought Paul down, and set him before them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>