<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="44" name="Acts" bookPage="acts.html" title="Acts" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="romans_1.html" nextTitle="Romans" prevBook="john_1.html" prevTitle="John">
    <chapter number="18" verseCount="28" nextChapter="acts_19.html" nextTitle="Acts 19" prevChapter="acts_17.html" prevTitle="Acts 17" chapterPage="acts_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">After these things Paul departed from Athens, and came to Corinth;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And found a certain Jew named Aquila, born in Pontus, lately come from Italy, with his wife Priscilla; (because that Claudius had commanded all Jews to depart from Rome:) and came unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And because he was of the same craft, he abode with them, and wrought: for by their occupation they were tentmakers.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And he reasoned in the synagogue every sabbath, and persuaded the Jews and the Greeks.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And when Silas and Timotheus were come from Macedonia, Paul was pressed in the spirit, and testified to the Jews &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; Jesus &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And when they opposed themselves, and blasphemed, he shook &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; raiment, and said unto them, Your blood &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; upon your own heads; I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; clean: from henceforth I will go unto the Gentiles.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7" newPara="true">And he departed thence, and entered into a certain &lt;i&gt;man's&lt;/i&gt; house, named Justus, &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; that worshipped God, whose house joined hard to the synagogue.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And Crispus, the chief ruler of the synagogue, believed on the Lord with all his house; and many of the Corinthians hearing believed, and were baptized.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then spake the Lord to Paul in the night by a vision, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Be not afraid, but speak, and hold not thy peace:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;For I am with thee, and no man shall set on thee to hurt thee: for I have much people in this city.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And he continued &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt; a year and six months, teaching the word of God among them.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12" newPara="true">And when Gallio was the deputy of Achaia, the Jews made insurrection with one accord against Paul, and brought him to the judgment seat,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Saying, This &lt;i&gt;fellow&lt;/i&gt; persuadeth men to worship God contrary to the law.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And when Paul was now about to open &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; mouth, Gallio said unto the Jews, If it were a matter of wrong or wicked lewdness, O &lt;i&gt;ye&lt;/i&gt; Jews, reason would that I should bear with you:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But if it be a question of words and names, and &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; your law, look ye &lt;i&gt;to it&lt;/i&gt;; for I will be no judge of such &lt;i&gt;matters&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he drave them from the judgment seat.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then all the Greeks took Sosthenes, the chief ruler of the synagogue, and beat &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; before the judgment seat. And Gallio cared for none of those things.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18" newPara="true">And Paul &lt;i&gt;after this&lt;/i&gt; tarried &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt; yet a good while, and then took his leave of the brethren, and sailed thence into Syria, and with him Priscilla and Aquila; having shorn &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; head in Cenchrea: for he had a vow.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And he came to Ephesus, and left them there: but he himself entered into the synagogue, and reasoned with the Jews.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">When they desired &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; to tarry longer time with them, he consented not;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But bade them farewell, saying, I must by all means keep this feast that cometh in Jerusalem: but I will return again unto you, if God will. And he sailed from Ephesus.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And when he had landed at Caesarea, and gone up, and saluted the church, he went down to Antioch.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And after he had spent some time &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt;, he departed, and went over &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; the country of Galatia and Phrygia in order, strengthening all the disciples.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24" newPara="true">And a certain Jew named Apollos, born at Alexandria, an eloquent man, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; mighty in the scriptures, came to Ephesus.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">This man was instructed in the way of the Lord; and being fervent in the spirit, he spake and taught diligently the things of the Lord, knowing only the baptism of John.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And he began to speak boldly in the synagogue: whom when Aquila and Priscilla had heard, they took him unto &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;, and expounded unto him the way of God more perfectly.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And when he was disposed to pass into Achaia, the brethren wrote, exhorting the disciples to receive him: who, when he was come, helped them much which had believed through grace:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">For he mightily convinced the Jews, &lt;i&gt;and that&lt;/i&gt; publickly, shewing by the scriptures that Jesus was Christ.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>