<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="44" name="Acts" bookPage="acts.html" title="Acts" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="romans_1.html" nextTitle="Romans" prevBook="john_1.html" prevTitle="John">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="48" nextChapter="acts_11.html" nextTitle="Acts 11" prevChapter="acts_9.html" prevTitle="Acts 9" chapterPage="acts_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">There was a certain man in Caesarea called Cornelius, a centurion of the band called the Italian &lt;i&gt;band&lt;/i&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt; devout &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;, and one that feared God with all his house, which gave much alms to the people, and prayed to God alway.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">He saw in a vision evidently about the ninth hour of the day an angel of God coming in to him, and saying unto him, Cornelius.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And when he looked on him, he was afraid, and said, What is it, Lord? And he said unto him, Thy prayers and thine alms are come up for a memorial before God.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And now send men to Joppa, and call for &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; Simon, whose surname is Peter:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">He lodgeth with one Simon a tanner, whose house is by the sea side: he shall tell thee what thou oughtest to do.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when the angel which spake unto Cornelius was departed, he called two of his household servants, and a devout soldier of them that waited on him continually;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And when he had declared all &lt;i&gt;these&lt;/i&gt; things unto them, he sent them to Joppa.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9" newPara="true">On the morrow, as they went on their journey, and drew nigh unto the city, Peter went up upon the housetop to pray about the sixth hour:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he became very hungry, and would have eaten: but while they made ready, he fell into a trance,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And saw heaven opened, and a certain vessel descending unto him, as it had been a great sheet knit at the four corners, and let down to the earth:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Wherein were all manner of fourfooted beasts of the earth, and wild beasts, and creeping things, and fowls of the air.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And there came a voice to him, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Rise, Peter; kill, and eat.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But Peter said, Not so, Lord; for I have never eaten any thing that is common or unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the voice &lt;i&gt;spake&lt;/i&gt; unto him again the second time, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;What God hath cleansed, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; call not thou common.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">This was done thrice: and the vessel was received up again into heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Now while Peter doubted in himself what this vision which he had seen should mean, behold, the men which were sent from Cornelius had made enquiry for Simon's house, and stood before the gate,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And called, and asked whether Simon, which was surnamed Peter, were lodged there.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19" newPara="true">While Peter thought on the vision, the Spirit said unto him, Behold, three men seek thee.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Arise therefore, and get thee down, and go with them, doubting nothing: for I have sent them.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Then Peter went down to the men which were sent unto him from Cornelius; and said, Behold, I am he whom ye seek: what &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the cause wherefore ye are come?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And they said, Cornelius the centurion, a just man, and one that feareth God, and of good report among all the nation of the Jews, was warned from God by an holy angel to send for thee into his house, and to hear words of thee.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Then called he them in, and lodged &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;. And on the morrow Peter went away with them, and certain brethren from Joppa accompanied him.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the morrow after they entered into Caesarea. And Cornelius waited for them, and had called together his kinsmen and near friends.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And as Peter was coming in, Cornelius met him, and fell down at his feet, and worshipped &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">But Peter took him up, saying, Stand up; I myself also am a man.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And as he talked with him, he went in, and found many that were come together.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And he said unto them, Ye know how that it is an unlawful thing for a man that is a Jew to keep company, or come unto one of another nation; but God hath shewed me that I should not call any man common or unclean.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Therefore came I &lt;i&gt;unto you&lt;/i&gt; without gainsaying, as soon as I was sent for: I ask therefore for what intent ye have sent for me?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Cornelius said, Four days ago I was fasting until this hour; and at the ninth hour I prayed in my house, and, behold, a man stood before me in bright clothing,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And said, Cornelius, thy prayer is heard, and thine alms are had in remembrance in the sight of God.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Send therefore to Joppa, and call hither Simon, whose surname is Peter; he is lodged in the house of &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; Simon a tanner by the sea side: who, when he cometh, shall speak unto thee.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Immediately therefore I sent to thee; and thou hast well done that thou art come. Now therefore are we all here present before God, to hear all things that are commanded thee of God.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34" newPara="true">Then Peter opened &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; mouth, and said, Of a truth I perceive that God is no respecter of persons:</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">But in every nation he that feareth him, and worketh righteousness, is accepted with him.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">The word which &lt;i&gt;God&lt;/i&gt; sent unto the children of Israel, preaching peace by Jesus Christ: (he is Lord of all:)</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">That word, &lt;i&gt;I say&lt;/i&gt;, ye know, which was published throughout all Judaea, and began from Galilee, after the baptism which John preached;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">How God anointed Jesus of Nazareth with the Holy Ghost and with power: who went about doing good, and healing all that were oppressed of the devil; for God was with him.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And we are witnesses of all things which he did both in the land of the Jews, and in Jerusalem; whom they slew and hanged on a tree:</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Him God raised up the third day, and shewed him openly;</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">Not to all the people, but unto witnesses chosen before of God, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; to us, who did eat and drink with him after he rose from the dead.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And he commanded us to preach unto the people, and to testify that it is he which was ordained of God &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; the Judge of quick and dead.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">To him give all the prophets witness, that through his name whosoever believeth in him shall receive remission of sins.</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44" newPara="true">While Peter yet spake these words, the Holy Ghost fell on all them which heard the word.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And they of the circumcision which believed were astonished, as many as came with Peter, because that on the Gentiles also was poured out the gift of the Holy Ghost.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">For they heard them speak with tongues, and magnify God. Then answered Peter,</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">Can any man forbid water, that these should not be baptized, which have received the Holy Ghost as well as we?</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">And he commanded them to be baptized in the name of the Lord. Then prayed they him to tarry certain days.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>