<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="44" name="Acts" bookPage="acts.html" title="Acts" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="romans_1.html" nextTitle="Romans" prevBook="john_1.html" prevTitle="John">
    <chapter number="26" verseCount="32" nextChapter="acts_27.html" nextTitle="Acts 27" prevChapter="acts_25.html" prevTitle="Acts 25" chapterPage="acts_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Then Agrippa said unto Paul, Thou art permitted to speak for thyself. Then Paul stretched forth the hand, and answered for himself:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I think myself happy, king Agrippa, because I shall answer for myself this day before thee touching all the things whereof I am accused of the Jews:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Especially &lt;span class="extra"&gt;because I know&lt;/span&gt; thee to be expert in all customs and questions which are among the Jews: wherefore I beseech thee to hear me patiently.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">My manner of life from my youth, which was at the first among mine own nation at Jerusalem, know all the Jews;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Which knew me from the beginning, if they would testify, that after the most straitest sect of our religion I lived a Pharisee.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And now I stand and am judged for the hope of the promise made of God unto our fathers:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Unto which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;promise&lt;/span&gt; our twelve tribes, instantly serving &lt;span class="extra"&gt;God&lt;/span&gt; day and night, hope to come. For which hope's sake, king Agrippa, I am accused of the Jews.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Why should it be thought a thing incredible with you, that God should raise the dead?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I verily thought with myself, that I ought to do many things contrary to the name of Jesus of Nazareth.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Which thing I also did in Jerusalem: and many of the saints did I shut up in prison, having received authority from the chief priests; and when they were put to death, I gave my voice against &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I punished them oft in every synagogue, and compelled &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; to blaspheme; and being exceedingly mad against them, I persecuted &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; even unto strange cities.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Whereupon as I went to Damascus with authority and commission from the chief priests,</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">At midday, O king, I saw in the way a light from heaven, above the brightness of the sun, shining round about me and them which journeyed with me.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And when we were all fallen to the earth, I heard a voice speaking unto me, and saying in the Hebrew tongue, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Saul, Saul, why persecutest thou me? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; hard for thee to kick against the pricks.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And I said, Who art thou, Lord? And he said, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;I am Jesus whom thou persecutest.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;But rise, and stand upon thy feet: for I have appeared unto thee for this purpose, to make thee a minister and a witness both of these things which thou hast seen, and of those things in the which I will appear unto thee;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Delivering thee from the people, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the Gentiles, unto whom now I send thee,&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;To open their eyes, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to turn &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; from darkness to light, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the power of Satan unto God, that they may receive forgiveness of sins, and inheritance among them which are sanctified by faith that is in me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Whereupon, O king Agrippa, I was not disobedient unto the heavenly vision:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But shewed first unto them of Damascus, and at Jerusalem, and throughout all the coasts of Judaea, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; to the Gentiles, that they should repent and turn to God, and do works meet for repentance.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For these causes the Jews caught me in the temple, and went about to kill &lt;span class="extra"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Having therefore obtained help of God, I continue unto this day, witnessing both to small and great, saying none other things than those which the prophets and Moses did say should come:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">That Christ should suffer, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; that he should be the first that should rise from the dead, and should shew light unto the people, and to the Gentiles.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And as he thus spake for himself, Festus said with a loud voice, Paul, thou art beside thyself; much learning doth make thee mad.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">But he said, I am not mad, most noble Festus; but speak forth the words of truth and soberness.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For the king knoweth of these things, before whom also I speak freely: for I am persuaded that none of these things are hidden from him; for this thing was not done in a corner.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">King Agrippa, believest thou the prophets? I know that thou believest.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Then Agrippa said unto Paul, Almost thou persuadest me to be a Christian.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And Paul said, I would to God, that not only thou, but also all that hear me this day, were both almost, and altogether such as I am, except these bonds.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And when he had thus spoken, the king rose up, and the governor, and Bernice, and they that sat with them:</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And when they were gone aside, they talked between themselves, saying, This man doeth nothing worthy of death or of bonds.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Then said Agrippa unto Festus, This man might have been set at liberty, if he had not appealed unto Caesar.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>