<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="44" name="Acts" bookPage="acts.html" title="Acts" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="romans_1.html" nextTitle="Romans" prevBook="john_1.html" prevTitle="John">
    <chapter number="27" verseCount="44" nextChapter="acts_28.html" nextTitle="Acts 28" prevChapter="acts_26.html" prevTitle="Acts 26" chapterPage="acts_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And when it was determined that we should sail into Italy, they delivered Paul and certain other prisoners unto &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; named Julius, a centurion of Augustus' band.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And entering into a ship of Adramyttium, we launched, meaning to sail by the coasts of Asia; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; Aristarchus, a Macedonian of Thessalonica, being with us.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And the next &lt;span class='extra'&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; we touched at Sidon. And Julius courteously entreated Paul, and gave &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; liberty to go unto his friends to refresh himself.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And when we had launched from thence, we sailed under Cyprus, because the winds were contrary.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And when we had sailed over the sea of Cilicia and Pamphylia, we came to Myra, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;a city&lt;/span&gt; of Lycia.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And there the centurion found a ship of Alexandria sailing into Italy; and he put us therein.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when we had sailed slowly many days, and scarce were come over against Cnidus, the wind not suffering us, we sailed under Crete, over against Salmone;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And, hardly passing it, came unto a place which is called The fair havens; nigh whereunto was the city &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; Lasea.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Now when much time was spent, and when sailing was now dangerous, because the fast was now already past, Paul admonished &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And said unto them, Sirs, I perceive that this voyage will be with hurt and much damage, not only of the lading and ship, but also of our lives.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Nevertheless the centurion believed the master and the owner of the ship, more than those things which were spoken by Paul.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And because the haven was not commodious to winter in, the more part advised to depart thence also, if by any means they might attain to Phenice, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and there&lt;/span&gt; to winter; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which is&lt;/span&gt; an haven of Crete, and lieth toward the south west and north west.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And when the south wind blew softly, supposing that they had obtained &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; purpose, loosing &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thence&lt;/span&gt;, they sailed close by Crete.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But not long after there arose against it a tempestuous wind, called Euroclydon.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And when the ship was caught, and could not bear up into the wind, we let &lt;span class='extra'&gt;her&lt;/span&gt; drive.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And running under a certain island which is called Clauda, we had much work to come by the boat:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Which when they had taken up, they used helps, undergirding the ship; and, fearing lest they should fall into the quicksands, strake sail, and so were driven.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And we being exceedingly tossed with a tempest, the next &lt;span class='extra'&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; they lightened the ship;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the third &lt;span class='extra'&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; we cast out with our own hands the tackling of the ship.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And when neither sun nor stars in many days appeared, and no small tempest lay on &lt;span class='extra'&gt;us&lt;/span&gt;, all hope that we should be saved was then taken away.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But after long abstinence Paul stood forth in the midst of them, and said, Sirs, ye should have hearkened unto me, and not have loosed from Crete, and to have gained this harm and loss.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And now I exhort you to be of good cheer: for there shall be no loss of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any man's&lt;/span&gt; life among you, but of the ship.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For there stood by me this night the angel of God, whose I am, and whom I serve,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Saying, Fear not, Paul; thou must be brought before Caesar: and, lo, God hath given thee all them that sail with thee.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Wherefore, sirs, be of good cheer: for I believe God, that it shall be even as it was told me.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Howbeit we must be cast upon a certain island.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">But when the fourteenth night was come, as we were driven up and down in Adria, about midnight the shipmen deemed that they drew near to some country;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And sounded, and found &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; twenty fathoms: and when they had gone a little further, they sounded again, and found &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; fifteen fathoms.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Then fearing lest we should have fallen upon rocks, they cast four anchors out of the stern, and wished for the day.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And as the shipmen were about to flee out of the ship, when they had let down the boat into the sea, under colour as though they would have cast anchors out of the foreship,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Paul said to the centurion and to the soldiers, Except these abide in the ship, ye cannot be saved.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Then the soldiers cut off the ropes of the boat, and let her fall off.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And while the day was coming on, Paul besought &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; all to take meat, saying, This day is the fourteenth day that ye have tarried and continued fasting, having taken nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Wherefore I pray you to take &lt;span class='extra'&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; meat: for this is for your health: for there shall not an hair fall from the head of any of you.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And when he had thus spoken, he took bread, and gave thanks to God in presence of them all: and when he had broken &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, he began to eat.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">Then were they all of good cheer, and they also took &lt;span class='extra'&gt;some&lt;/span&gt; meat.</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And we were in all in the ship two hundred threescore and sixteen souls.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And when they had eaten enough, they lightened the ship, and cast out the wheat into the sea.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And when it was day, they knew not the land: but they discovered a certain creek with a shore, into the which they were minded, if it were possible, to thrust in the ship.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">And when they had taken up the anchors, they committed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt; unto the sea, and loosed the rudder bands, and hoised up the mainsail to the wind, and made toward shore.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">And falling into a place where two seas met, they ran the ship aground; and the forepart stuck fast, and remained unmoveable, but the hinder part was broken with the violence of the waves.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">And the soldiers' counsel was to kill the prisoners, lest any of them should swim out, and escape.</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">But the centurion, willing to save Paul, kept them from &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; purpose; and commanded that they which could swim should cast &lt;span class='extra'&gt;themselves&lt;/span&gt; first &lt;span class='extra'&gt;into the sea&lt;/span&gt;, and get to land:</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">And the rest, some on boards, and some on &lt;span class='extra'&gt;broken pieces&lt;/span&gt; of the ship. And so it came to pass, that they escaped all safe to land.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>