<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="44" name="Acts" bookPage="acts.html" title="Acts" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="romans_1.html" nextTitle="Romans" prevBook="john_1.html" prevTitle="John">
    <chapter number="28" verseCount="31" nextChapter="romans_1.html" nextTitle="Romans 1" prevChapter="acts_27.html" prevTitle="Acts 27" chapterPage="acts_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And when they were escaped, then they knew that the island was called Melita.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the barbarous people shewed us no little kindness: for they kindled a fire, and received us every one, because of the present rain, and because of the cold.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And when Paul had gathered a bundle of sticks, and laid &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; on the fire, there came a viper out of the heat, and fastened on his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And when the barbarians saw the &lt;span class='extra'&gt;venomous&lt;/span&gt; beast hang on his hand, they said among themselves, No doubt this man is a murderer, whom, though he hath escaped the sea, yet vengeance suffereth not to live.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he shook off the beast into the fire, and felt no harm.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Howbeit they looked when he should have swollen, or fallen down dead suddenly: but after they had looked a great while, and saw no harm come to him, they changed their minds, and said that he was a god.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">In the same quarters were possessions of the chief man of the island, whose name was Publius; who received us, and lodged us three days courteously.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And it came to pass, that the father of Publius lay sick of a fever and of a bloody flux: to whom Paul entered in, and prayed, and laid his hands on him, and healed him.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">So when this was done, others also, which had diseases in the island, came, and were healed:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Who also honoured us with many honours; and when we departed, they laded &lt;span class='extra'&gt;us&lt;/span&gt; with such things as were necessary.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And after three months we departed in a ship of Alexandria, which had wintered in the isle, whose sign was Castor and Pollux.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And landing at Syracuse, we tarried &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there&lt;/span&gt; three days.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And from thence we fetched a compass, and came to Rhegium: and after one day the south wind blew, and we came the next day to Puteoli:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Where we found brethren, and were desired to tarry with them seven days: and so we went toward Rome.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And from thence, when the brethren heard of us, they came to meet us as far as Appii forum, and The three taverns: whom when Paul saw, he thanked God, and took courage.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And when we came to Rome, the centurion delivered the prisoners to the captain of the guard: but Paul was suffered to dwell by himself with a soldier that kept him.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And it came to pass, that after three days Paul called the chief of the Jews together: and when they were come together, he said unto them, Men &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; brethren, though I have committed nothing against the people, or customs of our fathers, yet was I delivered prisoner from Jerusalem into the hands of the Romans.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Who, when they had examined me, would have let &lt;span class='extra'&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; go, because there was no cause of death in me.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But when the Jews spake against &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, I was constrained to appeal unto Caesar; not that I had ought to accuse my nation of.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For this cause therefore have I called for you, to see &lt;span class='extra'&gt;you&lt;/span&gt;, and to speak with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;you&lt;/span&gt;: because that for the hope of Israel I am bound with this chain.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And they said unto him, We neither received letters out of Judaea concerning thee, neither any of the brethren that came shewed or spake any harm of thee.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But we desire to hear of thee what thou thinkest: for as concerning this sect, we know that every where it is spoken against.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And when they had appointed him a day, there came many to him into &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; lodging; to whom he expounded and testified the kingdom of God, persuading them concerning Jesus, both out of the law of Moses, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;out of&lt;/span&gt; the prophets, from morning till evening.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And some believed the things which were spoken, and some believed not.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And when they agreed not among themselves, they departed, after that Paul had spoken one word, Well spake the Holy Ghost by Esaias the prophet unto our fathers,</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Saying, Go unto this people, and say, Hearing ye shall hear, and shall not understand; and seeing ye shall see, and not perceive:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For the heart of this people is waxed gross, and their ears are dull of hearing, and their eyes have they closed; lest they should see with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; eyes, and hear with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; ears, and understand with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; heart, and should be converted, and I should heal them.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Be it known therefore unto you, that the salvation of God is sent unto the Gentiles, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; they will hear it.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And when he had said these words, the Jews departed, and had great reasoning among themselves.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Paul dwelt two whole years in his own hired house, and received all that came in unto him,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Preaching the kingdom of God, and teaching those things which concern the Lord Jesus Christ, with all confidence, no man forbidding him.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>