<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="44" name="Acts" bookPage="acts.html" title="Acts" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="romans_1.html" nextTitle="Romans" prevBook="john_1.html" prevTitle="John">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="40" nextChapter="acts_9.html" nextTitle="Acts 9" prevChapter="acts_7.html" prevTitle="Acts 7" chapterPage="acts_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And Saul was consenting unto his death. And at that time there was a great persecution against the church which was at Jerusalem; and they were all scattered abroad throughout the regions of Judaea and Samaria, except the apostles.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And devout men carried Stephen &lt;i&gt;to his burial&lt;/i&gt;, and made great lamentation over him.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">As for Saul, he made havock of the church, entering into every house, and haling men and women committed &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; to prison.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Therefore they that were scattered abroad went every where preaching the word.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Then Philip went down to the city of Samaria, and preached Christ unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the people with one accord gave heed unto those things which Philip spake, hearing and seeing the miracles which he did.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For unclean spirits, crying with loud voice, came out of many that were possessed &lt;i&gt;with them&lt;/i&gt;: and many taken with palsies, and that were lame, were healed.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And there was great joy in that city.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But there was a certain man, called Simon, which beforetime in the same city used sorcery, and bewitched the people of Samaria, giving out that himself was some great one:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">To whom they all gave heed, from the least to the greatest, saying, This man is the great power of God.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And to him they had regard, because that of long time he had bewitched them with sorceries.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But when they believed Philip preaching the things concerning the kingdom of God, and the name of Jesus Christ, they were baptized, both men and women.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Then Simon himself believed also: and when he was baptized, he continued with Philip, and wondered, beholding the miracles and signs which were done.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Now when the apostles which were at Jerusalem heard that Samaria had received the word of God, they sent unto them Peter and John:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Who, when they were come down, prayed for them, that they might receive the Holy Ghost:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">(For as yet he was fallen upon none of them: only they were baptized in the name of the Lord Jesus.)</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then laid they &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; hands on them, and they received the Holy Ghost.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And when Simon saw that through laying on of the apostles' hands the Holy Ghost was given, he offered them money,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Saying, Give me also this power, that on whomsoever I lay hands, he may receive the Holy Ghost.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But Peter said unto him, Thy money perish with thee, because thou hast thought that the gift of God may be purchased with money.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Thou hast neither part nor lot in this matter: for thy heart is not right in the sight of God.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Repent therefore of this thy wickedness, and pray God, if perhaps the thought of thine heart may be forgiven thee.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For I perceive that thou art in the gall of bitterness, and &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the bond of iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Then answered Simon, and said, Pray ye to the Lord for me, that none of these things which ye have spoken come upon me.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And they, when they had testified and preached the word of the Lord, returned to Jerusalem, and preached the gospel in many villages of the Samaritans.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And the angel of the Lord spake unto Philip, saying, Arise, and go toward the south unto the way that goeth down from Jerusalem unto Gaza, which is desert.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And he arose and went: and, behold, a man of Ethiopia, an eunuch of great authority under Candace queen of the Ethiopians, who had the charge of all her treasure, and had come to Jerusalem for to worship,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Was returning, and sitting in his chariot read Esaias the prophet.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Then the Spirit said unto Philip, Go near, and join thyself to this chariot.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And Philip ran thither to &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, and heard him read the prophet Esaias, and said, Understandest thou what thou readest?</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">And he said, How can I, except some man should guide me? And he desired Philip that he would come up and sit with him.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">The place of the scripture which he read was this, He was led as a sheep to the slaughter; and like a lamb dumb before his shearer, so opened he not his mouth:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">In his humiliation his judgment was taken away: and who shall declare his generation? for his life is taken from the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And the eunuch answered Philip, and said, I pray thee, of whom speaketh the prophet this? of himself, or of some other man?</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Then Philip opened his mouth, and began at the same scripture, and preached unto him Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And as they went on &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; way, they came unto a certain water: and the eunuch said, See, &lt;i&gt;here is&lt;/i&gt; water; what doth hinder me to be baptized?</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And Philip said, If thou believest with all thine heart, thou mayest. And he answered and said, I believe that Jesus Christ is the Son of God.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">And he commanded the chariot to stand still: and they went down both into the water, both Philip and the eunuch; and he baptized him.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And when they were come up out of the water, the Spirit of the Lord caught away Philip, that the eunuch saw him no more: and he went on his way rejoicing.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">But Philip was found at Azotus: and passing through he preached in all the cities, till he came to Caesarea.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>