<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="44" name="Acts" bookPage="acts.html" title="Acts" chapterCount="28" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="romans_1.html" nextTitle="Romans" prevBook="john_1.html" prevTitle="John">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="37" nextChapter="acts_5.html" nextTitle="Acts 5" prevChapter="acts_3.html" prevTitle="Acts 3" chapterPage="acts_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And as they spake unto the people, the priests, and the captain of the temple, and the Sadducees, came upon them,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Being grieved that they taught the people, and preached through Jesus the resurrection from the dead.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they laid hands on them, and put &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in hold unto the next day: for it was now eventide.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Howbeit many of them which heard the word believed; and the number of the men was about five thousand.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5" newPara="true">And it came to pass on the morrow, that their rulers, and elders, and scribes,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And Annas the high priest, and Caiaphas, and John, and Alexander, and as many as were of the kindred of the high priest, were gathered together at Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when they had set them in the midst, they asked, By what power, or by what name, have ye done this?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Then Peter, filled with the Holy Ghost, said unto them, Ye rulers of the people, and elders of Israel,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">If we this day be examined of the good deed done to the impotent man, by what means he is made whole;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Be it known unto you all, and to all the people of Israel, that by the name of Jesus Christ of Nazareth, whom ye crucified, whom God raised from the dead, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; by him doth this man stand here before you whole.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">This is the stone which was set at nought of you builders, which is become the head of the corner.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Neither is there salvation in any other: for there is none other name under heaven given among men, whereby we must be saved.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13" newPara="true">Now when they saw the boldness of Peter and John, and perceived that they were unlearned and ignorant men, they marvelled; and they took knowledge of them, that they had been with Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And beholding the man which was healed standing with them, they could say nothing against it.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But when they had commanded them to go aside out of the council, they conferred among themselves,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Saying, What shall we do to these men? for that indeed a notable miracle hath been done by them &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; manifest to all them that dwell in Jerusalem; and we cannot deny &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But that it spread no further among the people, let us straitly threaten them, that they speak henceforth to no man in this name.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And they called them, and commanded them not to speak at all nor teach in the name of Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But Peter and John answered and said unto them, Whether it be right in the sight of God to hearken unto you more than unto God, judge ye.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For we cannot but speak the things which we have seen and heard.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">So when they had further threatened them, they let them go, finding nothing how they might punish them, because of the people: for all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; glorified God for that which was done.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For the man was above forty years old, on whom this miracle of healing was shewed.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23" newPara="true">And being let go, they went to their own company, and reported all that the chief priests and elders had said unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And when they heard that, they lifted up their voice to God with one accord, and said, Lord, thou &lt;i&gt;art&lt;/i&gt; God, which hast made heaven, and earth, and the sea, and all that in them is:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Who by the mouth of thy servant David hast said, Why did the heathen rage, and the people imagine vain things?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The kings of the earth stood up, and the rulers were gathered together against the Lord, and against his Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For of a truth against thy holy child Jesus, whom thou hast anointed, both Herod, and Pontius Pilate, with the Gentiles, and the people of Israel, were gathered together,</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">For to do whatsoever thy hand and thy counsel determined before to be done.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And now, Lord, behold their threatenings: and grant unto thy servants, that with all boldness they may speak thy word,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">By stretching forth thine hand to heal; and that signs and wonders may be done by the name of thy holy child Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31" newPara="true">And when they had prayed, the place was shaken where they were assembled together; and they were all filled with the Holy Ghost, and they spake the word of God with boldness.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And the multitude of them that believed were of one heart and of one soul: neither said any &lt;i&gt;of them&lt;/i&gt; that ought of the things which he possessed was his own; but they had all things common.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And with great power gave the apostles witness of the resurrection of the Lord Jesus: and great grace was upon them all.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Neither was there any among them that lacked: for as many as were possessors of lands or houses sold them, and brought the prices of the things that were sold,</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And laid &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; down at the apostles' feet: and distribution was made unto every man according as he had need.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And Joses, who by the apostles was surnamed Barnabas, (which is, being interpreted, The son of consolation,) a Levite, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; of the country of Cyprus,</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">Having land, sold &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and brought the money, and laid &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; at the apostles' feet.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>