<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="45" name="Romans" bookPage="romans.html" title="Romans" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians" prevBook="acts_1.html" prevTitle="Acts">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="14" nextChapter="romans_14.html" nextTitle="Romans 14" prevChapter="romans_12.html" prevTitle="Romans 12" chapterPage="romans_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Let every soul be subject unto the higher powers. For there is no power but of God: the powers that be are ordained of God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Whosoever therefore resisteth the power, resisteth the ordinance of God: and they that resist shall receive to themselves damnation.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For rulers are not a terror to good works, but to the evil. Wilt thou then not be afraid of the power? do that which is good, and thou shalt have praise of the same:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For he is the minister of God to thee for good. But if thou do that which is evil, be afraid; for he beareth not the sword in vain: for he is the minister of God, a revenger to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;execute&lt;/span&gt; wrath upon him that doeth evil.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Wherefore &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ye&lt;/span&gt; must needs be subject, not only for wrath, but also for conscience sake.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For for this cause pay ye tribute also: for they are God's ministers, attending continually upon this very thing.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Render therefore to all their dues: tribute to whom tribute &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is due&lt;/span&gt;; custom to whom custom; fear to whom fear; honour to whom honour.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Owe no man any thing, but to love one another; for he that loveth another hath fulfilled the law.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For this, Thou shalt not commit adultery, Thou shalt not kill, Thou shalt not steal, Thou shalt not bear false witness, Thou shalt not covet; and if &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; any other commandment, it is briefly comprehended in this saying, namely, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Love worketh no ill to his neighbour: therefore love &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the fulfilling of the law.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And that, knowing the time, that now &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; high time to awake out of sleep: for now &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our salvation nearer than when we believed.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">The night is far spent, the day is at hand: let us therefore cast off the works of darkness, and let us put on the armour of light.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Let us walk honestly, as in the day; not in rioting and drunkenness, not in chambering and wantonness, not in strife and envying.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But put ye on the Lord Jesus Christ, and make not provision for the flesh, to &lt;span class="extra"&gt;fulfil&lt;/span&gt; the lusts &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thereof&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>