<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="45" name="Romans" bookPage="romans.html" title="Romans" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians" prevBook="acts_1.html" prevTitle="Acts">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="31" nextChapter="romans_4.html" nextTitle="Romans 4" prevChapter="romans_2.html" prevTitle="Romans 2" chapterPage="romans_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">What advantage then hath the Jew? or what profit &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is there&lt;/span&gt; of circumcision?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Much every way: chiefly, because that unto them were committed the oracles of God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For what if some did not believe? shall their unbelief make the faith of God without effect?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">God forbid: yea, let God be true, but every man a liar; as it is written, That thou mightest be justified in thy sayings, and mightest overcome when thou art judged.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But if our unrighteousness commend the righteousness of God, what shall we say? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Is&lt;/span&gt; God unrighteous who taketh vengeance? (I speak as a man)</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">God forbid: for then how shall God judge the world?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For if the truth of God hath more abounded through my lie unto his glory; why yet am I also judged as a sinner?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And not &lt;span class="extra"&gt;rather&lt;/span&gt;, (as we be slanderously reported, and as some affirm that we say,) Let us do evil, that good may come? whose damnation is just.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">What then? are we better &lt;span class="extra"&gt;than they&lt;/span&gt;? No, in no wise: for we have before proved both Jews and Gentiles, that they are all under sin;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">As it is written, There is none righteous, no, not one:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">There is none that understandeth, there is none that seeketh after God.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">They are all gone out of the way, they are together become unprofitable; there is none that doeth good, no, not one.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Their throat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; an open sepulchre; with their tongues they have used deceit; the poison of asps &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; under their lips:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Whose mouth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; full of cursing and bitterness:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Their feet &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; swift to shed blood:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Destruction and misery &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in their ways:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the way of peace have they not known:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">There is no fear of God before their eyes.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Now we know that what things soever the law saith, it saith to them who are under the law: that every mouth may be stopped, and all the world may become guilty before God.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Therefore by the deeds of the law there shall no flesh be justified in his sight: for by the law &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the knowledge of sin.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">But now the righteousness of God without the law is manifested, being witnessed by the law and the prophets;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Even the righteousness of God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which is&lt;/span&gt; by faith of Jesus Christ unto all and upon all them that believe: for there is no difference:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For all have sinned, and come short of the glory of God;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Being justified freely by his grace through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Whom God hath set forth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; a propitiation through faith in his blood, to declare his righteousness for the remission of sins that are past, through the forbearance of God;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">To declare, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;I say&lt;/span&gt;, at this time his righteousness: that he might be just, and the justifier of him which believeth in Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; boasting then? It is excluded. By what law? of works? Nay: but by the law of faith.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Therefore we conclude that a man is justified by faith without the deeds of the law.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Is he&lt;/span&gt; the God of the Jews only? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is he&lt;/span&gt; not also of the Gentiles? Yes, of the Gentiles also:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Seeing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; one God, which shall justify the circumcision by faith, and uncircumcision through faith.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Do we then make void the law through faith? God forbid: yea, we establish the law.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>