<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="45" name="Romans" bookPage="romans.html" title="Romans" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians" prevBook="acts_1.html" prevTitle="Acts">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="32" nextChapter="romans_2.html" nextTitle="Romans 2" prevChapter="acts_28.html" prevTitle="Acts 28" chapterPage="romans_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Paul, a servant of Jesus Christ, called &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; an apostle, separated unto the gospel of God,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">(Which he had promised afore by his prophets in the holy scriptures,)</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Concerning his Son Jesus Christ our Lord, which was made of the seed of David according to the flesh;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And declared &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; the Son of God with power, according to the spirit of holiness, by the resurrection from the dead:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">By whom we have received grace and apostleship, for obedience to the faith among all nations, for his name:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Among whom are ye also the called of Jesus Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">To all that be in Rome, beloved of God, called &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; saints: Grace to you and peace from God our Father, and the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">First, I thank my God through Jesus Christ for you all, that your faith is spoken of throughout the whole world.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For God is my witness, whom I serve with my spirit in the gospel of his Son, that without ceasing I make mention of you always in my prayers;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Making request, if by any means now at length I might have a prosperous journey by the will of God to come unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For I long to see you, that I may impart unto you some spiritual gift, to the end ye may be established;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">That is, that I may be comforted together with you by the mutual faith both of you and me.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Now I would not have you ignorant, brethren, that oftentimes I purposed to come unto you, (but was let hitherto,) that I might have some fruit among you also, even as among other Gentiles.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I am debtor both to the Greeks, and to the Barbarians; both to the wise, and to the unwise.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">So, as much as in me is, I am ready to preach the gospel to you that are at Rome also.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For I am not ashamed of the gospel of Christ: for it is the power of God unto salvation to every one that believeth; to the Jew first, and also to the Greek.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For therein is the righteousness of God revealed from faith to faith: as it is written, The just shall live by faith.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For the wrath of God is revealed from heaven against all ungodliness and unrighteousness of men, who hold the truth in unrighteousness;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Because that which may be known of God is manifest in them; for God hath shewed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; unto them.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For the invisible things of him from the creation of the world are clearly seen, being understood by the things that are made, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; his eternal power and Godhead; so that they are without excuse:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Because that, when they knew God, they glorified &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; not as God, neither were thankful; but became vain in their imaginations, and their foolish heart was darkened.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Professing themselves to be wise, they became fools,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And changed the glory of the uncorruptible God into an image made like to corruptible man, and to birds, and fourfooted beasts, and creeping things.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Wherefore God also gave them up to uncleanness through the lusts of their own hearts, to dishonour their own bodies between themselves:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Who changed the truth of God into a lie, and worshipped and served the creature more than the Creator, who is blessed for ever. Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For this cause God gave them up unto vile affections: for even their women did change the natural use into that which is against nature:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And likewise also the men, leaving the natural use of the woman, burned in their lust one toward another; men with men working that which is unseemly, and receiving in themselves that recompence of their error which was meet.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And even as they did not like to retain God in &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; knowledge, God gave them over to a reprobate mind, to do those things which are not convenient;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Being filled with all unrighteousness, fornication, wickedness, covetousness, maliciousness; full of envy, murder, debate, deceit, malignity; whisperers,</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Backbiters, haters of God, despiteful, proud, boasters, inventors of evil things, disobedient to parents,</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Without understanding, covenantbreakers, without natural affection, implacable, unmerciful:</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Who knowing the judgment of God, that they which commit such things are worthy of death, not only do the same, but have pleasure in them that do them.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>