<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="45" name="Romans" bookPage="romans.html" title="Romans" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians" prevBook="acts_1.html" prevTitle="Acts">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="21" nextChapter="romans_6.html" nextTitle="Romans 6" prevChapter="romans_4.html" prevTitle="Romans 4" chapterPage="romans_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Therefore being justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">By whom also we have access by faith into this grace wherein we stand, and rejoice in hope of the glory of God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And not only &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;, but we glory in tribulations also: knowing that tribulation worketh patience;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And patience, experience; and experience, hope:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And hope maketh not ashamed; because the love of God is shed abroad in our hearts by the Holy Ghost which is given unto us.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For when we were yet without strength, in due time Christ died for the ungodly.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For scarcely for a righteous man will one die: yet peradventure for a good man some would even dare to die.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But God commendeth his love toward us, in that, while we were yet sinners, Christ died for us.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Much more then, being now justified by his blood, we shall be saved from wrath through him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For if, when we were enemies, we were reconciled to God by the death of his Son, much more, being reconciled, we shall be saved by his life.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And not only &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt;, but we also joy in God through our Lord Jesus Christ, by whom we have now received the atonement.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Wherefore, as by one man sin entered into the world, and death by sin; and so death passed upon all men, for that all have sinned:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">(For until the law sin was in the world: but sin is not imputed when there is no law.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Nevertheless death reigned from Adam to Moses, even over them that had not sinned after the similitude of Adam's transgression, who is the figure of him that was to come.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But not as the offence, so also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the free gift. For if through the offence of one many be dead, much more the grace of God, and the gift by grace, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which is&lt;/span&gt; by one man, Jesus Christ, hath abounded unto many.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And not as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it was&lt;/span&gt; by one that sinned, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so is&lt;/span&gt; the gift: for the judgment &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; by one to condemnation, but the free gift &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; of many offences unto justification.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For if by one man's offence death reigned by one; much more they which receive abundance of grace and of the gift of righteousness shall reign in life by one, Jesus Christ.)</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Therefore as by the offence of one &lt;span class="extra"&gt;judgment came&lt;/span&gt; upon all men to condemnation; even so by the righteousness of one &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the free gift came&lt;/span&gt; upon all men unto justification of life.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For as by one man's disobedience many were made sinners, so by the obedience of one shall many be made righteous.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Moreover the law entered, that the offence might abound. But where sin abounded, grace did much more abound:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">That as sin hath reigned unto death, even so might grace reign through righteousness unto eternal life by Jesus Christ our Lord.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>