<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="45" name="Romans" bookPage="romans.html" title="Romans" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians" prevBook="acts_1.html" prevTitle="Acts">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="21" nextChapter="romans_13.html" nextTitle="Romans 13" prevChapter="romans_11.html" prevTitle="Romans 11" chapterPage="romans_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I beseech you therefore, brethren, by the mercies of God, that ye present your bodies a living sacrifice, holy, acceptable unto God, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;which is&lt;/span&gt; your reasonable service.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And be not conformed to this world: but be ye transformed by the renewing of your mind, that ye may prove what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; that good, and acceptable, and perfect, will of God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For I say, through the grace given unto me, to every man that is among you, not to think &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of himself&lt;/span&gt; more highly than he ought to think; but to think soberly, according as God hath dealt to every man the measure of faith.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For as we have many members in one body, and all members have not the same office:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">So we, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; many, are one body in Christ, and every one members one of another.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Having then gifts differing according to the grace that is given to us, whether prophecy, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;let us prophesy&lt;/span&gt; according to the proportion of faith;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Or ministry, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;let us wait&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class='extra'&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; ministering: or he that teacheth, on teaching;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Or he that exhorteth, on exhortation: he that giveth, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;let him do it&lt;/span&gt; with simplicity; he that ruleth, with diligence; he that sheweth mercy, with cheerfulness.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Let&lt;/span&gt; love be without dissimulation. Abhor that which is evil; cleave to that which is good.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Be&lt;/span&gt; kindly affectioned one to another with brotherly love; in honour preferring one another;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Not slothful in business; fervent in spirit; serving the Lord;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Rejoicing in hope; patient in tribulation; continuing instant in prayer;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Distributing to the necessity of saints; given to hospitality.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Bless them which persecute you: bless, and curse not.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Rejoice with them that do rejoice, and weep with them that weep.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Be&lt;/span&gt; of the same mind one toward another. Mind not high things, but condescend to men of low estate. Be not wise in your own conceits.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Recompense to no man evil for evil. Provide things honest in the sight of all men.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">If it be possible, as much as lieth in you, live peaceably with all men.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Dearly beloved, avenge not yourselves, but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;rather&lt;/span&gt; give place unto wrath: for it is written, Vengeance &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; mine; I will repay, saith the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Therefore if thine enemy hunger, feed him; if he thirst, give him drink: for in so doing thou shalt heap coals of fire on his head.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Be not overcome of evil, but overcome evil with good.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>