<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="45" name="Romans" bookPage="romans.html" title="Romans" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians" prevBook="acts_1.html" prevTitle="Acts">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="23" nextChapter="romans_7.html" nextTitle="Romans 7" prevChapter="romans_5.html" prevTitle="Romans 5" chapterPage="romans_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">What shall we say then? Shall we continue in sin, that grace may abound?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">God forbid. How shall we, that are dead to sin, live any longer therein?</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Know ye not, that so many of us as were baptized into Jesus Christ were baptized into his death?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Therefore we are buried with him by baptism into death: that like as Christ was raised up from the dead by the glory of the Father, even so we also should walk in newness of life.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For if we have been planted together in the likeness of his death, we shall be also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in the likeness&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; resurrection:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Knowing this, that our old man is crucified with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, that the body of sin might be destroyed, that henceforth we should not serve sin.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For he that is dead is freed from sin.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Now if we be dead with Christ, we believe that we shall also live with him:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Knowing that Christ being raised from the dead dieth no more; death hath no more dominion over him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For in that he died, he died unto sin once: but in that he liveth, he liveth unto God.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Likewise reckon ye also yourselves to be dead indeed unto sin, but alive unto God through Jesus Christ our Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Let not sin therefore reign in your mortal body, that ye should obey it in the lusts thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Neither yield ye your members &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; instruments of unrighteousness unto sin: but yield yourselves unto God, as those that are alive from the dead, and your members &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; instruments of righteousness unto God.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For sin shall not have dominion over you: for ye are not under the law, but under grace.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">What then? shall we sin, because we are not under the law, but under grace? God forbid.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Know ye not, that to whom ye yield yourselves servants to obey, his servants ye are to whom ye obey; whether of sin unto death, or of obedience unto righteousness?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But God be thanked, that ye were the servants of sin, but ye have obeyed from the heart that form of doctrine which was delivered you.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Being then made free from sin, ye became the servants of righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">I speak after the manner of men because of the infirmity of your flesh: for as ye have yielded your members servants to uncleanness and to iniquity unto iniquity; even so now yield your members servants to righteousness unto holiness.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For when ye were the servants of sin, ye were free from righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">What fruit had ye then in those things whereof ye are now ashamed? for the end of those things &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; death.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But now being made free from sin, and become servants to God, ye have your fruit unto holiness, and the end everlasting life.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For the wages of sin &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; death; but the gift of God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; eternal life through Jesus Christ our Lord.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>