<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="45" name="Romans" bookPage="romans.html" title="Romans" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians" prevBook="acts_1.html" prevTitle="Acts">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="33" nextChapter="romans_10.html" nextTitle="Romans 10" prevChapter="romans_8.html" prevTitle="Romans 8" chapterPage="romans_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I say the truth in Christ, I lie not, my conscience also bearing me witness in the Holy Ghost,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That I have great heaviness and continual sorrow in my heart.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For I could wish that myself were accursed from Christ for my brethren, my kinsmen according to the flesh:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Who are Israelites; to whom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;pertaineth&lt;/span&gt; the adoption, and the glory, and the covenants, and the giving of the law, and the service &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of God&lt;/span&gt;, and the promises;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Whose &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the fathers, and of whom as concerning the flesh Christ &lt;span class="extra"&gt;came&lt;/span&gt;, who is over all, God blessed for ever. Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Not as though the word of God hath taken none effect. For they &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not all Israel, which are of Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Neither, because they are the seed of Abraham, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are they&lt;/span&gt; all children: but, In Isaac shall thy seed be called.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">That is, They which are the children of the flesh, these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not the children of God: but the children of the promise are counted for the seed.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the word of promise, At this time will I come, and Sara shall have a son.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And not only &lt;span class="extra"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;; but when Rebecca also had conceived by one, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; by our father Isaac;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">(For &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the children&lt;/span&gt; being not yet born, neither having done any good or evil, that the purpose of God according to election might stand, not of works, but of him that calleth;)</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">It was said unto her, The elder shall serve the younger.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">As it is written, Jacob have I loved, but Esau have I hated.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">What shall we say then? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;Is there&lt;/span&gt; unrighteousness with God? God forbid.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For he saith to Moses, I will have mercy on whom I will have mercy, and I will have compassion on whom I will have compassion.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">So then &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; not of him that willeth, nor of him that runneth, but of God that sheweth mercy.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For the scripture saith unto Pharaoh, Even for this same purpose have I raised thee up, that I might shew my power in thee, and that my name might be declared throughout all the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Therefore hath he mercy on whom he will &lt;span class="extra"&gt;have mercy&lt;/span&gt;, and whom he will he hardeneth.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thou wilt say then unto me, Why doth he yet find fault? For who hath resisted his will?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Nay but, O man, who art thou that repliest against God? Shall the thing formed say to him that formed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, Why hast thou made me thus?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Hath not the potter power over the clay, of the same lump to make one vessel unto honour, and another unto dishonour?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;What&lt;/span&gt; if God, willing to shew &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; wrath, and to make his power known, endured with much longsuffering the vessels of wrath fitted to destruction:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And that he might make known the riches of his glory on the vessels of mercy, which he had afore prepared unto glory,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Even us, whom he hath called, not of the Jews only, but also of the Gentiles?</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">As he saith also in Osee, I will call them my people, which were not my people; and her beloved, which was not beloved.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And it shall come to pass, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; in the place where it was said unto them, Ye &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not my people; there shall they be called the children of the living God.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Esaias also crieth concerning Israel, Though the number of the children of Israel be as the sand of the sea, a remnant shall be saved:</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">For he will finish the work, and cut &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; short in righteousness: because a short work will the Lord make upon the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">And as Esaias said before, Except the Lord of Sabaoth had left us a seed, we had been as Sodoma, and been made like unto Gomorrha.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">What shall we say then? That the Gentiles, which followed not after righteousness, have attained to righteousness, even the righteousness which is of faith.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">But Israel, which followed after the law of righteousness, hath not attained to the law of righteousness.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Wherefore? Because &lt;span class="extra"&gt;they sought it&lt;/span&gt; not by faith, but as it were by the works of the law. For they stumbled at that stumblingstone;</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">As it is written, Behold, I lay in Sion a stumblingstone and rock of offence: and whosoever believeth on him shall not be ashamed.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>