<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="45" name="Romans" bookPage="romans.html" title="Romans" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians" prevBook="acts_1.html" prevTitle="Acts">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="29" nextChapter="romans_3.html" nextTitle="Romans 3" prevChapter="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans 1" chapterPage="romans_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Therefore thou art inexcusable, O man, whosoever thou art that judgest: for wherein thou judgest another, thou condemnest thyself; for thou that judgest doest the same things.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">But we are sure that the judgment of God is according to truth against them which commit such things.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And thinkest thou this, O man, that judgest them which do such things, and doest the same, that thou shalt escape the judgment of God?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Or despisest thou the riches of his goodness and forbearance and longsuffering; not knowing that the goodness of God leadeth thee to repentance?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But after thy hardness and impenitent heart treasurest up unto thyself wrath against the day of wrath and revelation of the righteous judgment of God;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Who will render to every man according to his deeds:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">To them who by patient continuance in well doing seek for glory and honour and immortality, eternal life:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But unto them that are contentious, and do not obey the truth, but obey unrighteousness, indignation and wrath,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Tribulation and anguish, upon every soul of man that doeth evil, of the Jew first, and also of the Gentile;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But glory, honour, and peace, to every man that worketh good, to the Jew first, and also to the Gentile:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For there is no respect of persons with God.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For as many as have sinned without law shall also perish without law: and as many as have sinned in the law shall be judged by the law;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">(For not the hearers of the law &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; just before God, but the doers of the law shall be justified.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For when the Gentiles, which have not the law, do by nature the things contained in the law, these, having not the law, are a law unto themselves:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Which shew the work of the law written in their hearts, their conscience also bearing witness, and &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; thoughts the mean while accusing or else excusing one another;)</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">In the day when God shall judge the secrets of men by Jesus Christ according to my gospel.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Behold, thou art called a Jew, and restest in the law, and makest thy boast of God,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And knowest &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; will, and approvest the things that are more excellent, being instructed out of the law;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And art confident that thou thyself art a guide of the blind, a light of them which are in darkness,</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">An instructor of the foolish, a teacher of babes, which hast the form of knowledge and of the truth in the law.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Thou therefore which teachest another, teachest thou not thyself? thou that preachest a man should not steal, dost thou steal?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Thou that sayest a man should not commit adultery, dost thou commit adultery? thou that abhorrest idols, dost thou commit sacrilege?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Thou that makest thy boast of the law, through breaking the law dishonourest thou God?</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For the name of God is blasphemed among the Gentiles through you, as it is written.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For circumcision verily profiteth, if thou keep the law: but if thou be a breaker of the law, thy circumcision is made uncircumcision.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Therefore if the uncircumcision keep the righteousness of the law, shall not his uncircumcision be counted for circumcision?</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And shall not uncircumcision which is by nature, if it fulfil the law, judge thee, who by the letter and circumcision dost transgress the law?</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">For he is not a Jew, which is one outwardly; neither &lt;i&gt;is that&lt;/i&gt; circumcision, which is outward in the flesh:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">But he &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a Jew, which is one inwardly; and circumcision &lt;i&gt;is that&lt;/i&gt; of the heart, in the spirit, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; not in the letter; whose praise &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not of men, but of God.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>