<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="13" nextChapter="1corinthians_14.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 14" prevChapter="1corinthians_12.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 12" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Though I speak with the tongues of men and of angels, and have not charity, I am become &lt;span class="extra"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; sounding brass, or a tinkling cymbal.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And though I have &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the gift of&lt;/span&gt; prophecy, and understand all mysteries, and all knowledge; and though I have all faith, so that I could remove mountains, and have not charity, I am nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And though I bestow all my goods to feed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the poor&lt;/span&gt;, and though I give my body to be burned, and have not charity, it profiteth me nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Charity suffereth long, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; is kind; charity envieth not; charity vaunteth not itself, is not puffed up,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Doth not behave itself unseemly, seeketh not her own, is not easily provoked, thinketh no evil;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Rejoiceth not in iniquity, but rejoiceth in the truth;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth all things, endureth all things.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Charity never faileth: but whether &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; prophecies, they shall fail; whether &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; tongues, they shall cease; whether &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; knowledge, it shall vanish away.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For we know in part, and we prophesy in part.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But when that which is perfect is come, then that which is in part shall be done away.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">When I was a child, I spake as a child, I understood as a child, I thought as a child: but when I became a man, I put away childish things.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For now we see through a glass, darkly; but then face to face: now I know in part; but then shall I know even as also I am known.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And now abideth faith, hope, charity, these three; but the greatest of these &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; charity.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>