<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="40" nextChapter="1corinthians_15.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 15" prevChapter="1corinthians_13.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 13" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Follow after charity, and desire spiritual &lt;span class="extra"&gt;gifts&lt;/span&gt;, but rather that ye may prophesy.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For he that speaketh in an &lt;span class="extra"&gt;unknown&lt;/span&gt; tongue speaketh not unto men, but unto God: for no man understandeth &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;; howbeit in the spirit he speaketh mysteries.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But he that prophesieth speaketh unto men &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; edification, and exhortation, and comfort.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He that speaketh in an &lt;span class="extra"&gt;unknown&lt;/span&gt; tongue edifieth himself; but he that prophesieth edifieth the church.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">I would that ye all spake with tongues, but rather that ye prophesied: for greater &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he that prophesieth than he that speaketh with tongues, except he interpret, that the church may receive edifying.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Now, brethren, if I come unto you speaking with tongues, what shall I profit you, except I shall speak to you either by revelation, or by knowledge, or by prophesying, or by doctrine?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And even things without life giving sound, whether pipe or harp, except they give a distinction in the sounds, how shall it be known what is piped or harped?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For if the trumpet give an uncertain sound, who shall prepare himself to the battle?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">So likewise ye, except ye utter by the tongue words easy to be understood, how shall it be known what is spoken? for ye shall speak into the air.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">There are, it may be, so many kinds of voices in the world, and none of them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; without signification.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Therefore if I know not the meaning of the voice, I shall be unto him that speaketh a barbarian, and he that speaketh &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; a barbarian unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Even so ye, forasmuch as ye are zealous of spiritual &lt;span class="extra"&gt;gifts&lt;/span&gt;, seek that ye may excel to the edifying of the church.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Wherefore let him that speaketh in an &lt;span class="extra"&gt;unknown&lt;/span&gt; tongue pray that he may interpret.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For if I pray in an &lt;span class="extra"&gt;unknown&lt;/span&gt; tongue, my spirit prayeth, but my understanding is unfruitful.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">What is it then? I will pray with the spirit, and I will pray with the understanding also: I will sing with the spirit, and I will sing with the understanding also.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Else when thou shalt bless with the spirit, how shall he that occupieth the room of the unlearned say Amen at thy giving of thanks, seeing he understandeth not what thou sayest?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For thou verily givest thanks well, but the other is not edified.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">I thank my God, I speak with tongues more than ye all:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Yet in the church I had rather speak five words with my understanding, that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;by my voice&lt;/span&gt; I might teach others also, than ten thousand words in an &lt;span class="extra"&gt;unknown&lt;/span&gt; tongue.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Brethren, be not children in understanding: howbeit in malice be ye children, but in understanding be men.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">In the law it is written, With &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men of&lt;/span&gt; other tongues and other lips will I speak unto this people; and yet for all that will they not hear me, saith the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Wherefore tongues are for a sign, not to them that believe, but to them that believe not: but prophesying &lt;span class="extra"&gt;serveth&lt;/span&gt; not for them that believe not, but for them which believe.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">If therefore the whole church be come together into one place, and all speak with tongues, and there come in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;those that are&lt;/span&gt; unlearned, or unbelievers, will they not say that ye are mad?</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But if all prophesy, and there come in one that believeth not, or &lt;span class="extra"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; unlearned, he is convinced of all, he is judged of all:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And thus are the secrets of his heart made manifest; and so falling down on &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; face he will worship God, and report that God is in you of a truth.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">How is it then, brethren? when ye come together, every one of you hath a psalm, hath a doctrine, hath a tongue, hath a revelation, hath an interpretation. Let all things be done unto edifying.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">If any man speak in an &lt;span class="extra"&gt;unknown&lt;/span&gt; tongue, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;let it be&lt;/span&gt; by two, or at the most &lt;span class="extra"&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; three, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; by course; and let one interpret.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">But if there be no interpreter, let him keep silence in the church; and let him speak to himself, and to God.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Let the prophets speak two or three, and let the other judge.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">If &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any thing&lt;/span&gt; be revealed to another that sitteth by, let the first hold his peace.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">For ye may all prophesy one by one, that all may learn, and all may be comforted.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And the spirits of the prophets are subject to the prophets.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">For God is not &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the author&lt;/span&gt; of confusion, but of peace, as in all churches of the saints.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Let your women keep silence in the churches: for it is not permitted unto them to speak; but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;they are commanded&lt;/span&gt; to be under obedience, as also saith the law.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">And if they will learn any thing, let them ask their husbands at home: for it is a shame for women to speak in the church.</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">What? came the word of God out from you? or came it unto you only?</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">If any man think himself to be a prophet, or spiritual, let him acknowledge that the things that I write unto you are the commandments of the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">But if any man be ignorant, let him be ignorant.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">Wherefore, brethren, covet to prophesy, and forbid not to speak with tongues.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">Let all things be done decently and in order.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>