<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="15" verseCount="58" nextChapter="1corinthians_16.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 16" prevChapter="1corinthians_14.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 14" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover, brethren, I declare unto you the gospel which I preached unto you, which also ye have received, and wherein ye stand;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">By which also ye are saved, if ye keep in memory what I preached unto you, unless ye have believed in vain.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For I delivered unto you first of all that which I also received, how that Christ died for our sins according to the scriptures;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And that he was buried, and that he rose again the third day according to the scriptures:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And that he was seen of Cephas, then of the twelve:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">After that, he was seen of above five hundred brethren at once; of whom the greater part remain unto this present, but some are fallen asleep.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">After that, he was seen of James; then of all the apostles.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And last of all he was seen of me also, as of one born out of due time.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For I am the least of the apostles, that am not meet to be called an apostle, because I persecuted the church of God.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But by the grace of God I am what I am: and his grace which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was bestowed&lt;/span&gt; upon me was not in vain; but I laboured more abundantly than they all: yet not I, but the grace of God which was with me.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Therefore whether &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it were&lt;/span&gt; I or they, so we preach, and so ye believed.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Now if Christ be preached that he rose from the dead, how say some among you that there is no resurrection of the dead?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But if there be no resurrection of the dead, then is Christ not risen:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And if Christ be not risen, then &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; our preaching vain, and your faith &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; also vain.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Yea, and we are found false witnesses of God; because we have testified of God that he raised up Christ: whom he raised not up, if so be that the dead rise not.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For if the dead rise not, then is not Christ raised:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And if Christ be not raised, your faith &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vain; ye are yet in your sins.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Then they also which are fallen asleep in Christ are perished.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">If in this life only we have hope in Christ, we are of all men most miserable.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But now is Christ risen from the dead, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; become the firstfruits of them that slept.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For since by man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;came&lt;/span&gt; death, by man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;came&lt;/span&gt; also the resurrection of the dead.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For as in Adam all die, even so in Christ shall all be made alive.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But every man in his own order: Christ the firstfruits; afterward they that are Christ's at his coming.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Then &lt;span class='extra'&gt;cometh&lt;/span&gt; the end, when he shall have delivered up the kingdom to God, even the Father; when he shall have put down all rule and all authority and power.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">For he must reign, till he hath put all enemies under his feet.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">The last enemy &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; shall be destroyed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; death.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">For he hath put all things under his feet. But when he saith all things are put under &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him, it is&lt;/span&gt; manifest that he is excepted, which did put all things under him.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And when all things shall be subdued unto him, then shall the Son also himself be subject unto him that put all things under him, that God may be all in all.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Else what shall they do which are baptized for the dead, if the dead rise not at all? why are they then baptized for the dead?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">And why stand we in jeopardy every hour?</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">I protest by your rejoicing which I have in Christ Jesus our Lord, I die daily.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">If after the manner of men I have fought with beasts at Ephesus, what advantageth it me, if the dead rise not? let us eat and drink; for to morrow we die.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Be not deceived: evil communications corrupt good manners.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Awake to righteousness, and sin not; for some have not the knowledge of God: I speak &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; to your shame.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">But some &lt;span class='extra'&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; will say, How are the dead raised up? and with what body do they come?</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Thou&lt;/span&gt; fool, that which thou sowest is not quickened, except it die:</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">And that which thou sowest, thou sowest not that body that shall be, but bare grain, it may chance of wheat, or of some other &lt;span class='extra'&gt;grain&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">But God giveth it a body as it hath pleased him, and to every seed his own body.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">All flesh &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not the same flesh: but &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; one &lt;span class='extra'&gt;kind of&lt;/span&gt; flesh of men, another flesh of beasts, another of fishes, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; another of birds.</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;There are&lt;/span&gt; also celestial bodies, and bodies terrestrial: but the glory of the celestial &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; one, and the &lt;span class='extra'&gt;glory&lt;/span&gt; of the terrestrial &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; another.</verse>
      <verse number="41" id="v41">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;There is&lt;/span&gt; one glory of the sun, and another glory of the moon, and another glory of the stars: for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; star differeth from &lt;span class='extra'&gt;another&lt;/span&gt; star in glory.</verse>
      <verse number="42" id="v42">So also &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the resurrection of the dead. It is sown in corruption; it is raised in incorruption:</verse>
      <verse number="43" id="v43">It is sown in dishonour; it is raised in glory: it is sown in weakness; it is raised in power:</verse>
      <verse number="44" id="v44">It is sown a natural body; it is raised a spiritual body. There is a natural body, and there is a spiritual body.</verse>
      <verse number="45" id="v45">And so it is written, The first man Adam was made a living soul; the last Adam &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was made&lt;/span&gt; a quickening spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="46" id="v46">Howbeit that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; not first which is spiritual, but that which is natural; and afterward that which is spiritual.</verse>
      <verse number="47" id="v47">The first man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; of the earth, earthy: the second man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the Lord from heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="48" id="v48">As &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the earthy, such &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they also that are earthy: and as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the heavenly, such &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they also that are heavenly.</verse>
      <verse number="49" id="v49">And as we have borne the image of the earthy, we shall also bear the image of the heavenly.</verse>
      <verse number="50" id="v50">Now this I say, brethren, that flesh and blood cannot inherit the kingdom of God; neither doth corruption inherit incorruption.</verse>
      <verse number="51" id="v51">Behold, I shew you a mystery; We shall not all sleep, but we shall all be changed,</verse>
      <verse number="52" id="v52">In a moment, in the twinkling of an eye, at the last trump: for the trumpet shall sound, and the dead shall be raised incorruptible, and we shall be changed.</verse>
      <verse number="53" id="v53">For this corruptible must put on incorruption, and this mortal &lt;span class='extra'&gt;must&lt;/span&gt; put on immortality.</verse>
      <verse number="54" id="v54">So when this corruptible shall have put on incorruption, and this mortal shall have put on immortality, then shall be brought to pass the saying that is written, Death is swallowed up in victory.</verse>
      <verse number="55" id="v55">O death, where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy sting? O grave, where &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; thy victory?</verse>
      <verse number="56" id="v56">The sting of death &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; sin; and the strength of sin &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the law.</verse>
      <verse number="57" id="v57">But thanks &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; to God, which giveth us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="58" id="v58">Therefore, my beloved brethren, be ye stedfast, unmoveable, always abounding in the work of the Lord, forasmuch as ye know that your labour is not in vain in the Lord.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>