<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="21" nextChapter="1corinthians_5.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 5" prevChapter="1corinthians_3.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 3" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Let a man so account of us, as of the ministers of Christ, and stewards of the mysteries of God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Moreover it is required in stewards, that a man be found faithful.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But with me it is a very small thing that I should be judged of you, or of man's judgment: yea, I judge not mine own self.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For I know nothing by myself; yet am I not hereby justified: but he that judgeth me is the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Therefore judge nothing before the time, until the Lord come, who both will bring to light the hidden things of darkness, and will make manifest the counsels of the hearts: and then shall every man have praise of God.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And these things, brethren, I have in a figure transferred to myself and &lt;i&gt;to&lt;/i&gt; Apollos for your sakes; that ye might learn in us not to think &lt;i&gt;of men&lt;/i&gt; above that which is written, that no one of you be puffed up for one against another.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For who maketh thee to differ &lt;i&gt;from another&lt;/i&gt;? and what hast thou that thou didst not receive? now if thou didst receive &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, why dost thou glory, as if thou hadst not received &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Now ye are full, now ye are rich, ye have reigned as kings without us: and I would to God ye did reign, that we also might reign with you.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For I think that God hath set forth us the apostles last, as it were appointed to death: for we are made a spectacle unto the world, and to angels, and to men.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">We &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; fools for Christ's sake, but ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; wise in Christ; we &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; weak, but ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; strong; ye &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; honourable, but we &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; despised.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Even unto this present hour we both hunger, and thirst, and are naked, and are buffeted, and have no certain dwellingplace;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And labour, working with our own hands: being reviled, we bless; being persecuted, we suffer it:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Being defamed, we intreat: we are made as the filth of the world, &lt;i&gt;and are&lt;/i&gt; the offscouring of all things unto this day.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I write not these things to shame you, but as my beloved sons I warn &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For though ye have ten thousand instructors in Christ, yet &lt;i&gt;have ye&lt;/i&gt; not many fathers: for in Christ Jesus I have begotten you through the gospel.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Wherefore I beseech you, be ye followers of me.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For this cause have I sent unto you Timotheus, who is my beloved son, and faithful in the Lord, who shall bring you into remembrance of my ways which be in Christ, as I teach every where in every church.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Now some are puffed up, as though I would not come to you.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But I will come to you shortly, if the Lord will, and will know, not the speech of them which are puffed up, but the power.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For the kingdom of God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; not in word, but in power.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">What will ye? shall I come unto you with a rod, or in love, and &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; the spirit of meekness?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>