<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="27" nextChapter="1corinthians_10.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 10" prevChapter="1corinthians_8.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 8" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Am I not an apostle? am I not free? have I not seen Jesus Christ our Lord? are not ye my work in the Lord?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">If I be not an apostle unto others, yet doubtless I am to you: for the seal of mine apostleship are ye in the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Mine answer to them that do examine me is this,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Have we not power to eat and to drink?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Have we not power to lead about a sister, a wife, as well as other apostles, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; the brethren of the Lord, and Cephas?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Or I only and Barnabas, have not we power to forbear working?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Who goeth a warfare any time at his own charges? who planteth a vineyard, and eateth not of the fruit thereof? or who feedeth a flock, and eateth not of the milk of the flock?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Say I these things as a man? or saith not the law the same also?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For it is written in the law of Moses, Thou shalt not muzzle the mouth of the ox that treadeth out the corn. Doth God take care for oxen?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Or saith he &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; altogether for our sakes? For our sakes, no doubt, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; is written: that he that ploweth should plow in hope; and that he that thresheth in hope should be partaker of his hope.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">If we have sown unto you spiritual things, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is it&lt;/span&gt; a great thing if we shall reap your carnal things?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">If others be partakers of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; power over you, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not we rather? Nevertheless we have not used this power; but suffer all things, lest we should hinder the gospel of Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Do ye not know that they which minister about holy things live &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of the things&lt;/span&gt; of the temple? and they which wait at the altar are partakers with the altar?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Even so hath the Lord ordained that they which preach the gospel should live of the gospel.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But I have used none of these things: neither have I written these things, that it should be so done unto me: for &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it were&lt;/span&gt; better for me to die, than that any man should make my glorying void.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For though I preach the gospel, I have nothing to glory of: for necessity is laid upon me; yea, woe is unto me, if I preach not the gospel!</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For if I do this thing willingly, I have a reward: but if against my will, a dispensation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of the gospel&lt;/span&gt; is committed unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">What is my reward then? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;Verily&lt;/span&gt; that, when I preach the gospel, I may make the gospel of Christ without charge, that I abuse not my power in the gospel.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For though I be free from all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;, yet have I made myself servant unto all, that I might gain the more.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And unto the Jews I became as a Jew, that I might gain the Jews; to them that are under the law, as under the law, that I might gain them that are under the law;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">To them that are without law, as without law, (being not without law to God, but under the law to Christ,) that I might gain them that are without law.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">To the weak became I as weak, that I might gain the weak: I am made all things to all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;, that I might by all means save some.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And this I do for the gospel's sake, that I might be partaker thereof with &lt;span class='extra'&gt;you&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Know ye not that they which run in a race run all, but one receiveth the prize? So run, that ye may obtain.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And every man that striveth for the mastery is temperate in all things. Now they &lt;span class='extra'&gt;do it&lt;/span&gt; to obtain a corruptible crown; but we an incorruptible.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">I therefore so run, not as uncertainly; so fight I, not as one that beateth the air:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">But I keep under my body, and bring &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; into subjection: lest that by any means, when I have preached to others, I myself should be a castaway.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>