<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="23" nextChapter="1corinthians_4.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 4" prevChapter="1corinthians_2.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 2" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And I, brethren, could not speak unto you as unto spiritual, but as unto carnal, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; as unto babes in Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I have fed you with milk, and not with meat: for hitherto ye were not able &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to bear it&lt;/span&gt;, neither yet now are ye able.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For ye are yet carnal: for whereas &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; among you envying, and strife, and divisions, are ye not carnal, and walk as men?</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For while one saith, I am of Paul; and another, I &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; of Apollos; are ye not carnal?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Who then is Paul, and who &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Apollos, but ministers by whom ye believed, even as the Lord gave to every man?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I have planted, Apollos watered; but God gave the increase.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">So then neither is he that planteth any thing, neither he that watereth; but God that giveth the increase.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Now he that planteth and he that watereth are one: and every man shall receive his own reward according to his own labour.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For we are labourers together with God: ye are God's husbandry, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ye are&lt;/span&gt; God's building.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">According to the grace of God which is given unto me, as a wise masterbuilder, I have laid the foundation, and another buildeth thereon. But let every man take heed how he buildeth thereupon.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For other foundation can no man lay than that is laid, which is Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Now if any man build upon this foundation gold, silver, precious stones, wood, hay, stubble;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Every man's work shall be made manifest: for the day shall declare it, because it shall be revealed by fire; and the fire shall try every man's work of what sort it is.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">If any man's work abide which he hath built thereupon, he shall receive a reward.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">If any man's work shall be burned, he shall suffer loss: but he himself shall be saved; yet so as by fire.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Know ye not that ye are the temple of God, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the Spirit of God dwelleth in you?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">If any man defile the temple of God, him shall God destroy; for the temple of God is holy, which &lt;span class="extra"&gt;temple&lt;/span&gt; ye are.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Let no man deceive himself. If any man among you seemeth to be wise in this world, let him become a fool, that he may be wise.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For the wisdom of this world is foolishness with God. For it is written, He taketh the wise in their own craftiness.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And again, The Lord knoweth the thoughts of the wise, that they are vain.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Therefore let no man glory in men. For all things are yours;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Whether Paul, or Apollos, or Cephas, or the world, or life, or death, or things present, or things to come; all are yours;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And ye are Christ's; and Christ &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; God's.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>