<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="16" verseCount="24" nextChapter="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians 1" prevChapter="1corinthians_15.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 15" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now concerning the collection for the saints, as I have given order to the churches of Galatia, even so do ye.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Upon the first &lt;i&gt;day&lt;/i&gt; of the week let every one of you lay by him in store, as &lt;i&gt;God&lt;/i&gt; hath prospered him, that there be no gatherings when I come.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And when I come, whomsoever ye shall approve by &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; letters, them will I send to bring your liberality unto Jerusalem.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And if it be meet that I go also, they shall go with me.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Now I will come unto you, when I shall pass through Macedonia: for I do pass through Macedonia.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And it may be that I will abide, yea, and winter with you, that ye may bring me on my journey whithersoever I go.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For I will not see you now by the way; but I trust to tarry a while with you, if the Lord permit.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But I will tarry at Ephesus until Pentecost.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For a great door and effectual is opened unto me, and &lt;i&gt;there are&lt;/i&gt; many adversaries.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Now if Timotheus come, see that he may be with you without fear: for he worketh the work of the Lord, as I also &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Let no man therefore despise him: but conduct him forth in peace, that he may come unto me: for I look for him with the brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">As touching &lt;i&gt;our&lt;/i&gt; brother Apollos, I greatly desired him to come unto you with the brethren: but his will was not at all to come at this time; but he will come when he shall have convenient time.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Watch ye, stand fast in the faith, quit you like men, be strong.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Let all your things be done with charity.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I beseech you, brethren, (ye know the house of Stephanas, that it is the firstfruits of Achaia, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; they have addicted themselves to the ministry of the saints,)</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">That ye submit yourselves unto such, and to every one that helpeth with &lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt;, and laboureth.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">I am glad of the coming of Stephanas and Fortunatus and Achaicus: for that which was lacking on your part they have supplied.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For they have refreshed my spirit and yours: therefore acknowledge ye them that are such.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">The churches of Asia salute you. Aquila and Priscilla salute you much in the Lord, with the church that is in their house.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">All the brethren greet you. Greet ye one another with an holy kiss.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The salutation of &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; Paul with mine own hand.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">If any man love not the Lord Jesus Christ, let him be Anathema Maran-atha.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; with you.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">My love &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; with you all in Christ Jesus. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>