<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="13" nextChapter="1corinthians_9.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 9" prevChapter="1corinthians_7.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 7" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now as touching things offered unto idols, we know that we all have knowledge. Knowledge puffeth up, but charity edifieth.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And if any man think that he knoweth any thing, he knoweth nothing yet as he ought to know.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But if any man love God, the same is known of him.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">As concerning therefore the eating of those things that are offered in sacrifice unto idols, we know that an idol &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; nothing in the world, and that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; none other God but one.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For though there be that are called gods, whether in heaven or in earth, (as there be gods many, and lords many,)</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But to us &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is but&lt;/span&gt; one God, the Father, of whom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all things, and we in him; and one Lord Jesus Christ, by whom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all things, and we by him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Howbeit &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there is&lt;/span&gt; not in every man that knowledge: for some with conscience of the idol unto this hour eat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; as a thing offered unto an idol; and their conscience being weak is defiled.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But meat commendeth us not to God: for neither, if we eat, are we the better; neither, if we eat not, are we the worse.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But take heed lest by any means this liberty of yours become a stumblingblock to them that are weak.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For if any man see thee which hast knowledge sit at meat in the idol's temple, shall not the conscience of him which is weak be emboldened to eat those things which are offered to idols;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And through thy knowledge shall the weak brother perish, for whom Christ died?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But when ye sin so against the brethren, and wound their weak conscience, ye sin against Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Wherefore, if meat make my brother to offend, I will eat no flesh while the world standeth, lest I make my brother to offend.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>