<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="31" nextChapter="1corinthians_2.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 2" prevChapter="romans_16.html" prevTitle="Romans 16" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Paul, called &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; an apostle of Jesus Christ through the will of God, and Sosthenes &lt;span class="extra"&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; brother,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Unto the church of God which is at Corinth, to them that are sanctified in Christ Jesus, called &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; saints, with all that in every place call upon the name of Jesus Christ our Lord, both theirs and ours:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Grace &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; unto you, and peace, from God our Father, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I thank my God always on your behalf, for the grace of God which is given you by Jesus Christ;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">That in every thing ye are enriched by him, in all utterance, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; all knowledge;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Even as the testimony of Christ was confirmed in you:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">So that ye come behind in no gift; waiting for the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Who shall also confirm you unto the end, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that ye may be&lt;/span&gt; blameless in the day of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; faithful, by whom ye were called unto the fellowship of his Son Jesus Christ our Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Now I beseech you, brethren, by the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, that ye all speak the same thing, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; there be no divisions among you; but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; ye be perfectly joined together in the same mind and in the same judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For it hath been declared unto me of you, my brethren, by them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which are of the house&lt;/span&gt; of Chloe, that there are contentions among you.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Now this I say, that every one of you saith, I am of Paul; and I of Apollos; and I of Cephas; and I of Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Is Christ divided? was Paul crucified for you? or were ye baptized in the name of Paul?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I thank God that I baptized none of you, but Crispus and Gaius;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Lest any should say that I had baptized in mine own name.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And I baptized also the household of Stephanas: besides, I know not whether I baptized any other.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For Christ sent me not to baptize, but to preach the gospel: not with wisdom of words, lest the cross of Christ should be made of none effect.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For the preaching of the cross is to them that perish foolishness; but unto us which are saved it is the power of God.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For it is written, I will destroy the wisdom of the wise, and will bring to nothing the understanding of the prudent.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the wise? where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the scribe? where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the disputer of this world? hath not God made foolish the wisdom of this world?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For after that in the wisdom of God the world by wisdom knew not God, it pleased God by the foolishness of preaching to save them that believe.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">For the Jews require a sign, and the Greeks seek after wisdom:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But we preach Christ crucified, unto the Jews a stumblingblock, and unto the Greeks foolishness;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">But unto them which are called, both Jews and Greeks, Christ the power of God, and the wisdom of God.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Because the foolishness of God is wiser than men; and the weakness of God is stronger than men.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For ye see your calling, brethren, how that not many wise men after the flesh, not many mighty, not many noble, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are called&lt;/span&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">But God hath chosen the foolish things of the world to confound the wise; and God hath chosen the weak things of the world to confound the things which are mighty;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And base things of the world, and things which are despised, hath God chosen, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;yea&lt;/span&gt;, and things which are not, to bring to nought things that are:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">That no flesh should glory in his presence.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">But of him are ye in Christ Jesus, who of God is made unto us wisdom, and righteousness, and sanctification, and redemption:</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">That, according as it is written, He that glorieth, let him glory in the Lord.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>