<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="34" nextChapter="1corinthians_12.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 12" prevChapter="1corinthians_10.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 10" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Be ye followers of me, even as I also &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; of Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Now I praise you, brethren, that ye remember me in all things, and keep the ordinances, as I delivered &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; to you.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But I would have you know, that the head of every man is Christ; and the head of the woman &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the man; and the head of Christ &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; God.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Every man praying or prophesying, having &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; head covered, dishonoureth his head.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But every woman that prayeth or prophesieth with &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; head uncovered dishonoureth her head: for that is even all one as if she were shaven.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For if the woman be not covered, let her also be shorn: but if it be a shame for a woman to be shorn or shaven, let her be covered.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For a man indeed ought not to cover &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; head, forasmuch as he is the image and glory of God: but the woman is the glory of the man.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For the man is not of the woman; but the woman of the man.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Neither was the man created for the woman; but the woman for the man.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For this cause ought the woman to have power on &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; head because of the angels.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Nevertheless neither is the man without the woman, neither the woman without the man, in the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For as the woman &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; of the man, even so &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the man also by the woman; but all things of God.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Judge in yourselves: is it comely that a woman pray unto God uncovered?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Doth not even nature itself teach you, that, if a man have long hair, it is a shame unto him?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But if a woman have long hair, it is a glory to her: for &lt;i&gt;her&lt;/i&gt; hair is given her for a covering.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But if any man seem to be contentious, we have no such custom, neither the churches of God.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Now in this that I declare &lt;i&gt;unto you&lt;/i&gt; I praise &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; not, that ye come together not for the better, but for the worse.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For first of all, when ye come together in the church, I hear that there be divisions among you; and I partly believe it.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For there must be also heresies among you, that they which are approved may be made manifest among you.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">When ye come together therefore into one place, &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; is not to eat the Lord's supper.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For in eating every one taketh before &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; his own supper: and one is hungry, and another is drunken.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">What? have ye not houses to eat and to drink in? or despise ye the church of God, and shame them that have not? What shall I say to you? shall I praise you in this? I praise &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; not.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For I have received of the Lord that which also I delivered unto you, That the Lord Jesus the &lt;i&gt;same&lt;/i&gt; night in which he was betrayed took bread:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And when he had given thanks, he brake &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, and said, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Take, eat: this is my body, which is broken for you: this do in remembrance of me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">After the same manner also &lt;i&gt;he took&lt;/i&gt; the cup, when he had supped, saying, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;This cup is the new testament in my blood: this do ye, as oft as ye drink &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;, in remembrance of me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For as often as ye eat this bread, and drink this cup, ye do shew the Lord's death till he come.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Wherefore whosoever shall eat this bread, and drink &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; cup of the Lord, unworthily, shall be guilty of the body and blood of the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">But let a man examine himself, and so let him eat of &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; bread, and drink of &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; cup.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For he that eateth and drinketh unworthily, eateth and drinketh damnation to himself, not discerning the Lord's body.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">For this cause many &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; weak and sickly among you, and many sleep.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">For if we would judge ourselves, we should not be judged.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">But when we are judged, we are chastened of the Lord, that we should not be condemned with the world.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Wherefore, my brethren, when ye come together to eat, tarry one for another.</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">And if any man hunger, let him eat at home; that ye come not together unto condemnation. And the rest will I set in order when I come.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>