<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="31" nextChapter="1corinthians_13.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 13" prevChapter="1corinthians_11.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 11" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now concerning spiritual &lt;span class="extra"&gt;gifts&lt;/span&gt;, brethren, I would not have you ignorant.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Ye know that ye were Gentiles, carried away unto these dumb idols, even as ye were led.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Wherefore I give you to understand, that no man speaking by the Spirit of God calleth Jesus accursed: and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; no man can say that Jesus is the Lord, but by the Holy Ghost.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Now there are diversities of gifts, but the same Spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And there are differences of administrations, but the same Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And there are diversities of operations, but it is the same God which worketh all in all.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But the manifestation of the Spirit is given to every man to profit withal.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For to one is given by the Spirit the word of wisdom; to another the word of knowledge by the same Spirit;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">To another faith by the same Spirit; to another the gifts of healing by the same Spirit;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">To another the working of miracles; to another prophecy; to another discerning of spirits; to another &lt;span class="extra"&gt;divers&lt;/span&gt; kinds of tongues; to another the interpretation of tongues:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But all these worketh that one and the selfsame Spirit, dividing to every man severally as he will.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For as the body is one, and hath many members, and all the members of that one body, being many, are one body: so also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For by one Spirit are we all baptized into one body, whether &lt;span class="extra"&gt;we be&lt;/span&gt; Jews or Gentiles, whether &lt;span class="extra"&gt;we be&lt;/span&gt; bond or free; and have been all made to drink into one Spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For the body is not one member, but many.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">If the foot shall say, Because I am not the hand, I am not of the body; is it therefore not of the body?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And if the ear shall say, Because I am not the eye, I am not of the body; is it therefore not of the body?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">If the whole body &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; an eye, where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the hearing? If the whole &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; hearing, where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the smelling?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But now hath God set the members every one of them in the body, as it hath pleased him.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And if they were all one member, where &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; the body?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But now &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are they&lt;/span&gt; many members, yet but one body.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the eye cannot say unto the hand, I have no need of thee: nor again the head to the feet, I have no need of you.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Nay, much more those members of the body, which seem to be more feeble, are necessary:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And those &lt;span class="extra"&gt;members&lt;/span&gt; of the body, which we think to be less honourable, upon these we bestow more abundant honour; and our uncomely &lt;span class="extra"&gt;parts&lt;/span&gt; have more abundant comeliness.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For our comely &lt;span class="extra"&gt;parts&lt;/span&gt; have no need: but God hath tempered the body together, having given more abundant honour to that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;part&lt;/span&gt; which lacked:</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">That there should be no schism in the body; but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; the members should have the same care one for another.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And whether one member suffer, all the members suffer with it; or one member be honoured, all the members rejoice with it.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Now ye are the body of Christ, and members in particular.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And God hath set some in the church, first apostles, secondarily prophets, thirdly teachers, after that miracles, then gifts of healings, helps, governments, diversities of tongues.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Are&lt;/span&gt; all apostles? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all prophets? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all teachers? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; all workers of miracles?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Have all the gifts of healing? do all speak with tongues? do all interpret?</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">But covet earnestly the best gifts: and yet shew I unto you a more excellent way.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>