<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="46" name="1 Corinthians" bookPage="1corinthians.html" title="1 Corinthians" chapterCount="16" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2corinthians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians" prevBook="romans_1.html" prevTitle="Romans">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="33" nextChapter="1corinthians_11.html" nextTitle="1 Corinthians 11" prevChapter="1corinthians_9.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians 9" chapterPage="1corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover, brethren, I would not that ye should be ignorant, how that all our fathers were under the cloud, and all passed through the sea;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And were all baptized unto Moses in the cloud and in the sea;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And did all eat the same spiritual meat;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And did all drink the same spiritual drink: for they drank of that spiritual Rock that followed them: and that Rock was Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But with many of them God was not well pleased: for they were overthrown in the wilderness.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Now these things were our examples, to the intent we should not lust after evil things, as they also lusted.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Neither be ye idolaters, as &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; some of them; as it is written, The people sat down to eat and drink, and rose up to play.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Neither let us commit fornication, as some of them committed, and fell in one day three and twenty thousand.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Neither let us tempt Christ, as some of them also tempted, and were destroyed of serpents.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Neither murmur ye, as some of them also murmured, and were destroyed of the destroyer.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Now all these things happened unto them for ensamples: and they are written for our admonition, upon whom the ends of the world are come.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Wherefore let him that thinketh he standeth take heed lest he fall.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">There hath no temptation taken you but such as is common to man: but God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; faithful, who will not suffer you to be tempted above that ye are able; but will with the temptation also make a way to escape, that ye may be able to bear &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Wherefore, my dearly beloved, flee from idolatry.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">I speak as to wise men; judge ye what I say.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The cup of blessing which we bless, is it not the communion of the blood of Christ? The bread which we break, is it not the communion of the body of Christ?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For we &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; many are one bread, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; one body: for we are all partakers of that one bread.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Behold Israel after the flesh: are not they which eat of the sacrifices partakers of the altar?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">What say I then? that the idol is any thing, or that which is offered in sacrifice to idols is any thing?</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But &lt;i&gt;I&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;say&lt;/i&gt;, that the things which the Gentiles sacrifice, they sacrifice to devils, and not to God: and I would not that ye should have fellowship with devils.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Ye cannot drink the cup of the Lord, and the cup of devils: ye cannot be partakers of the Lord's table, and of the table of devils.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Do we provoke the Lord to jealousy? are we stronger than he?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">All things are lawful for me, but all things are not expedient: all things are lawful for me, but all things edify not.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Let no man seek his own, but every man another's &lt;i&gt;wealth&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Whatsoever is sold in the shambles, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; eat, asking no question for conscience sake:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For the earth &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the Lord's, and the fulness thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">If any of them that believe not bid you &lt;i&gt;to a feast&lt;/i&gt;, and ye be disposed to go; whatsoever is set before you, eat, asking no question for conscience sake.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">But if any man say unto you, This is offered in sacrifice unto idols, eat not for his sake that shewed it, and for conscience sake: for the earth &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the Lord's, and the fulness thereof:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Conscience, I say, not thine own, but of the other: for why is my liberty judged of another &lt;i&gt;man's&lt;/i&gt; conscience?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">For if I by grace be a partaker, why am I evil spoken of for that for which I give thanks?</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">Whether therefore ye eat, or drink, or whatsoever ye do, do all to the glory of God.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">Give none offence, neither to the Jews, nor to the Gentiles, nor to the church of God:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Even as I please all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt; in all &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt;, not seeking mine own profit, but the &lt;i&gt;profit&lt;/i&gt; of many, that they may be saved.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>