<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="47" name="2 Corinthians" bookPage="2corinthians.html" title="2 Corinthians" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="galatians_1.html" nextTitle="Galatians" prevBook="1corinthians_1.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="21" nextChapter="2corinthians_13.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians 13" prevChapter="2corinthians_11.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians 11" chapterPage="2corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">It is not expedient for me doubtless to glory. I will come to visions and revelations of the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I knew a man in Christ above fourteen years ago, (whether in the body, I cannot tell; or whether out of the body, I cannot tell: God knoweth;) such an one caught up to the third heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I knew such a man, (whether in the body, or out of the body, I cannot tell: God knoweth;)</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">How that he was caught up into paradise, and heard unspeakable words, which it is not lawful for a man to utter.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Of such an one will I glory: yet of myself I will not glory, but in mine infirmities.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For though I would desire to glory, I shall not be a fool; for I will say the truth: but &lt;i&gt;now&lt;/i&gt; I forbear, lest any man should think of me above that which he seeth me &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt;, or &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; he heareth of me.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And lest I should be exalted above measure through the abundance of the revelations, there was given to me a thorn in the flesh, the messenger of Satan to buffet me, lest I should be exalted above measure.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For this thing I besought the Lord thrice, that it might depart from me.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And he said unto me, &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;My grace is sufficient for thee: for my strength is made perfect in weakness.&lt;/span&gt; Most gladly therefore will I rather glory in my infirmities, that the power of Christ may rest upon me.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Therefore I take pleasure in infirmities, in reproaches, in necessities, in persecutions, in distresses for Christ's sake: for when I am weak, then am I strong.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">I am become a fool in glorying; ye have compelled me: for I ought to have been commended of you: for in nothing am I behind the very chiefest apostles, though I be nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Truly the signs of an apostle were wrought among you in all patience, in signs, and wonders, and mighty deeds.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For what is it wherein ye were inferior to other churches, except &lt;i&gt;it be&lt;/i&gt; that I myself was not burdensome to you? forgive me this wrong.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Behold, the third time I am ready to come to you; and I will not be burdensome to you: for I seek not yours, but you: for the children ought not to lay up for the parents, but the parents for the children.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And I will very gladly spend and be spent for you; though the more abundantly I love you, the less I be loved.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But be it so, I did not burden you: nevertheless, being crafty, I caught you with guile.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Did I make a gain of you by any of them whom I sent unto you?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">I desired Titus, and with &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt; I sent a brother. Did Titus make a gain of you? walked we not in the same spirit? &lt;i&gt;walked we&lt;/i&gt; not in the same steps?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Again, think ye that we excuse ourselves unto you? we speak before God in Christ: but &lt;i&gt;we do&lt;/i&gt; all things, dearly beloved, for your edifying.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For I fear, lest, when I come, I shall not find you such as I would, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I shall be found unto you such as ye would not: lest &lt;i&gt;there be&lt;/i&gt; debates, envyings, wraths, strifes, backbitings, whisperings, swellings, tumults:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;i&gt;And&lt;/i&gt; lest, when I come again, my God will humble me among you, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I shall bewail many which have sinned already, and have not repented of the uncleanness and fornication and lasciviousness which they have committed.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>