<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="47" name="2 Corinthians" bookPage="2corinthians.html" title="2 Corinthians" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="galatians_1.html" nextTitle="Galatians" prevBook="1corinthians_1.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="14" nextChapter="galatians_1.html" nextTitle="Galatians 1" prevChapter="2corinthians_12.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians 12" chapterPage="2corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the third &lt;i&gt;time&lt;/i&gt; I am coming to you. In the mouth of two or three witnesses shall every word be established.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I told you before, and foretell you, as if I were present, the second time; and being absent now I write to them which heretofore have sinned, and to all other, that, if I come again, I will not spare:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Since ye seek a proof of Christ speaking in me, which to you-ward is not weak, but is mighty in you.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For though he was crucified through weakness, yet he liveth by the power of God. For we also are weak in him, but we shall live with him by the power of God toward you.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Examine yourselves, whether ye be in the faith; prove your own selves. Know ye not your own selves, how that Jesus Christ is in you, except ye be reprobates?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But I trust that ye shall know that we are not reprobates.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Now I pray to God that ye do no evil; not that we should appear approved, but that ye should do that which is honest, though we be as reprobates.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For we can do nothing against the truth, but for the truth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For we are glad, when we are weak, and ye are strong: and this also we wish, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; your perfection.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Therefore I write these things being absent, lest being present I should use sharpness, according to the power which the Lord hath given me to edification, and not to destruction.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Finally, brethren, farewell. Be perfect, be of good comfort, be of one mind, live in peace; and the God of love and peace shall be with you.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Greet one another with an holy kiss.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">All the saints salute you.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">The grace of the Lord Jesus Christ, and the love of God, and the communion of the Holy Ghost, &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; with you all. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>