<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="47" name="2 Corinthians" bookPage="2corinthians.html" title="2 Corinthians" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="galatians_1.html" nextTitle="Galatians" prevBook="1corinthians_1.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="33" nextChapter="2corinthians_12.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians 12" prevChapter="2corinthians_10.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians 10" chapterPage="2corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Would to God ye could bear with me a little in &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; folly: and indeed bear with me.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For I am jealous over you with godly jealousy: for I have espoused you to one husband, that I may present &lt;i&gt;you as&lt;/i&gt; a chaste virgin to Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But I fear, lest by any means, as the serpent beguiled Eve through his subtilty, so your minds should be corrupted from the simplicity that is in Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For if he that cometh preacheth another Jesus, whom we have not preached, or &lt;i&gt;if&lt;/i&gt; ye receive another spirit, which ye have not received, or another gospel, which ye have not accepted, ye might well bear with &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For I suppose I was not a whit behind the very chiefest apostles.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But though &lt;i&gt;I be&lt;/i&gt; rude in speech, yet not in knowledge; but we have been throughly made manifest among you in all things.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Have I committed an offence in abasing myself that ye might be exalted, because I have preached to you the gospel of God freely?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I robbed other churches, taking wages &lt;i&gt;of them&lt;/i&gt;, to do you service.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And when I was present with you, and wanted, I was chargeable to no man: for that which was lacking to me the brethren which came from Macedonia supplied: and in all &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; I have kept myself from being burdensome unto you, and &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; will I keep &lt;i&gt;myself&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">As the truth of Christ is in me, no man shall stop me of this boasting in the regions of Achaia.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Wherefore? because I love you not? God knoweth.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But what I do, that I will do, that I may cut off occasion from them which desire occasion; that wherein they glory, they may be found even as we.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For such &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; false apostles, deceitful workers, transforming themselves into the apostles of Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And no marvel; for Satan himself is transformed into an angel of light.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Therefore &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; no great thing if his ministers also be transformed as the ministers of righteousness; whose end shall be according to their works.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">I say again, Let no man think me a fool; if otherwise, yet as a fool receive me, that I may boast myself a little.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">That which I speak, I speak &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; not after the Lord, but as it were foolishly, in this confidence of boasting.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Seeing that many glory after the flesh, I will glory also.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For ye suffer fools gladly, seeing ye &lt;i&gt;yourselves&lt;/i&gt; are wise.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For ye suffer, if a man bring you into bondage, if a man devour &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;, if a man take &lt;i&gt;of you&lt;/i&gt;, if a man exalt himself, if a man smite you on the face.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">I speak as concerning reproach, as though we had been weak. Howbeit whereinsoever any is bold, (I speak foolishly,) I am bold also.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Are they Hebrews? so &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I. Are they Israelites? so &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I. Are they the seed of Abraham? so &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; I.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Are they ministers of Christ? (I speak as a fool) I &lt;i&gt;am&lt;/i&gt; more; in labours more abundant, in stripes above measure, in prisons more frequent, in deaths oft.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Of the Jews five times received I forty &lt;i&gt;stripes&lt;/i&gt; save one.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Thrice was I beaten with rods, once was I stoned, thrice I suffered shipwreck, a night and a day I have been in the deep;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;i&gt;In&lt;/i&gt; journeyings often, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; perils of waters, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; perils of robbers, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; perils by &lt;i&gt;mine own&lt;/i&gt; countrymen, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; perils by the heathen, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; perils in the city, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; perils in the wilderness, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; perils in the sea, &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; perils among false brethren;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">In weariness and painfulness, in watchings often, in hunger and thirst, in fastings often, in cold and nakedness.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Beside those things that are without, that which cometh upon me daily, the care of all the churches.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">Who is weak, and I am not weak? who is offended, and I burn not?</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">If I must needs glory, I will glory of the things which concern mine infirmities.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">The God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, which is blessed for evermore, knoweth that I lie not.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">In Damascus the governor under Aretas the king kept the city of the Damascenes with a garrison, desirous to apprehend me:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">And through a window in a basket was I let down by the wall, and escaped his hands.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>