<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="47" name="2 Corinthians" bookPage="2corinthians.html" title="2 Corinthians" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="galatians_1.html" nextTitle="Galatians" prevBook="1corinthians_1.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians">
    <chapter number="8" verseCount="24" nextChapter="2corinthians_9.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians 9" prevChapter="2corinthians_7.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians 7" chapterPage="2corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Moreover, brethren, we do you to wit of the grace of God bestowed on the churches of Macedonia;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">How that in a great trial of affliction the abundance of their joy and their deep poverty abounded unto the riches of their liberality.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For to &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; power, I bear record, yea, and beyond &lt;span class='extra'&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; power &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they were&lt;/span&gt; willing of themselves;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Praying us with much intreaty that we would receive the gift, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;take upon us&lt;/span&gt; the fellowship of the ministering to the saints.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this they did&lt;/span&gt;, not as we hoped, but first gave their own selves to the Lord, and unto us by the will of God.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Insomuch that we desired Titus, that as he had begun, so he would also finish in you the same grace also.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Therefore, as ye abound in every &lt;span class='extra'&gt;thing, in&lt;/span&gt; faith, and utterance, and knowledge, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; all diligence, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; your love to us, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;see&lt;/span&gt; that ye abound in this grace also.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I speak not by commandment, but by occasion of the forwardness of others, and to prove the sincerity of your love.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For ye know the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, that, though he was rich, yet for your sakes he became poor, that ye through his poverty might be rich.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And herein I give &lt;span class='extra'&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; advice: for this is expedient for you, who have begun before, not only to do, but also to be forward a year ago.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Now therefore perform the doing &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of it&lt;/span&gt;; that as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there was&lt;/span&gt; a readiness to will, so &lt;span class='extra'&gt;there may be&lt;/span&gt; a performance also out of that which ye have.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For if there be first a willing mind, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; accepted according to that a man hath, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; not according to that he hath not.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For &lt;span class='extra'&gt;I mean&lt;/span&gt; not that other men be eased, and ye burdened:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But by an equality, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; now at this time your abundance &lt;span class='extra'&gt;may be a supply&lt;/span&gt; for their want, that their abundance also may be &lt;span class='extra'&gt;a supply&lt;/span&gt; for your want: that there may be equality:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">As it is written, He that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;had gathered&lt;/span&gt; much had nothing over; and he that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;had gathered&lt;/span&gt; little had no lack.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But thanks &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; to God, which put the same earnest care into the heart of Titus for you.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For indeed he accepted the exhortation; but being more forward, of his own accord he went unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And we have sent with him the brother, whose praise &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in the gospel throughout all the churches;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; only, but who was also chosen of the churches to travel with us with this grace, which is administered by us to the glory of the same Lord, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;declaration of&lt;/span&gt; your ready mind:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Avoiding this, that no man should blame us in this abundance which is administered by us:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Providing for honest things, not only in the sight of the Lord, but also in the sight of men.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And we have sent with them our brother, whom we have oftentimes proved diligent in many things, but now much more diligent, upon the great confidence which &lt;span class='extra'&gt;I have&lt;/span&gt; in you.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Whether &lt;span class='extra'&gt;any do enquire&lt;/span&gt; of Titus, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he is&lt;/span&gt; my partner and fellowhelper concerning you: or our brethren &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be enquired of, they are&lt;/span&gt; the messengers of the churches, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the glory of Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Wherefore shew ye to them, and before the churches, the proof of your love, and of our boasting on your behalf.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>