<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="47" name="2 Corinthians" bookPage="2corinthians.html" title="2 Corinthians" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="galatians_1.html" nextTitle="Galatians" prevBook="1corinthians_1.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians">
    <chapter number="9" verseCount="15" nextChapter="2corinthians_10.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians 10" prevChapter="2corinthians_8.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians 8" chapterPage="2corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">For as touching the ministering to the saints, it is superfluous for me to write to you:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For I know the forwardness of your mind, for which I boast of you to them of Macedonia, that Achaia was ready a year ago; and your zeal hath provoked very many.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Yet have I sent the brethren, lest our boasting of you should be in vain in this behalf; that, as I said, ye may be ready:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Lest haply if they of Macedonia come with me, and find you unprepared, we (that we say not, ye) should be ashamed in this same confident boasting.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Therefore I thought it necessary to exhort the brethren, that they would go before unto you, and make up beforehand your bounty, whereof ye had notice before, that the same might be ready, as &lt;i&gt;a matter of&lt;/i&gt; bounty, and not as &lt;i&gt;of&lt;/i&gt; covetousness.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But this &lt;i&gt;I say&lt;/i&gt;, He which soweth sparingly shall reap also sparingly; and he which soweth bountifully shall reap also bountifully.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Every man according as he purposeth in his heart, &lt;i&gt;so let him give&lt;/i&gt;; not grudgingly, or of necessity: for God loveth a cheerful giver.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; able to make all grace abound toward you; that ye, always having all sufficiency in all &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt;, may abound to every good work:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">(As it is written, He hath dispersed abroad; he hath given to the poor: his righteousness remaineth for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Now he that ministereth seed to the sower both minister bread for &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; food, and multiply your seed sown, and increase the fruits of your righteousness;)</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Being enriched in every thing to all bountifulness, which causeth through us thanksgiving to God.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For the administration of this service not only supplieth the want of the saints, but is abundant also by many thanksgivings unto God;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Whiles by the experiment of this ministration they glorify God for your professed subjection unto the gospel of Christ, and for &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; liberal distribution unto them, and unto all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And by their prayer for you, which long after you for the exceeding grace of God in you.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Thanks &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; unto God for his unspeakable gift.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>