<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="47" name="2 Corinthians" bookPage="2corinthians.html" title="2 Corinthians" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="galatians_1.html" nextTitle="Galatians" prevBook="1corinthians_1.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians">
    <chapter number="10" verseCount="18" nextChapter="2corinthians_11.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians 11" prevChapter="2corinthians_9.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians 9" chapterPage="2corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now I Paul myself beseech you by the meekness and gentleness of Christ, who in presence &lt;span class="extra"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; base among you, but being absent am bold toward you:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">But I beseech &lt;span class="extra"&gt;you&lt;/span&gt;, that I may not be bold when I am present with that confidence, wherewith I think to be bold against some, which think of us as if we walked according to the flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For though we walk in the flesh, we do not war after the flesh:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">(For the weapons of our warfare &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; not carnal, but mighty through God to the pulling down of strong holds;)</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Casting down imaginations, and every high thing that exalteth itself against the knowledge of God, and bringing into captivity every thought to the obedience of Christ;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And having in a readiness to revenge all disobedience, when your obedience is fulfilled.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Do ye look on things after the outward appearance? If any man trust to himself that he is Christ's, let him of himself think this again, that, as he &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; Christ's, even so &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; we Christ's.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For though I should boast somewhat more of our authority, which the Lord hath given us for edification, and not for your destruction, I should not be ashamed:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">That I may not seem as if I would terrify you by letters.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; letters, say they, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; weighty and powerful; but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; bodily presence &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; weak, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; speech contemptible.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Let such an one think this, that, such as we are in word by letters when we are absent, such &lt;span class="extra"&gt;will we be&lt;/span&gt; also in deed when we are present.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For we dare not make ourselves of the number, or compare ourselves with some that commend themselves: but they measuring themselves by themselves, and comparing themselves among themselves, are not wise.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But we will not boast of things without &lt;span class="extra"&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; measure, but according to the measure of the rule which God hath distributed to us, a measure to reach even unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For we stretch not ourselves beyond &lt;span class="extra"&gt;our measure&lt;/span&gt;, as though we reached not unto you: for we are come as far as to you also in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;preaching&lt;/span&gt; the gospel of Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Not boasting of things without &lt;span class="extra"&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; measure, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that is&lt;/span&gt;, of other men's labours; but having hope, when your faith is increased, that we shall be enlarged by you according to our rule abundantly,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">To preach the gospel in the &lt;span class="extra"&gt;regions&lt;/span&gt; beyond you, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; not to boast in another man's line of things made ready to our hand.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But he that glorieth, let him glory in the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For not he that commendeth himself is approved, but whom the Lord commendeth.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>