<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="47" name="2 Corinthians" bookPage="2corinthians.html" title="2 Corinthians" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="galatians_1.html" nextTitle="Galatians" prevBook="1corinthians_1.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="18" nextChapter="2corinthians_7.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians 7" prevChapter="2corinthians_5.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians 5" chapterPage="2corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">We then, &lt;i&gt;as&lt;/i&gt; workers together &lt;i&gt;with him&lt;/i&gt;, beseech &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; also that ye receive not the grace of God in vain.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">(For he saith, I have heard thee in a time accepted, and in the day of salvation have I succoured thee: behold, now &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the accepted time; behold, now &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the day of salvation.)</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Giving no offence in any thing, that the ministry be not blamed:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But in all &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; approving ourselves as the ministers of God, in much patience, in afflictions, in necessities, in distresses,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">In stripes, in imprisonments, in tumults, in labours, in watchings, in fastings;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">By pureness, by knowledge, by longsuffering, by kindness, by the Holy Ghost, by love unfeigned,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">By the word of truth, by the power of God, by the armour of righteousness on the right hand and on the left,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">By honour and dishonour, by evil report and good report: as deceivers, and &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; true;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">As unknown, and &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; well known; as dying, and, behold, we live; as chastened, and not killed;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">As sorrowful, yet alway rejoicing; as poor, yet making many rich; as having nothing, and &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; possessing all things.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">O &lt;i&gt;ye&lt;/i&gt; Corinthians, our mouth is open unto you, our heart is enlarged.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Ye are not straitened in us, but ye are straitened in your own bowels.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Now for a recompence in the same, (I speak as unto &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; children,) be ye also enlarged.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Be ye not unequally yoked together with unbelievers: for what fellowship hath righteousness with unrighteousness? and what communion hath light with darkness?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And what concord hath Christ with Belial? or what part hath he that believeth with an infidel?</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And what agreement hath the temple of God with idols? for ye are the temple of the living God; as God hath said, I will dwell in them, and walk in &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;; and I will be their God, and they shall be my people.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Wherefore come out from among them, and be ye separate, saith the Lord, and touch not the unclean &lt;i&gt;thing&lt;/i&gt;; and I will receive you,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And will be a Father unto you, and ye shall be my sons and daughters, saith the Lord Almighty.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>