<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="47" name="2 Corinthians" bookPage="2corinthians.html" title="2 Corinthians" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="galatians_1.html" nextTitle="Galatians" prevBook="1corinthians_1.html" prevTitle="1 Corinthians">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="18" nextChapter="2corinthians_4.html" nextTitle="2 Corinthians 4" prevChapter="2corinthians_2.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians 2" chapterPage="2corinthians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Do we begin again to commend ourselves? or need we, as some &lt;i&gt;others&lt;/i&gt;, epistles of commendation to you, or &lt;i&gt;letters&lt;/i&gt; of commendation from you?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Ye are our epistle written in our hearts, known and read of all men:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;i&gt;Forasmuch as ye are&lt;/i&gt; manifestly declared to be the epistle of Christ ministered by us, written not with ink, but with the Spirit of the living God; not in tables of stone, but in fleshy tables of the heart.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And such trust have we through Christ to God-ward:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Not that we are sufficient of ourselves to think any thing as of ourselves; but our sufficiency &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; of God;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Who also hath made us able ministers of the new testament; not of the letter, but of the spirit: for the letter killeth, but the spirit giveth life.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But if the ministration of death, written &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; engraven in stones, was glorious, so that the children of Israel could not stedfastly behold the face of Moses for the glory of his countenance; which &lt;i&gt;glory&lt;/i&gt; was to be done away:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">How shall not the ministration of the spirit be rather glorious?</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For if the ministration of condemnation &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; glory, much more doth the ministration of righteousness exceed in glory.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For even that which was made glorious had no glory in this respect, by reason of the glory that excelleth.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For if that which is done away &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; glorious, much more that which remaineth &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; glorious.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Seeing then that we have such hope, we use great plainness of speech:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And not as Moses, &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; put a vail over his face, that the children of Israel could not stedfastly look to the end of that which is abolished:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But their minds were blinded: for until this day remaineth the same vail untaken away in the reading of the old testament; which &lt;i&gt;vail&lt;/i&gt; is done away in Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But even unto this day, when Moses is read, the vail is upon their heart.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Nevertheless when it shall turn to the Lord, the vail shall be taken away.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Now the Lord is that Spirit: and where the Spirit of the Lord &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt;, there &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; liberty.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But we all, with open face beholding as in a glass the glory of the Lord, are changed into the same image from glory to glory, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; as by the Spirit of the Lord.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>