<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="48" name="Galatians" bookPage="galatians.html" title="Galatians" chapterCount="6" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="ephesians_1.html" nextTitle="Ephesians" prevBook="2corinthians_1.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="26" nextChapter="galatians_6.html" nextTitle="Galatians 6" prevChapter="galatians_4.html" prevTitle="Galatians 4" chapterPage="galatians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Stand fast therefore in the liberty wherewith Christ hath made us free, and be not entangled again with the yoke of bondage.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Behold, I Paul say unto you, that if ye be circumcised, Christ shall profit you nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For I testify again to every man that is circumcised, that he is a debtor to do the whole law.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Christ is become of no effect unto you, whosoever of you are justified by the law; ye are fallen from grace.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For we through the Spirit wait for the hope of righteousness by faith.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For in Jesus Christ neither circumcision availeth any thing, nor uncircumcision; but faith which worketh by love.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Ye did run well; who did hinder you that ye should not obey the truth?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">This persuasion &lt;i&gt;cometh&lt;/i&gt; not of him that calleth you.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">A little leaven leaveneth the whole lump.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I have confidence in you through the Lord, that ye will be none otherwise minded: but he that troubleth you shall bear his judgment, whosoever he be.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I, brethren, if I yet preach circumcision, why do I yet suffer persecution? then is the offence of the cross ceased.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I would they were even cut off which trouble you.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For, brethren, ye have been called unto liberty; only &lt;i&gt;use&lt;/i&gt; not liberty for an occasion to the flesh, but by love serve one another.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For all the law is fulfilled in one word, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; in this; Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But if ye bite and devour one another, take heed that ye be not consumed one of another.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;i&gt;This&lt;/i&gt; I say then, Walk in the Spirit, and ye shall not fulfil the lust of the flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For the flesh lusteth against the Spirit, and the Spirit against the flesh: and these are contrary the one to the other: so that ye cannot do the things that ye would.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But if ye be led of the Spirit, ye are not under the law.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Now the works of the flesh are manifest, which are &lt;i&gt;these&lt;/i&gt;; Adultery, fornication, uncleanness, lasciviousness,</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Idolatry, witchcraft, hatred, variance, emulations, wrath, strife, seditions, heresies,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Envyings, murders, drunkenness, revellings, and such like: of the which I tell you before, as I have also told &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; in time past, that they which do such things shall not inherit the kingdom of God.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness, goodness, faith,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Meekness, temperance: against such there is no law.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they that are Christ's have crucified the flesh with the affections and lusts.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">If we live in the Spirit, let us also walk in the Spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Let us not be desirous of vain glory, provoking one another, envying one another.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>