<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="48" name="Galatians" bookPage="galatians.html" title="Galatians" chapterCount="6" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="ephesians_1.html" nextTitle="Ephesians" prevBook="2corinthians_1.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="24" nextChapter="galatians_2.html" nextTitle="Galatians 2" prevChapter="2corinthians_13.html" prevTitle="2 Corinthians 13" chapterPage="galatians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Paul, an apostle, (not of men, neither by man, but by Jesus Christ, and God the Father, who raised him from the dead;)</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And all the brethren which are with me, unto the churches of Galatia:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Grace &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; to you and peace from God the Father, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Who gave himself for our sins, that he might deliver us from this present evil world, according to the will of God and our Father:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">To whom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; glory for ever and ever. Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">I marvel that ye are so soon removed from him that called you into the grace of Christ unto another gospel:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Which is not another; but there be some that trouble you, and would pervert the gospel of Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But though we, or an angel from heaven, preach any other gospel unto you than that which we have preached unto you, let him be accursed.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">As we said before, so say I now again, If any &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; preach any other gospel unto you than that ye have received, let him be accursed.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For do I now persuade men, or God? or do I seek to please men? for if I yet pleased men, I should not be the servant of Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But I certify you, brethren, that the gospel which was preached of me is not after man.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For I neither received it of man, neither was I taught &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;, but by the revelation of Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For ye have heard of my conversation in time past in the Jews' religion, how that beyond measure I persecuted the church of God, and wasted it:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And profited in the Jews' religion above many my equals in mine own nation, being more exceedingly zealous of the traditions of my fathers.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But when it pleased God, who separated me from my mother's womb, and called &lt;span class="extra"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; by his grace,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">To reveal his Son in me, that I might preach him among the heathen; immediately I conferred not with flesh and blood:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Neither went I up to Jerusalem to them which were apostles before me; but I went into Arabia, and returned again unto Damascus.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Then after three years I went up to Jerusalem to see Peter, and abode with him fifteen days.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But other of the apostles saw I none, save James the Lord's brother.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Now the things which I write unto you, behold, before God, I lie not.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Afterwards I came into the regions of Syria and Cilicia;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And was unknown by face unto the churches of Judaea which were in Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But they had heard only, That he which persecuted us in times past now preacheth the faith which once he destroyed.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And they glorified God in me.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>