<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="49" name="Ephesians" bookPage="ephesians.html" title="Ephesians" chapterCount="6" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="philippians_1.html" nextTitle="Philippians" prevBook="galatians_1.html" prevTitle="Galatians">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="33" nextChapter="ephesians_6.html" nextTitle="Ephesians 6" prevChapter="ephesians_4.html" prevTitle="Ephesians 4" chapterPage="ephesians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Be ye therefore followers of God, as dear children;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And walk in love, as Christ also hath loved us, and hath given himself for us an offering and a sacrifice to God for a sweetsmelling savour.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But fornication, and all uncleanness, or covetousness, let it not be once named among you, as becometh saints;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Neither filthiness, nor foolish talking, nor jesting, which are not convenient: but rather giving of thanks.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For this ye know, that no whoremonger, nor unclean person, nor covetous man, who is an idolater, hath any inheritance in the kingdom of Christ and of God.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Let no man deceive you with vain words: for because of these things cometh the wrath of God upon the children of disobedience.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Be not ye therefore partakers with them.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For ye were sometimes darkness, but now &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are ye&lt;/span&gt; light in the Lord: walk as children of light:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">(For the fruit of the Spirit &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in all goodness and righteousness and truth;)</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Proving what is acceptable unto the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And have no fellowship with the unfruitful works of darkness, but rather reprove &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For it is a shame even to speak of those things which are done of them in secret.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But all things that are reproved are made manifest by the light: for whatsoever doth make manifest is light.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Wherefore he saith, Awake thou that sleepest, and arise from the dead, and Christ shall give thee light.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">See then that ye walk circumspectly, not as fools, but as wise,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Redeeming the time, because the days are evil.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Wherefore be ye not unwise, but understanding what the will of the Lord &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And be not drunk with wine, wherein is excess; but be filled with the Spirit;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Speaking to yourselves in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody in your heart to the Lord;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Giving thanks always for all things unto God and the Father in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Submitting yourselves one to another in the fear of God.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Wives, submit yourselves unto your own husbands, as unto the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For the husband is the head of the wife, even as Christ is the head of the church: and he is the saviour of the body.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Therefore as the church is subject unto Christ, so &lt;span class='extra'&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; the wives &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; to their own husbands in every thing.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Husbands, love your wives, even as Christ also loved the church, and gave himself for it;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">That he might sanctify and cleanse it with the washing of water by the word,</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">That he might present it to himself a glorious church, not having spot, or wrinkle, or any such thing; but that it should be holy and without blemish.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">So ought men to love their wives as their own bodies. He that loveth his wife loveth himself.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For no man ever yet hated his own flesh; but nourisheth and cherisheth it, even as the Lord the church:</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">For we are members of his body, of his flesh, and of his bones.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">For this cause shall a man leave his father and mother, and shall be joined unto his wife, and they two shall be one flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">This is a great mystery: but I speak concerning Christ and the church.</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Nevertheless let every one of you in particular so love his wife even as himself; and the wife &lt;span class='extra'&gt;see&lt;/span&gt; that she reverence &lt;span class='extra'&gt;her&lt;/span&gt; husband.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>