<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="49" name="Ephesians" bookPage="ephesians.html" title="Ephesians" chapterCount="6" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="philippians_1.html" nextTitle="Philippians" prevBook="galatians_1.html" prevTitle="Galatians">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="22" nextChapter="ephesians_3.html" nextTitle="Ephesians 3" prevChapter="ephesians_1.html" prevTitle="Ephesians 1" chapterPage="ephesians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And you &lt;i&gt;hath he quickened&lt;/i&gt;, who were dead in trespasses and sins;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Wherein in time past ye walked according to the course of this world, according to the prince of the power of the air, the spirit that now worketh in the children of disobedience:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Among whom also we all had our conversation in times past in the lusts of our flesh, fulfilling the desires of the flesh and of the mind; and were by nature the children of wrath, even as others.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But God, who is rich in mercy, for his great love wherewith he loved us,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Even when we were dead in sins, hath quickened us together with Christ, (by grace ye are saved;)</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And hath raised &lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt; up together, and made &lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt; sit together in heavenly &lt;i&gt;places&lt;/i&gt; in Christ Jesus:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">That in the ages to come he might shew the exceeding riches of his grace in &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; kindness toward us through Christ Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For by grace are ye saved through faith; and that not of yourselves: &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; the gift of God:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Not of works, lest any man should boast.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus unto good works, which God hath before ordained that we should walk in them.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Wherefore remember, that ye &lt;i&gt;being&lt;/i&gt; in time past Gentiles in the flesh, who are called Uncircumcision by that which is called the Circumcision in the flesh made by hands;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">That at that time ye were without Christ, being aliens from the commonwealth of Israel, and strangers from the covenants of promise, having no hope, and without God in the world:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But now in Christ Jesus ye who sometimes were far off are made nigh by the blood of Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For he is our peace, who hath made both one, and hath broken down the middle wall of partition &lt;i&gt;between us&lt;/i&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Having abolished in his flesh the enmity, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the law of commandments &lt;i&gt;contained&lt;/i&gt; in ordinances; for to make in himself of twain one new man, &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; making peace;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And that he might reconcile both unto God in one body by the cross, having slain the enmity thereby:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And came and preached peace to you which were afar off, and to them that were nigh.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For through him we both have access by one Spirit unto the Father.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Now therefore ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And are built upon the foundation of the apostles and prophets, Jesus Christ himself being the chief corner &lt;i&gt;stone&lt;/i&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">In whom all the building fitly framed together groweth unto an holy temple in the Lord:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">In whom ye also are builded together for an habitation of God through the Spirit.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>