<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="49" name="Ephesians" bookPage="ephesians.html" title="Ephesians" chapterCount="6" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="philippians_1.html" nextTitle="Philippians" prevBook="galatians_1.html" prevTitle="Galatians">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="23" nextChapter="ephesians_2.html" nextTitle="Ephesians 2" prevChapter="galatians_6.html" prevTitle="Galatians 6" chapterPage="ephesians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Paul, an apostle of Jesus Christ by the will of God, to the saints which are at Ephesus, and to the faithful in Christ Jesus:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Grace &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; to you, and peace, from God our Father, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who hath blessed us with all spiritual blessings in heavenly &lt;span class="extra"&gt;places&lt;/span&gt; in Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">According as he hath chosen us in him before the foundation of the world, that we should be holy and without blame before him in love:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Having predestinated us unto the adoption of children by Jesus Christ to himself, according to the good pleasure of his will,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">To the praise of the glory of his grace, wherein he hath made us accepted in the beloved.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">In whom we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of sins, according to the riches of his grace;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Wherein he hath abounded toward us in all wisdom and prudence;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Having made known unto us the mystery of his will, according to his good pleasure which he hath purposed in himself:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">That in the dispensation of the fulness of times he might gather together in one all things in Christ, both which are in heaven, and which are on earth; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; in him:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">In whom also we have obtained an inheritance, being predestinated according to the purpose of him who worketh all things after the counsel of his own will:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">That we should be to the praise of his glory, who first trusted in Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">In whom ye also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;trusted&lt;/span&gt;, after that ye heard the word of truth, the gospel of your salvation: in whom also after that ye believed, ye were sealed with that holy Spirit of promise,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Which is the earnest of our inheritance until the redemption of the purchased possession, unto the praise of his glory.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Wherefore I also, after I heard of your faith in the Lord Jesus, and love unto all the saints,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Cease not to give thanks for you, making mention of you in my prayers;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">That the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of glory, may give unto you the spirit of wisdom and revelation in the knowledge of him:</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">The eyes of your understanding being enlightened; that ye may know what is the hope of his calling, and what the riches of the glory of his inheritance in the saints,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And what &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the exceeding greatness of his power to us-ward who believe, according to the working of his mighty power,</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Which he wrought in Christ, when he raised him from the dead, and set &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; at his own right hand in the heavenly &lt;span class="extra"&gt;places&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Far above all principality, and power, and might, and dominion, and every name that is named, not only in this world, but also in that which is to come:</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And hath put all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; under his feet, and gave him &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; the head over all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;things&lt;/span&gt; to the church,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Which is his body, the fulness of him that filleth all in all.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>