<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="50" name="Philippians" bookPage="philippians.html" title="Philippians" chapterCount="4" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="colossians_1.html" nextTitle="Colossians" prevBook="ephesians_1.html" prevTitle="Ephesians">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="30" nextChapter="philippians_2.html" nextTitle="Philippians 2" prevChapter="ephesians_6.html" prevTitle="Ephesians 6" chapterPage="philippians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Paul and Timotheus, the servants of Jesus Christ, to all the saints in Christ Jesus which are at Philippi, with the bishops and deacons:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Grace &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; unto you, and peace, from God our Father, and &lt;i&gt;from&lt;/i&gt; the Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">I thank my God upon every remembrance of you,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Always in every prayer of mine for you all making request with joy,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For your fellowship in the gospel from the first day until now;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Being confident of this very thing, that he which hath begun a good work in you will perform &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; until the day of Jesus Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Even as it is meet for me to think this of you all, because I have you in my heart; inasmuch as both in my bonds, and in the defence and confirmation of the gospel, ye all are partakers of my grace.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For God is my record, how greatly I long after you all in the bowels of Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And this I pray, that your love may abound yet more and more in knowledge and &lt;i&gt;in&lt;/i&gt; all judgment;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">That ye may approve things that are excellent; that ye may be sincere and without offence till the day of Christ;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Being filled with the fruits of righteousness, which are by Jesus Christ, unto the glory and praise of God.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But I would ye should understand, brethren, that the things &lt;i&gt;which happened&lt;/i&gt; unto me have fallen out rather unto the furtherance of the gospel;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">So that my bonds in Christ are manifest in all the palace, and in all other &lt;i&gt;places&lt;/i&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And many of the brethren in the Lord, waxing confident by my bonds, are much more bold to speak the word without fear.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Some indeed preach Christ even of envy and strife; and some also of good will:</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">The one preach Christ of contention, not sincerely, supposing to add affliction to my bonds:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But the other of love, knowing that I am set for the defence of the gospel.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">What then? notwithstanding, every way, whether in pretence, or in truth, Christ is preached; and I therein do rejoice, yea, and will rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">For I know that this shall turn to my salvation through your prayer, and the supply of the Spirit of Jesus Christ,</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">According to my earnest expectation and &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; hope, that in nothing I shall be ashamed, but &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; with all boldness, as always, &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; now also Christ shall be magnified in my body, whether &lt;i&gt;it be&lt;/i&gt; by life, or by death.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For to me to live &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Christ, and to die &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; gain.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But if I live in the flesh, this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the fruit of my labour: yet what I shall choose I wot not.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For I am in a strait betwixt two, having a desire to depart, and to be with Christ; which is far better:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Nevertheless to abide in the flesh &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; more needful for you.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And having this confidence, I know that I shall abide and continue with you all for your furtherance and joy of faith;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">That your rejoicing may be more abundant in Jesus Christ for me by my coming to you again.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Only let your conversation be as it becometh the gospel of Christ: that whether I come and see you, or else be absent, I may hear of your affairs, that ye stand fast in one spirit, with one mind striving together for the faith of the gospel;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">And in nothing terrified by your adversaries: which is to them an evident token of perdition, but to you of salvation, and that of God.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For unto you it is given in the behalf of Christ, not only to believe on him, but also to suffer for his sake;</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">Having the same conflict which ye saw in me, and now hear &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; in me.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>