<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="50" name="Philippians" bookPage="philippians.html" title="Philippians" chapterCount="4" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="colossians_1.html" nextTitle="Colossians" prevBook="ephesians_1.html" prevTitle="Ephesians">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="23" nextChapter="colossians_1.html" nextTitle="Colossians 1" prevChapter="philippians_3.html" prevTitle="Philippians 3" chapterPage="philippians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Therefore, my brethren dearly beloved and longed for, my joy and crown, so stand fast in the Lord, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; dearly beloved.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">I beseech Euodias, and beseech Syntyche, that they be of the same mind in the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I intreat thee also, true yokefellow, help those women which laboured with me in the gospel, with Clement also, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; other my fellowlabourers, whose names &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; in the book of life.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Rejoice in the Lord alway: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; again I say, Rejoice.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Let your moderation be known unto all men. The Lord &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; at hand.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Be careful for nothing; but in every thing by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known unto God.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And the peace of God, which passeth all understanding, shall keep your hearts and minds through Christ Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Finally, brethren, whatsoever things are true, whatsoever things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; honest, whatsoever things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; just, whatsoever things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; pure, whatsoever things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; lovely, whatsoever things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; of good report; if &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; any virtue, and if &lt;span class="extra"&gt;there be&lt;/span&gt; any praise, think on these things.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Those things, which ye have both learned, and received, and heard, and seen in me, do: and the God of peace shall be with you.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But I rejoiced in the Lord greatly, that now at the last your care of me hath flourished again; wherein ye were also careful, but ye lacked opportunity.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Not that I speak in respect of want: for I have learned, in whatsoever state I am, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;therewith&lt;/span&gt; to be content.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">I know both how to be abased, and I know how to abound: every where and in all things I am instructed both to be full and to be hungry, both to abound and to suffer need.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">I can do all things through Christ which strengtheneth me.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Notwithstanding ye have well done, that ye did communicate with my affliction.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Now ye Philippians know also, that in the beginning of the gospel, when I departed from Macedonia, no church communicated with me as concerning giving and receiving, but ye only.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For even in Thessalonica ye sent once and again unto my necessity.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Not because I desire a gift: but I desire fruit that may abound to your account.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">But I have all, and abound: I am full, having received of Epaphroditus the things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;which were sent&lt;/span&gt; from you, an odour of a sweet smell, a sacrifice acceptable, wellpleasing to God.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But my God shall supply all your need according to his riches in glory by Christ Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Now unto God and our Father &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; glory for ever and ever. Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Salute every saint in Christ Jesus. The brethren which are with me greet you.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">All the saints salute you, chiefly they that are of Caesar's household.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; with you all. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>