<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="50" name="Philippians" bookPage="philippians.html" title="Philippians" chapterCount="4" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="colossians_1.html" nextTitle="Colossians" prevBook="ephesians_1.html" prevTitle="Ephesians">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="21" nextChapter="philippians_4.html" nextTitle="Philippians 4" prevChapter="philippians_2.html" prevTitle="Philippians 2" chapterPage="philippians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Finally, my brethren, rejoice in the Lord. To write the same things to you, to me indeed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; not grievous, but for you &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; safe.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Beware of dogs, beware of evil workers, beware of the concision.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For we are the circumcision, which worship God in the spirit, and rejoice in Christ Jesus, and have no confidence in the flesh.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Though I might also have confidence in the flesh. If any other man thinketh that he hath whereof he might trust in the flesh, I more:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Circumcised the eighth day, of the stock of Israel, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; the tribe of Benjamin, an Hebrew of the Hebrews; as touching the law, a Pharisee;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Concerning zeal, persecuting the church; touching the righteousness which is in the law, blameless.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But what things were gain to me, those I counted loss for Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Yea doubtless, and I count all things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; loss for the excellency of the knowledge of Christ Jesus my Lord: for whom I have suffered the loss of all things, and do count them &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; dung, that I may win Christ,</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And be found in him, not having mine own righteousness, which is of the law, but that which is through the faith of Christ, the righteousness which is of God by faith:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">That I may know him, and the power of his resurrection, and the fellowship of his sufferings, being made conformable unto his death;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">If by any means I might attain unto the resurrection of the dead.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Not as though I had already attained, either were already perfect: but I follow after, if that I may apprehend that for which also I am apprehended of Christ Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Brethren, I count not myself to have apprehended: but &lt;span class="extra"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; one thing &lt;span class="extra"&gt;I do&lt;/span&gt;, forgetting those things which are behind, and reaching forth unto those things which are before,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I press toward the mark for the prize of the high calling of God in Christ Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Let us therefore, as many as be perfect, be thus minded: and if in any thing ye be otherwise minded, God shall reveal even this unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Nevertheless, whereto we have already attained, let us walk by the same rule, let us mind the same thing.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Brethren, be followers together of me, and mark them which walk so as ye have us for an ensample.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">(For many walk, of whom I have told you often, and now tell you even weeping, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that they are&lt;/span&gt; the enemies of the cross of Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Whose end &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; destruction, whose God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is their&lt;/span&gt; belly, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;whose&lt;/span&gt; glory &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; in their shame, who mind earthly things.)</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For our conversation is in heaven; from whence also we look for the Saviour, the Lord Jesus Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Who shall change our vile body, that it may be fashioned like unto his glorious body, according to the working whereby he is able even to subdue all things unto himself.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>