<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="51" name="Colossians" bookPage="colossians.html" title="Colossians" chapterCount="4" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1thessalonians_1.html" nextTitle="1 Thessalonians" prevBook="philippians_1.html" prevTitle="Philippians">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="25" nextChapter="colossians_4.html" nextTitle="Colossians 4" prevChapter="colossians_2.html" prevTitle="Colossians 2" chapterPage="colossians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">If ye then be risen with Christ, seek those things which are above, where Christ sitteth on the right hand of God.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Set your affection on things above, not on things on the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For ye are dead, and your life is hid with Christ in God.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">When Christ, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;who is&lt;/span&gt; our life, shall appear, then shall ye also appear with him in glory.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Mortify therefore your members which are upon the earth; fornication, uncleanness, inordinate affection, evil concupiscence, and covetousness, which is idolatry:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For which things' sake the wrath of God cometh on the children of disobedience:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">In the which ye also walked some time, when ye lived in them.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But now ye also put off all these; anger, wrath, malice, blasphemy, filthy communication out of your mouth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Lie not one to another, seeing that ye have put off the old man with his deeds;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And have put on the new &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt;, which is renewed in knowledge after the image of him that created him:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Where there is neither Greek nor Jew, circumcision nor uncircumcision, Barbarian, Scythian, bond &lt;span class="extra"&gt;nor&lt;/span&gt; free: but Christ &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; all, and in all.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Put on therefore, as the elect of God, holy and beloved, bowels of mercies, kindness, humbleness of mind, meekness, longsuffering;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Forbearing one another, and forgiving one another, if any man have a quarrel against any: even as Christ forgave you, so also &lt;span class="extra"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; ye.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And above all these things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;put on&lt;/span&gt; charity, which is the bond of perfectness.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And let the peace of God rule in your hearts, to the which also ye are called in one body; and be ye thankful.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly in all wisdom; teaching and admonishing one another in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing with grace in your hearts to the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And whatsoever ye do in word or deed, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; all in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God and the Father by him.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Wives, submit yourselves unto your own husbands, as it is fit in the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Husbands, love &lt;span class="extra"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; wives, and be not bitter against them.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Children, obey &lt;span class="extra"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; parents in all things: for this is well pleasing unto the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Fathers, provoke not your children &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to anger&lt;/span&gt;, lest they be discouraged.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Servants, obey in all things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; masters according to the flesh; not with eyeservice, as menpleasers; but in singleness of heart, fearing God:</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And whatsoever ye do, do &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; heartily, as to the Lord, and not unto men;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Knowing that of the Lord ye shall receive the reward of the inheritance: for ye serve the Lord Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">But he that doeth wrong shall receive for the wrong which he hath done: and there is no respect of persons.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>