<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="52" name="1 Thessalonians" bookPage="1thessalonians.html" title="1 Thessalonians" chapterCount="5" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2thessalonians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Thessalonians" prevBook="colossians_1.html" prevTitle="Colossians">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="28" nextChapter="2thessalonians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Thessalonians 1" prevChapter="1thessalonians_4.html" prevTitle="1 Thessalonians 4" chapterPage="1thessalonians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">But of the times and the seasons, brethren, ye have no need that I write unto you.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For yourselves know perfectly that the day of the Lord so cometh as a thief in the night.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For when they shall say, Peace and safety; then sudden destruction cometh upon them, as travail upon a woman with child; and they shall not escape.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But ye, brethren, are not in darkness, that that day should overtake you as a thief.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Ye are all the children of light, and the children of the day: we are not of the night, nor of darkness.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Therefore let us not sleep, as &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; others; but let us watch and be sober.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For they that sleep sleep in the night; and they that be drunken are drunken in the night.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But let us, who are of the day, be sober, putting on the breastplate of faith and love; and for an helmet, the hope of salvation.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">For God hath not appointed us to wrath, but to obtain salvation by our Lord Jesus Christ,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Who died for us, that, whether we wake or sleep, we should live together with him.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Wherefore comfort yourselves together, and edify one another, even as also ye do.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And we beseech you, brethren, to know them which labour among you, and are over you in the Lord, and admonish you;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And to esteem them very highly in love for their work's sake. &lt;i&gt;And&lt;/i&gt; be at peace among yourselves.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Now we exhort you, brethren, warn them that are unruly, comfort the feebleminded, support the weak, be patient toward all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">See that none render evil for evil unto any &lt;i&gt;man&lt;/i&gt;; but ever follow that which is good, both among yourselves, and to all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Rejoice evermore.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Pray without ceasing.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">In every thing give thanks: for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus concerning you.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Quench not the Spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Despise not prophesyings.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Prove all things; hold fast that which is good.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Abstain from all appearance of evil.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the very God of peace sanctify you wholly; and &lt;i&gt;I pray God&lt;/i&gt; your whole spirit and soul and body be preserved blameless unto the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Faithful &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he that calleth you, who also will do &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Brethren, pray for us.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Greet all the brethren with an holy kiss.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">I charge you by the Lord that this epistle be read unto all the holy brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; with you. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>