<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="52" name="1 Thessalonians" bookPage="1thessalonians.html" title="1 Thessalonians" chapterCount="5" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2thessalonians_1.html" nextTitle="2 Thessalonians" prevBook="colossians_1.html" prevTitle="Colossians">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="18" nextChapter="1thessalonians_5.html" nextTitle="1 Thessalonians 5" prevChapter="1thessalonians_3.html" prevTitle="1 Thessalonians 3" chapterPage="1thessalonians_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Furthermore then we beseech you, brethren, and exhort &lt;span class="extra"&gt;you&lt;/span&gt; by the Lord Jesus, that as ye have received of us how ye ought to walk and to please God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;so&lt;/span&gt; ye would abound more and more.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For ye know what commandments we gave you by the Lord Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For this is the will of God, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; your sanctification, that ye should abstain from fornication:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">That every one of you should know how to possess his vessel in sanctification and honour;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Not in the lust of concupiscence, even as the Gentiles which know not God:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">That no &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; go beyond and defraud his brother in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;any&lt;/span&gt; matter: because that the Lord &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the avenger of all such, as we also have forewarned you and testified.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For God hath not called us unto uncleanness, but unto holiness.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He therefore that despiseth, despiseth not man, but God, who hath also given unto us his holy Spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But as touching brotherly love ye need not that I write unto you: for ye yourselves are taught of God to love one another.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And indeed ye do it toward all the brethren which are in all Macedonia: but we beseech you, brethren, that ye increase more and more;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And that ye study to be quiet, and to do your own business, and to work with your own hands, as we commanded you;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">That ye may walk honestly toward them that are without, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; ye may have lack of nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But I would not have you to be ignorant, brethren, concerning them which are asleep, that ye sorrow not, even as others which have no hope.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For if we believe that Jesus died and rose again, even so them also which sleep in Jesus will God bring with him.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For this we say unto you by the word of the Lord, that we which are alive &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; remain unto the coming of the Lord shall not prevent them which are asleep.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For the Lord himself shall descend from heaven with a shout, with the voice of the archangel, and with the trump of God: and the dead in Christ shall rise first:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Then we which are alive &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; remain shall be caught up together with them in the clouds, to meet the Lord in the air: and so shall we ever be with the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Wherefore comfort one another with these words.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>