<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="54" name="1 Timothy" bookPage="1timothy.html" title="1 Timothy" chapterCount="6" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2timothy_1.html" nextTitle="2 Timothy" prevBook="2thessalonians_1.html" prevTitle="2 Thessalonians">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="21" nextChapter="2timothy_1.html" nextTitle="2 Timothy 1" prevChapter="1timothy_5.html" prevTitle="1 Timothy 5" chapterPage="1timothy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Let as many servants as are under the yoke count their own masters worthy of all honour, that the name of God and &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; doctrine be not blasphemed.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And they that have believing masters, let them not despise &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;, because they are brethren; but rather do &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; service, because they are faithful and beloved, partakers of the benefit. These things teach and exhort.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">If any man teach otherwise, and consent not to wholesome words, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; the words of our Lord Jesus Christ, and to the doctrine which is according to godliness;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">He is proud, knowing nothing, but doting about questions and strifes of words, whereof cometh envy, strife, railings, evil surmisings,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Perverse disputings of men of corrupt minds, and destitute of the truth, supposing that gain is godliness: from such withdraw thyself.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But godliness with contentment is great gain.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For we brought nothing into &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; world, &lt;i&gt;and it is&lt;/i&gt; certain we can carry nothing out.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And having food and raiment let us be therewith content.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But they that will be rich fall into temptation and a snare, and &lt;i&gt;into&lt;/i&gt; many foolish and hurtful lusts, which drown men in destruction and perdition.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For the love of money is the root of all evil: which while some coveted after, they have erred from the faith, and pierced themselves through with many sorrows.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But thou, O man of God, flee these things; and follow after righteousness, godliness, faith, love, patience, meekness.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Fight the good fight of faith, lay hold on eternal life, whereunto thou art also called, and hast professed a good profession before many witnesses.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">I give thee charge in the sight of God, who quickeneth all things, and &lt;i&gt;before&lt;/i&gt; Christ Jesus, who before Pontius Pilate witnessed a good confession;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">That thou keep &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; commandment without spot, unrebukeable, until the appearing of our Lord Jesus Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Which in his times he shall shew, &lt;i&gt;who is&lt;/i&gt; the blessed and only Potentate, the King of kings, and Lord of lords;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Who only hath immortality, dwelling in the light which no man can approach unto; whom no man hath seen, nor can see: to whom &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; honour and power everlasting. Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Charge them that are rich in this world, that they be not highminded, nor trust in uncertain riches, but in the living God, who giveth us richly all things to enjoy;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">That they do good, that they be rich in good works, ready to distribute, willing to communicate;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Laying up in store for themselves a good foundation against the time to come, that they may lay hold on eternal life.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">O Timothy, keep that which is committed to thy trust, avoiding profane &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; vain babblings, and oppositions of science falsely so called:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Which some professing have erred concerning the faith. Grace &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; with thee. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>