<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="54" name="1 Timothy" bookPage="1timothy.html" title="1 Timothy" chapterCount="6" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2timothy_1.html" nextTitle="2 Timothy" prevBook="2thessalonians_1.html" prevTitle="2 Thessalonians">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="15" nextChapter="1timothy_3.html" nextTitle="1 Timothy 3" prevChapter="1timothy_1.html" prevTitle="1 Timothy 1" chapterPage="1timothy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I exhort therefore, that, first of all, supplications, prayers, intercessions, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; giving of thanks, be made for all men;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For kings, and &lt;i&gt;for&lt;/i&gt; all that are in authority; that we may lead a quiet and peaceable life in all godliness and honesty.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For this &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; good and acceptable in the sight of God our Saviour;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Who will have all men to be saved, and to come unto the knowledge of the truth.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For &lt;i&gt;there is&lt;/i&gt; one God, and one mediator between God and men, the man Christ Jesus;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Who gave himself a ransom for all, to be testified in due time.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Whereunto I am ordained a preacher, and an apostle, (I speak the truth in Christ, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; lie not;) a teacher of the Gentiles in faith and verity.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">I will therefore that men pray every where, lifting up holy hands, without wrath and doubting.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">In like manner also, that women adorn themselves in modest apparel, with shamefacedness and sobriety; not with broided hair, or gold, or pearls, or costly array;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But (which becometh women professing godliness) with good works.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Let the woman learn in silence with all subjection.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">But I suffer not a woman to teach, nor to usurp authority over the man, but to be in silence.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For Adam was first formed, then Eve.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And Adam was not deceived, but the woman being deceived was in the transgression.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Notwithstanding she shall be saved in childbearing, if they continue in faith and charity and holiness with sobriety.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>