<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="54" name="1 Timothy" bookPage="1timothy.html" title="1 Timothy" chapterCount="6" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2timothy_1.html" nextTitle="2 Timothy" prevBook="2thessalonians_1.html" prevTitle="2 Thessalonians">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="25" nextChapter="1timothy_6.html" nextTitle="1 Timothy 6" prevChapter="1timothy_4.html" prevTitle="1 Timothy 4" chapterPage="1timothy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Rebuke not an elder, but intreat &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; as a father; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the younger men as brethren;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">The elder women as mothers; the younger as sisters, with all purity.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Honour widows that are widows indeed.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But if any widow have children or nephews, let them learn first to shew piety at home, and to requite their parents: for that is good and acceptable before God.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Now she that is a widow indeed, and desolate, trusteth in God, and continueth in supplications and prayers night and day.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But she that liveth in pleasure is dead while she liveth.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And these things give in charge, that they may be blameless.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But if any provide not for his own, and specially for those of his own house, he hath denied the faith, and is worse than an infidel.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Let not a widow be taken into the number under threescore years old, having been the wife of one man,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Well reported of for good works; if she have brought up children, if she have lodged strangers, if she have washed the saints' feet, if she have relieved the afflicted, if she have diligently followed every good work.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">But the younger widows refuse: for when they have begun to wax wanton against Christ, they will marry;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Having damnation, because they have cast off their first faith.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And withal they learn &lt;span class="extra"&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; idle, wandering about from house to house; and not only idle, but tattlers also and busybodies, speaking things which they ought not.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">I will therefore that the younger women marry, bear children, guide the house, give none occasion to the adversary to speak reproachfully.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For some are already turned aside after Satan.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">If any man or woman that believeth have widows, let them relieve them, and let not the church be charged; that it may relieve them that are widows indeed.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Let the elders that rule well be counted worthy of double honour, especially they who labour in the word and doctrine.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For the scripture saith, Thou shalt not muzzle the ox that treadeth out the corn. And, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;The labourer &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; worthy of his reward.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Against an elder receive not an accusation, but before two or three witnesses.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Them that sin rebuke before all, that others also may fear.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">I charge &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt; before God, and the Lord Jesus Christ, and the elect angels, that thou observe these things without preferring one before another, doing nothing by partiality.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Lay hands suddenly on no man, neither be partaker of other men's sins: keep thyself pure.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Drink no longer water, but use a little wine for thy stomach's sake and thine often infirmities.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Some men's sins are open beforehand, going before to judgment; and some &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; they follow after.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Likewise also the good works &lt;span class="extra"&gt;of some&lt;/span&gt; are manifest beforehand; and they that are otherwise cannot be hid.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>