<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="54" name="1 Timothy" bookPage="1timothy.html" title="1 Timothy" chapterCount="6" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2timothy_1.html" nextTitle="2 Timothy" prevBook="2thessalonians_1.html" prevTitle="2 Thessalonians">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="16" nextChapter="1timothy_4.html" nextTitle="1 Timothy 4" prevChapter="1timothy_2.html" prevTitle="1 Timothy 2" chapterPage="1timothy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">This &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a true saying, If a man desire the office of a bishop, he desireth a good work.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">A bishop then must be blameless, the husband of one wife, vigilant, sober, of good behaviour, given to hospitality, apt to teach;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Not given to wine, no striker, not greedy of filthy lucre; but patient, not a brawler, not covetous;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">One that ruleth well his own house, having his children in subjection with all gravity;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">(For if a man know not how to rule his own house, how shall he take care of the church of God?)</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Not a novice, lest being lifted up with pride he fall into the condemnation of the devil.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Moreover he must have a good report of them which are without; lest he fall into reproach and the snare of the devil.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Likewise &lt;span class='extra'&gt;must&lt;/span&gt; the deacons &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; grave, not doubletongued, not given to much wine, not greedy of filthy lucre;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Holding the mystery of the faith in a pure conscience.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And let these also first be proved; then let them use the office of a deacon, being &lt;span class='extra'&gt;found&lt;/span&gt; blameless.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Even so &lt;span class='extra'&gt;must their&lt;/span&gt; wives &lt;span class='extra'&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; grave, not slanderers, sober, faithful in all things.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Let the deacons be the husbands of one wife, ruling their children and their own houses well.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For they that have used the office of a deacon well purchase to themselves a good degree, and great boldness in the faith which is in Christ Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">These things write I unto thee, hoping to come unto thee shortly:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">But if I tarry long, that thou mayest know how thou oughtest to behave thyself in the house of God, which is the church of the living God, the pillar and ground of the truth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And without controversy great is the mystery of godliness: God was manifest in the flesh, justified in the Spirit, seen of angels, preached unto the Gentiles, believed on in the world, received up into glory.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>