<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="54" name="1 Timothy" bookPage="1timothy.html" title="1 Timothy" chapterCount="6" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2timothy_1.html" nextTitle="2 Timothy" prevBook="2thessalonians_1.html" prevTitle="2 Thessalonians">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="16" nextChapter="1timothy_5.html" nextTitle="1 Timothy 5" prevChapter="1timothy_3.html" prevTitle="1 Timothy 3" chapterPage="1timothy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now the Spirit speaketh expressly, that in the latter times some shall depart from the faith, giving heed to seducing spirits, and doctrines of devils;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Speaking lies in hypocrisy; having their conscience seared with a hot iron;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Forbidding to marry, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and commanding&lt;/span&gt; to abstain from meats, which God hath created to be received with thanksgiving of them which believe and know the truth.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For every creature of God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; good, and nothing to be refused, if it be received with thanksgiving:</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For it is sanctified by the word of God and prayer.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">If thou put the brethren in remembrance of these things, thou shalt be a good minister of Jesus Christ, nourished up in the words of faith and of good doctrine, whereunto thou hast attained.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">But refuse profane and old wives' fables, and exercise thyself &lt;span class="extra"&gt;rather&lt;/span&gt; unto godliness.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For bodily exercise profiteth little: but godliness is profitable unto all things, having promise of the life that now is, and of that which is to come.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">This &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a faithful saying and worthy of all acceptation.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For therefore we both labour and suffer reproach, because we trust in the living God, who is the Saviour of all men, specially of those that believe.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">These things command and teach.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Let no man despise thy youth; but be thou an example of the believers, in word, in conversation, in charity, in spirit, in faith, in purity.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Till I come, give attendance to reading, to exhortation, to doctrine.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Neglect not the gift that is in thee, which was given thee by prophecy, with the laying on of the hands of the presbytery.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Meditate upon these things; give thyself wholly to them; that thy profiting may appear to all.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Take heed unto thyself, and unto the doctrine; continue in them: for in doing this thou shalt both save thyself, and them that hear thee.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>