<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="55" name="2 Timothy" bookPage="2timothy.html" title="2 Timothy" chapterCount="4" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="titus_1.html" nextTitle="Titus" prevBook="1timothy_1.html" prevTitle="1 Timothy">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="26" nextChapter="2timothy_3.html" nextTitle="2 Timothy 3" prevChapter="2timothy_1.html" prevTitle="2 Timothy 1" chapterPage="2timothy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Thou therefore, my son, be strong in the grace that is in Christ Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the things that thou hast heard of me among many witnesses, the same commit thou to faithful men, who shall be able to teach others also.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Thou therefore endure hardness, as a good soldier of Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">No man that warreth entangleth himself with the affairs of &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; life; that he may please him who hath chosen him to be a soldier.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And if a man also strive for masteries, &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; is he not crowned, except he strive lawfully.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">The husbandman that laboureth must be first partaker of the fruits.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Consider what I say; and the Lord give thee understanding in all things.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Remember that Jesus Christ of the seed of David was raised from the dead according to my gospel:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Wherein I suffer trouble, as an evil doer, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; unto bonds; but the word of God is not bound.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Therefore I endure all things for the elect's sakes, that they may also obtain the salvation which is in Christ Jesus with eternal glory.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;i&gt;It is&lt;/i&gt; a faithful saying: For if we be dead with &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, we shall also live with &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;:</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">If we suffer, we shall also reign with &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;: if we deny &lt;i&gt;him&lt;/i&gt;, he also will deny us:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">If we believe not, &lt;i&gt;yet&lt;/i&gt; he abideth faithful: he cannot deny himself.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Of these things put &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; in remembrance, charging &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; before the Lord that they strive not about words to no profit, &lt;i&gt;but&lt;/i&gt; to the subverting of the hearers.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Study to shew thyself approved unto God, a workman that needeth not to be ashamed, rightly dividing the word of truth.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But shun profane &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; vain babblings: for they will increase unto more ungodliness.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And their word will eat as doth a canker: of whom is Hymenaeus and Philetus;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Who concerning the truth have erred, saying that the resurrection is past already; and overthrow the faith of some.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Nevertheless the foundation of God standeth sure, having this seal, The Lord knoweth them that are his. And, Let every one that nameth the name of Christ depart from iniquity.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But in a great house there are not only vessels of gold and of silver, but also of wood and of earth; and some to honour, and some to dishonour.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">If a man therefore purge himself from these, he shall be a vessel unto honour, sanctified, and meet for the master's use, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; prepared unto every good work.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Flee also youthful lusts: but follow righteousness, faith, charity, peace, with them that call on the Lord out of a pure heart.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">But foolish and unlearned questions avoid, knowing that they do gender strifes.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the servant of the Lord must not strive; but be gentle unto all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;, apt to teach, patient,</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">In meekness instructing those that oppose themselves; if God peradventure will give them repentance to the acknowledging of the truth;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; they may recover themselves out of the snare of the devil, who are taken captive by him at his will.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>