<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="55" name="2 Timothy" bookPage="2timothy.html" title="2 Timothy" chapterCount="4" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="titus_1.html" nextTitle="Titus" prevBook="1timothy_1.html" prevTitle="1 Timothy">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="22" nextChapter="titus_1.html" nextTitle="Titus 1" prevChapter="2timothy_3.html" prevTitle="2 Timothy 3" chapterPage="2timothy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">I charge &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thee&lt;/span&gt; therefore before God, and the Lord Jesus Christ, who shall judge the quick and the dead at his appearing and his kingdom;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Preach the word; be instant in season, out of season; reprove, rebuke, exhort with all longsuffering and doctrine.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For the time will come when they will not endure sound doctrine; but after their own lusts shall they heap to themselves teachers, having itching ears;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they shall turn away &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; ears from the truth, and shall be turned unto fables.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">But watch thou in all things, endure afflictions, do the work of an evangelist, make full proof of thy ministry.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For I am now ready to be offered, and the time of my departure is at hand.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">I have fought a good fight, I have finished &lt;span class="extra"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt; course, I have kept the faith:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Henceforth there is laid up for me a crown of righteousness, which the Lord, the righteous judge, shall give me at that day: and not to me only, but unto all them also that love his appearing.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Do thy diligence to come shortly unto me:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For Demas hath forsaken me, having loved this present world, and is departed unto Thessalonica; Crescens to Galatia, Titus unto Dalmatia.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Only Luke is with me. Take Mark, and bring him with thee: for he is profitable to me for the ministry.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And Tychicus have I sent to Ephesus.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The cloke that I left at Troas with Carpus, when thou comest, bring &lt;span class="extra"&gt;with thee&lt;/span&gt;, and the books, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;but&lt;/span&gt; especially the parchments.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Alexander the coppersmith did me much evil: the Lord reward him according to his works:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Of whom be thou ware also; for he hath greatly withstood our words.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">At my first answer no man stood with me, but all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; forsook me: &lt;span class="extra"&gt;I pray God&lt;/span&gt; that it may not be laid to their charge.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Notwithstanding the Lord stood with me, and strengthened me; that by me the preaching might be fully known, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; all the Gentiles might hear: and I was delivered out of the mouth of the lion.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the Lord shall deliver me from every evil work, and will preserve &lt;span class="extra"&gt;me&lt;/span&gt; unto his heavenly kingdom: to whom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; glory for ever and ever. Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Salute Prisca and Aquila, and the household of Onesiphorus.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Erastus abode at Corinth: but Trophimus have I left at Miletum sick.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Do thy diligence to come before winter. Eubulus greeteth thee, and Pudens, and Linus, and Claudia, and all the brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">The Lord Jesus Christ &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; with thy spirit. Grace &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; with you. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>