<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="55" name="2 Timothy" bookPage="2timothy.html" title="2 Timothy" chapterCount="4" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="titus_1.html" nextTitle="Titus" prevBook="1timothy_1.html" prevTitle="1 Timothy">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="17" nextChapter="2timothy_4.html" nextTitle="2 Timothy 4" prevChapter="2timothy_2.html" prevTitle="2 Timothy 2" chapterPage="2timothy_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">This know also, that in the last days perilous times shall come.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For men shall be lovers of their own selves, covetous, boasters, proud, blasphemers, disobedient to parents, unthankful, unholy,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Without natural affection, trucebreakers, false accusers, incontinent, fierce, despisers of those that are good,</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Traitors, heady, highminded, lovers of pleasures more than lovers of God;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Having a form of godliness, but denying the power thereof: from such turn away.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For of this sort are they which creep into houses, and lead captive silly women laden with sins, led away with divers lusts,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Ever learning, and never able to come to the knowledge of the truth.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Now as Jannes and Jambres withstood Moses, so do these also resist the truth: men of corrupt minds, reprobate concerning the faith.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But they shall proceed no further: for their folly shall be manifest unto all &lt;span class="extra"&gt;men&lt;/span&gt;, as theirs also was.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But thou hast fully known my doctrine, manner of life, purpose, faith, longsuffering, charity, patience,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Persecutions, afflictions, which came unto me at Antioch, at Iconium, at Lystra; what persecutions I endured: but out of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; all the Lord delivered me.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Yea, and all that will live godly in Christ Jesus shall suffer persecution.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But evil men and seducers shall wax worse and worse, deceiving, and being deceived.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But continue thou in the things which thou hast learned and hast been assured of, knowing of whom thou hast learned &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And that from a child thou hast known the holy scriptures, which are able to make thee wise unto salvation through faith which is in Christ Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">All scripture &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; given by inspiration of God, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; profitable for doctrine, for reproof, for correction, for instruction in righteousness:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">That the man of God may be perfect, throughly furnished unto all good works.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>