<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="56" name="Titus" bookPage="titus.html" title="Titus" chapterCount="3" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="philemon_1.html" nextTitle="Philemon" prevBook="2timothy_1.html" prevTitle="2 Timothy">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="16" nextChapter="titus_2.html" nextTitle="Titus 2" prevChapter="2timothy_4.html" prevTitle="2 Timothy 4" chapterPage="titus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Paul, a servant of God, and an apostle of Jesus Christ, according to the faith of God's elect, and the acknowledging of the truth which is after godliness;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">In hope of eternal life, which God, that cannot lie, promised before the world began;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">But hath in due times manifested his word through preaching, which is committed unto me according to the commandment of God our Saviour;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">To Titus, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;mine&lt;/span&gt; own son after the common faith: Grace, mercy, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; peace, from God the Father and the Lord Jesus Christ our Saviour.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For this cause left I thee in Crete, that thou shouldest set in order the things that are wanting, and ordain elders in every city, as I had appointed thee:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">If any be blameless, the husband of one wife, having faithful children not accused of riot or unruly.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For a bishop must be blameless, as the steward of God; not selfwilled, not soon angry, not given to wine, no striker, not given to filthy lucre;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But a lover of hospitality, a lover of good men, sober, just, holy, temperate;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Holding fast the faithful word as he hath been taught, that he may be able by sound doctrine both to exhort and to convince the gainsayers.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For there are many unruly and vain talkers and deceivers, specially they of the circumcision:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Whose mouths must be stopped, who subvert whole houses, teaching things which they ought not, for filthy lucre's sake.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">One of themselves, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; a prophet of their own, said, The Cretians &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; alway liars, evil beasts, slow bellies.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">This witness is true. Wherefore rebuke them sharply, that they may be sound in the faith;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Not giving heed to Jewish fables, and commandments of men, that turn from the truth.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Unto the pure all things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; pure: but unto them that are defiled and unbelieving &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; nothing pure; but even their mind and conscience is defiled.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">They profess that they know God; but in works they deny &lt;span class="extra"&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;, being abominable, and disobedient, and unto every good work reprobate.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>