<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="56" name="Titus" bookPage="titus.html" title="Titus" chapterCount="3" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="philemon_1.html" nextTitle="Philemon" prevBook="2timothy_1.html" prevTitle="2 Timothy">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="15" nextChapter="titus_3.html" nextTitle="Titus 3" prevChapter="titus_1.html" prevTitle="Titus 1" chapterPage="titus_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">But speak thou the things which become sound doctrine:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">That the aged men be sober, grave, temperate, sound in faith, in charity, in patience.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">The aged women likewise, that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;they be&lt;/span&gt; in behaviour as becometh holiness, not false accusers, not given to much wine, teachers of good things;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">That they may teach the young women to be sober, to love their husbands, to love their children,</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;To be&lt;/span&gt; discreet, chaste, keepers at home, good, obedient to their own husbands, that the word of God be not blasphemed.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Young men likewise exhort to be sober minded.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">In all things shewing thyself a pattern of good works: in doctrine &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shewing&lt;/span&gt; uncorruptness, gravity, sincerity,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Sound speech, that cannot be condemned; that he that is of the contrary part may be ashamed, having no evil thing to say of you.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class='extra'&gt;Exhort&lt;/span&gt; servants to be obedient unto their own masters, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to please &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; well in all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;things&lt;/span&gt;; not answering again;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Not purloining, but shewing all good fidelity; that they may adorn the doctrine of God our Saviour in all things.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For the grace of God that bringeth salvation hath appeared to all men,</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Teaching us that, denying ungodliness and worldly lusts, we should live soberly, righteously, and godly, in this present world;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Looking for that blessed hope, and the glorious appearing of the great God and our Saviour Jesus Christ;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Who gave himself for us, that he might redeem us from all iniquity, and purify unto himself a peculiar people, zealous of good works.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">These things speak, and exhort, and rebuke with all authority. Let no man despise thee.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>