<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="58" name="Hebrews" bookPage="hebrews.html" title="Hebrews" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="james_1.html" nextTitle="James" prevBook="philemon_1.html" prevTitle="Philemon">
    <chapter number="11" verseCount="40" nextChapter="hebrews_12.html" nextTitle="Hebrews 12" prevChapter="hebrews_10.html" prevTitle="Hebrews 10" chapterPage="hebrews_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Now faith is the substance of things hoped for, the evidence of things not seen.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For by it the elders obtained a good report.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Through faith we understand that the worlds were framed by the word of God, so that things which are seen were not made of things which do appear.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">By faith Abel offered unto God a more excellent sacrifice than Cain, by which he obtained witness that he was righteous, God testifying of his gifts: and by it he being dead yet speaketh.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">By faith Enoch was translated that he should not see death; and was not found, because God had translated him: for before his translation he had this testimony, that he pleased God.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But without faith &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; impossible to please &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt;: for he that cometh to God must believe that he is, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; he is a rewarder of them that diligently seek him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">By faith Noah, being warned of God of things not seen as yet, moved with fear, prepared an ark to the saving of his house; by the which he condemned the world, and became heir of the righteousness which is by faith.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">By faith Abraham, when he was called to go out into a place which he should after receive for an inheritance, obeyed; and he went out, not knowing whither he went.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">By faith he sojourned in the land of promise, as &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; a strange country, dwelling in tabernacles with Isaac and Jacob, the heirs with him of the same promise:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For he looked for a city which hath foundations, whose builder and maker &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; God.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Through faith also Sara herself received strength to conceive seed, and was delivered of a child when she was past age, because she judged him faithful who had promised.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Therefore sprang there even of one, and him as good as dead, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;so many&lt;/span&gt; as the stars of the sky in multitude, and as the sand which is by the sea shore innumerable.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">These all died in faith, not having received the promises, but having seen them afar off, and were persuaded of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, and embraced &lt;span class='extra'&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;, and confessed that they were strangers and pilgrims on the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For they that say such things declare plainly that they seek a country.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And truly, if they had been mindful of that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;country&lt;/span&gt; from whence they came out, they might have had opportunity to have returned.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But now they desire a better &lt;span class='extra'&gt;country&lt;/span&gt;, that is, an heavenly: wherefore God is not ashamed to be called their God: for he hath prepared for them a city.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">By faith Abraham, when he was tried, offered up Isaac: and he that had received the promises offered up his only begotten &lt;span class='extra'&gt;son&lt;/span&gt;,</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Of whom it was said, That in Isaac shall thy seed be called:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Accounting that God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; able to raise &lt;span class='extra'&gt;him&lt;/span&gt; up, even from the dead; from whence also he received him in a figure.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">By faith Isaac blessed Jacob and Esau concerning things to come.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">By faith Jacob, when he was a dying, blessed both the sons of Joseph; and worshipped, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;leaning&lt;/span&gt; upon the top of his staff.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">By faith Joseph, when he died, made mention of the departing of the children of Israel; and gave commandment concerning his bones.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">By faith Moses, when he was born, was hid three months of his parents, because they saw &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he was&lt;/span&gt; a proper child; and they were not afraid of the king's commandment.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">By faith Moses, when he was come to years, refused to be called the son of Pharaoh's daughter;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Choosing rather to suffer affliction with the people of God, than to enjoy the pleasures of sin for a season;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Esteeming the reproach of Christ greater riches than the treasures in Egypt: for he had respect unto the recompence of the reward.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">By faith he forsook Egypt, not fearing the wrath of the king: for he endured, as seeing him who is invisible.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Through faith he kept the passover, and the sprinkling of blood, lest he that destroyed the firstborn should touch them.</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">By faith they passed through the Red sea as by dry &lt;span class='extra'&gt;land&lt;/span&gt;: which the Egyptians assaying to do were drowned.</verse>
      <verse number="30" id="v30">By faith the walls of Jericho fell down, after they were compassed about seven days.</verse>
      <verse number="31" id="v31">By faith the harlot Rahab perished not with them that believed not, when she had received the spies with peace.</verse>
      <verse number="32" id="v32">And what shall I more say? for the time would fail me to tell of Gedeon, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; Barak, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; Samson, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; Jephthae; &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; David also, and Samuel, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; the prophets:</verse>
      <verse number="33" id="v33">Who through faith subdued kingdoms, wrought righteousness, obtained promises, stopped the mouths of lions,</verse>
      <verse number="34" id="v34">Quenched the violence of fire, escaped the edge of the sword, out of weakness were made strong, waxed valiant in fight, turned to flight the armies of the aliens.</verse>
      <verse number="35" id="v35">Women received their dead raised to life again: and others were tortured, not accepting deliverance; that they might obtain a better resurrection:</verse>
      <verse number="36" id="v36">And others had trial of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;cruel&lt;/span&gt; mockings and scourgings, yea, moreover of bonds and imprisonment:</verse>
      <verse number="37" id="v37">They were stoned, they were sawn asunder, were tempted, were slain with the sword: they wandered about in sheepskins and goatskins; being destitute, afflicted, tormented;</verse>
      <verse number="38" id="v38">(Of whom the world was not worthy:) they wandered in deserts, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; mountains, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; dens and caves of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="39" id="v39">And these all, having obtained a good report through faith, received not the promise:</verse>
      <verse number="40" id="v40">God having provided some better thing for us, that they without us should not be made perfect.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>