<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="58" name="Hebrews" bookPage="hebrews.html" title="Hebrews" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="james_1.html" nextTitle="James" prevBook="philemon_1.html" prevTitle="Philemon">
    <chapter number="12" verseCount="29" nextChapter="hebrews_13.html" nextTitle="Hebrews 13" prevChapter="hebrews_11.html" prevTitle="Hebrews 11" chapterPage="hebrews_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Wherefore seeing we also are compassed about with so great a cloud of witnesses, let us lay aside every weight, and the sin which doth so easily beset &lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt;, and let us run with patience the race that is set before us,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Looking unto Jesus the author and finisher of &lt;i&gt;our&lt;/i&gt; faith; who for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame, and is set down at the right hand of the throne of God.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For consider him that endured such contradiction of sinners against himself, lest ye be wearied and faint in your minds.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Ye have not yet resisted unto blood, striving against sin.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And ye have forgotten the exhortation which speaketh unto you as unto children, My son, despise not thou the chastening of the Lord, nor faint when thou art rebuked of him:</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">For whom the Lord loveth he chasteneth, and scourgeth every son whom he receiveth.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">If ye endure chastening, God dealeth with you as with sons; for what son is he whom the father chasteneth not?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But if ye be without chastisement, whereof all are partakers, then are ye bastards, and not sons.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Furthermore we have had fathers of our flesh which corrected &lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt;, and we gave &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt; reverence: shall we not much rather be in subjection unto the Father of spirits, and live?</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For they verily for a few days chastened &lt;i&gt;us&lt;/i&gt; after their own pleasure; but he for &lt;i&gt;our&lt;/i&gt; profit, that &lt;i&gt;we&lt;/i&gt; might be partakers of his holiness.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Now no chastening for the present seemeth to be joyous, but grievous: nevertheless afterward it yieldeth the peaceable fruit of righteousness unto them which are exercised thereby.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Wherefore lift up the hands which hang down, and the feeble knees;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And make straight paths for your feet, lest that which is lame be turned out of the way; but let it rather be healed.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Follow peace with all &lt;i&gt;men&lt;/i&gt;, and holiness, without which no man shall see the Lord:</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Looking diligently lest any man fail of the grace of God; lest any root of bitterness springing up trouble &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;, and thereby many be defiled;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Lest there &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; any fornicator, or profane person, as Esau, who for one morsel of meat sold his birthright.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For ye know how that afterward, when he would have inherited the blessing, he was rejected: for he found no place of repentance, though he sought it carefully with tears.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For ye are not come unto the mount that might be touched, and that burned with fire, nor unto blackness, and darkness, and tempest,</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the sound of a trumpet, and the voice of words; which &lt;i&gt;voice&lt;/i&gt; they that heard intreated that the word should not be spoken to them any more:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">(For they could not endure that which was commanded, And if so much as a beast touch the mountain, it shall be stoned, or thrust through with a dart:</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And so terrible was the sight, &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; Moses said, I exceedingly fear and quake:)</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But ye are come unto mount Sion, and unto the city of the living God, the heavenly Jerusalem, and to an innumerable company of angels,</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">To the general assembly and church of the firstborn, which are written in heaven, and to God the Judge of all, and to the spirits of just men made perfect,</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And to Jesus the mediator of the new covenant, and to the blood of sprinkling, that speaketh better things than &lt;i&gt;that of&lt;/i&gt; Abel.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">See that ye refuse not him that speaketh. For if they escaped not who refused him that spake on earth, much more &lt;i&gt;shall not&lt;/i&gt; we &lt;i&gt;escape&lt;/i&gt;, if we turn away from him that &lt;i&gt;speaketh&lt;/i&gt; from heaven:</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">Whose voice then shook the earth: but now he hath promised, saying, Yet once more I shake not the earth only, but also heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And this &lt;i&gt;word&lt;/i&gt;, Yet once more, signifieth the removing of those things that are shaken, as of things that are made, that those things which cannot be shaken may remain.</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">Wherefore we receiving a kingdom which cannot be moved, let us have grace, whereby we may serve God acceptably with reverence and godly fear:</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">For our God &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a consuming fire.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>