<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="58" name="Hebrews" bookPage="hebrews.html" title="Hebrews" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="james_1.html" nextTitle="James" prevBook="philemon_1.html" prevTitle="Philemon">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="25" nextChapter="james_1.html" nextTitle="James 1" prevChapter="hebrews_12.html" prevTitle="Hebrews 12" chapterPage="hebrews_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Let brotherly love continue.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Be not forgetful to entertain strangers: for thereby some have entertained angels unawares.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Remember them that are in bonds, as bound with them; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; them which suffer adversity, as being yourselves also in the body.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Marriage &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; honourable in all, and the bed undefiled: but whoremongers and adulterers God will judge.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class="extra"&gt;Let your&lt;/span&gt; conversation &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; without covetousness; &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and be&lt;/span&gt; content with such things as ye have: for he hath said, I will never leave thee, nor forsake thee.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">So that we may boldly say, The Lord &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; my helper, and I will not fear what man shall do unto me.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Remember them which have the rule over you, who have spoken unto you the word of God: whose faith follow, considering the end of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; conversation.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Jesus Christ the same yesterday, and to day, and for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Be not carried about with divers and strange doctrines. For &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it is&lt;/span&gt; a good thing that the heart be established with grace; not with meats, which have not profited them that have been occupied therein.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">We have an altar, whereof they have no right to eat which serve the tabernacle.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For the bodies of those beasts, whose blood is brought into the sanctuary by the high priest for sin, are burned without the camp.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Wherefore Jesus also, that he might sanctify the people with his own blood, suffered without the gate.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Let us go forth therefore unto him without the camp, bearing his reproach.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For here have we no continuing city, but we seek one to come.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">By him therefore let us offer the sacrifice of praise to God continually, that is, the fruit of &lt;span class="extra"&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; lips giving thanks to his name.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But to do good and to communicate forget not: for with such sacrifices God is well pleased.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Obey them that have the rule over you, and submit yourselves: for they watch for your souls, as they that must give account, that they may do it with joy, and not with grief: for that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unprofitable for you.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Pray for us: for we trust we have a good conscience, in all things willing to live honestly.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">But I beseech &lt;span class="extra"&gt;you&lt;/span&gt; the rather to do this, that I may be restored to you the sooner.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Now the God of peace, that brought again from the dead our Lord Jesus, that great shepherd of the sheep, through the blood of the everlasting covenant,</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Make you perfect in every good work to do his will, working in you that which is wellpleasing in his sight, through Jesus Christ; to whom &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; glory for ever and ever. Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And I beseech you, brethren, suffer the word of exhortation: for I have written a letter unto you in few words.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">Know ye that &lt;span class="extra"&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; brother Timothy is set at liberty; with whom, if he come shortly, I will see you.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Salute all them that have the rule over you, and all the saints. They of Italy salute you.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Grace &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; with you all. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>