<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="58" name="Hebrews" bookPage="hebrews.html" title="Hebrews" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="james_1.html" nextTitle="James" prevBook="philemon_1.html" prevTitle="Philemon">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="14" nextChapter="hebrews_2.html" nextTitle="Hebrews 2" prevChapter="philemon_1.html" prevTitle="Philemon 1" chapterPage="hebrews_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">God, who at sundry times and in divers manners spake in time past unto the fathers by the prophets,</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Hath in these last days spoken unto us by &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; Son, whom he hath appointed heir of all things, by whom also he made the worlds;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Who being the brightness of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; glory, and the express image of his person, and upholding all things by the word of his power, when he had by himself purged our sins, sat down on the right hand of the Majesty on high;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Being made so much better than the angels, as he hath by inheritance obtained a more excellent name than they.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">For unto which of the angels said he at any time, Thou art my Son, this day have I begotten thee? And again, I will be to him a Father, and he shall be to me a Son?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And again, when he bringeth in the firstbegotten into the world, he saith, And let all the angels of God worship him.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And of the angels he saith, Who maketh his angels spirits, and his ministers a flame of fire.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But unto the Son &lt;span class='extra'&gt;he saith&lt;/span&gt;, Thy throne, O God, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; for ever and ever: a sceptre of righteousness &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the sceptre of thy kingdom.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Thou hast loved righteousness, and hated iniquity; therefore God, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; thy God, hath anointed thee with the oil of gladness above thy fellows.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And, Thou, Lord, in the beginning hast laid the foundation of the earth; and the heavens are the works of thine hands:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">They shall perish; but thou remainest; and they all shall wax old as doth a garment;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And as a vesture shalt thou fold them up, and they shall be changed: but thou art the same, and thy years shall not fail.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But to which of the angels said he at any time, Sit on my right hand, until I make thine enemies thy footstool?</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Are they not all ministering spirits, sent forth to minister for them who shall be heirs of salvation?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>