<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="58" name="Hebrews" bookPage="hebrews.html" title="Hebrews" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="james_1.html" nextTitle="James" prevBook="philemon_1.html" prevTitle="Philemon">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="19" nextChapter="hebrews_4.html" nextTitle="Hebrews 4" prevChapter="hebrews_2.html" prevTitle="Hebrews 2" chapterPage="hebrews_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Wherefore, holy brethren, partakers of the heavenly calling, consider the Apostle and High Priest of our profession, Christ Jesus;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Who was faithful to him that appointed him, as also Moses &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was faithful&lt;/span&gt; in all his house.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt; was counted worthy of more glory than Moses, inasmuch as he who hath builded the house hath more honour than the house.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For every house is builded by some &lt;span class="extra"&gt;man&lt;/span&gt;; but he that built all things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; God.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And Moses verily &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; faithful in all his house, as a servant, for a testimony of those things which were to be spoken after;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But Christ as a son over his own house; whose house are we, if we hold fast the confidence and the rejoicing of the hope firm unto the end.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Wherefore (as the Holy Ghost saith, To day if ye will hear his voice,</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Harden not your hearts, as in the provocation, in the day of temptation in the wilderness:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">When your fathers tempted me, proved me, and saw my works forty years.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Wherefore I was grieved with that generation, and said, They do alway err in &lt;span class="extra"&gt;their&lt;/span&gt; heart; and they have not known my ways.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">So I sware in my wrath, They shall not enter into my rest.)</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Take heed, brethren, lest there be in any of you an evil heart of unbelief, in departing from the living God.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">But exhort one another daily, while it is called To day; lest any of you be hardened through the deceitfulness of sin.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">For we are made partakers of Christ, if we hold the beginning of our confidence stedfast unto the end;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">While it is said, To day if ye will hear his voice, harden not your hearts, as in the provocation.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For some, when they had heard, did provoke: howbeit not all that came out of Egypt by Moses.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But with whom was he grieved forty years? &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was it&lt;/span&gt; not with them that had sinned, whose carcases fell in the wilderness?</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And to whom sware he that they should not enter into his rest, but to them that believed not?</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">So we see that they could not enter in because of unbelief.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>