<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="58" name="Hebrews" bookPage="hebrews.html" title="Hebrews" chapterCount="13" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="james_1.html" nextTitle="James" prevBook="philemon_1.html" prevTitle="Philemon">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="16" nextChapter="hebrews_5.html" nextTitle="Hebrews 5" prevChapter="hebrews_3.html" prevTitle="Hebrews 3" chapterPage="hebrews_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Let us therefore fear, lest, a promise being left &lt;span class="extra"&gt;us&lt;/span&gt; of entering into his rest, any of you should seem to come short of it.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For unto us was the gospel preached, as well as unto them: but the word preached did not profit them, not being mixed with faith in them that heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">For we which have believed do enter into rest, as he said, As I have sworn in my wrath, if they shall enter into my rest: although the works were finished from the foundation of the world.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">For he spake in a certain place of the seventh &lt;span class="extra"&gt;day&lt;/span&gt; on this wise, And God did rest the seventh day from all his works.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And in this &lt;span class="extra"&gt;place&lt;/span&gt; again, If they shall enter into my rest.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Seeing therefore it remaineth that some must enter therein, and they to whom it was first preached entered not in because of unbelief:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Again, he limiteth a certain day, saying in David, To day, after so long a time; as it is said, To day if ye will hear his voice, harden not your hearts.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For if Jesus had given them rest, then would he not afterward have spoken of another day.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">There remaineth therefore a rest to the people of God.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For he that is entered into his rest, he also hath ceased from his own works, as God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;did&lt;/span&gt; from his.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Let us labour therefore to enter into that rest, lest any man fall after the same example of unbelief.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">For the word of God &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; quick, and powerful, and sharper than any twoedged sword, piercing even to the dividing asunder of soul and spirit, and of the joints and marrow, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; a discerner of the thoughts and intents of the heart.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Neither is there any creature that is not manifest in his sight: but all things &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; naked and opened unto the eyes of him with whom we have to do.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Seeing then that we have a great high priest, that is passed into the heavens, Jesus the Son of God, let us hold fast &lt;span class="extra"&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; profession.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For we have not an high priest which cannot be touched with the feeling of our infirmities; but was in all points tempted like as &lt;span class="extra"&gt;we are, yet&lt;/span&gt; without sin.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Let us therefore come boldly unto the throne of grace, that we may obtain mercy, and find grace to help in time of need.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>