<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="59" name="James" bookPage="james.html" title="James" chapterCount="5" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1peter_1.html" nextTitle="1 Peter" prevBook="hebrews_1.html" prevTitle="Hebrews">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="17" nextChapter="james_5.html" nextTitle="James 5" prevChapter="james_3.html" prevTitle="James 3" chapterPage="james_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">From whence &lt;span class='extra'&gt;come&lt;/span&gt; wars and fightings among you? &lt;span class='extra'&gt;come they&lt;/span&gt; not hence, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;even&lt;/span&gt; of your lusts that war in your members?</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Ye lust, and have not: ye kill, and desire to have, and cannot obtain: ye fight and war, yet ye have not, because ye ask not.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Ye ask, and receive not, because ye ask amiss, that ye may consume &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; upon your lusts.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Ye adulterers and adulteresses, know ye not that the friendship of the world is enmity with God? whosoever therefore will be a friend of the world is the enemy of God.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Do ye think that the scripture saith in vain, The spirit that dwelleth in us lusteth to envy?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But he giveth more grace. Wherefore he saith, God resisteth the proud, but giveth grace unto the humble.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Submit yourselves therefore to God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Draw nigh to God, and he will draw nigh to you. Cleanse &lt;span class='extra'&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; hands, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;ye&lt;/span&gt; sinners; and purify &lt;span class='extra'&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; hearts, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;ye&lt;/span&gt; double minded.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Be afflicted, and mourn, and weep: let your laughter be turned to mourning, and &lt;span class='extra'&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; joy to heaviness.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Humble yourselves in the sight of the Lord, and he shall lift you up.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Speak not evil one of another, brethren. He that speaketh evil of &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; brother, and judgeth his brother, speaketh evil of the law, and judgeth the law: but if thou judge the law, thou art not a doer of the law, but a judge.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">There is one lawgiver, who is able to save and to destroy: who art thou that judgest another?</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Go to now, ye that say, To day or to morrow we will go into such a city, and continue there a year, and buy and sell, and get gain:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Whereas ye know not what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; on the morrow. For what &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; your life? It is even a vapour, that appeareth for a little time, and then vanisheth away.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For that ye &lt;span class='extra'&gt;ought&lt;/span&gt; to say, If the Lord will, we shall live, and do this, or that.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">But now ye rejoice in your boastings: all such rejoicing is evil.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Therefore to him that knoweth to do good, and doeth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; not, to him it is sin.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>