<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="59" name="James" bookPage="james.html" title="James" chapterCount="5" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1peter_1.html" nextTitle="1 Peter" prevBook="hebrews_1.html" prevTitle="Hebrews">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="26" nextChapter="james_3.html" nextTitle="James 3" prevChapter="james_1.html" prevTitle="James 1" chapterPage="james_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">My brethren, have not the faith of our Lord Jesus Christ, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;the Lord&lt;/span&gt; of glory, with respect of persons.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For if there come unto your assembly a man with a gold ring, in goodly apparel, and there come in also a poor man in vile raiment;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And ye have respect to him that weareth the gay clothing, and say unto him, Sit thou here in a good place; and say to the poor, Stand thou there, or sit here under my footstool:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Are ye not then partial in yourselves, and are become judges of evil thoughts?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Hearken, my beloved brethren, Hath not God chosen the poor of this world rich in faith, and heirs of the kingdom which he hath promised to them that love him?</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But ye have despised the poor. Do not rich men oppress you, and draw you before the judgment seats?</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Do not they blaspheme that worthy name by the which ye are called?</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">If ye fulfil the royal law according to the scripture, Thou shalt love thy neighbour as thyself, ye do well:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But if ye have respect to persons, ye commit sin, and are convinced of the law as transgressors.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">For whosoever shall keep the whole law, and yet offend in one &lt;span class="extra"&gt;point&lt;/span&gt;, he is guilty of all.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For he that said, Do not commit adultery, said also, Do not kill. Now if thou commit no adultery, yet if thou kill, thou art become a transgressor of the law.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">So speak ye, and so do, as they that shall be judged by the law of liberty.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">For he shall have judgment without mercy, that hath shewed no mercy; and mercy rejoiceth against judgment.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">What &lt;span class="extra"&gt;doth it&lt;/span&gt; profit, my brethren, though a man say he hath faith, and have not works? can faith save him?</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">If a brother or sister be naked, and destitute of daily food,</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And one of you say unto them, Depart in peace, be &lt;span class="extra"&gt;ye&lt;/span&gt; warmed and filled; notwithstanding ye give them not those things which are needful to the body; what &lt;span class="extra"&gt;doth it&lt;/span&gt; profit?</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Even so faith, if it hath not works, is dead, being alone.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Yea, a man may say, Thou hast faith, and I have works: shew me thy faith without thy works, and I will shew thee my faith by my works.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Thou believest that there is one God; thou doest well: the devils also believe, and tremble.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">But wilt thou know, O vain man, that faith without works is dead?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Was not Abraham our father justified by works, when he had offered Isaac his son upon the altar?</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">Seest thou how faith wrought with his works, and by works was faith made perfect?</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the scripture was fulfilled which saith, Abraham believed God, and it was imputed unto him for righteousness: and he was called the Friend of God.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">Ye see then how that by works a man is justified, and not by faith only.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">Likewise also was not Rahab the harlot justified by works, when she had received the messengers, and had sent &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt; out another way?</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">For as the body without the spirit is dead, so faith without works is dead also.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>