<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="59" name="James" bookPage="james.html" title="James" chapterCount="5" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1peter_1.html" nextTitle="1 Peter" prevBook="hebrews_1.html" prevTitle="Hebrews">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="27" nextChapter="james_2.html" nextTitle="James 2" prevChapter="hebrews_13.html" prevTitle="Hebrews 13" chapterPage="james_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">James, a servant of God and of the Lord Jesus Christ, to the twelve tribes which are scattered abroad, greeting.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">My brethren, count it all joy when ye fall into divers temptations;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Knowing &lt;span class='extra'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;, that the trying of your faith worketh patience.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">But let patience have &lt;span class='extra'&gt;her&lt;/span&gt; perfect work, that ye may be perfect and entire, wanting nothing.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask of God, that giveth to all &lt;span class='extra'&gt;men&lt;/span&gt; liberally, and upbraideth not; and it shall be given him.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">But let him ask in faith, nothing wavering. For he that wavereth is like a wave of the sea driven with the wind and tossed.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For let not that man think that he shall receive any thing of the Lord.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">A double minded man &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; unstable in all his ways.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Let the brother of low degree rejoice in that he is exalted:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But the rich, in that he is made low: because as the flower of the grass he shall pass away.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For the sun is no sooner risen with a burning heat, but it withereth the grass, and the flower thereof falleth, and the grace of the fashion of it perisheth: so also shall the rich man fade away in his ways.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the man that endureth temptation: for when he is tried, he shall receive the crown of life, which the Lord hath promised to them that love him.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Let no man say when he is tempted, I am tempted of God: for God cannot be tempted with evil, neither tempteth he any man:</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But every man is tempted, when he is drawn away of his own lust, and enticed.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Then when lust hath conceived, it bringeth forth sin: and sin, when it is finished, bringeth forth death.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">Do not err, my beloved brethren.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Every good gift and every perfect gift is from above, and cometh down from the Father of lights, with whom is no variableness, neither shadow of turning.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Of his own will begat he us with the word of truth, that we should be a kind of firstfruits of his creatures.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">Wherefore, my beloved brethren, let every man be swift to hear, slow to speak, slow to wrath:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">For the wrath of man worketh not the righteousness of God.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">Wherefore lay apart all filthiness and superfluity of naughtiness, and receive with meekness the engrafted word, which is able to save your souls.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">But be ye doers of the word, and not hearers only, deceiving your own selves.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">For if any be a hearer of the word, and not a doer, he is like unto a man beholding his natural face in a glass:</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">For he beholdeth himself, and goeth his way, and straightway forgetteth what manner of man he was.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">But whoso looketh into the perfect law of liberty, and continueth &lt;span class='extra'&gt;therein&lt;/span&gt;, he being not a forgetful hearer, but a doer of the work, this man shall be blessed in his deed.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">If any man among you seem to be religious, and bridleth not his tongue, but deceiveth his own heart, this man's religion &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; vain.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">Pure religion and undefiled before God and the Father is this, To visit the fatherless and widows in their affliction, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; to keep himself unspotted from the world.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>