<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="59" name="James" bookPage="james.html" title="James" chapterCount="5" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1peter_1.html" nextTitle="1 Peter" prevBook="hebrews_1.html" prevTitle="Hebrews">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="18" nextChapter="james_4.html" nextTitle="James 4" prevChapter="james_2.html" prevTitle="James 2" chapterPage="james_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">My brethren, be not many masters, knowing that we shall receive the greater condemnation.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For in many things we offend all. If any man offend not in word, the same &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a perfect man, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; able also to bridle the whole body.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Behold, we put bits in the horses' mouths, that they may obey us; and we turn about their whole body.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Behold also the ships, which though &lt;i&gt;they be&lt;/i&gt; so great, and &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; driven of fierce winds, yet are they turned about with a very small helm, whithersoever the governor listeth.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Even so the tongue is a little member, and boasteth great things. Behold, how great a matter a little fire kindleth!</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And the tongue &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a fire, a world of iniquity: so is the tongue among our members, that it defileth the whole body, and setteth on fire the course of nature; and it is set on fire of hell.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For every kind of beasts, and of birds, and of serpents, and of things in the sea, is tamed, and hath been tamed of mankind:</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But the tongue can no man tame; &lt;i&gt;it is&lt;/i&gt; an unruly evil, full of deadly poison.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Therewith bless we God, even the Father; and therewith curse we men, which are made after the similitude of God.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Out of the same mouth proceedeth blessing and cursing. My brethren, these things ought not so to be.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Doth a fountain send forth at the same place sweet &lt;i&gt;water&lt;/i&gt; and bitter?</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Can the fig tree, my brethren, bear olive berries? either a vine, figs? so &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; no fountain both yield salt water and fresh.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a wise man and endued with knowledge among you? let him shew out of a good conversation his works with meekness of wisdom.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">But if ye have bitter envying and strife in your hearts, glory not, and lie not against the truth.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">This wisdom descendeth not from above, but &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; earthly, sensual, devilish.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For where envying and strife &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt;, there &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; confusion and every evil work.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">But the wisdom that is from above is first pure, then peaceable, gentle, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; easy to be intreated, full of mercy and good fruits, without partiality, and without hypocrisy.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the fruit of righteousness is sown in peace of them that make peace.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>