<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="60" name="1 Peter" bookPage="1peter.html" title="1 Peter" chapterCount="5" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2peter_1.html" nextTitle="2 Peter" prevBook="james_1.html" prevTitle="James">
    <chapter number="5" verseCount="14" nextChapter="2peter_1.html" nextTitle="2 Peter 1" prevChapter="1peter_4.html" prevTitle="1 Peter 4" chapterPage="1peter_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The elders which are among you I exhort, who am also an elder, and a witness of the sufferings of Christ, and also a partaker of the glory that shall be revealed:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Feed the flock of God which is among you, taking the oversight &lt;i&gt;thereof&lt;/i&gt;, not by constraint, but willingly; not for filthy lucre, but of a ready mind;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Neither as being lords over &lt;i&gt;God's&lt;/i&gt; heritage, but being ensamples to the flock.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And when the chief Shepherd shall appear, ye shall receive a crown of glory that fadeth not away.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">Likewise, ye younger, submit yourselves unto the elder. Yea, all &lt;i&gt;of you&lt;/i&gt; be subject one to another, and be clothed with humility: for God resisteth the proud, and giveth grace to the humble.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">Humble yourselves therefore under the mighty hand of God, that he may exalt you in due time:</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Casting all your care upon him; for he careth for you.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Be sober, be vigilant; because your adversary the devil, as a roaring lion, walketh about, seeking whom he may devour:</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Whom resist stedfast in the faith, knowing that the same afflictions are accomplished in your brethren that are in the world.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">But the God of all grace, who hath called us unto his eternal glory by Christ Jesus, after that ye have suffered a while, make you perfect, stablish, strengthen, settle &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">To him &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; glory and dominion for ever and ever. Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">By Silvanus, a faithful brother unto you, as I suppose, I have written briefly, exhorting, and testifying that this is the true grace of God wherein ye stand.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The &lt;i&gt;church that is&lt;/i&gt; at Babylon, elected together with &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;, saluteth you; and &lt;i&gt;so doth&lt;/i&gt; Marcus my son.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Greet ye one another with a kiss of charity. Peace &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; with you all that are in Christ Jesus. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>