<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="61" name="2 Peter" bookPage="2peter.html" title="2 Peter" chapterCount="3" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="1john_1.html" nextTitle="1 John" prevBook="1peter_1.html" prevTitle="1 Peter">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="21" nextChapter="2peter_2.html" nextTitle="2 Peter 2" prevChapter="1peter_5.html" prevTitle="1 Peter 5" chapterPage="2peter_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Simon Peter, a servant and an apostle of Jesus Christ, to them that have obtained like precious faith with us through the righteousness of God and our Saviour Jesus Christ:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Grace and peace be multiplied unto you through the knowledge of God, and of Jesus our Lord,</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">According as his divine power hath given unto us all things that &lt;i&gt;pertain&lt;/i&gt; unto life and godliness, through the knowledge of him that hath called us to glory and virtue:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Whereby are given unto us exceeding great and precious promises: that by these ye might be partakers of the divine nature, having escaped the corruption that is in the world through lust.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And beside this, giving all diligence, add to your faith virtue; and to virtue knowledge;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And to knowledge temperance; and to temperance patience; and to patience godliness;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And to godliness brotherly kindness; and to brotherly kindness charity.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">For if these things be in you, and abound, they make &lt;i&gt;you that ye shall&lt;/i&gt; neither &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; barren nor unfruitful in the knowledge of our Lord Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">But he that lacketh these things is blind, and cannot see afar off, and hath forgotten that he was purged from his old sins.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Wherefore the rather, brethren, give diligence to make your calling and election sure: for if ye do these things, ye shall never fall:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For so an entrance shall be ministered unto you abundantly into the everlasting kingdom of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Wherefore I will not be negligent to put you always in remembrance of these things, though ye know &lt;i&gt;them&lt;/i&gt;, and be established in the present truth.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Yea, I think it meet, as long as I am in this tabernacle, to stir you up by putting &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; in remembrance;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Knowing that shortly I must put off &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; my tabernacle, even as our Lord Jesus Christ hath shewed me.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Moreover I will endeavour that ye may be able after my decease to have these things always in remembrance.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">For we have not followed cunningly devised fables, when we made known unto you the power and coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, but were eyewitnesses of his majesty.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For he received from God the Father honour and glory, when there came such a voice to him from the excellent glory, This is my beloved Son, in whom I am well pleased.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And this voice which came from heaven we heard, when we were with him in the holy mount.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">We have also a more sure word of prophecy; whereunto ye do well that ye take heed, as unto a light that shineth in a dark place, until the day dawn, and the day star arise in your hearts:</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">Knowing this first, that no prophecy of the scripture is of any private interpretation.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">For the prophecy came not in old time by the will of man: but holy men of God spake &lt;i&gt;as they were&lt;/i&gt; moved by the Holy Ghost.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>