<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="62" name="1 John" bookPage="1john.html" title="1 John" chapterCount="5" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="2john_1.html" nextTitle="2 John" prevBook="2peter_1.html" prevTitle="2 Peter">
    <chapter number="4" verseCount="21" nextChapter="1john_5.html" nextTitle="1 John 5" prevChapter="1john_3.html" prevTitle="1 John 3" chapterPage="1john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">Beloved, believe not every spirit, but try the spirits whether they are of God: because many false prophets are gone out into the world.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Hereby know ye the Spirit of God: Every spirit that confesseth that Jesus Christ is come in the flesh is of God:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And every spirit that confesseth not that Jesus Christ is come in the flesh is not of God: and this is that &lt;span class='extra'&gt;spirit&lt;/span&gt; of antichrist, whereof ye have heard that it should come; and even now already is it in the world.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">Ye are of God, little children, and have overcome them: because greater is he that is in you, than he that is in the world.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">They are of the world: therefore speak they of the world, and the world heareth them.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">We are of God: he that knoweth God heareth us; he that is not of God heareth not us. Hereby know we the spirit of truth, and the spirit of error.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Beloved, let us love one another: for love is of God; and every one that loveth is born of God, and knoweth God.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">He that loveth not knoweth not God; for God is love.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">In this was manifested the love of God toward us, because that God sent his only begotten Son into the world, that we might live through him.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">Herein is love, not that we loved God, but that he loved us, and sent his Son &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; the propitiation for our sins.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Beloved, if God so loved us, we ought also to love one another.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">No man hath seen God at any time. If we love one another, God dwelleth in us, and his love is perfected in us.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">Hereby know we that we dwell in him, and he in us, because he hath given us of his Spirit.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And we have seen and do testify that the Father sent the Son &lt;span class='extra'&gt;to be&lt;/span&gt; the Saviour of the world.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">Whosoever shall confess that Jesus is the Son of God, God dwelleth in him, and he in God.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And we have known and believed the love that God hath to us. God is love; and he that dwelleth in love dwelleth in God, and God in him.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">Herein is our love made perfect, that we may have boldness in the day of judgment: because as he is, so are we in this world.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">There is no fear in love; but perfect love casteth out fear: because fear hath torment. He that feareth is not made perfect in love.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">We love him, because he first loved us.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">If a man say, I love God, and hateth his brother, he is a liar: for he that loveth not his brother whom he hath seen, how can he love God whom he hath not seen?</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And this commandment have we from him, That he who loveth God love his brother also.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>