<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="63" name="2 John" bookPage="2john.html" title="2 John" chapterCount="1" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="3john_1.html" nextTitle="3 John" prevBook="1john_1.html" prevTitle="1 John">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="13" nextChapter="3john_1.html" nextTitle="3 John 1" prevChapter="1john_5.html" prevTitle="1 John 5" chapterPage="2john_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The elder unto the elect lady and her children, whom I love in the truth; and not I only, but also all they that have known the truth;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">For the truth's sake, which dwelleth in us, and shall be with us for ever.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Grace be with you, mercy, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; peace, from God the Father, and from the Lord Jesus Christ, the Son of the Father, in truth and love.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">I rejoiced greatly that I found of thy children walking in truth, as we have received a commandment from the Father.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And now I beseech thee, lady, not as though I wrote a new commandment unto thee, but that which we had from the beginning, that we love one another.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And this is love, that we walk after his commandments. This is the commandment, That, as ye have heard from the beginning, ye should walk in it.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">For many deceivers are entered into the world, who confess not that Jesus Christ is come in the flesh. This is a deceiver and an antichrist.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">Look to yourselves, that we lose not those things which we have wrought, but that we receive a full reward.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Whosoever transgresseth, and abideth not in the doctrine of Christ, hath not God. He that abideth in the doctrine of Christ, he hath both the Father and the Son.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">If there come any unto you, and bring not this doctrine, receive him not into &lt;span class='extra'&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; house, neither bid him God speed:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">For he that biddeth him God speed is partaker of his evil deeds.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Having many things to write unto you, I would not &lt;span class='extra'&gt;write&lt;/span&gt; with paper and ink: but I trust to come unto you, and speak face to face, that our joy may be full.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">The children of thy elect sister greet thee. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>