<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="66" name="Revelation" bookPage="revelation.html" title="Revelation" chapterCount="22" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="genesis_1.html" nextTitle="Genesis" prevBook="jude_1.html" prevTitle="Jude">
    <chapter number="14" verseCount="20" nextChapter="revelation_15.html" nextTitle="Revelation 15" prevChapter="revelation_13.html" prevTitle="Revelation 13" chapterPage="revelation_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And I looked, and, lo, a Lamb stood on the mount Sion, and with him an hundred forty &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; four thousand, having his Father's name written in their foreheads.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And I heard a voice from heaven, as the voice of many waters, and as the voice of a great thunder: and I heard the voice of harpers harping with their harps:</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And they sung as it were a new song before the throne, and before the four beasts, and the elders: and no man could learn that song but the hundred &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; forty &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; four thousand, which were redeemed from the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">These are they which were not defiled with women; for they are virgins. These are they which follow the Lamb whithersoever he goeth. These were redeemed from among men, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;being&lt;/span&gt; the firstfruits unto God and to the Lamb.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And in their mouth was found no guile: for they are without fault before the throne of God.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I saw another angel fly in the midst of heaven, having the everlasting gospel to preach unto them that dwell on the earth, and to every nation, and kindred, and tongue, and people,</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Saying with a loud voice, Fear God, and give glory to him; for the hour of his judgment is come: and worship him that made heaven, and earth, and the sea, and the fountains of waters.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And there followed another angel, saying, Babylon is fallen, is fallen, that great city, because she made all nations drink of the wine of the wrath of her fornication.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And the third angel followed them, saying with a loud voice, If any man worship the beast and his image, and receive &lt;span class='extra'&gt;his&lt;/span&gt; mark in his forehead, or in his hand,</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">The same shall drink of the wine of the wrath of God, which is poured out without mixture into the cup of his indignation; and he shall be tormented with fire and brimstone in the presence of the holy angels, and in the presence of the Lamb:</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And the smoke of their torment ascendeth up for ever and ever: and they have no rest day nor night, who worship the beast and his image, and whosoever receiveth the mark of his name.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">Here is the patience of the saints: here &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they that keep the commandments of God, and the faith of Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And I heard a voice from heaven saying unto me, Write, Blessed &lt;span class='extra'&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; the dead which die in the Lord from henceforth: Yea, saith the Spirit, that they may rest from their labours; and their works do follow them.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And I looked, and behold a white cloud, and upon the cloud &lt;span class='extra'&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; sat like unto the Son of man, having on his head a golden crown, and in his hand a sharp sickle.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And another angel came out of the temple, crying with a loud voice to him that sat on the cloud, Thrust in thy sickle, and reap: for the time is come for thee to reap; for the harvest of the earth is ripe.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he that sat on the cloud thrust in his sickle on the earth; and the earth was reaped.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And another angel came out of the temple which is in heaven, he also having a sharp sickle.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And another angel came out from the altar, which had power over fire; and cried with a loud cry to him that had the sharp sickle, saying, Thrust in thy sharp sickle, and gather the clusters of the vine of the earth; for her grapes are fully ripe.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the angel thrust in his sickle into the earth, and gathered the vine of the earth, and cast &lt;span class='extra'&gt;it&lt;/span&gt; into the great winepress of the wrath of God.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">And the winepress was trodden without the city, and blood came out of the winepress, even unto the horse bridles, by the space of a thousand &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; six hundred furlongs.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>