<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="66" name="Revelation" bookPage="revelation.html" title="Revelation" chapterCount="22" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="genesis_1.html" nextTitle="Genesis" prevBook="jude_1.html" prevTitle="Jude">
    <chapter number="3" verseCount="22" nextChapter="revelation_4.html" nextTitle="Revelation 4" prevChapter="revelation_2.html" prevTitle="Revelation 2" chapterPage="revelation_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And unto the angel of the church in Sardis write; These things saith he that hath the seven Spirits of God, and the seven stars; I know thy works, that thou hast a name that thou livest, and art dead.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Be watchful, and strengthen the things which remain, that are ready to die: for I have not found thy works perfect before God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Remember therefore how thou hast received and heard, and hold fast, and repent. If therefore thou shalt not watch, I will come on thee as a thief, and thou shalt not know what hour I will come upon thee.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Thou hast a few names even in Sardis which have not defiled their garments; and they shall walk with me in white: for they are worthy.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;He that overcometh, the same shall be clothed in white raiment; and I will not blot out his name out of the book of life, but I will confess his name before my Father, and before his angels.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And to the angel of the church in Philadelphia write; These things saith he that is holy, he that is true, he that hath the key of David, he that openeth, and no man shutteth; and shutteth, and no man openeth;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I know thy works: behold, I have set before thee an open door, and no man can shut it: for thou hast a little strength, and hast kept my word, and hast not denied my name.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold, I will make them of the synagogue of Satan, which say they are Jews, and are not, but do lie; behold, I will make them to come and worship before thy feet, and to know that I have loved thee.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Because thou hast kept the word of my patience, I also will keep thee from the hour of temptation, which shall come upon all the world, to try them that dwell upon the earth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold, I come quickly: hold that fast which thou hast, that no man take thy crown.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Him that overcometh will I make a pillar in the temple of my God, and he shall go no more out: and I will write upon him the name of my God, and the name of the city of my God, &lt;i&gt;which is&lt;/i&gt; new Jerusalem, which cometh down out of heaven from my God: and &lt;i&gt;I will write upon him&lt;/i&gt; my new name.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And unto the angel of the church of the Laodiceans write; These things saith the Amen, the faithful and true witness, the beginning of the creation of God;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I know thy works, that thou art neither cold nor hot: I would thou wert cold or hot.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;So then because thou art lukewarm, and neither cold nor hot, I will spue thee out of my mouth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Because thou sayest, I am rich, and increased with goods, and have need of nothing; and knowest not that thou art wretched, and miserable, and poor, and blind, and naked:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I counsel thee to buy of me gold tried in the fire, that thou mayest be rich; and white raiment, that thou mayest be clothed, and &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; the shame of thy nakedness do not appear; and anoint thine eyes with eyesalve, that thou mayest see.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;As many as I love, I rebuke and chasten: be zealous therefore, and repent.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold, I stand at the door, and knock: if any man hear my voice, and open the door, I will come in to him, and will sup with him, and he with me.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;To him that overcometh will I grant to sit with me in my throne, even as I also overcame, and am set down with my Father in his throne.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>