<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="66" name="Revelation" bookPage="revelation.html" title="Revelation" chapterCount="22" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="genesis_1.html" nextTitle="Genesis" prevBook="jude_1.html" prevTitle="Jude">
    <chapter number="6" verseCount="17" nextChapter="revelation_7.html" nextTitle="Revelation 7" prevChapter="revelation_5.html" prevTitle="Revelation 5" chapterPage="revelation_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And I saw when the Lamb opened one of the seals, and I heard, as it were the noise of thunder, one of the four beasts saying, Come and see.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And I saw, and behold a white horse: and he that sat on him had a bow; and a crown was given unto him: and he went forth conquering, and to conquer.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And when he had opened the second seal, I heard the second beast say, Come and see.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And there went out another horse &lt;i&gt;that was&lt;/i&gt; red: and &lt;i&gt;power&lt;/i&gt; was given to him that sat thereon to take peace from the earth, and that they should kill one another: and there was given unto him a great sword.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And when he had opened the third seal, I heard the third beast say, Come and see. And I beheld, and lo a black horse; and he that sat on him had a pair of balances in his hand.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And I heard a voice in the midst of the four beasts say, A measure of wheat for a penny, and three measures of barley for a penny; and &lt;i&gt;see&lt;/i&gt; thou hurt not the oil and the wine.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And when he had opened the fourth seal, I heard the voice of the fourth beast say, Come and see.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I looked, and behold a pale horse: and his name that sat on him was Death, and Hell followed with him. And power was given unto them over the fourth part of the earth, to kill with sword, and with hunger, and with death, and with the beasts of the earth.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And when he had opened the fifth seal, I saw under the altar the souls of them that were slain for the word of God, and for the testimony which they held:</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And they cried with a loud voice, saying, How long, O Lord, holy and true, dost thou not judge and avenge our blood on them that dwell on the earth?</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And white robes were given unto every one of them; and it was said unto them, that they should rest yet for a little season, until their fellowservants also and their brethren, that should be killed as they &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt;, should be fulfilled.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I beheld when he had opened the sixth seal, and, lo, there was a great earthquake; and the sun became black as sackcloth of hair, and the moon became as blood;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And the stars of heaven fell unto the earth, even as a fig tree casteth her untimely figs, when she is shaken of a mighty wind.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the heaven departed as a scroll when it is rolled together; and every mountain and island were moved out of their places.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And the kings of the earth, and the great men, and the rich men, and the chief captains, and the mighty men, and every bondman, and every free man, hid themselves in the dens and in the rocks of the mountains;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And said to the mountains and rocks, Fall on us, and hide us from the face of him that sitteth on the throne, and from the wrath of the Lamb:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">For the great day of his wrath is come; and who shall be able to stand?</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>