<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="66" name="Revelation" bookPage="revelation.html" title="Revelation" chapterCount="22" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="genesis_1.html" nextTitle="Genesis" prevBook="jude_1.html" prevTitle="Jude">
    <chapter number="13" verseCount="18" nextChapter="revelation_14.html" nextTitle="Revelation 14" prevChapter="revelation_12.html" prevTitle="Revelation 12" chapterPage="revelation_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And I stood upon the sand of the sea, and saw a beast rise up out of the sea, having seven heads and ten horns, and upon his horns ten crowns, and upon his heads the name of blasphemy.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And the beast which I saw was like unto a leopard, and his feet were as &lt;i&gt;the feet&lt;/i&gt; of a bear, and his mouth as the mouth of a lion: and the dragon gave him his power, and his seat, and great authority.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I saw one of his heads as it were wounded to death; and his deadly wound was healed: and all the world wondered after the beast.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they worshipped the dragon which gave power unto the beast: and they worshipped the beast, saying, Who &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; like unto the beast? who is able to make war with him?</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And there was given unto him a mouth speaking great things and blasphemies; and power was given unto him to continue forty &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; two months.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he opened his mouth in blasphemy against God, to blaspheme his name, and his tabernacle, and them that dwell in heaven.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">And it was given unto him to make war with the saints, and to overcome them: and power was given him over all kindreds, and tongues, and nations.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And all that dwell upon the earth shall worship him, whose names are not written in the book of life of the Lamb slain from the foundation of the world.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">If any man have an ear, let him hear.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">He that leadeth into captivity shall go into captivity: he that killeth with the sword must be killed with the sword. Here is the patience and the faith of the saints.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">And I beheld another beast coming up out of the earth; and he had two horns like a lamb, and he spake as a dragon.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And he exerciseth all the power of the first beast before him, and causeth the earth and them which dwell therein to worship the first beast, whose deadly wound was healed.</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And he doeth great wonders, so that he maketh fire come down from heaven on the earth in the sight of men,</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And deceiveth them that dwell on the earth by &lt;i&gt;the means of&lt;/i&gt; those miracles which he had power to do in the sight of the beast; saying to them that dwell on the earth, that they should make an image to the beast, which had the wound by a sword, and did live.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he had power to give life unto the image of the beast, that the image of the beast should both speak, and cause that as many as would not worship the image of the beast should be killed.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he causeth all, both small and great, rich and poor, free and bond, to receive a mark in their right hand, or in their foreheads:</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And that no man might buy or sell, save he that had the mark, or the name of the beast, or the number of his name.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">Here is wisdom. Let him that hath understanding count the number of the beast: for it is the number of a man; and his number &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; Six hundred threescore &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; six.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>