<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="66" name="Revelation" bookPage="revelation.html" title="Revelation" chapterCount="22" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="genesis_1.html" nextTitle="Genesis" prevBook="jude_1.html" prevTitle="Jude">
    <chapter number="1" verseCount="20" nextChapter="revelation_2.html" nextTitle="Revelation 2" prevChapter="jude_1.html" prevTitle="Jude 1" chapterPage="revelation_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">The Revelation of Jesus Christ, which God gave unto him, to shew unto his servants things which must shortly come to pass; and he sent and signified &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; by his angel unto his servant John:</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">Who bare record of the word of God, and of the testimony of Jesus Christ, and of all things that he saw.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">Blessed &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; he that readeth, and they that hear the words of this prophecy, and keep those things which are written therein: for the time &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; at hand.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">John to the seven churches which are in Asia: Grace &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; unto you, and peace, from him which is, and which was, and which is to come; and from the seven Spirits which are before his throne;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And from Jesus Christ, &lt;i&gt;who is&lt;/i&gt; the faithful witness, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the first begotten of the dead, and the prince of the kings of the earth. Unto him that loved us, and washed us from our sins in his own blood,</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And hath made us kings and priests unto God and his Father; to him &lt;i&gt;be&lt;/i&gt; glory and dominion for ever and ever. Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">Behold, he cometh with clouds; and every eye shall see him, and they &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; which pierced him: and all kindreds of the earth shall wail because of him. Even so, Amen.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;woc&gt;I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the ending,&lt;/woc&gt; saith the Lord, &lt;woc&gt;which is, and which was, and which is to come, the Almighty.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">I John, who also am your brother, and companion in tribulation, and in the kingdom and patience of Jesus Christ, was in the isle that is called Patmos, for the word of God, and for the testimony of Jesus Christ.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">I was in the Spirit on the Lord's day, and heard behind me a great voice, as of a trumpet,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Saying, &lt;woc&gt;I am Alpha and Omega, the first and the last: and, What thou seest, write in a book, and send &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt; unto the seven churches which are in Asia; unto Ephesus, and unto Smyrna, and unto Pergamos, and unto Thyatira, and unto Sardis, and unto Philadelphia, and unto Laodicea.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And I turned to see the voice that spake with me. And being turned, I saw seven golden candlesticks;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">And in the midst of the seven candlesticks &lt;i&gt;one&lt;/i&gt; like unto the Son of man, clothed with a garment down to the foot, and girt about the paps with a golden girdle.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">His head and &lt;i&gt;his&lt;/i&gt; hairs &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; white like wool, as white as snow; and his eyes &lt;i&gt;were&lt;/i&gt; as a flame of fire;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And his feet like unto fine brass, as if they burned in a furnace; and his voice as the sound of many waters.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And he had in his right hand seven stars: and out of his mouth went a sharp twoedged sword: and his countenance &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; as the sun shineth in his strength.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And when I saw him, I fell at his feet as dead. And he laid his right hand upon me, saying unto me, &lt;woc&gt;Fear not; I am the first and the last:&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;woc&gt;&lt;i&gt;I am&lt;/i&gt; he that liveth, and was dead; and, behold, I am alive for evermore, Amen; and have the keys of hell and of death.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;woc&gt;Write the things which thou hast seen, and the things which are, and the things which shall be hereafter;&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;woc&gt;The mystery of the seven stars which thou sawest in my right hand, and the seven golden candlesticks. The seven stars are the angels of the seven churches: and the seven candlesticks which thou sawest are the seven churches.&lt;/woc&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>