<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="66" name="Revelation" bookPage="revelation.html" title="Revelation" chapterCount="22" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="genesis_1.html" nextTitle="Genesis" prevBook="jude_1.html" prevTitle="Jude">
    <chapter number="21" verseCount="27" nextChapter="revelation_22.html" nextTitle="Revelation 22" prevChapter="revelation_20.html" prevTitle="Revelation 20" chapterPage="revelation_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And I saw a new heaven and a new earth: for the first heaven and the first earth were passed away; and there was no more sea.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">And I John saw the holy city, new Jerusalem, coming down from God out of heaven, prepared as a bride adorned for her husband.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And I heard a great voice out of heaven saying, Behold, the tabernacle of God &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with men, and he will dwell with them, and they shall be his people, and God himself shall be with them, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and be&lt;/span&gt; their God.</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And God shall wipe away all tears from their eyes; and there shall be no more death, neither sorrow, nor crying, neither shall there be any more pain: for the former things are passed away.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And he that sat upon the throne said, Behold, I make all things new. And he said unto me, Write: for these words are true and faithful.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he said unto me, It is done. I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the end. I will give unto him that is athirst of the fountain of the water of life freely.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">He that overcometh shall inherit all things; and I will be his God, and he shall be my son.</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">But the fearful, and unbelieving, and the abominable, and murderers, and whoremongers, and sorcerers, and idolaters, and all liars, shall have their part in the lake which burneth with fire and brimstone: which is the second death.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">And there came unto me one of the seven angels which had the seven vials full of the seven last plagues, and talked with me, saying, Come hither, I will shew thee the bride, the Lamb's wife.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he carried me away in the spirit to a great and high mountain, and shewed me that great city, the holy Jerusalem, descending out of heaven from God,</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">Having the glory of God: and her light &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; like unto a stone most precious, even like a jasper stone, clear as crystal;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">And had a wall great and high, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; had twelve gates, and at the gates twelve angels, and names written thereon, which are &lt;span class='extra'&gt;the names&lt;/span&gt; of the twelve tribes of the children of Israel:</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">On the east three gates; on the north three gates; on the south three gates; and on the west three gates.</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">And the wall of the city had twelve foundations, and in them the names of the twelve apostles of the Lamb.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">And he that talked with me had a golden reed to measure the city, and the gates thereof, and the wall thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">And the city lieth foursquare, and the length is as large as the breadth: and he measured the city with the reed, twelve thousand furlongs. The length and the breadth and the height of it are equal.</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And he measured the wall thereof, an hundred &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; forty &lt;span class='extra'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; four cubits, &lt;span class='extra'&gt;according to&lt;/span&gt; the measure of a man, that is, of the angel.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">And the building of the wall of it was &lt;span class='extra'&gt;of&lt;/span&gt; jasper: and the city &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; pure gold, like unto clear glass.</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And the foundations of the wall of the city &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; garnished with all manner of precious stones. The first foundation &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; jasper; the second, sapphire; the third, a chalcedony; the fourth, an emerald;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">The fifth, sardonyx; the sixth, sardius; the seventh, chrysolite; the eighth, beryl; the ninth, a topaz; the tenth, a chrysoprasus; the eleventh, a jacinth; the twelfth, an amethyst.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">And the twelve gates &lt;span class='extra'&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; twelve pearls; every several gate was of one pearl: and the street of the city &lt;span class='extra'&gt;was&lt;/span&gt; pure gold, as it were transparent glass.</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">And I saw no temple therein: for the Lord God Almighty and the Lamb are the temple of it.</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">And the city had no need of the sun, neither of the moon, to shine in it: for the glory of God did lighten it, and the Lamb &lt;span class='extra'&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; the light thereof.</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">And the nations of them which are saved shall walk in the light of it: and the kings of the earth do bring their glory and honour into it.</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">And the gates of it shall not be shut at all by day: for there shall be no night there.</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">And they shall bring the glory and honour of the nations into it.</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">And there shall in no wise enter into it any thing that defileth, neither &lt;span class='extra'&gt;whatsoever&lt;/span&gt; worketh abomination, or &lt;span class='extra'&gt;maketh&lt;/span&gt; a lie: but they which are written in the Lamb's book of life.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>