<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="66" name="Revelation" bookPage="revelation.html" title="Revelation" chapterCount="22" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="genesis_1.html" nextTitle="Genesis" prevBook="jude_1.html" prevTitle="Jude">
    <chapter number="2" verseCount="29" nextChapter="revelation_3.html" nextTitle="Revelation 3" prevChapter="revelation_1.html" prevTitle="Revelation 1" chapterPage="revelation_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Unto the angel of the church of Ephesus write; These things saith he that holdeth the seven stars in his right hand, who walketh in the midst of the seven golden candlesticks;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;I know thy works, and thy labour, and thy patience, and how thou canst not bear them which are evil: and thou hast tried them which say they are apostles, and are not, and hast found them liars:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And hast borne, and hast patience, and for my name's sake hast laboured, and hast not fainted.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Nevertheless I have &lt;i&gt;somewhat&lt;/i&gt; against thee, because thou hast left thy first love.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Remember therefore from whence thou art fallen, and repent, and do the first works; or else I will come unto thee quickly, and will remove thy candlestick out of his place, except thou repent.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But this thou hast, that thou hatest the deeds of the Nicolaitans, which I also hate.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches; To him that overcometh will I give to eat of the tree of life, which is in the midst of the paradise of God.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And unto the angel of the church in Smyrna write; These things saith the first and the last, which was dead, and is alive;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;I know thy works, and tribulation, and poverty, (but thou art rich) and &lt;i&gt;I know&lt;/i&gt; the blasphemy of them which say they are Jews, and are not, but &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; the synagogue of Satan.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Fear none of those things which thou shalt suffer: behold, the devil shall cast &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; of you into prison, that ye may be tried; and ye shall have tribulation ten days: be thou faithful unto death, and I will give thee a crown of life.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches; He that overcometh shall not be hurt of the second death.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And to the angel of the church in Pergamos write; These things saith he which hath the sharp sword with two edges;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;I know thy works, and where thou dwellest, &lt;i&gt;even&lt;/i&gt; where Satan's seat &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt;: and thou holdest fast my name, and hast not denied my faith, even in those days wherein Antipas &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; my faithful martyr, who was slain among you, where Satan dwelleth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But I have a few things against thee, because thou hast there them that hold the doctrine of Balaam, who taught Balac to cast a stumblingblock before the children of Israel, to eat things sacrificed unto idols, and to commit fornication.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;So hast thou also them that hold the doctrine of the Nicolaitans, which thing I hate.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Repent; or else I will come unto thee quickly, and will fight against them with the sword of my mouth.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches; To him that overcometh will I give to eat of the hidden manna, and will give him a white stone, and in the stone a new name written, which no man knoweth saving he that receiveth &lt;i&gt;it&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And unto the angel of the church in Thyatira write; These things saith the Son of God, who hath his eyes like unto a flame of fire, and his feet &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; like fine brass;&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;I know thy works, and charity, and service, and faith, and thy patience, and thy works; and the last &lt;i&gt;to be&lt;/i&gt; more than the first.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Notwithstanding I have a few things against thee, because thou sufferest that woman Jezebel, which calleth herself a prophetess, to teach and to seduce my servants to commit fornication, and to eat things sacrificed unto idols.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And I gave her space to repent of her fornication; and she repented not.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="22" id="v22">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Behold, I will cast her into a bed, and them that commit adultery with her into great tribulation, except they repent of their deeds.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="23" id="v23">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And I will kill her children with death; and all the churches shall know that I am he which searcheth the reins and hearts: and I will give unto every one of you according to your works.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="24" id="v24">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But unto you I say, and unto the rest in Thyatira, as many as have not this doctrine, and which have not known the depths of Satan, as they speak; I will put upon you none other burden.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="25" id="v25">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;But that which ye have &lt;i&gt;already&lt;/i&gt; hold fast till I come.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="26" id="v26">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And he that overcometh, and keepeth my works unto the end, to him will I give power over the nations:&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="27" id="v27">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And he shall rule them with a rod of iron; as the vessels of a potter shall they be broken to shivers: even as I received of my Father.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="28" id="v28">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;And I will give him the morning star.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="29" id="v29">&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;He that hath an ear, let him hear what the Spirit saith unto the churches.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>