<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bible version="kjv" title="King James Bible" biblePage="kjv_king_james_bible.html" otPage="ot_old_testament.html" ntPage="nt_new_testament.html">
  <book number="66" name="Revelation" bookPage="revelation.html" title="Revelation" chapterCount="22" testament="new" nt="true" ot="false" nextBook="genesis_1.html" nextTitle="Genesis" prevBook="jude_1.html" prevTitle="Jude">
    <chapter number="22" verseCount="21" nextChapter="genesis_1.html" nextTitle="Genesis 1" prevChapter="revelation_21.html" prevTitle="Revelation 21" chapterPage="revelation_">
      <verse number="1" id="v1">And he shewed me a pure river of water of life, clear as crystal, proceeding out of the throne of God and of the Lamb.</verse>
      <verse number="2" id="v2">In the midst of the street of it, and on either side of the river, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;was there&lt;/span&gt; the tree of life, which bare twelve &lt;span class="extra"&gt;manner of&lt;/span&gt; fruits, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; yielded her fruit every month: and the leaves of the tree &lt;span class="extra"&gt;were&lt;/span&gt; for the healing of the nations.</verse>
      <verse number="3" id="v3">And there shall be no more curse: but the throne of God and of the Lamb shall be in it; and his servants shall serve him:</verse>
      <verse number="4" id="v4">And they shall see his face; and his name &lt;span class="extra"&gt;shall be&lt;/span&gt; in their foreheads.</verse>
      <verse number="5" id="v5">And there shall be no night there; and they need no candle, neither light of the sun; for the Lord God giveth them light: and they shall reign for ever and ever.</verse>
      <verse number="6" id="v6">And he said unto me, These sayings &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; faithful and true: and the Lord God of the holy prophets sent his angel to shew unto his servants the things which must shortly be done.</verse>
      <verse number="7" id="v7">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;Behold, I come quickly: blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; he that keepeth the sayings of the prophecy of this book.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="8" id="v8">And I John saw these things, and heard &lt;span class="extra"&gt;them&lt;/span&gt;. And when I had heard and seen, I fell down to worship before the feet of the angel which shewed me these things.</verse>
      <verse number="9" id="v9">Then saith he unto me, See &lt;span class="extra"&gt;thou do it&lt;/span&gt; not: for I am thy fellowservant, and of thy brethren the prophets, and of them which keep the sayings of this book: worship God.</verse>
      <verse number="10" id="v10">And he saith unto me, Seal not the sayings of the prophecy of this book: for the time is at hand.</verse>
      <verse number="11" id="v11">He that is unjust, let him be unjust still: and he which is filthy, let him be filthy still: and he that is righteous, let him be righteous still: and he that is holy, let him be holy still.</verse>
      <verse number="12" id="v12">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;And, behold, I come quickly; and my reward &lt;span class="extra"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt; with me, to give every man according as his work shall be.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="13" id="v13">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I am Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the end, the first and the last.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="14" id="v14">Blessed &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; they that do his commandments, that they may have right to the tree of life, and may enter in through the gates into the city.</verse>
      <verse number="15" id="v15">For without &lt;span class="extra"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt; dogs, and sorcerers, and whoremongers, and murderers, and idolaters, and whosoever loveth and maketh a lie.</verse>
      <verse number="16" id="v16">&lt;span class="woc"&gt;I Jesus have sent mine angel to testify unto you these things in the churches. I am the root and the offspring of David, &lt;span class="extra"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; the bright and morning star.&lt;/span&gt;</verse>
      <verse number="17" id="v17">And the Spirit and the bride say, Come. And let him that heareth say, Come. And let him that is athirst come. And whosoever will, let him take the water of life freely.</verse>
      <verse number="18" id="v18">For I testify unto every man that heareth the words of the prophecy of this book, If any man shall add unto these things, God shall add unto him the plagues that are written in this book:</verse>
      <verse number="19" id="v19">And if any man shall take away from the words of the book of this prophecy, God shall take away his part out of the book of life, and out of the holy city, and &lt;span class="extra"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; the things which are written in this book.</verse>
      <verse number="20" id="v20">He which testifieth these things saith, &lt;span class="woc"&gt;Surely I come quickly.&lt;/span&gt; Amen. Even so, come, Lord Jesus.</verse>
      <verse number="21" id="v21">The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ &lt;span class="extra"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt; with you all. Amen.</verse>
    </chapter>
  </book>
</bible>